<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Arxivaction recognition</title><link></link><description>Arxiv paper</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 06:00:47 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.0.0</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Learning Domain-Invariant Temporal Dynamics for Few-Shot Action Recognition</title><link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12706v1</link><description>Few-shot action recognition aims at quickly adapting a pre-trained model tothe novel data with a distribution shift using only a limited number ofsamples. Key challenges include how to identify and leverage the transferableknowledge learned by the pre-trained model. Our central hypothesis is thattemporal invariance in the dynamic system between latent variables lends itselfto transferability (domain-invariance). We therefore propose DITeD, orDomain-Invariant Temporal Dynamics for knowledge transfer. To detect thetemporal invariance part, we propose a generative framework with a two-stagetraining strategy during pre-training. Specifically, we explicitly modelinvariant dynamics including temporal dynamic generation and transitions, andthe variant visual and domain encoders. Then we pre-train the model with theself-supervised signals to learn the representation. After that, we fix thewhole representation model and tune the classifier. During adaptation, we fixthe transferable temporal dynamics and update the image encoder. The efficacyof our approach is revealed by the superior accuracy of DITeD over leadingalternatives across standard few-shot action recognition datasets. Moreover, wevalidate that the learned temporal dynamic transition and temporal dynamicgeneration modules possess transferable qualities.</description><author>Yuke Li, Guangyi Chen, Ben Abramowitz, Stefano Anzellott, Donglai Wei</author><pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 04:09:58 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://arxiv.org/abs/2402.12706v1</guid></item><item><title>TikTokActions: A TikTok-Derived Video Dataset for Human Action Recognition</title><link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2402.08875v1</link><description>The increasing variety and quantity of tagged multimedia content on platformssuch as TikTok provides an opportunity to advance computer vision modeling. Wehave curated a distinctive dataset of 283,582 unique video clips categorizedunder 386 hashtags relating to modern human actions. We release this dataset asa valuable resource for building domain-specific foundation models for humanmovement modeling tasks such as action recognition. To validate this dataset,which we name TikTokActions, we perform two sets of experiments. First, wepretrain the state-of-the-art VideoMAEv2 with a ViT-base backbone onTikTokActions subset, and then fine-tune and evaluate on popular datasets suchas UCF101 and the HMDB51. We find that the performance of the model pre-trainedusing our Tik-Tok dataset is comparable to models trained on larger actionrecognition datasets (95.3% on UCF101 and 53.24% on HMDB51). Furthermore, ourinvestigation into the relationship between pre-training dataset size andfine-tuning performance reveals that beyond a certain threshold, theincremental benefit of larger training sets diminishes. This work introduces auseful TikTok video dataset that is available for public use and providesinsights into the marginal benefit of increasing pre-training dataset sizes forvideo-based foundation models.</description><author>Yang Qian, Yinan Sun, Ali Kargarandehkordi, Onur Cezmi Mutlu, Saimourya Surabhi, Pingyi Chen, Zain Jabbar, Dennis Paul Wall, Peter Washington</author><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:41:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://arxiv.org/abs/2402.08875v1</guid></item><item><title>Human Goal Recognition as Bayesian Inference: Investigating the Impact of Actions, Timing, and Goal Solvability</title><link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2402.10510v1</link><description>Goal recognition is a fundamental cognitive process that enables individualsto infer intentions based on available cues. Current goal recognitionalgorithms often take only observed actions as input, but here we use aBayesian framework to explore the role of actions, timing, and goal solvabilityin goal recognition. We analyze human responses to goal-recognition problems inthe Sokoban domain, and find that actions are assigned most importance, butthat timing and solvability also influence goal recognition in some cases,especially when actions are uninformative. We leverage these findings todevelop a goal recognition model that matches human inferences more closelythan do existing algorithms. Our work provides new insight into human goalrecognition and takes a step towards more human-like AI models.</description><author>Chenyuan Zhang, Charles Kemp, Nir Lipovetzky</author><pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 08:55:23 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://arxiv.org/abs/2402.10510v1</guid></item><item><title>Ain't Misbehavin' -- Using LLMs to Generate Expressive Robot Behavior in Conversations with the Tabletop Robot Haru</title><link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2402.11571v1</link><description>Social robots aim to establish long-term bonds with humans through engagingconversation. However, traditional conversational approaches, reliant onscripted interactions, often fall short in maintaining engaging conversations.This paper addresses this limitation by integrating large language models(LLMs) into social robots to achieve more dynamic and expressive conversations.We introduce a fully-automated conversation system that leverages LLMs togenerate robot responses with expressive behaviors, congruent with the robot'spersonality. We incorporate robot behavior with two modalities: 1) atext-to-speech (TTS) engine capable of various delivery styles, and 2) alibrary of physical actions for the robot. We develop a custom,state-of-the-art emotion recognition model to dynamically select the robot'stone of voice and utilize emojis from LLM output as cues for generating robotactions. A demo of our system is available here. To illuminate design andimplementation issues, we conduct a pilot study where volunteers chat with asocial robot using our proposed system, and we analyze their feedback,conducting a rigorous error analysis of chat transcripts. Feedback wasoverwhelmingly positive, with participants commenting on the robot's empathy,helpfulness, naturalness, and entertainment. Most negative feedback was due toautomatic speech recognition (ASR) errors which had limited impact onconversations. However, we observed a small class of errors, such as the LLMrepeating itself or hallucinating fictitious information and human responses,that have the potential to derail conversations, raising important issues forLLM application.</description><author>Zining Wang, Paul Reisert, Eric Nichols, Randy Gomez</author><pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 12:35:52 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://arxiv.org/abs/2402.11571v1</guid></item></channel></rss>