<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Arxivfresh papers</title><link></link><description>Arxiv paper</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 12:00:05 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.0.0</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>SpaceTimePilot: Generative Rendering of Dynamic Scenes Across Space and Time</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25075v1</link><description>We present SpaceTimePilot, a video diffusion model that disentangles space and time for controllable generative rendering. Given a monocular video, SpaceTimePilot can independently alter the camera viewpoint and the motion sequence within the generative process, re-rendering the scene for continuous and arbitrary exploration across space and time. To achieve this, we introduce an effective animation time-embedding mechanism in the diffusion process, allowing explicit control of the output video's motion sequence with respect to that of the source video. As no datasets provide paired videos of the same dynamic scene with continuous temporal variations, we propose a simple yet effective temporal-warping training scheme that repurposes existing multi-view datasets to mimic temporal differences. This strategy effectively supervises the model to learn temporal control and achieve robust space-time disentanglement. To further enhance the precision of dual control, we introduce two additional components: an improved camera-conditioning mechanism that allows altering the camera from the first frame, and CamxTime, the first synthetic space-and-time full-coverage rendering dataset that provides fully free space-time video trajectories within a scene. Joint training on the temporal-warping scheme and the CamxTime dataset yields more precise temporal control. We evaluate SpaceTimePilot on both real-world and synthetic data, demonstrating clear space-time disentanglement and strong results compared to prior work. Project page: https://zheninghuang.github.io/Space-Time-Pilot/ Code: https://github.com/ZheningHuang/spacetimepilot</description><author>Zhening Huang, Hyeonho Jeong, Xuelin Chen, Yulia Gryaditskaya, Tuanfeng Y. Wang, Joan Lasenby, Chun-Hao Huang</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:59:57 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25075v1</guid></item><item><title>GaMO: Geometry-aware Multi-view Diffusion Outpainting for Sparse-View 3D Reconstruction</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25073v1</link><description>Recent advances in 3D reconstruction have achieved remarkable progress in high-quality scene capture from dense multi-view imagery, yet struggle when input views are limited. Various approaches, including regularization techniques, semantic priors, and geometric constraints, have been implemented to address this challenge. Latest diffusion-based methods have demonstrated substantial improvements by generating novel views from new camera poses to augment training data, surpassing earlier regularization and prior-based techniques. Despite this progress, we identify three critical limitations in these state-of-the-art approaches: inadequate coverage beyond known view peripheries, geometric inconsistencies across generated views, and computationally expensive pipelines. We introduce GaMO (Geometry-aware Multi-view Outpainter), a framework that reformulates sparse-view reconstruction through multi-view outpainting. Instead of generating new viewpoints, GaMO expands the field of view from existing camera poses, which inherently preserves geometric consistency while providing broader scene coverage. Our approach employs multi-view conditioning and geometry-aware denoising strategies in a zero-shot manner without training. Extensive experiments on Replica and ScanNet++ demonstrate state-of-the-art reconstruction quality across 3, 6, and 9 input views, outperforming prior methods in PSNR and LPIPS, while achieving a $25\times$ speedup over SOTA diffusion-based methods with processing time under 10 minutes. Project page: https://yichuanh.github.io/GaMO/</description><author>Yi-Chuan Huang, Hao-Jen Chien, Chin-Yang Lin, Ying-Huan Chen, Yu-Lun Liu</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:59:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25073v1</guid></item><item><title>Coordinated Humanoid Manipulation with Choice Policies</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25072v1</link><description>Humanoid robots hold great promise for operating in human-centric environments, yet achieving robust whole-body coordination across the head, hands, and legs remains a major challenge. We present a system that combines a modular teleoperation interface with a scalable learning framework to address this problem. Our teleoperation design decomposes humanoid control into intuitive submodules, which include hand-eye coordination, grasp primitives, arm end-effector tracking, and locomotion. This modularity allows us to collect high-quality demonstrations efficiently. Building on this, we introduce Choice Policy, an imitation learning approach that generates multiple candidate actions and learns to score them. This architecture enables both fast inference and effective modeling of multimodal behaviors. We validate our approach on two real-world tasks: dishwasher loading and whole-body loco-manipulation for whiteboard wiping. Experiments show that Choice Policy significantly outperforms diffusion policies and standard behavior cloning. Furthermore, our results indicate that hand-eye coordination is critical for success in long-horizon tasks. Our work demonstrates a practical path toward scalable data collection and learning for coordinated humanoid manipulation in unstructured environments.</description><author>Haozhi Qi, Yen-Jen Wang, Toru Lin, Brent Yi, Yi Ma, Koushil Sreenath, Jitendra Malik</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:59:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25072v1</guid></item><item><title>Edit3r: Instant 3D Scene Editing from Sparse Unposed Images</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25071v1</link><description>We present Edit3r, a feed-forward framework that reconstructs and edits 3D scenes in a single pass from unposed, view-inconsistent, instruction-edited images. Unlike prior methods requiring per-scene optimization, Edit3r directly predicts instruction-aligned 3D edits, enabling fast and photorealistic rendering without optimization or pose estimation. A key challenge in training such a model lies in the absence of multi-view consistent edited images for supervision. We address this with (i) a SAM2-based recoloring strategy that generates reliable, cross-view-consistent supervision, and (ii) an asymmetric input strategy that pairs a recolored reference view with raw auxiliary views, encouraging the network to fuse and align disparate observations. At inference, our model effectively handles images edited by 2D methods such as InstructPix2Pix, despite not being exposed to such edits during training. For large-scale quantitative evaluation, we introduce DL3DV-Edit-Bench, a benchmark built on the DL3DV test split, featuring 20 diverse scenes, 4 edit types and 100 edits in total. Comprehensive quantitative and qualitative results show that Edit3r achieves superior semantic alignment and enhanced 3D consistency compared to recent baselines, while operating at significantly higher inference speed, making it promising for real-time 3D editing applications.</description><author>Jiageng Liu, Weijie Lyu, Xueting Li, Yejie Guo, Ming-Hsuan Yang</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:59:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25071v1</guid></item><item><title>Scaling Open-Ended Reasoning to Predict the Future</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25070v1</link><description>High-stakes decision making involves reasoning under uncertainty about the future. In this work, we train language models to make predictions on open-ended forecasting questions. To scale up training data, we synthesize novel forecasting questions from global events reported in daily news, using a fully automated, careful curation recipe. We train the Qwen3 thinking models on our dataset, OpenForesight. To prevent leakage of future information during training and evaluation, we use an offline news corpus, both for data generation and retrieval in our forecasting system. Guided by a small validation set, we show the benefits of retrieval, and an improved reward function for reinforcement learning (RL). Once we obtain our final forecasting system, we perform held-out testing between May to August 2025. Our specialized model, OpenForecaster 8B, matches much larger proprietary models, with our training improving the accuracy, calibration, and consistency of predictions. We find calibration improvements from forecasting training generalize across popular benchmarks. We open-source all our models, code, and data to make research on language model forecasting broadly accessible.</description><author>Nikhil Chandak, Shashwat Goel, Ameya Prabhu, Moritz Hardt, Jonas Geiping</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:59:51 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25070v1</guid></item><item><title>FineTec: Fine-Grained Action Recognition Under Temporal Corruption via Skeleton Decomposition and Sequence Completion</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25067v1</link><description>Recognizing fine-grained actions from temporally corrupted skeleton sequences remains a significant challenge, particularly in real-world scenarios where online pose estimation often yields substantial missing data. Existing methods often struggle to accurately recover temporal dynamics and fine-grained spatial structures, resulting in the loss of subtle motion cues crucial for distinguishing similar actions. To address this, we propose FineTec, a unified framework for Fine-grained action recognition under Temporal Corruption. FineTec first restores a base skeleton sequence from corrupted input using context-aware completion with diverse temporal masking. Next, a skeleton-based spatial decomposition module partitions the skeleton into five semantic regions, further divides them into dynamic and static subgroups based on motion variance, and generates two augmented skeleton sequences via targeted perturbation. These, along with the base sequence, are then processed by a physics-driven estimation module, which utilizes Lagrangian dynamics to estimate joint accelerations. Finally, both the fused skeleton position sequence and the fused acceleration sequence are jointly fed into a GCN-based action recognition head. Extensive experiments on both coarse-grained (NTU-60, NTU-120) and fine-grained (Gym99, Gym288) benchmarks show that FineTec significantly outperforms previous methods under various levels of temporal corruption. Specifically, FineTec achieves top-1 accuracies of 89.1% and 78.1% on the challenging Gym99-severe and Gym288-severe settings, respectively, demonstrating its robustness and generalizability. Code and datasets could be found at https://smartdianlab.github.io/projects-FineTec/.</description><author>Dian Shao, Mingfei Shi, Like Liu</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:59:12 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25067v1</guid></item><item><title>From Inpainting to Editing: A Self-Bootstrapping Framework for Context-Rich Visual Dubbing</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25066v1</link><description>Audio-driven visual dubbing aims to synchronize a video's lip movements with new speech, but is fundamentally challenged by the lack of ideal training data: paired videos where only a subject's lip movements differ while all other visual conditions are identical. Existing methods circumvent this with a mask-based inpainting paradigm, where an incomplete visual conditioning forces models to simultaneously hallucinate missing content and sync lips, leading to visual artifacts, identity drift, and poor synchronization. In this work, we propose a novel self-bootstrapping framework that reframes visual dubbing from an ill-posed inpainting task into a well-conditioned video-to-video editing problem. Our approach employs a Diffusion Transformer, first as a data generator, to synthesize ideal training data: a lip-altered companion video for each real sample, forming visually aligned video pairs. A DiT-based audio-driven editor is then trained on these pairs end-to-end, leveraging the complete and aligned input video frames to focus solely on precise, audio-driven lip modifications. This complete, frame-aligned input conditioning forms a rich visual context for the editor, providing it with complete identity cues, scene interactions, and continuous spatiotemporal dynamics. Leveraging this rich context fundamentally enables our method to achieve highly accurate lip sync, faithful identity preservation, and exceptional robustness against challenging in-the-wild scenarios. We further introduce a timestep-adaptive multi-phase learning strategy as a necessary component to disentangle conflicting editing objectives across diffusion timesteps, thereby facilitating stable training and yielding enhanced lip synchronization and visual fidelity. Additionally, we propose ContextDubBench, a comprehensive benchmark dataset for robust evaluation in diverse and challenging practical application scenarios.</description><author>Xu He, Haoxian Zhang, Hejia Chen, Changyuan Zheng, Liyang Chen, Songlin Tang, Jiehui Huang, Xiaoqiang Liu, Pengfei Wan, Zhiyong Wu</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:58:30 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25066v1</guid></item><item><title>Vulcan: Instance-Optimal Systems Heuristics Through LLM-Driven Search</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25065v1</link><description>Resource-management tasks in modern operating and distributed systems continue to rely primarily on hand-designed heuristics for tasks such as scheduling, caching, or active queue management. Designing performant heuristics is an expensive, time-consuming process that we are forced to continuously go through due to the constant flux of hardware, workloads and environments. We propose a new alternative: synthesizing instance-optimal heuristics -- specialized for the exact workloads and hardware where they will be deployed -- using code-generating large language models (LLMs). To make this synthesis tractable, Vulcan separates policy and mechanism through LLM-friendly, task-agnostic interfaces. With these interfaces, users specify the inputs and objectives of their desired policy, while Vulcan searches for performant policies via evolutionary search over LLM-generated code. This interface is expressive enough to capture a wide range of system policies, yet sufficiently constrained to allow even small, inexpensive LLMs to generate correct and executable code. We use Vulcan to synthesize performant heuristics for cache eviction and memory tiering, and find that these heuristics outperform all human-designed state-of-the-art algorithms by upto 69% and 7.9% in performance for each of these tasks respectively.</description><author>Rohit Dwivedula, Divyanshu Saxena, Sujay Yadalam, Daehyeok Kim, Aditya Akella</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:58:19 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25065v1</guid></item><item><title>Deep sequence models tend to memorize geometrically; it is unclear why</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.26745v2</link><description>Deep sequence models are said to store atomic facts predominantly in the form of associative memory: a brute-force lookup of co-occurring entities. We identify a dramatically different form of storage of atomic facts that we term as geometric memory. Here, the model has synthesized embeddings encoding novel global relationships between all entities, including ones that do not co-occur in training. Such storage is powerful: for instance, we show how it transforms a hard reasoning task involving an $\ell$-fold composition into an easy-to-learn $1$-step navigation task. From this phenomenon, we extract fundamental aspects of neural embedding geometries that are hard to explain. We argue that the rise of such a geometry, as against a lookup of local associations, cannot be straightforwardly attributed to typical supervisory, architectural, or optimizational pressures. Counterintuitively, a geometry is learned even when it is more complex than the brute-force lookup. Then, by analyzing a connection to Node2Vec, we demonstrate how the geometry stems from a spectral bias that -- in contrast to prevailing theories -- indeed arises naturally despite the lack of various pressures. This analysis also points out to practitioners a visible headroom to make Transformer memory more strongly geometric. We hope the geometric view of parametric memory encourages revisiting the default intuitions that guide researchers in areas like knowledge acquisition, capacity, discovery, and unlearning.</description><author>Shahriar Noroozizadeh, Vaishnavh Nagarajan, Elan Rosenfeld, Sanjiv Kumar</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:57:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.26745v2</guid></item><item><title>Many Minds from One Model: Bayesian Transformers for Population Intelligence</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25063v1</link><description>Despite their scale and success, modern transformers are almost universally trained as single-minded systems: optimization produces one deterministic set of parameters, representing a single functional hypothesis about the data. Motivated by the idea that intelligence emerge from many minds, we propose Population Bayesian Transformers (B-Trans), which transform a standard Large Language Model into a Bayesian Transformer model to supports sampling diverse yet coherent model instances from a single set of pre-trained weights. B-Trans introduces a Bayesian-motivated posterior proxy by treating the bias-like offsets in normalization layers as stochastic variables with a Gaussian variational approximation, inducing a distribution over model behavior without the cost of training full Bayesian neural networks. Sampling from this proxy yields a set of model instances with diverse behaviors while maintaining general competence. To preserve coherence within each generation, we freeze the sampled noise at the sequence level, enforcing temporal consistency across tokens. B-Trans allows for population-level decision-making, where aggregating predictions across sampled individuals significantly enhances exploration. Experiments across zero-shot generation, Reinforcement Learning with Verifiable Rewards (RLVR), and RL without explicit labels demonstrate that B-Trans effectively leverage the wisdom of crowds, yielding superior semantic diversity while achieving better task performance compared to deterministic baselines.</description><author>Diji Yang, Yi Zhang</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:56:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25063v1</guid></item><item><title>On the geometry and topology of representations: the manifolds of modular addition</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25060v1</link><description>The Clock and Pizza interpretations, associated with architectures differing in either uniform or learnable attention, were introduced to argue that different architectural designs can yield distinct circuits for modular addition. In this work, we show that this is not the case, and that both uniform attention and trainable attention architectures implement the same algorithm via topologically and geometrically equivalent representations. Our methodology goes beyond the interpretation of individual neurons and weights. Instead, we identify all of the neurons corresponding to each learned representation and then study the collective group of neurons as one entity. This method reveals that each learned representation is a manifold that we can study utilizing tools from topology. Based on this insight, we can statistically analyze the learned representations across hundreds of circuits to demonstrate the similarity between learned modular addition circuits that arise naturally from common deep learning paradigms.</description><author>Gabriela Moisescu-Pareja, Gavin McCracken, Harley Wiltzer, Vincent Létourneau, Colin Daniels, Doina Precup, Jonathan Love</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:53:19 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25060v1</guid></item><item><title>Reliable and Resilient Collective Communication Library for LLM Training and Serving</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25059v1</link><description>Modern ML training and inference now span tens to tens of thousands of GPUs, where network faults can waste 10--15\% of GPU hours due to slow recovery. Common network errors and link fluctuations trigger timeouts that often terminate entire jobs, forcing expensive checkpoint rollback during training and request reprocessing during inference. We present R$^2$CCL, a fault-tolerant communication library that provides lossless, low-overhead failover by exploiting multi-NIC hardware. R$^2$CCL performs rapid connection migration, bandwidth-aware load redistribution, and resilient collective algorithms to maintain progress under failures. We evaluate R$^2$CCL on two 8-GPU H100 InfiniBand servers and via large-scale ML simulators modeling hundreds of GPUs with diverse failure patterns. Experiments show that R$^2$CCL is highly robust to NIC failures, incurring less than 1\% training and less than 3\% inference overheads. R$^2$CCL outperforms baselines AdapCC and DejaVu by 12.18$\times$ and 47$\times$, respectively.</description><author>Wei Wang, Nengneng Yu, Sixian Xiong, Zaoxing Liu</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:53:11 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25059v1</guid></item><item><title>Context-aware LLM-based AI Agents for Human-centered Energy Management Systems in Smart Buildings</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25055v1</link><description>This study presents a conceptual framework and a prototype assessment for Large Language Model (LLM)-based Building Energy Management System (BEMS) AI agents to facilitate context-aware energy management in smart buildings through natural language interaction. The proposed framework comprises three modules: perception (sensing), central control (brain), and action (actuation and user interaction), forming a closed feedback loop that captures, analyzes, and interprets energy data to respond intelligently to user queries and manage connected appliances. By leveraging the autonomous data analytics capabilities of LLMs, the BEMS AI agent seeks to offer context-aware insights into energy consumption, cost prediction, and device scheduling, thereby addressing limitations in existing energy management systems. The prototype's performance was evaluated using 120 user queries across four distinct real-world residential energy datasets and different evaluation metrics, including latency, functionality, capability, accuracy, and cost-effectiveness. The generalizability of the framework was demonstrated using ANOVA tests. The results revealed promising performance, measured by response accuracy in device control (86%), memory-related tasks (97%), scheduling and automation (74%), and energy analysis (77%), while more complex cost estimation tasks highlighted areas for improvement with an accuracy of 49%. This benchmarking study moves toward formalizing the assessment of LLM-based BEMS AI agents and identifying future research directions, emphasizing the trade-off between response accuracy and computational efficiency.</description><author>Tianzhi He, Farrokh Jazizadeh</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:51:19 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25055v1</guid></item><item><title>AdaGReS:Adaptive Greedy Context Selection via Redundancy-Aware Scoring for Token-Budgeted RAG</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25052v1</link><description>Retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) is highly sensitive to the quality of selected context, yet standard top-k retrieval often returns redundant or near-duplicate chunks that waste token budget and degrade downstream generation. We present AdaGReS, a redundancy-aware context selection framework for token-budgeted RAG that optimizes a set-level objective combining query-chunk relevance and intra-set redundancy penalties. AdaGReS performs greedy selection under a token-budget constraint using marginal gains derived from the objective, and introduces a closed-form, instance-adaptive calibration of the relevance-redundancy trade-off parameter to eliminate manual tuning and adapt to candidate-pool statistics and budget limits. We further provide a theoretical analysis showing that the proposed objective exhibits epsilon-approximate submodularity under practical embedding similarity conditions, yielding near-optimality guarantees for greedy selection. Experiments on open-domain question answering (Natural Questions) and a high-redundancy biomedical (drug) corpus demonstrate consistent improvements in redundancy control and context quality, translating to better end-to-end answer quality and robustness across settings.</description><author>Chao Peng, Bin Wang, Zhilei Long, Jinfang Sheng</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:48:07 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25052v1</guid></item><item><title>Semantic Parsing with Candidate Expressions for Knowledge Base Question Answering</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.00414v4</link><description>Semantic parsers convert natural language to logical forms, which can be evaluated on knowledge bases (KBs) to produce denotations. Recent semantic parsers have been developed with sequence-to-sequence (seq2seq) pre-trained language models (PLMs) or large language models, where the models treat logical forms as sequences of tokens. For syntactic and semantic validity, the semantic parsers use grammars that enable constrained decoding. However, the grammars lack the ability to utilize large information of KBs, although logical forms contain representations of KB elements, such as entities or relations. In this work, we propose a grammar augmented with candidate expressions for semantic parsing on a large KB with a seq2seq PLM. The grammar defines actions as production rules, and our semantic parser predicts actions during inference under the constraints by types and candidate expressions. We apply the grammar to knowledge base question answering, where the constraints by candidate expressions assist a semantic parser to generate valid KB elements. We also introduce two special rules, sub-type inference and union types, and a mask caching algorithm. In particular, sub-type inference and the mask caching algorithm greatly increase the decoding speed of our semantic parser. We experimented on two benchmarks, KQA Pro and Overnight, where the constraints by candidate expressions increased the accuracy of our semantic parser, whether it was trained with strong supervision or weak supervision. In addition, our semantic parser had a fast decoding speed in the experiments. Our source code is publicly available at https://github.com/daehwannam/candexpr-sp.git.</description><author>Daehwan Nam, Gary Geunbae Lee</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:45:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.00414v4</guid></item><item><title>End-to-End Test-Time Training for Long Context</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.23675v2</link><description>We formulate long-context language modeling as a problem in continual learning rather than architecture design. Under this formulation, we only use a standard architecture -- a Transformer with sliding-window attention. However, our model continues learning at test time via next-token prediction on the given context, compressing the context it reads into its weights. In addition, we improve the model's initialization for learning at test time via meta-learning at training time. Overall, our method, a form of Test-Time Training (TTT), is End-to-End (E2E) both at test time (via next-token prediction) and training time (via meta-learning), in contrast to previous forms. We conduct extensive experiments with a focus on scaling properties. In particular, for 3B models trained with 164B tokens, our method (TTT-E2E) scales with context length in the same way as Transformer with full attention, while others, such as Mamba 2 and Gated DeltaNet, do not. However, similar to RNNs, TTT-E2E has constant inference latency regardless of context length, making it 2.7 times faster than full attention for 128K context. Our code is publicly available.</description><author>Arnuv Tandon, Karan Dalal, Xinhao Li, Daniel Koceja, Marcel Rød, Sam Buchanan, Xiaolong Wang, Jure Leskovec, Sanmi Koyejo, Tatsunori Hashimoto, Carlos Guestrin, Jed McCaleb, Yejin Choi, Yu Sun</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:41:09 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.23675v2</guid></item><item><title>Generative Classifiers Avoid Shortcut Solutions</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25034v1</link><description>Discriminative approaches to classification often learn shortcuts that hold in-distribution but fail even under minor distribution shift. This failure mode stems from an overreliance on features that are spuriously correlated with the label. We show that generative classifiers, which use class-conditional generative models, can avoid this issue by modeling all features, both core and spurious, instead of mainly spurious ones. These generative classifiers are simple to train, avoiding the need for specialized augmentations, strong regularization, extra hyperparameters, or knowledge of the specific spurious correlations to avoid. We find that diffusion-based and autoregressive generative classifiers achieve state-of-the-art performance on five standard image and text distribution shift benchmarks and reduce the impact of spurious correlations in realistic applications, such as medical or satellite datasets. Finally, we carefully analyze a Gaussian toy setting to understand the inductive biases of generative classifiers, as well as the data properties that determine when generative classifiers outperform discriminative ones.</description><author>Alexander C. Li, Ananya Kumar, Deepak Pathak</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:31:46 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25034v1</guid></item><item><title>Plan Verification for LLM-Based Embodied Task Completion Agents</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.02761v4</link><description>Large language model (LLM) based task plans and corresponding human demonstrations for embodied AI may be noisy, with unnecessary actions, redundant navigation, and logical errors that reduce policy quality. We propose an iterative verification framework in which a Judge LLM critiques action sequences and a Planner LLM applies the revisions, yielding progressively cleaner and more spatially coherent trajectories. Unlike rule-based approaches, our method relies on natural language prompting, enabling broad generalization across error types including irrelevant actions, contradictions, and missing steps. On a set of manually annotated actions from the TEACh embodied AI dataset, our framework achieves up to 90% recall and 100% precision across four state-of-the-art LLMs (GPT o4-mini, DeepSeek-R1, Gemini 2.5, LLaMA 4 Scout). The refinement loop converges quickly, with 96.5% of sequences requiring at most three iterations, while improving both temporal efficiency and spatial action organization. Crucially, the method preserves human error-recovery patterns rather than collapsing them, supporting future work on robust corrective behavior. By establishing plan verification as a reliable LLM capability for spatial planning and action refinement, we provide a scalable path to higher-quality training data for imitation learning in embodied AI.</description><author>Ananth Hariharan, Vardhan Dongre, Dilek Hakkani-Tür, Gokhan Tur</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:31:30 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.02761v4</guid></item><item><title>Towards Generalisable Foundation Models for Brain MRI</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.23415v3</link><description>Foundation models in artificial intelligence (AI) are transforming medical imaging by enabling general-purpose feature learning from large-scale, unlabeled datasets. In this work, we introduce BrainFound, a self-supervised foundation model for brain MRI, built by extending DINO-v2, a vision transformer originally designed for 2D natural images. BrainFound adapts DINO-v2 to model full 3D brain anatomy by incorporating volumetric information from sequential MRI slices, moving beyond conventional single-slice paradigms. It supports both single- and multimodal inputs, enabling a broad range of downstream tasks, including disease detection and image segmentation, while generalising across varied imaging protocols and clinical scenarios. We show that BrainFound consistently outperforms existing self-supervised pretraining strategies and supervised baselines, particularly in label-scarce and multi-contrast settings. By integrating information from diverse 3D MRI modalities (e.g., T1, T2, FLAIR), it enhances diagnostic accuracy and reduces dependency on extensive expert annotations. This flexibility makes BrainFound a scalable and practical solution for 3D neuroimaging pipelines, with significant potential for clinical deployment and research innovation.</description><author>Moona Mazher, Geoff J. M. Parker, Daniel C. Alexander</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:26:04 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.23415v3</guid></item><item><title>Modeling Language as a Sequence of Thoughts</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25026v1</link><description>Transformer language models can generate strikingly natural text by modeling language as a sequence of tokens. Yet, by relying primarily on surface-level co-occurrence statistics, they fail to form globally consistent latent representations of entities and events, lack of which contributes to brittleness in relational direction (e.g., reversal curse), contextualization errors, and data inefficiency. On the other hand, cognitive science shows that human comprehension involves converting the input linguistic stream into compact, event-like representations that persist in memory while verbatim form is short-lived. Motivated by this view, we introduce Thought Gestalt (TG) model, a recurrent Transformer that models language at two levels of abstraction - tokens and sentence-level "thought" states. TG generates the tokens of one sentence at a time while cross-attending to a memory of prior sentence representations. In TG, token and sentence representations are generated using the same set of model parameters and trained with a single objective, the next-token cross-entropy: by retaining the computation graph of sentence representations written to memory, gradients from future token losses flow backward through cross-attention to optimize the parameters generating earlier sentence vectors. In scaling experiments, TG consistently improves efficiency over matched GPT-2 runs, among other baselines, with scaling fits indicating GPT-2 requires ~5-8% more data and ~33-42% more parameters to match TG's loss. TG also reduces errors on relational direction generalization on a father-son reversal curse probe.</description><author>Nasim Borazjanizadeh, James McClelland</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:24:57 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25026v1</guid></item><item><title>ResponseRank: Data-Efficient Reward Modeling through Preference Strength Learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25023v1</link><description>Binary choices, as often used for reinforcement learning from human feedback (RLHF), convey only the direction of a preference. A person may choose apples over oranges and bananas over grapes, but which preference is stronger? Strength is crucial for decision-making under uncertainty and generalization of preference models, but hard to measure reliably. Metadata such as response times and inter-annotator agreement can serve as proxies for strength, but are often noisy and confounded. We propose ResponseRank to address the challenge of learning from noisy strength signals. Our method uses relative differences in proxy signals to rank responses to pairwise comparisons by their inferred preference strength. To control for systemic variation, we compare signals only locally within carefully constructed strata. This enables robust learning of utility differences consistent with strength-derived rankings while making minimal assumptions about the strength signal. Our contributions are threefold: (1) ResponseRank, a novel method that robustly learns preference strength by leveraging locally valid relative strength signals; (2) empirical evidence of improved sample efficiency and robustness across diverse tasks: synthetic preference learning (with simulated response times), language modeling (with annotator agreement), and RL control tasks (with simulated episode returns); and (3) the Pearson Distance Correlation (PDC), a novel metric that isolates cardinal utility learning from ordinal accuracy.</description><author>Timo Kaufmann, Yannick Metz, Daniel Keim, Eyke Hüllermeier</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:21:52 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25023v1</guid></item><item><title>Statistical Taylor Expansion: A New and Path-Independent Method for Uncertainty Analysis</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.01223v14</link><description>As a rigorous statistical approach, statistical Taylor expansion extends the conventional Taylor expansion by replacing precise input variables with random variables of known distributions, to compute means and standard deviations of the results. Statistical Taylor expansion traces the dependency of the input uncertainties in the intermediate steps, so that the variables in the intermediate analytic expressions can no longer be regarded as independent of each other, and the result of the analytic expression is path independent. Thus, it differs fundamentally from the conventional common approaches in applied mathematics which optimize execution path for each calculation. In fact, statistical Taylor expansion may standardize numerical calculations for analytic expressions. Its statistical nature allows religious testing of its result when the sample size is large enough. This paper also introduces an implementation of statistical Taylor expansion called variance arithmetic and presents corresponding test results in a very wide range of mathematical applications. Another important conclusion of this paper is that the numerical errors in the library function can have significant effects on the result. For example, the periodic numerical errors in the trigonometric library functions can resonate with periodic signals, producing large numerical errors in the results.</description><author>Chengpu Wang</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:21:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.01223v14</guid></item><item><title>Convergence of the generalization error for deep gradient flow methods for PDEs</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25017v1</link><description>The aim of this article is to provide a firm mathematical foundation for the application of deep gradient flow methods (DGFMs) for the solution of (high-dimensional) partial differential equations (PDEs). We decompose the generalization error of DGFMs into an approximation and a training error. We first show that the solution of PDEs that satisfy reasonable and verifiable assumptions can be approximated by neural networks, thus the approximation error tends to zero as the number of neurons tends to infinity. Then, we derive the gradient flow that the training process follows in the ``wide network limit'' and analyze the limit of this flow as the training time tends to infinity. These results combined show that the generalization error of DGFMs tends to zero as the number of neurons and the training time tend to infinity.</description><author>Chenguang Liu, Antonis Papapantoleon, Jasper Rou</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:11:51 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25017v1</guid></item><item><title>MAMA-Memeia! Multi-Aspect Multi-Agent Collaboration for Depressive Symptoms Identification in Memes</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25015v1</link><description>Over the past years, memes have evolved from being exclusively a medium of humorous exchanges to one that allows users to express a range of emotions freely and easily. With the ever-growing utilization of memes in expressing depressive sentiments, we conduct a study on identifying depressive symptoms exhibited by memes shared by users of online social media platforms. We introduce RESTOREx as a vital resource for detecting depressive symptoms in memes on social media through the Large Language Model (LLM) generated and human-annotated explanations. We introduce MAMAMemeia, a collaborative multi-agent multi-aspect discussion framework grounded in the clinical psychology method of Cognitive Analytic Therapy (CAT) Competencies. MAMAMemeia improves upon the current state-of-the-art by 7.55% in macro-F1 and is established as the new benchmark compared to over 30 methods.</description><author>Siddhant Agarwal, Adya Dhuler, Polly Ruhnke, Melvin Speisman, Md Shad Akhtar, Shweta Yadav</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:06:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25015v1</guid></item><item><title>Spiking Manifesto</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.11843v2</link><description>Practically everything computers do is better, faster, and more power-efficient than the brain. For example, a calculator performs numerical computations more energy-efficiently than any human. Yet modern AI models are a thousand times less efficient than the brain. These models rely on larger and larger artificial neural networks (ANNs) to boost their encoding capacity, requiring GPUs to perform large-scale matrix multiplications. In contrast, the brain's spiking neural networks (SNNs) exhibit factorially explosive encoding capacity and compute through the polychronization of spikes rather than explicit matrix-vector products, resulting in lower energy requirements. This manifesto proposes a paradigm for framing popular AI models in terms of spiking networks and polychronization, and for interpreting spiking activity as nature's way of implementing look-up tables. This suggests a path toward converting AI models into a novel class of architectures with much smaller size yet combinatorially large encoding capacity, offering the promise of a thousandfold improvement in performance. Code is available at https://github.com/izhikevich/SNN</description><author>Eugene Izhikevich</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:03:46 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.11843v2</guid></item><item><title>Diffusion Language Models are Provably Optimal Parallel Samplers</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25014v1</link><description>Diffusion language models (DLMs) have emerged as a promising alternative to autoregressive models for faster inference via parallel token generation. We provide a rigorous foundation for this advantage by formalizing a model of parallel sampling and showing that DLMs augmented with polynomial-length chain-of-thought (CoT) can simulate any parallel sampling algorithm using an optimal number of sequential steps. Consequently, whenever a target distribution can be generated using a small number of sequential steps, a DLM can be used to generate the distribution using the same number of optimal sequential steps. However, without the ability to modify previously revealed tokens, DLMs with CoT can still incur large intermediate footprints. We prove that enabling remasking (converting unmasked tokens to masks) or revision (converting unmasked tokens to other unmasked tokens) together with CoT further allows DLMs to simulate any parallel sampling algorithm with optimal space complexity. We further justify the advantage of revision by establishing a strict expressivity gap: DLMs with revision or remasking are strictly more expressive than those without. Our results not only provide a theoretical justification for the promise of DLMs as the most efficient parallel sampler, but also advocate for enabling revision in DLMs.</description><author>Haozhe Jiang, Nika Haghtalab, Lijie Chen</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:03:05 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25014v1</guid></item><item><title>FoundationSLAM: Unleashing the Power of Depth Foundation Models for End-to-End Dense Visual SLAM</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25008v1</link><description>We present FoundationSLAM, a learning-based monocular dense SLAM system that addresses the absence of geometric consistency in previous flow-based approaches for accurate and robust tracking and mapping. Our core idea is to bridge flow estimation with geometric reasoning by leveraging the guidance from foundation depth models. To this end, we first develop a Hybrid Flow Network that produces geometry-aware correspondences, enabling consistent depth and pose inference across diverse keyframes. To enforce global consistency, we propose a Bi-Consistent Bundle Adjustment Layer that jointly optimizes keyframe pose and depth under multi-view constraints. Furthermore, we introduce a Reliability-Aware Refinement mechanism that dynamically adapts the flow update process by distinguishing between reliable and uncertain regions, forming a closed feedback loop between matching and optimization. Extensive experiments demonstrate that FoundationSLAM achieves superior trajectory accuracy and dense reconstruction quality across multiple challenging datasets, while running in real-time at 18 FPS, demonstrating strong generalization to various scenarios and practical applicability of our method.</description><author>Yuchen Wu, Jiahe Li, Fabio Tosi, Matteo Poggi, Jin Zheng, Xiao Bai</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 17:57:45 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25008v1</guid></item><item><title>Hybrid Learning: A Novel Combination of Self-Supervised and Supervised Learning for Joint MRI Reconstruction and Denoising in Low-Field MRI</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.05703v2</link><description>Deep learning has demonstrated strong potential for MRI reconstruction. However, conventional supervised learning requires high-quality, high-SNR references for network training, which are often difficult or impossible to obtain in different scenarios, particularly in low-field MRI. Self-supervised learning provides an alternative by removing the need for training references, but its reconstruction performance can degrade when the baseline SNR is low. To address these limitations, we propose hybrid learning, a two-stage training framework that integrates self-supervised and supervised learning for joint MRI reconstruction and denoising when only low-SNR training references are available. Hybrid learning is implemented in two sequential stages. In the first stage, self-supervised learning is applied to fully sampled low-SNR data to generate higher-quality pseudo-references. In the second stage, these pseudo-references are used as targets for supervised learning to reconstruct and denoise undersampled noisy data. The proposed technique was evaluated in multiple experiments involving simulated and real low-field MRI in the lung and brain at different field strengths. Hybrid learning consistently improved image quality over both standard self-supervised learning and supervised learning with noisy training references at different acceleration rates, noise levels, and field strengths, achieving higher SSIM and lower NMSE. The hybrid learning approach is effective for both Cartesian and non-Cartesian acquisitions. Hybrid learning provides an effective solution for training deep MRI reconstruction models in the absence of high-SNR references. By improving image quality in low-SNR settings, particularly for low-field MRI, it holds promise for broader clinical adoption of deep learning-based reconstruction methods.</description><author>Haoyang Pei, Nikola Janjuvsevic, Renqing Luo, Ding Xia, Xiang Xu, William Moore, Yao Wang, Hersh Chandarana, Li Feng</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 17:51:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.05703v2</guid></item><item><title>Bi-C2R: Bidirectional Continual Compatible Representation for Re-indexing Free Lifelong Person Re-identification</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25000v1</link><description>Lifelong person Re-IDentification (L-ReID) exploits sequentially collected data to continuously train and update a ReID model, focusing on the overall performance of all data. Its main challenge is to avoid the catastrophic forgetting problem of old knowledge while training on new data. Existing L-ReID methods typically re-extract new features for all historical gallery images for inference after each update, known as "re-indexing". However, historical gallery data typically suffers from direct saving due to the data privacy issue and the high re-indexing costs for large-scale gallery images. As a result, it inevitably leads to incompatible retrieval between query features extracted by the updated model and gallery features extracted by those before the update, greatly impairing the re-identification performance. To tackle the above issue, this paper focuses on a new task called Re-index Free Lifelong person Re-IDentification (RFL-ReID), which requires performing lifelong person re-identification without re-indexing historical gallery images. Therefore, RFL-ReID is more challenging than L-ReID, requiring continuous learning and balancing new and old knowledge in diverse streaming data, and making the features output by the new and old models compatible with each other. To this end, we propose a Bidirectional Continuous Compatible Representation (Bi-C2R) framework to continuously update the gallery features extracted by the old model to perform efficient L-ReID in a compatible manner. We verify our proposed Bi-C2R method through theoretical analysis and extensive experiments on multiple benchmarks, which demonstrate that the proposed method can achieve leading performance on both the introduced RFL-ReID task and the traditional L-ReID task.</description><author>Zhenyu Cui, Jiahuan Zhou, Yuxin Peng</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 17:50:05 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.25000v1</guid></item><item><title>Basic Inequalities for First-Order Optimization with Applications to Statistical Risk Analysis</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24999v1</link><description>We introduce \textit{basic inequalities} for first-order iterative optimization algorithms, forming a simple and versatile framework that connects implicit and explicit regularization. While related inequalities appear in the literature, we isolate and highlight a specific form and develop it as a well-rounded tool for statistical analysis. Let $f$ denote the objective function to be optimized. Given a first-order iterative algorithm initialized at $θ_0$ with current iterate $θ_T$, the basic inequality upper bounds $f(θ_T)-f(z)$ for any reference point $z$ in terms of the accumulated step sizes and the distances between $θ_0$, $θ_T$, and $z$. The bound translates the number of iterations into an effective regularization coefficient in the loss function. We demonstrate this framework through analyses of training dynamics and prediction risk bounds. In addition to revisiting and refining known results on gradient descent, we provide new results for mirror descent with Bregman divergence projection, for generalized linear models trained by gradient descent and exponentiated gradient descent, and for randomized predictors. We illustrate and supplement these theoretical findings with experiments on generalized linear models.</description><author>Seunghoon Paik, Kangjie Zhou, Matus Telgarsky, Ryan J. Tibshirani</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 17:49:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24999v1</guid></item><item><title>Can machines think efficiently?</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.26954v2</link><description>The Turing Test is no longer adequate for distinguishing human and machine intelligence. With advanced artificial intelligence systems already passing the original Turing Test and contributing to serious ethical and environmental concerns, we urgently need to update the test. This work expands upon the original imitation game by accounting for an additional factor: the energy spent answering the questions. By adding the constraint of energy, the new test forces us to evaluate intelligence through the lens of efficiency, connecting the abstract problem of thinking to the concrete reality of finite resources. Further, this proposed new test ensures the evaluation of intelligence has a measurable, practical finish line that the original test lacks. This additional constraint compels society to weigh the time savings of using artificial intelligence against its total resource cost.</description><author>Adam Winchell</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 17:49:19 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.26954v2</guid></item><item><title>Classifying long legal documents using short random chunks</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24997v1</link><description>Classifying legal documents is a challenge, besides their specialized vocabulary, sometimes they can be very long. This means that feeding full documents to a Transformers-based models for classification might be impossible, expensive or slow. Thus, we present a legal document classifier based on DeBERTa V3 and a LSTM, that uses as input a collection of 48 randomly-selected short chunks (max 128 tokens). Besides, we present its deployment pipeline using Temporal, a durable execution solution, which allow us to have a reliable and robust processing workflow. The best model had a weighted F-score of 0.898, while the pipeline running on CPU had a processing median time of 498 seconds per 100 files.</description><author>Luis Adrián Cabrera-Diego</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 17:48:08 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24997v1</guid></item><item><title>Concentration Inequalities for Stochastic Optimization of Unbounded Objective Functions with Application to Denoising Score Matching</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.08628v2</link><description>We derive novel concentration inequalities that bound the statistical error for a large class of stochastic optimization problems, focusing on the case of unbounded objective functions. Our derivations utilize the following key tools: 1) A new form of McDiarmid's inequality that is based on sample-dependent one-component mean-difference bounds and which leads to a novel uniform law of large numbers result for unbounded functions. 2) A new Rademacher complexity bound for families of functions that satisfy an appropriate sample-dependent Lipschitz property, which allows for application to a large class of distributions with unbounded support. As an application of these results, we derive statistical error bounds for denoising score matching (DSM), an application that inherently requires one to consider unbounded objective functions and distributions with unbounded support, even in cases where the data distribution has bounded support. In addition, our results quantify the benefit of sample-reuse in algorithms that employ easily-sampled auxiliary random variables in addition to the training data, e.g., as in DSM, which uses auxiliary Gaussian random variables.</description><author>Jeremiah Birrell</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 17:45:23 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.08628v2</guid></item><item><title>A Context-Aware Temporal Modeling through Unified Multi-Scale Temporal Encoding and Hierarchical Sequence Learning for Single-Channel EEG Sleep Staging</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.22976v2</link><description>Automatic sleep staging is a critical task in healthcare due to the global prevalence of sleep disorders. This study focuses on single-channel electroencephalography (EEG), a practical and widely available signal for automatic sleep staging. Existing approaches face challenges such as class imbalance, limited receptive-field modeling, and insufficient interpretability. This work proposes a context-aware and interpretable framework for single-channel EEG sleep staging, with particular emphasis on improving detection of the N1 stage. Many prior models operate as black boxes with stacked layers, lacking clearly defined and interpretable feature extraction roles.The proposed model combines compact multi-scale feature extraction with temporal modeling to capture both local and long-range dependencies. To address data imbalance, especially in the N1 stage, classweighted loss functions and data augmentation are applied. EEG signals are segmented into sub-epoch chunks, and final predictions are obtained by averaging softmax probabilities across chunks, enhancing contextual representation and robustness.The proposed framework achieves an overall accuracy of 89.72% and a macro-average F1-score of 85.46%. Notably, it attains an F1- score of 61.7% for the challenging N1 stage, demonstrating a substantial improvement over previous methods on the SleepEDF datasets. These results indicate that the proposed approach effectively improves sleep staging performance while maintaining interpretability and suitability for real-world clinical applications.</description><author>Amirali Vakili, Salar Jahanshiri, Armin Salimi-Badr</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 17:38:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.22976v2</guid></item><item><title>Efficiently Estimating Data Efficiency for Language Model Fine-tuning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24991v1</link><description>While large language models (LLMs) demonstrate reasonable zero-shot capability across many downstream tasks, fine-tuning is a common practice to improve their performance. However, a task's data efficiency--i.e., the number of fine-tuning examples needed to achieve a desired level of performance--is often unknown, resulting in costly cycles of incremental annotation and retraining. Indeed, we demonstrate across a curated set of 30 specialized tasks that performant LLMs may struggle zero-shot but can attain stronger performance after fine-tuning. This motivates the need for methods to predict a task's data efficiency without requiring incremental annotation. After introducing a concrete metric that quantifies a task's data efficiency, we propose using the gradient cosine similarity of low-confidence examples to predict data efficiency based on a small number of labeled samples. We validate our approach on a diverse set of tasks with varying data efficiencies, attaining 8.6% error in overall data efficiency prediction and typically eliminating hundreds of unnecessary annotations on each task. Our experiment results and implementation code are available on GitHub.</description><author>Gyung Hyun Je, Colin Raffel</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 17:37:29 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24991v1</guid></item><item><title>PhysTalk: Language-driven Real-time Physics in 3D Gaussian Scenes</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24986v1</link><description>Realistic visual simulations are omnipresent, yet their creation requires computing time, rendering, and expert animation knowledge. Open-vocabulary visual effects generation from text inputs emerges as a promising solution that can unlock immense creative potential. However, current pipelines lack both physical realism and effective language interfaces, requiring slow offline optimization. In contrast, PhysTalk takes a 3D Gaussian Splatting (3DGS) scene as input and translates arbitrary user prompts into real time, physics based, interactive 4D animations. A large language model (LLM) generates executable code that directly modifies 3DGS parameters through lightweight proxies and particle dynamics. Notably, PhysTalk is the first framework to couple 3DGS directly with a physics simulator without relying on time consuming mesh extraction. While remaining open vocabulary, this design enables interactive 3D Gaussian animation via collision aware, physics based manipulation of arbitrary, multi material objects. Finally, PhysTalk is train-free and computationally lightweight: this makes 4D animation broadly accessible and shifts these workflows from a "render and wait" paradigm toward an interactive dialogue with a modern, physics-informed pipeline.</description><author>Luca Collorone, Mert Kiray, Indro Spinelli, Fabio Galasso, Benjamin Busam</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 17:32:31 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24986v1</guid></item><item><title>DarkEQA: Benchmarking Vision-Language Models for Embodied Question Answering in Low-Light Indoor Environments</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24985v1</link><description>Vision Language Models (VLMs) are increasingly adopted as central reasoning modules for embodied agents. Existing benchmarks evaluate their capabilities under ideal, well-lit conditions, yet robust 24/7 operation demands performance under a wide range of visual degradations, including low-light conditions at night or in dark environments--a core necessity that has been largely overlooked. To address this underexplored challenge, we present DarkEQA, an open-source benchmark for evaluating EQA-relevant perceptual primitives under multi-level low-light conditions. DarkEQA isolates the perception bottleneck by evaluating question answering from egocentric observations under controlled degradations, enabling attributable robustness analysis. A key design feature of DarkEQA is its physical fidelity: visual degradations are modeled in linear RAW space, simulating physics-based illumination drop and sensor noise followed by an ISP-inspired rendering pipeline. We demonstrate the utility of DarkEQA by evaluating a wide range of state-of-the-art VLMs and Low-Light Image Enhancement (LLIE) models. Our analysis systematically reveals VLMs' limitations when operating under these challenging visual conditions. Our code and benchmark dataset will be released upon acceptance.</description><author>Yohan Park, Hyunwoo Ha, Wonjun Jo, Tae-Hyun Oh</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 17:31:29 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24985v1</guid></item><item><title>Interpretable Perturbation Modeling Through Biomedical Knowledge Graphs</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.22251v2</link><description>Understanding how small molecules perturb gene expression is essential for uncovering drug mechanisms, predicting off-target effects, and identifying repurposing opportunities. While prior deep learning frameworks have integrated multimodal embeddings into biomedical knowledge graphs (BKGs) and further improved these representations through graph neural network message-passing paradigms, these models have been applied to tasks such as link prediction and binary drug-disease association, rather than the task of gene perturbation, which may unveil more about mechanistic transcriptomic effects. To address this gap, we construct a merged biomedical graph that integrates (i) PrimeKG++, an augmentation of PrimeKG containing semantically rich embeddings for nodes with (ii) LINCS L1000 drug and cell line nodes, initialized with multimodal embeddings from foundation models such as MolFormerXL and BioBERT. Using this heterogeneous graph, we train a graph attention network (GAT) with a downstream prediction head that learns the delta expression profile of over 978 landmark genes for a given drug-cell pair. Our results show that our framework outperforms MLP baselines for differentially expressed genes (DEG) -- which predict the delta expression given a concatenated embedding of drug features, target features, and baseline cell expression -- under the scaffold and random splits. Ablation experiments with edge shuffling and node feature randomization further demonstrate that the edges provided by biomedical KGs enhance perturbation-level prediction. More broadly, our framework provides a path toward mechanistic drug modeling: moving beyond binary drug-disease association tasks to granular transcriptional effects of therapeutic intervention.</description><author>Pascal Passigan, Kevin Zhu, Angelina Ning</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 17:30:56 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.22251v2</guid></item><item><title>DAVE: A VLM Vision Encoder for Document Understanding and Web Agents</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.17221v3</link><description>While Vision-language models (VLMs) have demonstrated remarkable performance across multi-modal tasks, their choice of vision encoders presents a fundamental weakness: their low-level features lack the robust structural and spatial information essential for document understanding and web agents. To bridge this gap, we introduce DAVE, a vision encoder purpose-built for VLMs and tailored for these tasks. Our training pipeline is designed to leverage abundant unlabeled data to bypass the need for costly large-scale annotations for document and web images. We begin with a self-supervised pretraining stage on unlabeled images, followed by a supervised autoregressive pretraining stage, where the model learns tasks like parsing and localization from limited, high-quality data. Within the supervised stage, we adopt two strategies to improve our encoder's alignment with both general visual knowledge and diverse document and web agentic tasks: (i) We introduce a novel model-merging scheme, combining encoders trained with different text decoders to ensure broad compatibility with different web agentic architectures. (ii) We use ensemble training to fuse features from pretrained generalist encoders (e.g., SigLIP2) with our own document and web-specific representations. Extensive experiments on classic document tasks, VQAs, web localization, and agent-based benchmarks validate the effectiveness of our approach, establishing DAVE as a strong vision encoder for document and web applications.</description><author>Brandon Huang, Hang Hua, Zhuoran Yu, Trevor Darrell, Rogerio Feris, Roei Herzig</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 17:30:11 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.17221v3</guid></item><item><title>A Modal Logic for Possibilistic Reasoning with Fuzzy Formal Contexts</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24980v1</link><description>We introduce a two-sort weighted modal logic for possibilistic reasoning with fuzzy formal contexts. The syntax of the logic includes two types of weighted modal operators corresponding to classical necessity ($\Box$) and sufficiency ($\boxminus$) modalities and its formulas are interpreted in fuzzy formal contexts based on possibility theory. We present its axiomatization that is \emph{sound} with respect to the class of all fuzzy context models. In addition, both the necessity and sufficiency fragments of the logic are also individually complete with respect to the class of all fuzzy context models. We highlight the expressive power of the logic with some illustrative examples. As a formal context is the basic construct of formal concept analysis (FCA), we generalize three main notions in FCA, i.e., formal concepts, object oriented concepts, and property oriented concepts, to their corresponding $c$-cut concepts in fuzzy formal contexts. Then, we show that our logical language can represent all three of these generalized notions. Finally, we demonstrate the possibility of extending our logic to reasoning with multi-relational fuzzy contexts, in which the Boolean combinations of different fuzzy relations are allowed.</description><author>Prosenjit Howlader, Churn-Jung Liau</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 17:27:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24980v1</guid></item><item><title>SymSeqBench: a unified framework for the generation and analysis of rule-based symbolic sequences and datasets</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24977v1</link><description>Sequential structure is a key feature of multiple domains of natural cognition and behavior, such as language, movement and decision-making. Likewise, it is also a central property of tasks to which we would like to apply artificial intelligence. It is therefore of great importance to develop frameworks that allow us to evaluate sequence learning and processing in a domain agnostic fashion, whilst simultaneously providing a link to formal theories of computation and computability. To address this need, we introduce two complementary software tools: SymSeq, designed to rigorously generate and analyze structured symbolic sequences, and SeqBench, a comprehensive benchmark suite of rule-based sequence processing tasks to evaluate the performance of artificial learning systems in cognitively relevant domains. In combination, SymSeqBench offers versatility in investigating sequential structure across diverse knowledge domains, including experimental psycholinguistics, cognitive psychology, behavioral analysis, neuromorphic computing and artificial intelligence. Due to its basis in Formal Language Theory (FLT), SymSeqBench provides researchers in multiple domains with a convenient and practical way to apply the concepts of FLT to conceptualize and standardize their experiments, thus advancing our understanding of cognition and behavior through shared computational frameworks and formalisms. The tool is modular, openly available and accessible to the research community.</description><author>Barna Zajzon, Younes Bouhadjar, Maxime Fabre, Felix Schmidt, Noah Ostendorf, Emre Neftci, Abigail Morrison, Renato Duarte</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 17:18:26 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24977v1</guid></item><item><title>Attribution-Guided Distillation of Matryoshka Sparse Autoencoders</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24975v1</link><description>Sparse autoencoders (SAEs) aim to disentangle model activations into monosemantic, human-interpretable features. In practice, learned features are often redundant and vary across training runs and sparsity levels, which makes interpretations difficult to transfer and reuse. We introduce Distilled Matryoshka Sparse Autoencoders (DMSAEs), a training pipeline that distills a compact core of consistently useful features and reuses it to train new SAEs. DMSAEs run an iterative distillation cycle: train a Matryoshka SAE with a shared core, use gradient X activation to measure each feature's contribution to next-token loss in the most nested reconstruction, and keep only the smallest subset that explains a fixed fraction of the attribution. Only the core encoder weight vectors are transferred across cycles; the core decoder and all non-core latents are reinitialized each time. On Gemma-2-2B layer 12 residual stream activations, seven cycles of distillation (500M tokens, 65k width) yielded a distilled core of 197 features that were repeatedly selected. Training using this distilled core improves several SAEBench metrics and demonstrates that consistent sets of latent features can be transferred across sparsity levels</description><author>Cristina P. Martin-Linares, Jonathan P. Ling</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 17:12:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24975v1</guid></item><item><title>Kolmogorov-Arnold Energy Models: Fast and Interpretable Generative Modeling</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.14167v7</link><description>Learning an energy-based model (EBM) in the latent space of a top-down generative model offers a powerful framework for generation across many data modalities. However, it remains unclear how its interpretability can be used to guide model design, improve generative quality, and reduce training time. Moreover, the reliance on Langevin Monte Carlo (LMC) sampling presents challenges in efficiency and sampling multimodal latent distributions. We propose a novel adaptation of the Kolmogorov-Arnold representation theorem for generative modeling and introduce the Kolmogorov-Arnold Energy Model (KAEM) to take advantage of structural and inductive biases. By constraining the prior to univariate relationships, KAEM enables fast and exact inference via the inverse transform method. With the low dimensionality of the latent space and suitable inductive biases encoded, we demonstrate that importance sampling (IS) becomes a viable, unbiased, and highly efficient posterior sampler. For domains where IS fails, we introduce a strategy based on population-based LMC, decomposing the posterior into a sequence of annealed distributions to improve LMC mixing. KAEM balances common generative modeling trade-offs, offering fast inference, interpretability, and stable training, while being naturally suited to Zettascale Computing hardware.</description><author>Prithvi Raj</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 17:07:22 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.14167v7</guid></item><item><title>Distribution-Dependent Rates for Multi-Distribution Learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13130v2</link><description>To address the needs of modeling uncertainty in sensitive machine learning applications, the setup of distributionally robust optimization (DRO) seeks good performance uniformly across a variety of tasks. The recent multi-distribution learning (MDL) framework tackles this objective in a dynamic interaction with the environment, where the learner has sampling access to each target distribution. Drawing inspiration from the field of pure-exploration multi-armed bandits, we provide distribution-dependent guarantees in the MDL regime, that scale with suboptimality gaps and result in superior dependence on the sample size when compared to the existing distribution-independent analyses. We investigate two non-adaptive strategies, uniform and non-uniform exploration, and present non-asymptotic regret bounds using novel tools from empirical process theory. Furthermore, we devise an adaptive optimistic algorithm, LCB-DR, that showcases enhanced dependence on the gaps, mirroring the contrast between uniform and optimistic allocation in the multi-armed bandit literature. We also conduct a small synthetic experiment illustrating the comparative strengths of each strategy.</description><author>Rafael Hanashiro, Patrick Jaillet</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 17:05:43 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13130v2</guid></item><item><title>Evaluating the Impact of Compression Techniques on the Robustness of CNNs under Natural Corruptions</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24971v1</link><description>Compressed deep learning models are crucial for deploying computer vision systems on resource-constrained devices. However, model compression may affect robustness, especially under natural corruption. Therefore, it is important to consider robustness evaluation while validating computer vision systems. This paper presents a comprehensive evaluation of compression techniques - quantization, pruning, and weight clustering applied individually and in combination to convolutional neural networks (ResNet-50, VGG-19, and MobileNetV2). Using the CIFAR-10-C and CIFAR 100-C datasets, we analyze the trade-offs between robustness, accuracy, and compression ratio. Our results show that certain compression strategies not only preserve but can also improve robustness, particularly on networks with more complex architectures. Utilizing multiobjective assessment, we determine the best configurations, showing that customized technique combinations produce beneficial multi-objective results. This study provides insights into selecting compression methods for robust and efficient deployment of models in corrupted real-world environments.</description><author>Itallo Patrick Castro Alves Da Silva, Emanuel Adler Medeiros Pereira, Erick de Andrade Barboza, Baldoino Fonseca dos Santos Neto, Marcio de Medeiros Ribeiro</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 17:00:01 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24971v1</guid></item><item><title>Large language models and the entropy of English</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24969v1</link><description>We use large language models (LLMs) to uncover long-ranged structure in English texts from a variety of sources. The conditional entropy or code length in many cases continues to decrease with context length at least to $N\sim 10^4$ characters, implying that there are direct dependencies or interactions across these distances. A corollary is that there are small but significant correlations between characters at these separations, as we show from the data independent of models. The distribution of code lengths reveals an emergent certainty about an increasing fraction of characters at large $N$. Over the course of model training, we observe different dynamics at long and short context lengths, suggesting that long-ranged structure is learned only gradually. Our results constrain efforts to build statistical physics models of LLMs or language itself.</description><author>Colin Scheibner, Lindsay M. Smith, William Bialek</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 16:54:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24969v1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of LLMs on Online News Consumption and Production</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24968v1</link><description>Large language models (LLMs) change how consumers acquire information online; their bots also crawl news publishers' websites for training data and to answer consumer queries; and they provide tools that can lower the cost of content creation. These changes lead to predictions of adverse impact on news publishers in the form of lowered consumer demand, reduced demand for newsroom employees, and an increase in news "slop." Consequently, some publishers strategically responded by blocking LLM access to their websites using the robots.txt file standard. Using high-frequency granular data, we document four effects related to the predicted shifts in news publishing following the introduction of generative AI (GenAI). First, we find a consistent and moderate decline in traffic to news publishers occurring after August 2024. Second, using a difference-in-differences approach, we find that blocking GenAI bots can have adverse effects on large publishers by reducing total website traffic by 23% and real consumer traffic by 14% compared to not blocking. Third, on the hiring side, we do not find evidence that LLMs are replacing editorial or content-production jobs yet. The share of new editorial and content-production job listings increases over time. Fourth, regarding content production, we find no evidence that large publishers increased text volume; instead, they significantly increased rich content and use more advertising and targeting technologies. Together, these findings provide early evidence of some unforeseen impacts of the introduction of LLMs on news production and consumption.</description><author>Hangcheng Zhao, Ron Berman</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 16:54:29 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24968v1</guid></item><item><title>ShowUI-$π$: Flow-based Generative Models as GUI Dexterous Hands</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24965v1</link><description>Building intelligent agents capable of dexterous manipulation is essential for achieving human-like automation in both robotics and digital environments. However, existing GUI agents rely on discrete click predictions (x,y), which prohibits free-form, closed-loop trajectories (e.g. dragging a progress bar) that require continuous, on-the-fly perception and adjustment. In this work, we develop ShowUI-$π$, the first flow-based generative model as GUI dexterous hand, featuring the following designs: (i) Unified Discrete-Continuous Actions, integrating discrete clicks and continuous drags within a shared model, enabling flexible adaptation across diverse interaction modes; (ii) Flow-based Action Generation for drag modeling, which predicts incremental cursor adjustments from continuous visual observations via a lightweight action expert, ensuring smooth and stable trajectories; (iii) Drag Training data and Benchmark, where we manually collect and synthesize 20K drag trajectories across five domains (e.g. PowerPoint, Adobe Premiere Pro), and introduce ScreenDrag, a benchmark with comprehensive online and offline evaluation protocols for assessing GUI agents' drag capabilities. Our experiments show that proprietary GUI agents still struggle on ScreenDrag (e.g. Operator scores 13.27, and the best Gemini-2.5-CUA reaches 22.18). In contrast, ShowUI-$π$ achieves 26.98 with only 450M parameters, underscoring both the difficulty of the task and the effectiveness of our approach. We hope this work advances GUI agents toward human-like dexterous control in digital world. The code is available at https://github.com/showlab/showui-pi.</description><author>Siyuan Hu, Kevin Qinghong Lin, Mike Zheng Shou</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 16:51:14 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24965v1</guid></item><item><title>Learning quadratic neural networks in high dimensions: SGD dynamics and scaling laws</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.03688v3</link><description>We study the optimization and sample complexity of gradient-based training of a two-layer neural network with quadratic activation function in the high-dimensional regime, where the data is generated as $f_*(\boldsymbol{x}) \propto \sum_{j=1}^{r}λ_j σ\left(\langle \boldsymbol{θ_j}, \boldsymbol{x}\rangle\right), \boldsymbol{x} \sim N(0,\boldsymbol{I}_d)$, $σ$ is the 2nd Hermite polynomial, and $\lbrace\boldsymbolθ_j \rbrace_{j=1}^{r} \subset \mathbb{R}^d$ are orthonormal signal directions. We consider the extensive-width regime $r \asymp d^β$ for $β\in [0, 1)$, and assume a power-law decay on the (non-negative) second-layer coefficients $λ_j\asymp j^{-α}$ for $α\geq 0$. We present a sharp analysis of the SGD dynamics in the feature learning regime, for both the population limit and the finite-sample (online) discretization, and derive scaling laws for the prediction risk that highlight the power-law dependencies on the optimization time, sample size, and model width. Our analysis combines a precise characterization of the associated matrix Riccati differential equation with novel matrix monotonicity arguments to establish convergence guarantees for the infinite-dimensional effective dynamics.</description><author>Gérard Ben Arous, Murat A. Erdogdu, Nuri Mert Vural, Denny Wu</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 16:43:30 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.03688v3</guid></item><item><title>Semi-overlapping Multi-bandit Best Arm Identification for Sequential Support Network Learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24959v1</link><description>Many modern AI and ML problems require evaluating partners' contributions through shared yet asymmetric, computationally intensive processes and the simultaneous selection of the most beneficial candidates. Sequential approaches to these problems can be unified under a new framework, Sequential Support Network Learning (SSNL), in which the goal is to select the most beneficial candidate set of partners for all participants using trials; that is, to learn a directed graph that represents the highest-performing contributions. We demonstrate that a new pure-exploration model, the semi-overlapping multi-(multi-armed) bandit (SOMMAB), in which a single evaluation provides distinct feedback to multiple bandits due to structural overlap among their arms, can be used to learn a support network from sparse candidate lists efficiently. We develop a generalized GapE algorithm for SOMMABs and derive new exponential error bounds that improve the best known constant in the exponent for multi-bandit best-arm identification. The bounds scale linearly with the degree of overlap, revealing significant sample-complexity gains arising from shared evaluations. From an application point of view, this work provides a theoretical foundation and improved performance guarantees for sequential learning tools for identifying support networks from sparse candidates in multiple learning problems, such as in multi-task learning (MTL), auxiliary task learning (ATL), federated learning (FL), and in multi-agent systems (MAS).</description><author>András Antos, András Millinghoffer, Péter Antal</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 16:42:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24959v1</guid></item><item><title>AMAP Agentic Planning Technical Report</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24957v1</link><description>We present STAgent, an agentic large language model tailored for spatio-temporal understanding, designed to solve complex tasks such as constrained point-of-interest discovery and itinerary planning. STAgent is a specialized model capable of interacting with ten distinct tools within spatio-temporal scenarios, enabling it to explore, verify, and refine intermediate steps during complex reasoning. Notably, STAgent effectively preserves its general capabilities. We empower STAgent with these capabilities through three key contributions: (1) a stable tool environment that supports over ten domain-specific tools, enabling asynchronous rollout and training; (2) a hierarchical data curation framework that identifies high-quality data like a needle in a haystack, curating high-quality queries with a filter ratio of 1:10,000, emphasizing both diversity and difficulty; and (3) a cascaded training recipe that starts with a seed SFT stage acting as a guardian to measure query difficulty, followed by a second SFT stage fine-tuned on queries with high certainty, and an ultimate RL stage that leverages data of low certainty. Initialized with Qwen3-30B-A3B to establish a strong SFT foundation and leverage insights into sample difficulty, STAgent yields promising performance on TravelBench while maintaining its general capabilities across a wide range of general benchmarks, thereby demonstrating the effectiveness of our proposed agentic model.</description><author>Yulan Hu, Xiangwen Zhang, Sheng Ouyang, Hao Yi, Lu Xu, Qinglin Lang, Lide Tan, Xiang Cheng, Tianchen Ye, Zhicong Li, Ge Chen, Wenjin Yang, Zheng Pan, Shaopan Xiong, Siran Yang, Ju Huang, Yan Zhang, Jiamang Wang, Yong Liu, Yinfeng Huang, Tucheng Lin, Xin Li, Ning Guo</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 16:39:09 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24957v1</guid></item><item><title>MSACL: Multi-Step Actor-Critic Learning with Lyapunov Certificates for Exponentially Stabilizing Control</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24955v1</link><description>Achieving provable stability in model-free reinforcement learning (RL) remains a challenge, particularly in balancing exploration with rigorous safety. This article introduces MSACL, a framework that integrates exponential stability theory with maximum entropy RL through multi-step Lyapunov certificate learning. Unlike methods relying on complex reward engineering, MSACL utilizes off-policy multi-step data to learn Lyapunov certificates satisfying theoretical stability conditions. By introducing Exponential Stability Labels (ESL) and a $λ$-weighted aggregation mechanism, the framework effectively balances the bias-variance trade-off in multi-step learning. Policy optimization is guided by a stability-aware advantage function, ensuring the learned policy promotes rapid Lyapunov descent. We evaluate MSACL across six benchmarks, including stabilization and nonlinear tracking tasks, demonstrating its superiority over state-of-the-art Lyapunov-based RL algorithms. MSACL achieves exponential stability and rapid convergence under simple rewards, while exhibiting significant robustness to uncertainties and generalization to unseen trajectories. Sensitivity analysis establishes the multi-step horizon $n=20$ as a robust default across diverse systems. By linking Lyapunov theory with off-policy actor-critic frameworks, MSACL provides a foundation for verifiably safe learning-based control. Source code and benchmark environments will be made publicly available.</description><author>Yongwei Zhang, Yuanzhe Xing, Quan Quan, Zhikun She</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 16:36:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24955v1</guid></item><item><title>A Geometric Theory of Cognition</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.12225v2</link><description>Human cognition spans perception, memory, intuitive judgment, deliberative reasoning, action selection, and social inference, yet these capacities are often explained through distinct computational theories. Here we present a unified mathematical framework in which diverse cognitive processes emerge from a single geometric principle. We represent the cognitive state as a point on a differentiable manifold endowed with a learned Riemannian metric that encodes representational constraints, computational costs, and structural relations among cognitive variables. A scalar cognitive potential combines predictive accuracy, structural parsimony, task utility, and normative or logical requirements. Cognition unfolds as the Riemannian gradient flow of this potential, providing a universal dynamical law from which a broad range of psychological phenomena arise. Classical dual-process effects--rapid intuitive responses and slower deliberative reasoning--emerge naturally from metric-induced anisotropies that generate intrinsic time-scale separations and geometric phase transitions, without invoking modular or hybrid architectures. We derive analytical conditions for these regimes and demonstrate their behavioural signatures through simulations of canonical cognitive tasks. Together, these results establish a geometric foundation for cognition and suggest guiding principles for the development of more general and human-like artificial intelligence systems.</description><author>Laha Ale</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 16:33:03 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.12225v2</guid></item><item><title>Sampling from Gaussian Processes: A Tutorial and Applications in Global Sensitivity Analysis and Optimization</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.14746v2</link><description>High-fidelity simulations and physical experiments are essential for engineering analysis and design, yet their high cost often makes two critical tasks--global sensitivity analysis (GSA) and optimization--prohibitively expensive. This limitation motivates the common use of Gaussian processes (GPs) as proxy regression models that provide uncertainty-aware predictions from a limited number of high-quality observations. GPs naturally enable efficient sampling strategies that support informed decision-making under uncertainty by extracting information from a subset of possible functions for the model of interest. However, direct sampling from GPs is inefficient due to their infinite-dimensional nature and the high cost associated with large covariance matrix operations. Despite their popularity in machine learning and statistics communities, sampling from GPs has received little attention in the community of engineering optimization. In this paper, we present the formulation and detailed implementation of two notable sampling methods--random Fourier features and pathwise conditioning--for generating posterior samples from GPs at reduced computational cost. Alternative approaches are briefly described. Importantly, we detail how the generated samples can be applied in GSA, single-objective optimization, and multi-objective optimization. We show successful applications of these sampling methods through a series of numerical examples.</description><author>Bach Do, Nafeezat A. Ajenifuja, Taiwo A. Adebiyi, Ruda Zhang</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 16:32:29 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.14746v2</guid></item><item><title>VIPER: Process-aware Evaluation for Generative Video Reasoning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24952v1</link><description>Recent breakthroughs in video generation have demonstrated an emerging capability termed Chain-of-Frames (CoF) reasoning, where models resolve complex tasks through the generation of continuous frames. While these models show promise for Generative Video Reasoning (GVR), existing evaluation frameworks often rely on single-frame assessments, which can lead to outcome-hacking, where a model reaches a correct conclusion through an erroneous process. To address this, we propose a process-aware evaluation paradigm. We introduce VIPER, a comprehensive benchmark spanning 16 tasks across temporal, structural, symbolic, spatial, physics, and planning reasoning. Furthermore, we propose Process-outcome Consistency (POC@r), a new metric that utilizes VLM-as-Judge with a hierarchical rubric to evaluate both the validity of the intermediate steps and the final result. Our experiments reveal that state-of-the-art video models achieve only about 20% POC@1.0 and exhibit a significant outcome-hacking. We further explore the impact of test-time scaling and sampling robustness, highlighting a substantial gap between current video generation and true generalized visual reasoning. Our benchmark will be publicly released.</description><author>Yifan Li, Yukai Gu, Yingqian Min, Zikang Liu, Yifan Du, Kun Zhou, Min Yang, Wayne Xin Zhao, Minghui Qiu</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 16:31:59 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24952v1</guid></item><item><title>Physics-Informed Neural Networks for Device and Circuit Modeling: A Case Study of NeuroSPICE</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.23624v2</link><description>We present NeuroSPICE, a physics-informed neural network (PINN) framework for device and circuit simulation. Unlike conventional SPICE, which relies on time-discretized numerical solvers, NeuroSPICE leverages PINNs to solve circuit differential-algebraic equations (DAEs) by minimizing the residual of the equations through backpropagation. It models device and circuit waveforms using analytical equations in time domain with exact temporal derivatives. While PINNs do not outperform SPICE in speed or accuracy during training, they offer unique advantages such as surrogate models for design optimization and inverse problems. NeuroSPICE's flexibility enables the simulation of emerging devices, including highly nonlinear systems such as ferroelectric memories.</description><author>Chien-Ting Tung, Chenming Hu</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 16:31:06 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.23624v2</guid></item><item><title>ProDM: Synthetic Reality-driven Property-aware Progressive Diffusion Model for Coronary Calcium Motion Correction in Non-gated Chest CT</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24948v1</link><description>Coronary artery calcium (CAC) scoring from chest CT is a well-established tool to stratify and refine clinical cardiovascular disease risk estimation. CAC quantification relies on the accurate delineation of calcified lesions, but is oftentimes affected by artifacts introduced by cardiac and respiratory motion. ECG-gated cardiac CTs substantially reduce motion artifacts, but their use in population screening and routine imaging remains limited due to gating requirements and lack of insurance coverage. Although identification of incidental CAC from non-gated chest CT is increasingly considered for it offers an accessible and widely available alternative, this modality is limited by more severe motion artifacts. We present ProDM (Property-aware Progressive Correction Diffusion Model), a generative diffusion framework that restores motion-free calcified lesions from non-gated CTs. ProDM introduces three key components: (1) a CAC motion simulation data engine that synthesizes realistic non-gated acquisitions with diverse motion trajectories directly from cardiac-gated CTs, enabling supervised training without paired data; (2) a property-aware learning strategy incorporating calcium-specific priors through a differentiable calcium consistency loss to preserve lesion integrity; and (3) a progressive correction scheme that reduces artifacts gradually across diffusion steps to enhance stability and calcium fidelity. Experiments on real patient datasets show that ProDM significantly improves CAC scoring accuracy, spatial lesion fidelity, and risk stratification performance compared with several baselines. A reader study on real non-gated scans further confirms that ProDM suppresses motion artifacts and improves clinical usability. These findings highlight the potential of progressive, property-aware frameworks for reliable CAC quantification from routine chest CT imaging.</description><author>Xinran Gong, Gorkem Durak, Halil Ertugrul Aktas, Vedat Cicek, Jinkui Hao, Ulas Bagci, Nilay S. Shah, Bo Zhou</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 16:29:05 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24948v1</guid></item><item><title>CPJ: Explainable Agricultural Pest Diagnosis via Caption-Prompt-Judge with LLM-Judged Refinement</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24947v1</link><description>Accurate and interpretable crop disease diagnosis is essential for agricultural decision-making, yet existing methods often rely on costly supervised fine-tuning and perform poorly under domain shifts. We propose Caption--Prompt--Judge (CPJ), a training-free few-shot framework that enhances Agri-Pest VQA through structured, interpretable image captions. CPJ employs large vision-language models to generate multi-angle captions, refined iteratively via an LLM-as-Judge module, which then inform a dual-answer VQA process for both recognition and management responses. Evaluated on CDDMBench, CPJ significantly improves performance: using GPT-5-mini captions, GPT-5-Nano achieves \textbf{+22.7} pp in disease classification and \textbf{+19.5} points in QA score over no-caption baselines. The framework provides transparent, evidence-based reasoning, advancing robust and explainable agricultural diagnosis without fine-tuning. Our code and data are publicly available at: https://github.com/CPJ-Agricultural/CPJ-Agricultural-Diagnosis.</description><author>Wentao Zhang, Tao Fang, Lina Lu, Lifei Wang, Weihe Zhong</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 16:21:31 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24947v1</guid></item><item><title>HaineiFRDM: Explore Diffusion to Restore Defects in Fast-Movement Films</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24946v1</link><description>Existing open-source film restoration methods show limited performance compared to commercial methods due to training with low-quality synthetic data and employing noisy optical flows. In addition, high-resolution films have not been explored by the open-source methods.We propose HaineiFRDM(Film Restoration Diffusion Model), a film restoration framework, to explore diffusion model's powerful content-understanding ability to help human expert better restore indistinguishable film defects.Specifically, we employ a patch-wise training and testing strategy to make restoring high-resolution films on one 24GB-VRAMR GPU possible and design a position-aware Global Prompt and Frame Fusion Modules.Also, we introduce a global-local frequency module to reconstruct consistent textures among different patches. Besides, we firstly restore a low-resolution result and use it as global residual to mitigate blocky artifacts caused by patching process.Furthermore, we construct a film restoration dataset that contains restored real-degraded films and realistic synthetic data.Comprehensive experimental results conclusively demonstrate the superiority of our model in defect restoration ability over existing open-source methods. Code and the dataset will be released.</description><author>Rongji Xun, Junjie Yuan, Zhongjie Wang</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 16:18:07 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24946v1</guid></item><item><title>RAIR: A Rule-Aware Benchmark Uniting Challenging Long-Tail and Visual Salience Subset for E-commerce Relevance Assessment</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24943v1</link><description>Search relevance plays a central role in web e-commerce. While large language models (LLMs) have shown significant results on relevance task, existing benchmarks lack sufficient complexity for comprehensive model assessment, resulting in an absence of standardized relevance evaluation metrics across the industry. To address this limitation, we propose Rule-Aware benchmark with Image for Relevance assessment(RAIR), a Chinese dataset derived from real-world scenarios. RAIR established a standardized framework for relevance assessment and provides a set of universal rules, which forms the foundation for standardized evaluation. Additionally, RAIR analyzes essential capabilities required for current relevance models and introduces a comprehensive dataset consists of three subset: (1) a general subset with industry-balanced sampling to evaluate fundamental model competencies; (2) a long-tail hard subset focus on challenging cases to assess performance limits; (3) a visual salience subset for evaluating multimodal understanding capabilities. We conducted experiments on RAIR using 14 open and closed-source models. The results demonstrate that RAIR presents sufficient challenges even for GPT-5, which achieved the best performance. RAIR data are now available, serving as an industry benchmark for relevance assessment while providing new insights into general LLM and Visual Language Model(VLM) evaluation.</description><author>Chenji Lu, Zhuo Chen, Hui Zhao, Zhenyi Wang, Pengjie Wang, Jian Xu, Bo Zheng</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 16:09:08 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24943v1</guid></item><item><title>Iterative Deployment Improves Planning Skills in LLMs</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24940v1</link><description>We show that iterative deployment of large language models (LLMs), each fine-tuned on data carefully curated by users from the previous models' deployment, can significantly change the properties of the resultant models. By testing this mechanism on various planning domains, we observe substantial improvements in planning skills, with later models displaying emergent generalization by discovering much longer plans than the initial models. We then provide theoretical analysis showing that iterative deployment effectively implements reinforcement learning (RL) training in the outer-loop (i.e. not as part of intentional model training), with an implicit reward function. The connection to RL has two important implications: first, for the field of AI safety, as the reward function entailed by repeated deployment is not defined explicitly, and could have unexpected implications to the properties of future model deployments. Second, the mechanism highlighted here can be viewed as an alternative training regime to explicit RL, relying on data curation rather than explicit rewards.</description><author>Augusto B. Corrêa, Yoav Gelberg, Luckeciano C. Melo, Ilia Shumailov, André G. Pereira, Yarin Gal</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 16:03:14 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24940v1</guid></item><item><title>Vibe Coding, Interface Flattening</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24939v1</link><description>Large language models are reshaping programming by enabling 'vibe coding': the development of softwares through natural-language interaction with model-driven toolchains. This article argues that vibe coding is best understood as interface flattening, a reconfiguration in which previously distinct modalities (GUI, CLI, and API) appear to converge into a single conversational surface, even as the underlying chain of translation from intention to machinic effect lengthens and thickens. Drawing on Friedrich Kittler's materialist media theory and Alexander Galloway's account of interfaces as sites of protocol control, the paper situates programming as a historically localised interface arrangement rather than an essential relation to computation. Through a materialist reconstruction of the contemporary vibe-coding stack, it shows how remote compute infrastructures, latency and connectivity, structured outputs, function/tool calling, and interoperability standards such as the Model Context Protocol relocate control and meaning-making power to model and protocol providers. The apparent democratisation of technical capability therefore depends on new dependencies and new literacies. By foregrounding the tension between experiential flattening and infrastructural thickening, I demonstrate how LLM-mediated development redistributes symbolic labour/power, obscures responsibility, and privatises competencies previously dispersed across programming communities, contributing a critical lens on the political economy of AI-mediated human-computer interaction.</description><author>Hongrui Jin</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 16:00:59 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24939v1</guid></item><item><title>PoseStreamer: A Multi-modal Framework for 6DoF Pose Estimation of Unseen Moving Objects</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.22979v2</link><description>Six degree of freedom (6DoF) pose estimation for novel objects is a critical task in computer vision, yet it faces significant challenges in high-speed and low-light scenarios where standard RGB cameras suffer from motion blur. While event cameras offer a promising solution due to their high temporal resolution, current 6DoF pose estimation methods typically yield suboptimal performance in high-speed object moving scenarios. To address this gap, we propose PoseStreamer, a robust multi-modal 6DoF pose estimation framework designed specifically on high-speed moving scenarios. Our approach integrates three core components: an Adaptive Pose Memory Queue that utilizes historical orientation cues for temporal consistency, an Object-centric 2D Tracker that provides strong 2D priors to boost 3D center recall, and a Ray Pose Filter for geometric refinement along camera rays. Furthermore, we introduce MoCapCube6D, a novel multi-modal dataset constructed to benchmark performance under rapid motion. Extensive experiments demonstrate that PoseStreamer not only achieves superior accuracy in high-speed moving scenarios, but also exhibits strong generalizability as a template-free framework for unseen moving objects.</description><author>Huiming Yang, Linglin Liao, Fei Ding, Sibo Wang, Zijian Zeng</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 15:59:13 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.22979v2</guid></item><item><title>Adaptive Dependency-aware Prompt Optimization Framework for Multi-Step LLM Pipeline</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24933v1</link><description>Multi-step LLM pipelines invoke large language models multiple times in a structured sequence and can effectively solve complex tasks, but their performance heavily depends on the prompts used at each step. Jointly optimizing these prompts is difficult due to missing step-level supervision and inter-step dependencies. Existing end-to-end prompt optimization methods struggle under these conditions and often yield suboptimal or unstable updates. We propose ADOPT, an Adaptive Dependency-aware Prompt Optimization framework for multi-step LLM pipelines. ADOPT explicitly models the dependency between each LLM step and the final task outcome, enabling precise text-gradient estimation analogous to computing analytical derivatives. It decouples textual gradient estimation from gradient updates, reducing multi-prompt optimization to flexible single-prompt optimization steps, and employs a Shapley-based mechanism to adaptively allocate optimization resources. Experiments on real-world datasets and diverse pipeline structures show that ADOPT is effective and robust, consistently outperforming state-of-the-art prompt optimization baselines.</description><author>Minjun Zhao, Xinyu Zhang, Shuai Zhang, Deyang Li, Ruifeng Shi</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 15:46:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24933v1</guid></item><item><title>ReVision: A Dataset and Baseline VLM for Privacy-Preserving Task-Oriented Visual Instruction Rewriting</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.14780v2</link><description>Efficient and privacy-preserving multimodal interaction is essential as AR, VR, and modern smartphones with powerful cameras become primary interfaces for human-computer communication. Existing powerful large vision-language models (VLMs) enabling multimodal interaction often rely on cloud-based processing, raising significant concerns about (1) visual privacy by transmitting sensitive vision data to servers, and (2) their limited real-time, on-device usability. This paper explores Visual Instruction Rewriting, a novel approach that transforms multimodal instructions into text-only commands, allowing seamless integration of lightweight on-device instruction rewriter VLMs (250M parameters) with existing conversational AI systems, enhancing vision data privacy. To achieve this, we present a dataset of over 39,000 examples across 14 domains and develop a compact VLM, pretrained on image captioning datasets and fine-tuned for instruction rewriting. Experimental results, evaluated through NLG metrics such as BLEU, METEOR, and ROUGE, along with semantic parsing analysis, demonstrate that even a quantized version of the model (&lt;500MB storage footprint) can achieve effective instruction rewriting, thus enabling privacy-focused, multimodal AI applications.</description><author>Abhijit Mishra, Mingda Li, Hsiang Fu, Richard Noh, Minji Kim</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 15:43:05 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.14780v2</guid></item><item><title>HAROOD: A Benchmark for Out-of-distribution Generalization in Sensor-based Human Activity Recognition</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.10807v3</link><description>Sensor-based human activity recognition (HAR) mines activity patterns from the time-series sensory data. In realistic scenarios, variations across individuals, devices, environments, and time introduce significant distributional shifts for the same activities. Recent efforts attempt to solve this challenge by applying or adapting existing out-of-distribution (OOD) algorithms, but only in certain distribution shift scenarios (e.g., cross-device or cross-position), lacking comprehensive insights on the effectiveness of these algorithms. For instance, is OOD necessary to HAR? Which OOD algorithm performs the best? In this paper, we fill this gap by proposing HAROOD, a comprehensive benchmark for HAR in OOD settings. We define 4 OOD scenarios: cross-person, cross-position, cross-dataset, and cross-time, and build a testbed covering 6 datasets, 16 comparative methods (implemented with CNN-based and Transformer-based architectures), and two model selection protocols. Then, we conduct extensive experiments and present several findings for future research, e.g., no single method consistently outperforms others, highlighting substantial opportunity for advancement. Our codebase is highly modular and easy to extend for new datasets, algorithms, comparisons, and analysis, with the hope to facilitate the research in OOD-based HAR. Our implementation is released and can be found at https://github.com/AIFrontierLab/HAROOD.</description><author>Wang Lu, Yao Zhu, Jindong Wang</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 15:41:01 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.10807v3</guid></item><item><title>Are First-Order Diffusion Samplers Really Slower? A Fast Forward-Value Approach</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24927v1</link><description>Higher-order ODE solvers have become a standard tool for accelerating diffusion probabilistic model (DPM) sampling, motivating the widespread view that first-order methods are inherently slower and that increasing discretization order is the primary path to faster generation. This paper challenges this belief and revisits acceleration from a complementary angle: beyond solver order, the placement of DPM evaluations along the reverse-time dynamics can substantially affect sampling accuracy in the low-neural function evaluation (NFE) regime. We propose a novel training-free, first-order sampler whose leading discretization error has the opposite sign to that of DDIM. Algorithmically, the method approximates the forward-value evaluation via a cheap one-step lookahead predictor. We provide theoretical guarantees showing that the resulting sampler provably approximates the ideal forward-value trajectory while retaining first-order convergence. Empirically, across standard image generation benchmarks (CIFAR-10, ImageNet, FFHQ, and LSUN), the proposed sampler consistently improves sample quality under the same NFE budget and can be competitive with, and sometimes outperform, state-of-the-art higher-order samplers. Overall, the results suggest that the placement of DPM evaluations provides an additional and largely independent design angle for accelerating diffusion sampling.</description><author>Yuchen Jiao, Na Li, Changxiao Cai, Gen Li</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 15:35:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24927v1</guid></item><item><title>Distributed Information Bottleneck Theory for Multi-Modal Task-Aware Semantic Communication</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.04000v3</link><description>Semantic communication shifts the focus from bit-level accuracy to task-relevant semantic delivery, enabling efficient and intelligent communication for next-generation networks. However, existing multi-modal solutions often process all available data modalities indiscriminately, ignoring that their contributions to downstream tasks are often unequal. This not only leads to severe resource inefficiency but also degrades task inference performance due to irrelevant or redundant information. To tackle this issue, we propose a novel task-aware distributed information bottleneck (TADIB) framework, which quantifies the contribution of any set of modalities to given tasks. Based on this theoretical framework, we design a practical coding scheme that intelligently selects and compresses only the most task-relevant modalities at the transmitter. To find the optimal selection and the codecs in the network, we adopt the probabilistic relaxation of discrete selection, enabling distributed encoders to make coordinated decisions with score function estimation and common randomness. Extensive experiments on public datasets demonstrate that our solution matches or surpasses the inference quality of full-modal baselines while significantly reducing communication and computational costs.</description><author>Yujie Zhou, Cheng Peng, Rulong Wang, Yong Xiao, Yingyu Li, Guangming Shi, Ping Zhang</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 15:34:39 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.04000v3</guid></item><item><title>Semi-Supervised Diversity-Aware Domain Adaptation for 3D Object detection</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24922v1</link><description>3D object detectors are fundamental components of perception systems in autonomous vehicles. While these detectors achieve remarkable performance on standard autonomous driving benchmarks, they often struggle to generalize across different domains - for instance, a model trained in the U.S. may perform poorly in regions like Asia or Europe. This paper presents a novel lidar domain adaptation method based on neuron activation patterns, demonstrating that state-of-the-art performance can be achieved by annotating only a small, representative, and diverse subset of samples from the target domain if they are correctly selected. The proposed approach requires very small annotation budget and, when combined with post-training techniques inspired by continual learning prevent weight drift from the original model. Empirical evaluation shows that the proposed domain adaptation approach outperforms both linear probing and state-of-the-art domain adaptation techniques.</description><author>Bartłomiej Olber, Jakub Winter, Paweł Wawrzyński, Andrii Gamalii, Daniel Górniak, Marcin Łojek, Robert Nowak, Krystian Radlak</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 15:26:09 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24922v1</guid></item><item><title>Frequent subgraph-based persistent homology for graph classification</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24917v1</link><description>Persistent homology (PH) has recently emerged as a powerful tool for extracting topological features. Integrating PH into machine learning and deep learning models enhances topology awareness and interpretability. However, most PH methods on graphs rely on a limited set of filtrations, such as degree-based or weight-based filtrations, which overlook richer features like recurring information across the dataset and thus restrict expressive power. In this work, we propose a novel graph filtration called Frequent Subgraph Filtration (FSF), which is derived from frequent subgraphs and produces stable and information-rich frequency-based persistent homology (FPH) features. We study the theoretical properties of FSF and provide both proofs and experimental validation. Beyond persistent homology itself, we introduce two approaches for graph classification: an FPH-based machine learning model (FPH-ML) and a hybrid framework that integrates FPH with graph neural networks (FPH-GNNs) to enhance topology-aware graph representation learning. Our frameworks bridge frequent subgraph mining and topological data analysis, offering a new perspective on topology-aware feature extraction. Experimental results show that FPH-ML achieves competitive or superior accuracy compared with kernel-based and degree-based filtration methods. When integrated into graph neural networks, FPH yields relative performance gains ranging from 0.4 to 21 percent, with improvements of up to 8.2 percentage points over GCN and GIN backbones across benchmarks.</description><author>Xinyang Chen, Amaël Broustet, Guoting Chen</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 15:21:15 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24917v1</guid></item><item><title>Discovery and inference beyond linearity by integrating Bayesian regression, tree ensembles and Shapley values</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00571v2</link><description>Machine Learning (ML) is gaining popularity for hypothesis-free discovery of risk and protective factors in healthcare studies. ML is strong at discovering nonlinearities and interactions, but this power is compromised by a lack of reliable inference. Although Shapley values provide local measures of features' effects, valid uncertainty quantification for these effects is typically lacking, thus precluding statistical inference. We propose RuleSHAP, a framework that addresses this limitation by combining a dedicated Bayesian sparse regression model with a new tree-based rule generator and Shapley value attribution. RuleSHAP provides detection of nonlinear and interaction effects with uncertainty quantification at the individual level. We derive an efficient formula for computing marginal Shapley values within this framework. We demonstrate the validity of our framework on simulated data. Finally, we apply RuleSHAP to data from an epidemiological cohort to detect and infer several effects for high cholesterol and blood pressure, such as nonlinear interaction effects between features like age, sex, ethnicity, BMI and glucose level.</description><author>Giorgio Spadaccini, Marjolein Fokkema, Mark A. van de Wiel</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 15:18:33 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00571v2</guid></item><item><title>AI-Driven Cloud Resource Optimization for Multi-Cluster Environments</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24914v1</link><description>Modern cloud-native systems increasingly rely on multi-cluster deployments to support scalability, resilience, and geographic distribution. However, existing resource management approaches remain largely reactive and cluster-centric, limiting their ability to optimize system-wide behavior under dynamic workloads. These limitations result in inefficient resource utilization, delayed adaptation, and increased operational overhead across distributed environments. This paper presents an AI-driven framework for adaptive resource optimization in multi-cluster cloud systems. The proposed approach integrates predictive learning, policy-aware decision-making, and continuous feedback to enable proactive and coordinated resource management across clusters. By analyzing cross-cluster telemetry and historical execution patterns, the framework dynamically adjusts resource allocation to balance performance, cost, and reliability objectives. A prototype implementation demonstrates improved resource efficiency, faster stabilization during workload fluctuations, and reduced performance variability compared to conventional reactive approaches. The results highlight the effectiveness of intelligent, self-adaptive infrastructure management as a key enabler for scalable and resilient cloud platforms.</description><author>Vinoth Punniyamoorthy, Akash Kumar Agarwal, Bikesh Kumar, Abhirup Mazumder, Kabilan Kannan, Sumit Saha</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 15:15:46 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24914v1</guid></item><item><title>FinMMDocR: Benchmarking Financial Multimodal Reasoning with Scenario Awareness, Document Understanding, and Multi-Step Computation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24903v1</link><description>We introduce FinMMDocR, a novel bilingual multimodal benchmark for evaluating multimodal large language models (MLLMs) on real-world financial numerical reasoning. Compared to existing benchmarks, our work delivers three major advancements. (1) Scenario Awareness: 57.9% of 1,200 expert-annotated problems incorporate 12 types of implicit financial scenarios (e.g., Portfolio Management), challenging models to perform expert-level reasoning based on assumptions; (2) Document Understanding: 837 Chinese/English documents spanning 9 types (e.g., Company Research) average 50.8 pages with rich visual elements, significantly surpassing existing benchmarks in both breadth and depth of financial documents; (3) Multi-Step Computation: Problems demand 11-step reasoning on average (5.3 extraction + 5.7 calculation steps), with 65.0% requiring cross-page evidence (2.4 pages average). The best-performing MLLM achieves only 58.0% accuracy, and different retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) methods show significant performance variations on this task. We expect FinMMDocR to drive improvements in MLLMs and reasoning-enhanced methods on complex multimodal reasoning tasks in real-world scenarios.</description><author>Zichen Tang, Haihong E, Rongjin Li, Jiacheng Liu, Linwei Jia, Zhuodi Hao, Zhongjun Yang, Yuanze Li, Haolin Tian, Xinyi Hu, Peizhi Zhao, Yuan Liu, Zhengyu Wang, Xianghe Wang, Yiling Huang, Xueyuan Lin, Ruofei Bai, Zijian Xie, Qian Huang, Ruining Cao, Haocheng Gao</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 15:00:03 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24903v1</guid></item><item><title>Spectral Graph Neural Networks for Cognitive Task Classification in fMRI Connectomes</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24901v1</link><description>Cognitive task classification using machine learning plays a central role in decoding brain states from neuroimaging data. By integrating machine learning with brain network analysis, complex connectivity patterns can be extracted from functional magnetic resonance imaging connectomes. This process transforms raw blood-oxygen-level-dependent (BOLD) signals into interpretable representations of cognitive processes. Graph neural networks (GNNs) further advance this paradigm by modeling brain regions as nodes and functional connections as edges, capturing topological dependencies and multi-scale interactions that are often missed by conventional approaches. Our proposed SpectralBrainGNN model, a spectral convolution framework based on graph Fourier transforms (GFT) computed via normalized Laplacian eigendecomposition. Experiments on the Human Connectome Project-Task (HCPTask) dataset demonstrate the effectiveness of the proposed approach, achieving a classification accuracy of 96.25\%. The implementation is publicly available at https://github.com/gnnplayground/SpectralBrainGNN to support reproducibility and future research.</description><author>Debasis Maji, Arghya Banerjee, Debaditya Barman</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 14:54:06 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24901v1</guid></item><item><title>PRISM: A hierarchical multiscale approach for time series forecasting</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24898v1</link><description>Forecasting is critical in areas such as finance, biology, and healthcare. Despite the progress in the field, making accurate forecasts remains challenging because real-world time series contain both global trends, local fine-grained structure, and features on multiple scales in between. Here, we present a new forecasting method, PRISM (Partitioned Representation for Iterative Sequence Modeling), that addresses this challenge through a learnable tree-based partitioning of the signal. At the root of the tree, a global representation captures coarse trends in the signal, while recursive splits reveal increasingly localized views of the signal. At each level of the tree, data are projected onto a time-frequency basis (e.g., wavelets or exponential moving averages) to extract scale-specific features, which are then aggregated across the hierarchy. This design allows the model to jointly capture global structure and local dynamics of the signal, enabling accurate forecasting. Experiments across benchmark datasets show that our method outperforms state-of-the-art methods for forecasting. Overall, these results demonstrate that our hierarchical approach provides a lightweight and flexible framework for forecasting multivariate time series. The code is available at https://github.com/nerdslab/prism.</description><author>Zihao Chen, Alexandre Andre, Wenrui Ma, Ian Knight, Sergey Shuvaev, Eva Dyer</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 14:51:12 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24898v1</guid></item><item><title>Large Multimodal Models for Low-Resource Languages: A Survey</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.05568v2</link><description>In this survey, we systematically analyze techniques used to adapt large multimodal models (LMMs) for low-resource (LR) languages, examining approaches ranging from visual enhancement and data creation to cross-modal transfer and fusion strategies. Through a comprehensive analysis of 117 studies across 96 LR languages, we identify key patterns in how researchers tackle the challenges of limited data and computational resources. We categorize works into resource-oriented and method-oriented contributions, further dividing contributions into relevant sub-categories. We compare method-oriented contributions in terms of performance and efficiency, discussing benefits and limitations of representative studies. We find that visual information often serves as a crucial bridge for improving model performance in LR settings, though significant challenges remain in areas such as hallucination mitigation and computational efficiency. In summary, we provide researchers with a clear understanding of current approaches and remaining challenges in making LMMs more accessible to speakers of LR (understudied) languages. We complement our survey with an open-source repository available at: https://github.com/marianlupascu/LMM4LRL-Survey.</description><author>Marian Lupascu, Ana-Cristina Rogoz, Mihai Sorin Stupariu, Radu Tudor Ionescu</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 14:45:06 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.05568v2</guid></item><item><title>Semi-Automated Data Annotation in Multisensor Datasets for Autonomous Vehicle Testing</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24896v1</link><description>This report presents the design and implementation of a semi-automated data annotation pipeline developed within the DARTS project, whose goal is to create a large-scale, multimodal dataset of driving scenarios recorded in Polish conditions. Manual annotation of such heterogeneous data is both costly and time-consuming. To address this challenge, the proposed solution adopts a human-in-the-loop approach that combines artificial intelligence with human expertise to reduce annotation cost and duration. The system automatically generates initial annotations, enables iterative model retraining, and incorporates data anonymization and domain adaptation techniques. At its core, the tool relies on 3D object detection algorithms to produce preliminary annotations. Overall, the developed tools and methodology result in substantial time savings while ensuring consistent, high-quality annotations across different sensor modalities. The solution directly supports the DARTS project by accelerating the preparation of large annotated dataset in the project's standardized format, strengthening the technological base for autonomous vehicle research in Poland.</description><author>Andrii Gamalii, Daniel Górniak, Robert Nowak, Bartłomiej Olber, Krystian Radlak, Jakub Winter</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 14:43:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24896v1</guid></item><item><title>Towards autonomous time-calibration of large quantum-dot devices: Detection, real-time feedback, and noise spectroscopy</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24894v1</link><description>The performance and scalability of semiconductor quantum-dot (QD) qubits are limited by electrostatic drift and charge noise that shift operating points and destabilize qubit parameters. As systems expand to large one- and two-dimensional arrays, manual recalibration becomes impractical, creating a need for autonomous stabilization frameworks. Here, we introduce a method that uses the full network of charge-transition lines in repeatedly acquired double-quantum-dot charge stability diagrams (CSDs) as a multidimensional probe of the local electrostatic environment. By accurately tracking the motion of selected transitions in time, we detect voltage drifts, identify abrupt charge reconfigurations, and apply compensating updates to maintain stable operating conditions. We demonstrate our approach on a 10-QD device, showing robust stabilization and real-time diagnostic access to dot-specific noise processes. The high acquisition rate of radio-frequency reflectometry CSD measurements also enables time-domain noise spectroscopy, allowing the extraction of noise power spectral densities, the identification of two-level fluctuators, and the analysis of spatial noise correlations across the array. From our analysis, we find that the background noise at 100~$μ$\si{\hertz} is dominated by drift with a power law of $1/f^2$, accompanied by a few dominant two-level fluctuators and an average linear correlation length of $(188 \pm 38)$~\si{\nano\meter} in the device. These capabilities form the basis of a scalable, autonomous calibration and characterization module for QD-based quantum processors, providing essential feedback for long-duration, high-fidelity qubit operations.</description><author>Anantha S. Rao, Barnaby van Straaten, Valentin John, Cécile X. Yu, Stefan D. Oosterhout, Lucas Stehouwer, Giordano Scappucci, M. D. Stewart,, Menno Veldhorst, Francesco Borsoi, Justyna P. Zwolak</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 14:41:39 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24894v1</guid></item><item><title>Pre-DPO: Improving Data Utilization in Direct Preference Optimization Using a Guiding Reference Model</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.15843v3</link><description>Direct Preference Optimization (DPO) simplifies reinforcement learning from human feedback (RLHF) for large language models (LLMs) by directly optimizing human preferences without an explicit reward model. We find that during DPO training, the reference model plays the role of a data weight adjuster. However, the common practice of initializing the policy and reference models identically in DPO can lead to inefficient data utilization and impose a performance ceiling. Meanwhile, the lack of a reference model in Simple Preference Optimization (SimPO) reduces training robustness and necessitates stricter conditions to prevent catastrophic forgetting. In this work, we propose Pre-DPO, a simple yet effective DPO-based training paradigm that enhances preference optimization performance by leveraging a guiding reference model. This reference model provides foresight into the optimal policy state achievable through the training preference data, serving as a guiding mechanism that adaptively assigns higher weights to samples more suitable for the model and lower weights to those less suitable. Extensive experiments on AlpacaEval 2.0 and Arena-Hard v0.1 benchmarks demonstrate that Pre-DPO consistently improves the performance of both DPO and SimPO, without relying on external models or additional data.</description><author>Junshu Pan, Wei Shen, Shulin Huang, Qiji Zhou, Yue Zhang</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 14:41:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.15843v3</guid></item><item><title>SoulX-LiveTalk: Real-Time Infinite Streaming of Audio-Driven Avatars via Self-Correcting Bidirectional Distillation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.23379v2</link><description>Deploying massive diffusion models for real-time, infinite-duration, audio-driven avatar generation presents a significant engineering challenge, primarily due to the conflict between computational load and strict latency constraints. Existing approaches often compromise visual fidelity by enforcing strictly unidirectional attention mechanisms or reducing model capacity. To address this problem, we introduce \textbf{SoulX-LiveTalk}, a 14B-parameter framework optimized for high-fidelity real-time streaming. Diverging from conventional unidirectional paradigms, we use a \textbf{Self-correcting Bidirectional Distillation} strategy that retains bidirectional attention within video chunks. This design preserves critical spatiotemporal correlations, significantly enhancing motion coherence and visual detail. To ensure stability during infinite generation, we incorporate a \textbf{Multi-step Retrospective Self-Correction Mechanism}, enabling the model to autonomously recover from accumulated errors and preventing collapse. Furthermore, we engineered a full-stack inference acceleration suite incorporating hybrid sequence parallelism, Parallel VAE, and kernel-level optimizations. Extensive evaluations confirm that SoulX-LiveTalk is the first 14B-scale system to achieve a \textbf{sub-second start-up latency (0.87s)} while reaching a real-time throughput of \textbf{32 FPS}, setting a new standard for high-fidelity interactive digital human synthesis.</description><author>Le Shen, Qiao Qian, Tan Yu, Ke Zhou, Tianhang Yu, Yu Zhan, Zhenjie Wang, Ming Tao, Shunshun Yin, Siyuan Liu</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 14:38:59 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.23379v2</guid></item><item><title>BEDA: Belief Estimation as Probabilistic Constraints for Performing Strategic Dialogue Acts</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24885v1</link><description>Strategic dialogue requires agents to execute distinct dialogue acts, for which belief estimation is essential. While prior work often estimates beliefs accurately, it lacks a principled mechanism to use those beliefs during generation. We bridge this gap by first formalizing two core acts Adversarial and Alignment, and by operationalizing them via probabilistic constraints on what an agent may generate. We instantiate this idea in BEDA, a framework that consists of the world set, the belief estimator for belief estimation, and the conditional generator that selects acts and realizes utterances consistent with the inferred beliefs. Across three settings, Conditional Keeper Burglar (CKBG, adversarial), Mutual Friends (MF, cooperative), and CaSiNo (negotiation), BEDA consistently outperforms strong baselines: on CKBG it improves success rate by at least 5.0 points across backbones and by 20.6 points with GPT-4.1-nano; on Mutual Friends it achieves an average improvement of 9.3 points; and on CaSiNo it achieves the optimal deal relative to all baselines. These results indicate that casting belief estimation as constraints provides a simple, general mechanism for reliable strategic dialogue.</description><author>Hengli Li, Zhaoxin Yu, Qi Shen, Chenxi Li, Mengmeng Wang, Tinglang Wu, Yipeng Kang, Yuxuan Wang, Song-Chun Zhu, Zixia Jia, Zilong Zheng</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 14:26:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24885v1</guid></item><item><title>mHC: Manifold-Constrained Hyper-Connections</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24880v1</link><description>Recently, studies exemplified by Hyper-Connections (HC) have extended the ubiquitous residual connection paradigm established over the past decade by expanding the residual stream width and diversifying connectivity patterns. While yielding substantial performance gains, this diversification fundamentally compromises the identity mapping property intrinsic to the residual connection, which causes severe training instability and restricted scalability, and additionally incurs notable memory access overhead. To address these challenges, we propose Manifold-Constrained Hyper-Connections (mHC), a general framework that projects the residual connection space of HC onto a specific manifold to restore the identity mapping property, while incorporating rigorous infrastructure optimization to ensure efficiency. Empirical experiments demonstrate that mHC is effective for training at scale, offering tangible performance improvements and superior scalability. We anticipate that mHC, as a flexible and practical extension of HC, will contribute to a deeper understanding of topological architecture design and suggest promising directions for the evolution of foundational models.</description><author>Zhenda Xie, Yixuan Wei, Huanqi Cao, Chenggang Zhao, Chengqi Deng, Jiashi Li, Damai Dai, Huazuo Gao, Jiang Chang, Liang Zhao, Shangyan Zhou, Zhean Xu, Zhengyan Zhang, Wangding Zeng, Shengding Hu, Yuqing Wang, Jingyang Yuan, Lean Wang, Wenfeng Liang</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 14:16:26 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24880v1</guid></item><item><title>Let It Flow: Agentic Crafting on Rock and Roll, Building the ROME Model within an Open Agentic Learning Ecosystem</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24873v1</link><description>Agentic crafting requires LLMs to operate in real-world environments over multiple turns by taking actions, observing outcomes, and iteratively refining artifacts. Despite its importance, the open-source community lacks a principled, end-to-end ecosystem to streamline agent development. We introduce the Agentic Learning Ecosystem (ALE), a foundational infrastructure that optimizes the production pipeline for agent LLMs. ALE consists of three components: ROLL, a post-training framework for weight optimization; ROCK, a sandbox environment manager for trajectory generation; and iFlow CLI, an agent framework for efficient context engineering. We release ROME (ROME is Obviously an Agentic Model), an open-source agent grounded by ALE and trained on over one million trajectories. Our approach includes data composition protocols for synthesizing complex behaviors and a novel policy optimization algorithm, Interaction-based Policy Alignment (IPA), which assigns credit over semantic interaction chunks rather than individual tokens to improve long-horizon training stability. Empirically, we evaluate ROME within a structured setting and introduce Terminal Bench Pro, a benchmark with improved scale and contamination control. ROME demonstrates strong performance across benchmarks like SWE-bench Verified and Terminal Bench, proving the effectiveness of the ALE infrastructure.</description><author>Weixun Wang, XiaoXiao Xu, Wanhe An, Fangwen Dai, Wei Gao, Yancheng He, Ju Huang, Qiang Ji, Hanqi Jin, Xiaoyang Li, Yang Li, Zhongwen Li, Shirong Lin, Jiashun Liu, Zenan Liu, Tao Luo, Dilxat Muhtar, Yuanbin Qu, Jiaqiang Shi, Qinghui Sun, Yingshui Tan, Hao Tang, Runze Wang, Yi Wang, Zhaoguo Wang, Yanan Wu, Shaopan Xiong, Binchen Xu, Xander Xu, Yuchi Xu, Qipeng Zhang, Xixia Zhang, Haizhou Zhao, Jie Zhao, Shuaibing Zhao, Baihui Zheng, Jianhui Zheng, Suhang Zheng, Yanni Zhu, Mengze Cai, Kerui Cao, Xitong Chen, Yue Dai, Lifan Du, Tao Feng, Tao He, Jin Hu, Yijie Hu, Ziyu Jiang, Cheng Li, Xiang Li, Jing Liang, Chonghuan Liu, ZhenDong Liu, Haodong Mi, Yanhu Mo, Junjia Ni, Shixin Pei, Jingyu Shen, XiaoShuai Song, Cecilia Wang, Chaofan Wang, Kangyu Wang, Pei Wang, Tao Wang, Wei Wang, Ke Xiao, Mingyu </author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 14:03:39 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24873v1</guid></item><item><title>Encyclo-K: Evaluating LLMs with Dynamically Composed Knowledge Statements</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24867v1</link><description>Benchmarks play a crucial role in tracking the rapid advancement of large language models (LLMs) and identifying their capability boundaries. However, existing benchmarks predominantly curate questions at the question level, suffering from three fundamental limitations: vulnerability to data contamination, restriction to single-knowledge-point assessment, and reliance on costly domain expert annotation. We propose Encyclo-K, a statement-based benchmark that rethinks benchmark construction from the ground up. Our key insight is that knowledge statements, not questions, can serve as the unit of curation, and questions can then be constructed from them. We extract standalone knowledge statements from authoritative textbooks and dynamically compose them into evaluation questions through random sampling at test time. This design directly addresses all three limitations: the combinatorial space is too vast to memorize, and model rankings remain stable across dynamically generated question sets, enabling reliable periodic dataset refresh; each question aggregates 8-10 statements for comprehensive multi-knowledge assessment; annotators only verify formatting compliance without requiring domain expertise, substantially reducing annotation costs. Experiments on over 50 LLMs demonstrate that Encyclo-K poses substantial challenges with strong discriminative power. Even the top-performing OpenAI-GPT-5.1 achieves only 62.07% accuracy, and model performance displays a clear gradient distribution--reasoning models span from 16.04% to 62.07%, while chat models range from 9.71% to 50.40%. These results validate the challenges introduced by dynamic evaluation and multi-statement comprehensive understanding. These findings establish Encyclo-K as a scalable framework for dynamic evaluation of LLMs' comprehensive understanding over multiple fine-grained disciplinary knowledge statements.</description><author>Yiming Liang, Yizhi Li, Yantao Du, Ge Zhang, Jiayi Zhou, Yuchen Wu, Yinzhu Piao, Denghui Cao, Tong Sun, Ziniu Li, Li Du, Bo Lei, Jiaheng Liu, Chenghua Lin, Zhaoxiang Zhang, Wenhao Huang, Jiajun Zhang</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 13:55:54 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24867v1</guid></item><item><title>Characterization of Transfer Using Multi-task Learning Curves</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24866v1</link><description>Transfer effects manifest themselves both during training using a fixed data set and in inductive inference using accumulating data. We hypothesize that perturbing the data set by including more samples, instead of perturbing the model by gradient updates, provides a complementary and more fundamental characterization of transfer effects. To capture this phenomenon, we quantitatively model transfer effects using multi-task learning curves approximating the inductive performance over varying sample sizes. We describe an efficient method to approximate multi-task learning curves analogous to the Task Affinity Grouping method applied during training. We compare the statistical and computational approaches to transfer, which indicates considerably higher compute costs for the previous but better power and broader applicability. Evaluations are performed using a benchmark drug-target interaction data set. Our results show that learning curves can better capture the effects of multi-task learning and their multi-task extensions can delineate pairwise and contextual transfer effects in foundation models.</description><author>András Millinghoffer, Bence Bolgár, Péter Antal</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 13:55:18 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24866v1</guid></item><item><title>Big AI is accelerating the metacrisis: What can we do?</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24863v1</link><description>The world is in the grip of ecological, meaning, and language crises which are converging into a metacrisis. Big AI is accelerating them all. Language engineers are playing a central role, persisting with a scalability story that is failing humanity, supplying critical talent to plutocrats and kleptocrats, and creating new technologies as if the whole endeavour was value-free. We urgently need to explore alternatives, applying our collective intelligence to design a life-affirming future for NLP that is centered on human flourishing on a living planet.</description><author>Steven Bird</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 13:49:56 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24863v1</guid></item><item><title>OFL-SAM2: Prompt SAM2 with Online Few-shot Learner for Efficient Medical Image Segmentation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24861v1</link><description>The Segment Anything Model 2 (SAM2) has demonstrated remarkable promptable visual segmentation capabilities in video data, showing potential for extension to medical image segmentation (MIS) tasks involving 3D volumes and temporally correlated 2D image sequences. However, adapting SAM2 to MIS presents several challenges, including the need for extensive annotated medical data for fine-tuning and high-quality manual prompts, which are both labor-intensive and require intervention from medical experts. To address these challenges, we introduce OFL-SAM2, a prompt-free SAM2 framework for label-efficient MIS. Our core idea is to leverage limited annotated samples to train a lightweight mapping network that captures medical knowledge and transforms generic image features into target features, thereby providing additional discriminative target representations for each frame and eliminating the need for manual prompts. Crucially, the mapping network supports online parameter update during inference, enhancing the model's generalization across test sequences. Technically, we introduce two key components: (1) an online few-shot learner that trains the mapping network to generate target features using limited data, and (2) an adaptive fusion module that dynamically integrates the target features with the memory-attention features generated by frozen SAM2, leading to accurate and robust target representation. Extensive experiments on three diverse MIS datasets demonstrate that OFL-SAM2 achieves state-of-the-art performance with limited training data.</description><author>Meng Lan, Lefei Zhang, Xiaomeng Li</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 13:41:16 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24861v1</guid></item><item><title>A study on constraint extraction and exception exclusion in care worker scheduling</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24853v1</link><description>Technologies for automatically generating work schedules have been extensively studied; however, in long-term care facilities, the conditions vary between facilities, making it essential to interview the managers who create shift schedules to design facility-specific constraint conditions. The proposed method utilizes constraint templates to extract combinations of various components, such as shift patterns for consecutive days or staff combinations. The templates can extract a variety of constraints by changing the number of days and the number of staff members to focus on and changing the extraction focus to patterns or frequency. In addition, unlike existing constraint extraction techniques, this study incorporates mechanisms to exclude exceptional constraints. The extracted constraints can be employed by a constraint programming solver to create care worker schedules. Experiments demonstrated that our proposed method successfully created schedules that satisfied all hard constraints and reduced the number of violations for soft constraints by circumventing the extraction of exceptional constraints.</description><author>Koki Suenaga, Tomohiro Furuta, Satoshi Ono</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 13:22:50 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24853v1</guid></item><item><title>VLN-MME: Diagnosing MLLMs as Language-guided Visual Navigation agents</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24851v1</link><description>Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) have demonstrated remarkable capabilities across a wide range of vision-language tasks. However, their performance as embodied agents, which requires multi-round dialogue spatial reasoning and sequential action prediction, needs further exploration. Our work investigates this potential in the context of Vision-and-Language Navigation (VLN) by introducing a unified and extensible evaluation framework to probe MLLMs as zero-shot agents by bridging traditional navigation datasets into a standardized benchmark, named VLN-MME. We simplify the evaluation with a highly modular and accessible design. This flexibility streamlines experiments, enabling structured comparisons and component-level ablations across diverse MLLM architectures, agent designs, and navigation tasks. Crucially, enabled by our framework, we observe that enhancing our baseline agent with Chain-of-Thought (CoT) reasoning and self-reflection leads to an unexpected performance decrease. This suggests MLLMs exhibit poor context awareness in embodied navigation tasks; although they can follow instructions and structure their output, their 3D spatial reasoning fidelity is low. VLN-MME lays the groundwork for systematic evaluation of general-purpose MLLMs in embodied navigation settings and reveals limitations in their sequential decision-making capabilities. We believe these findings offer crucial guidance for MLLM post-training as embodied agents.</description><author>Xunyi Zhao, Gengze Zhou, Qi Wu</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 13:21:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24851v1</guid></item><item><title>Effective Online Exam Proctoring by Combining Lightweight Face Detection and Deep Recognition</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2206.13356v3</link><description>Online exams conducted via video conferencing platforms such as Zoom have become widespread, yet ensuring exam integrity remains challenging due to the difficulty of monitoring multiple video feeds in real time. We present iExam, an online exam proctoring and analysis system that combines lightweight real-time face detection with deep face recognition for postexam analysis. iExam assists invigilators by monitoring student presence during exams and identifies abnormal behaviors, such as face disappearance, face rotation, and identity substitution, from recorded videos. The system addresses three key challenges: (i)efficient real-time video capture and analysis, (ii) automated student identity labeling using enhanced OCR on dynamic Zoom name tags, and (iii) resource-efficient training and inference on standard teacher devices. Extensive experiments show that iExam achieves 90.4% accuracy in real-time face detection and 98.4% accuracy in post-exam recognition with low overhead, demonstrating its practicality and effectiveness for online exam proctoring.</description><author>Xu Yang, Juantao Zhong, Daoyuan Wu, Xiao Yi, Jimmy H. M. Lee, Tan Lee, Peng Han</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 13:17:08 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2206.13356v3</guid></item><item><title>PrivacyBench: A Conversational Benchmark for Evaluating Privacy in Personalized AI</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24848v1</link><description>Personalized AI agents rely on access to a user's digital footprint, which often includes sensitive data from private emails, chats and purchase histories. Yet this access creates a fundamental societal and privacy risk: systems lacking social-context awareness can unintentionally expose user secrets, threatening digital well-being. We introduce PrivacyBench, a benchmark with socially grounded datasets containing embedded secrets and a multi-turn conversational evaluation to measure secret preservation. Testing Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) assistants reveals that they leak secrets in up to 26.56% of interactions. A privacy-aware prompt lowers leakage to 5.12%, yet this measure offers only partial mitigation. The retrieval mechanism continues to access sensitive data indiscriminately, which shifts the entire burden of privacy preservation onto the generator. This creates a single point of failure, rendering current architectures unsafe for wide-scale deployment. Our findings underscore the urgent need for structural, privacy-by-design safeguards to ensure an ethical and inclusive web for everyone.</description><author>Srija Mukhopadhyay, Sathwik Reddy, Shruthi Muthukumar, Jisun An, Ponnurangam Kumaraguru</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 13:16:45 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24848v1</guid></item><item><title>AODDiff: Probabilistic Reconstruction of Aerosol Optical Depth via Diffusion-based Bayesian Inference</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24847v1</link><description>High-quality reconstruction of Aerosol Optical Depth (AOD) fields is critical for Atmosphere monitoring, yet current models remain constrained by the scarcity of complete training data and a lack of uncertainty quantification.To address these limitations, we propose AODDiff, a probabilistic reconstruction framework based on diffusion-based Bayesian inference. By leveraging the learned spatiotemporal probability distribution of the AOD field as a generative prior, this framework can be flexibly adapted to various reconstruction tasks without requiring task-specific retraining. We first introduce a corruption-aware training strategy to learns a spatiotemporal AOD prior solely from naturally incomplete data. Subsequently, we employ a decoupled annealing posterior sampling strategy that enables the more effective and integration of heterogeneous observations as constraints to guide the generation process. We validate the proposed framework through extensive experiments on Reanalysis data. Results across downscaling and inpainting tasks confirm the efficacy and robustness of AODDiff, specifically demonstrating its advantage in maintaining high spatial spectral fidelity. Furthermore, as a generative model, AODDiff inherently enables uncertainty quantification via multiple sampling, offering critical confidence metrics for downstream applications.</description><author>Linhao Fan, Hongqiang Fang, Jingyang Dai, Yong Jiang, Qixing Zhang</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 13:16:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24847v1</guid></item><item><title>Triangulation as an Acceptance Rule for Multilingual Mechanistic Interpretability</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24842v1</link><description>Multilingual language models achieve strong aggregate performance yet often behave unpredictably across languages, scripts, and cultures. We argue that mechanistic explanations for such models should satisfy a \emph{causal} standard: claims must survive causal interventions and must \emph{cross-reference} across environments that perturb surface form while preserving meaning. We formalize \emph{reference families} as predicate-preserving variants and introduce \emph{triangulation}, an acceptance rule requiring necessity (ablating the circuit degrades the target behavior), sufficiency (patching activations transfers the behavior), and invariance (both effects remain directionally stable and of sufficient magnitude across the reference family). To supply candidate subgraphs, we adopt automatic circuit discovery and \emph{accept or reject} those candidates by triangulation. We ground triangulation in causal abstraction by casting it as an approximate transformation score over a distribution of interchange interventions, connect it to the pragmatic interpretability agenda, and present a comparative experimental protocol across multiple model families, language pairs, and tasks. Triangulation provides a falsifiable standard for mechanistic claims that filters spurious circuits passing single-environment tests but failing cross-lingual invariance.</description><author>Yanan Long</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 13:03:34 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24842v1</guid></item><item><title>CropTrack: A Tracking with Re-Identification Framework for Precision Agriculture</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24838v1</link><description>Multiple-object tracking (MOT) in agricultural environments presents major challenges due to repetitive patterns, similar object appearances, sudden illumination changes, and frequent occlusions. Contemporary trackers in this domain rely on the motion of objects rather than appearance for association. Nevertheless, they struggle to maintain object identities when targets undergo frequent and strong occlusions. The high similarity of object appearances makes integrating appearance-based association nontrivial for agricultural scenarios. To solve this problem we propose CropTrack, a novel MOT framework based on the combination of appearance and motion information. CropTrack integrates a reranking-enhanced appearance association, a one-to-many association with appearance-based conflict resolution strategy, and an exponential moving average prototype feature bank to improve appearance-based association. Evaluated on publicly available agricultural MOT datasets, CropTrack demonstrates consistent identity preservation, outperforming traditional motion-based tracking methods. Compared to the state of the art, CropTrack achieves significant gains in identification F1 and association accuracy scores with a lower number of identity switches.</description><author>Md Ahmed Al Muzaddid, Jordan A. James, William J. Beksi</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 12:59:38 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24838v1</guid></item><item><title>GenZ: Foundational models as latent variable generators within traditional statistical models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24834v1</link><description>We present GenZ, a hybrid model that bridges foundational models and statistical modeling through interpretable semantic features. While large language models possess broad domain knowledge, they often fail to capture dataset-specific patterns critical for prediction tasks. Our approach addresses this by discovering semantic feature descriptions through an iterative process that contrasts groups of items identified via statistical modeling errors, rather than relying solely on the foundational model's domain understanding. We formulate this as a generalized EM algorithm that jointly optimizes semantic feature descriptors and statistical model parameters. The method prompts a frozen foundational model to classify items based on discovered features, treating these judgments as noisy observations of latent binary features that predict real-valued targets through learned statistical relationships. We demonstrate the approach on two domains: house price prediction (hedonic regression) and cold-start collaborative filtering for movie recommendations. On house prices, our model achieves 12\% median relative error using discovered semantic features from multimodal listing data, substantially outperforming a GPT-5 baseline (38\% error) that relies on the LLM's general domain knowledge. For Netflix movie embeddings, our model predicts collaborative filtering representations with 0.59 cosine similarity purely from semantic descriptions -- matching the performance that would require approximately 4000 user ratings through traditional collaborative filtering. The discovered features reveal dataset-specific patterns (e.g., architectural details predicting local housing markets, franchise membership predicting user preferences) that diverge from the model's domain knowledge alone.</description><author>Marko Jojic, Nebojsa Jojic</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 12:56:01 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24834v1</guid></item><item><title>Distilled HuBERT for Mobile Speech Emotion Recognition: A Cross-Corpus Validation Study</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.23435v2</link><description>Speech Emotion Recognition (SER) has significant potential for mobile applications, yet deployment remains constrained by the computational demands of state-of-the-art transformer architectures. This paper presents a mobile-efficient SER system based on DistilHuBERT, a distilled and 8-bit quantized transformer that achieves approximately 92% parameter reduction compared to full-scale Wav2Vec 2.0 models while maintaining competitive accuracy. We conduct a rigorous 5-fold Leave-One-Session-Out (LOSO) cross-validation on the IEMOCAP dataset to ensure speaker independence, augmented with cross-corpus training on CREMA-D to enhance generalization. Cross-corpus training with CREMA-D yields a 1.2% improvement in Weighted Accuracy, a 1.4% gain in Macro F1-score, and a 32% reduction in cross-fold variance, with the Neutral class showing the most substantial benefit at 5.4% F1-score improvement. Our approach achieves an Unweighted Accuracy of 61.4% with a quantized model footprint of only 23 MB, representing approximately 91% of the Unweighted Accuracy of a full-scale baseline. Cross-corpus evaluation on RAVDESS reveals that the theatrical nature of acted emotions causes predictions to cluster by arousal level rather than by specific emotion categories - happiness predictions systematically bleed into anger predictions, and sadness predictions bleed into neutral predictions, due to acoustic saturation when actors prioritize clarity over subtlety. Despite this theatricality effect reducing overall RAVDESS accuracy to 46.64%, the model maintains robust arousal detection with 99% recall for anger, 55% recall for neutral, and 27% recall for sadness. These findings demonstrate a Pareto-optimal tradeoff between model size and accuracy, enabling practical affect recognition on resource-constrained mobile devices.</description><author>Saifelden M. Ismail</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 12:50:30 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.23435v2</guid></item><item><title>Explaining Why Things Go Where They Go: Interpretable Constructs of Human Organizational Preferences</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24829v1</link><description>Robotic systems for household object rearrangement often rely on latent preference models inferred from human demonstrations. While effective at prediction, these models offer limited insight into the interpretable factors that guide human decisions. We introduce an explicit formulation of object arrangement preferences along four interpretable constructs: spatial practicality (putting items where they naturally fit best in the space), habitual convenience (making frequently used items easy to reach), semantic coherence (placing items together if they are used for the same task or are contextually related), and commonsense appropriateness (putting things where people would usually expect to find them). To capture these constructs, we designed and validated a self-report questionnaire through a 63-participant online study. Results confirm the psychological distinctiveness of these constructs and their explanatory power across two scenarios (kitchen and living room). We demonstrate the utility of these constructs by integrating them into a Monte Carlo Tree Search (MCTS) planner and show that when guided by participant-derived preferences, our planner can generate reasonable arrangements that closely align with those generated by participants. This work contributes a compact, interpretable formulation of object arrangement preferences and a demonstration of how it can be operationalized for robot planning.</description><author>Emmanuel Fashae, Michael Burke, Leimin Tian, Lingheng Meng, Pamela Carreno-Medrano</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 12:46:05 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24829v1</guid></item><item><title>Discovering Coordinated Joint Options via Inter-Agent Relative Dynamics</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24827v1</link><description>Temporally extended actions improve the ability to explore and plan in single-agent settings. In multi-agent settings, the exponential growth of the joint state space with the number of agents makes coordinated behaviours even more valuable. Yet, this same exponential growth renders the design of multi-agent options particularly challenging. Existing multi-agent option discovery methods often sacrifice coordination by producing loosely coupled or fully independent behaviours. Toward addressing these limitations, we describe a novel approach for multi-agent option discovery. Specifically, we propose a joint-state abstraction that compresses the state space while preserving the information necessary to discover strongly coordinated behaviours. Our approach builds on the inductive bias that synchronisation over agent states provides a natural foundation for coordination in the absence of explicit objectives. We first approximate a fictitious state of maximal alignment with the team, the \textit{Fermat} state, and use it to define a measure of \textit{spreadness}, capturing team-level misalignment on each individual state dimension. Building on this representation, we then employ a neural graph Laplacian estimator to derive options that capture state synchronisation patterns between agents. We evaluate the resulting options across multiple scenarios in two multi-agent domains, showing that they yield stronger downstream coordination capabilities compared to alternative option discovery methods.</description><author>Raul D. Steleac, Mohan Sridharan, David Abel</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 12:39:22 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24827v1</guid></item><item><title>Video and Language Alignment in 2D Systems for 3D Multi-object Scenes with Multi-Information Derivative-Free Control</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24826v1</link><description>Cross-modal systems trained on 2D visual inputs are presented with a dimensional shift when processing 3D scenes. An in-scene camera bridges the dimensionality gap but requires learning a control module. We introduce a new method that improves multivariate mutual information estimates by regret minimisation with derivative-free optimisation. Our algorithm enables off-the-shelf cross-modal systems trained on 2D visual inputs to adapt online to object occlusions and differentiate features. The pairing of expressive measures and value-based optimisation assists control of an in-scene camera to learn directly from the noisy outputs of vision-language models. The resulting pipeline improves performance in cross-modal tasks on multi-object 3D scenes without resorting to pretraining or finetuning.</description><author>Jason Armitage, Rico Sennnrich</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 12:39:03 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24826v1</guid></item><item><title>Theory of Mind for Explainable Human-Robot Interaction</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.23482v2</link><description>Within the context of human-robot interaction (HRI), Theory of Mind (ToM) is intended to serve as a user-friendly backend to the interface of robotic systems, enabling robots to infer and respond to human mental states. When integrated into robots, ToM allows them to adapt their internal models to users' behaviors, enhancing the interpretability and predictability of their actions. Similarly, Explainable Artificial Intelligence (XAI) aims to make AI systems transparent and interpretable, allowing humans to understand and interact with them effectively. Since ToM in HRI serves related purposes, we propose to consider ToM as a form of XAI and evaluate it through the eValuation XAI (VXAI) framework and its seven desiderata. This paper identifies a critical gap in the application of ToM within HRI, as existing methods rarely assess the extent to which explanations correspond to the robot's actual internal reasoning. To address this limitation, we propose to integrate ToM within XAI frameworks. By embedding ToM principles inside XAI, we argue for a shift in perspective, as current XAI research focuses predominantly on the AI system itself and often lacks user-centered explanations. Incorporating ToM would enable a change in focus, prioritizing the user's informational needs and perspective.</description><author>Marie S. Bauer, Julia Gachot, Matthias Kerzel, Cornelius Weber, Stefan Wermter</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 12:36:41 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.23482v2</guid></item></channel></rss>