<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Arxivfresh papers</title><link></link><description>Arxiv paper</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:01:35 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.0.0</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Reinforced Attention Learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04884v1</link><description>Post-training with Reinforcement Learning (RL) has substantially improved reasoning in Large Language Models (LLMs) via test-time scaling. However, extending this paradigm to Multimodal LLMs (MLLMs) through verbose rationales yields limited gains for perception and can even degrade performance. We propose Reinforced Attention Learning (RAL), a policy-gradient framework that directly optimizes internal attention distributions rather than output token sequences. By shifting optimization from what to generate to where to attend, RAL promotes effective information allocation and improved grounding in complex multimodal inputs. Experiments across diverse image and video benchmarks show consistent gains over GRPO and other baselines. We further introduce On-Policy Attention Distillation, demonstrating that transferring latent attention behaviors yields stronger cross-modal alignment than standard knowledge distillation. Our results position attention policies as a principled and general alternative for multimodal post-training.</description><author>Bangzheng Li, Jianmo Ni, Chen Qu, Ian Miao, Liu Yang, Xingyu Fu, Muhao Chen, Derek Zhiyuan Cheng</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:59:52 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04884v1</guid></item><item><title>Protein Autoregressive Modeling via Multiscale Structure Generation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04883v1</link><description>We present protein autoregressive modeling (PAR), the first multi-scale autoregressive framework for protein backbone generation via coarse-to-fine next-scale prediction. Using the hierarchical nature of proteins, PAR generates structures that mimic sculpting a statue, forming a coarse topology and refining structural details over scales. To achieve this, PAR consists of three key components: (i) multi-scale downsampling operations that represent protein structures across multiple scales during training; (ii) an autoregressive transformer that encodes multi-scale information and produces conditional embeddings to guide structure generation; (iii) a flow-based backbone decoder that generates backbone atoms conditioned on these embeddings. Moreover, autoregressive models suffer from exposure bias, caused by the training and the generation procedure mismatch, and substantially degrades structure generation quality. We effectively alleviate this issue by adopting noisy context learning and scheduled sampling, enabling robust backbone generation. Notably, PAR exhibits strong zero-shot generalization, supporting flexible human-prompted conditional generation and motif scaffolding without requiring fine-tuning. On the unconditional generation benchmark, PAR effectively learns protein distributions and produces backbones of high design quality, and exhibits favorable scaling behavior. Together, these properties establish PAR as a promising framework for protein structure generation.</description><author>Yanru Qu, Cheng-Yen Hsieh, Zaixiang Zheng, Ge Liu, Quanquan Gu</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:59:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04883v1</guid></item><item><title>Contrastive Continual Learning for Model Adaptability in Internet of Things</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04881v1</link><description>Internet of Things (IoT) deployments operate in nonstationary, dynamic environments where factors such as sensor drift, evolving user behavior, and heterogeneous user privacy requirements can affect application utility. Continual learning (CL) addresses this by adapting models over time without catastrophic forgetting. Meanwhile, contrastive learning has emerged as a powerful representation-learning paradigm that improves robustness and sample efficiency in a self-supervised manner. This paper reviews the usage of \emph{contrastive continual learning} (CCL) for IoT, connecting algorithmic design (replay, regularization, distillation, prompts) with IoT system realities (TinyML constraints, intermittent connectivity, privacy). We present a unifying problem formulation, derive common objectives that blend contrastive and distillation losses, propose an IoT-oriented reference architecture for on-device, edge, and cloud-based CCL, and provide guidance on evaluation protocols and metrics. Finally, we highlight open unique challenges with respect to the IoT domain, such as spanning tabular and streaming IoT data, concept drift, federated settings, and energy-aware training.</description><author>Ajesh Koyatan Chathoth</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:59:14 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04881v1</guid></item><item><title>Robust inverse material design with physical guarantees using the Voigt-Reuss Net</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.11388v2</link><description>We propose a spectrally normalized surrogate for forward and inverse mechanical homogenization with hard physical guarantees. Leveraging the Voigt-Reuss bounds, we factor their difference via a Cholesky-like operator and learn a dimensionless, symmetric positive semi-definite representation with eigenvalues in $[0,1]$; the inverse map returns symmetric positive-definite predictions that lie between the bounds in the Löwner sense. In 3D linear elasticity on an open dataset of stochastic biphasic microstructures, a fully connected Voigt-Reuss net trained on $&gt;\!7.5\times 10^{5}$ FFT-based labels with 236 isotropy-invariant descriptors and three contrast parameters recovers the isotropic projection with near-perfect fidelity (isotropy-related entries: $R^2 \ge 0.998$), while anisotropy-revealing couplings are unidentifiable from $SO(3)$-invariant inputs. Tensor-level relative Frobenius errors have median $\approx 1.7\%$ and mean $\approx 3.4\%$ across splits. For 2D plane strain on thresholded trigonometric microstructures, coupling spectral normalization with a differentiable renderer and a CNN yields $R^2&gt;0.99$ on all components, subpercent normalized losses, accurate tracking of percolation-induced eigenvalue jumps, and robust generalization to out-of-distribution images. Treating the parametric microstructure as design variables, batched first-order optimization with a single surrogate matches target tensors within a few percent and returns diverse near-optimal designs. Overall, the Voigt-Reuss net unifies accurate, physically admissible forward prediction with large-batch, constraint-consistent inverse design, and is generic to elliptic operators and coupled-physics settings.</description><author>Sanath Keshav, Felix Fritzen</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:59:08 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.11388v2</guid></item><item><title>Rethinking the Trust Region in LLM Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04879v1</link><description>Reinforcement learning (RL) has become a cornerstone for fine-tuning Large Language Models (LLMs), with Proximal Policy Optimization (PPO) serving as the de facto standard algorithm. Despite its ubiquity, we argue that the core ratio clipping mechanism in PPO is structurally ill-suited for the large vocabularies inherent to LLMs. PPO constrains policy updates based on the probability ratio of sampled tokens, which serves as a noisy single-sample Monte Carlo estimate of the true policy divergence. This creates a sub-optimal learning dynamic: updates to low-probability tokens are aggressively over-penalized, while potentially catastrophic shifts in high-probability tokens are under-constrained, leading to training inefficiency and instability. To address this, we propose Divergence Proximal Policy Optimization (DPPO), which substitutes heuristic clipping with a more principled constraint based on a direct estimate of policy divergence (e.g., Total Variation or KL). To avoid huge memory footprint, we introduce the efficient Binary and Top-K approximations to capture the essential divergence with negligible overhead. Extensive empirical evaluations demonstrate that DPPO achieves superior training stability and efficiency compared to existing methods, offering a more robust foundation for RL-based LLM fine-tuning.</description><author>Penghui Qi, Xiangxin Zhou, Zichen Liu, Tianyu Pang, Chao Du, Min Lin, Wee Sun Lee</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:59:04 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04879v1</guid></item><item><title>CoWTracker: Tracking by Warping instead of Correlation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04877v1</link><description>Dense point tracking is a fundamental problem in computer vision, with applications ranging from video analysis to robotic manipulation. State-of-the-art trackers typically rely on cost volumes to match features across frames, but this approach incurs quadratic complexity in spatial resolution, limiting scalability and efficiency. In this paper, we propose \method, a novel dense point tracker that eschews cost volumes in favor of warping. Inspired by recent advances in optical flow, our approach iteratively refines track estimates by warping features from the target frame to the query frame based on the current estimate. Combined with a transformer architecture that performs joint spatiotemporal reasoning across all tracks, our design establishes long-range correspondences without computing feature correlations. Our model is simple and achieves state-of-the-art performance on standard dense point tracking benchmarks, including TAP-Vid-DAVIS, TAP-Vid-Kinetics, and Robo-TAP. Remarkably, the model also excels at optical flow, sometimes outperforming specialized methods on the Sintel, KITTI, and Spring benchmarks. These results suggest that warping-based architectures can unify dense point tracking and optical flow estimation.</description><author>Zihang Lai, Eldar Insafutdinov, Edgar Sucar, Andrea Vedaldi</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:58:59 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04877v1</guid></item><item><title>PerpetualWonder: Long-Horizon Action-Conditioned 4D Scene Generation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04876v1</link><description>We introduce PerpetualWonder, a hybrid generative simulator that enables long-horizon, action-conditioned 4D scene generation from a single image. Current works fail at this task because their physical state is decoupled from their visual representation, which prevents generative refinements to update the underlying physics for subsequent interactions. PerpetualWonder solves this by introducing the first true closed-loop system. It features a novel unified representation that creates a bidirectional link between the physical state and visual primitives, allowing generative refinements to correct both the dynamics and appearance. It also introduces a robust update mechanism that gathers supervision from multiple viewpoints to resolve optimization ambiguity. Experiments demonstrate that from a single image, PerpetualWonder can successfully simulate complex, multi-step interactions from long-horizon actions, maintaining physical plausibility and visual consistency.</description><author>Jiahao Zhan, Zizhang Li, Hong-Xing Yu, Jiajun Wu</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:58:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04876v1</guid></item><item><title>Laminating Representation Autoencoders for Efficient Diffusion</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04873v1</link><description>Recent work has shown that diffusion models can generate high-quality images by operating directly on SSL patch features rather than pixel-space latents. However, the dense patch grids from encoders like DINOv2 contain significant redundancy, making diffusion needlessly expensive. We introduce FlatDINO, a variational autoencoder that compresses this representation into a one-dimensional sequence of just 32 continuous tokens -an 8x reduction in sequence length and 48x compression in total dimensionality. On ImageNet 256x256, a DiT-XL trained on FlatDINO latents achieves a gFID of 1.80 with classifier-free guidance while requiring 8x fewer FLOPs per forward pass and up to 4.5x fewer FLOPs per training step compared to diffusion on uncompressed DINOv2 features. These are preliminary results and this work is in progress.</description><author>Ramón Calvo-González, François Fleuret</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:57:33 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04873v1</guid></item><item><title>Multi-layer Cross-Attention is Provably Optimal for Multi-modal In-context Learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04872v1</link><description>Recent progress has rapidly advanced our understanding of the mechanisms underlying in-context learning in modern attention-based neural networks. However, existing results focus exclusively on unimodal data; in contrast, the theoretical underpinnings of in-context learning for multi-modal data remain poorly understood. We introduce a mathematically tractable framework for studying multi-modal learning and explore when transformer-like architectures can recover Bayes-optimal performance in-context. To model multi-modal problems, we assume the observed data arises from a latent factor model. Our first result comprises a negative take on expressibility: we prove that single-layer, linear self-attention fails to recover the Bayes-optimal predictor uniformly over the task distribution. To address this limitation, we introduce a novel, linearized cross-attention mechanism, which we study in the regime where both the number of cross-attention layers and the context length are large. We show that this cross-attention mechanism is provably Bayes optimal when optimized using gradient flow. Our results underscore the benefits of depth for in-context learning and establish the provable utility of cross-attention for multi-modal distributions.</description><author>Nicholas Barnfield, Subhabrata Sen, Pragya Sur</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:57:30 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04872v1</guid></item><item><title>Multi-Head LatentMoE and Head Parallel: Communication-Efficient and Deterministic MoE Parallelism</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04870v1</link><description>Large language models have transformed many applications but remain expensive to train. Sparse Mixture of Experts (MoE) addresses this through conditional computation, with Expert Parallel (EP) as the standard distributed training method. However, EP has three limitations: communication cost grows linearly with the number of activated experts $k$, load imbalance affects latency and memory usage, and data-dependent communication requires metadata exchange. We propose Multi-Head LatentMoE and Head Parallel (HP), a new architecture and parallelism achieving $O(1)$ communication cost regardless of $k$, completely balanced traffic, and deterministic communication, all while remaining compatible with EP. To accelerate Multi-Head LatentMoE, we propose IO-aware routing and expert computation. Compared to MoE with EP, Multi-Head LatentMoE with HP trains up to $1.61\times$ faster while having identical performance. With doubled granularity, it achieves higher overall performance while still being $1.11\times$ faster. Our method makes multi-billion-parameter foundation model research more accessible.</description><author>Chenwei Cui, Rockwell Jackson, Benjamin Joseph Herrera, Ana María Tárano, Hannah Kerner</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:57:19 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04870v1</guid></item><item><title>CRoSS: A Continual Robotic Simulation Suite for Scalable Reinforcement Learning with High Task Diversity and Realistic Physics Simulation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04868v1</link><description>Continual reinforcement learning (CRL) requires agents to learn from a sequence of tasks without forgetting previously acquired policies. In this work, we introduce a novel benchmark suite for CRL based on realistically simulated robots in the Gazebo simulator. Our Continual Robotic Simulation Suite (CRoSS) benchmarks rely on two robotic platforms: a two-wheeled differential-drive robot with lidar, camera and bumper sensor, and a robotic arm with seven joints. The former represent an agent in line-following and object-pushing scenarios, where variation of visual and structural parameters yields a large number of distinct tasks, whereas the latter is used in two goal-reaching scenarios with high-level cartesian hand position control (modeled after the Continual World benchmark), and low-level control based on joint angles. For the robotic arm benchmarks, we provide additional kinematics-only variants that bypass the need for physical simulation (as long as no sensor readings are required), and which can be run two orders of magnitude faster. CRoSS is designed to be easily extensible and enables controlled studies of continual reinforcement learning in robotic settings with high physical realism, and in particular allow the use of almost arbitrary simulated sensors. To ensure reproducibility and ease of use, we provide a containerized setup (Apptainer) that runs out-of-the-box, and report performances of standard RL algorithms, including Deep Q-Networks (DQN) and policy gradient methods. This highlights the suitability as a scalable and reproducible benchmark for CRL research.</description><author>Yannick Denker, Alexander Gepperth</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:54:26 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04868v1</guid></item><item><title>When LLaVA Meets Objects: Token Composition for Vision-Language-Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04864v1</link><description>Current autoregressive Vision Language Models (VLMs) usually rely on a large number of visual tokens to represent images, resulting in a need for more compute especially at inference time. To address this problem, we propose Mask-LLaVA, a framework that leverages different levels of visual features to create a compact yet information-rich visual representation for autoregressive VLMs. Namely, we combine mask-based object representations together with global tokens and local patch tokens. While all tokens are used during training, it shows that the resulting model can flexibly drop especially the number of mask-based object-tokens at test time, allowing to adapt the number of tokens during inference without the need to retrain the model and without a significant drop in performance. We evaluate the proposed approach on a suite of standard benchmarks showing results competitive to current token efficient methods and comparable to the original LLaVA baseline using only a fraction of visual tokens. Our analysis demonstrates that combining multi-level features enables efficient learning with fewer tokens while allowing dynamic token selection at test time for good performance.</description><author>Soumya Jahagirdar, Walid Bousselham, Anna Kukleva, Hilde Kuehne</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:50:46 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04864v1</guid></item><item><title>Subliminal Effects in Your Data: A General Mechanism via Log-Linearity</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04863v1</link><description>Training modern large language models (LLMs) has become a veritable smorgasbord of algorithms and datasets designed to elicit particular behaviors, making it critical to develop techniques to understand the effects of datasets on the model's properties. This is exacerbated by recent experiments that show datasets can transmit signals that are not directly observable from individual datapoints, posing a conceptual challenge for dataset-centric understandings of LLM training and suggesting a missing fundamental account of such phenomena. Towards understanding such effects, inspired by recent work on the linear structure of LLMs, we uncover a general mechanism through which hidden subtexts can arise in generic datasets. We introduce Logit-Linear-Selection (LLS), a method that prescribes how to select subsets of a generic preference dataset to elicit a wide range of hidden effects. We apply LLS to discover subsets of real-world datasets so that models trained on them exhibit behaviors ranging from having specific preferences, to responding to prompts in a different language not present in the dataset, to taking on a different persona. Crucially, the effect persists for the selected subset, across models with varying architectures, supporting its generality and universality.</description><author>Ishaq Aden-Ali, Noah Golowich, Allen Liu, Abhishek Shetty, Ankur Moitra, Nika Haghtalab</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:50:46 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04863v1</guid></item><item><title>From Evaluation to Design: Using Potential Energy Surface Smoothness Metrics to Guide Machine Learning Interatomic Potential Architectures</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04861v1</link><description>Machine Learning Interatomic Potentials (MLIPs) sometimes fail to reproduce the physical smoothness of the quantum potential energy surface (PES), leading to erroneous behavior in downstream simulations that standard energy and force regression evaluations can miss. Existing evaluations, such as microcanonical molecular dynamics (MD), are computationally expensive and primarily probe near-equilibrium states. To improve evaluation metrics for MLIPs, we introduce the Bond Smoothness Characterization Test (BSCT). This efficient benchmark probes the PES via controlled bond deformations and detects non-smoothness, including discontinuities, artificial minima, and spurious forces, both near and far from equilibrium. We show that BSCT correlates strongly with MD stability while requiring a fraction of the cost of MD. To demonstrate how BSCT can guide iterative model design, we utilize an unconstrained Transformer backbone as a testbed, illustrating how refinements such as a new differentiable $k$-nearest neighbors algorithm and temperature-controlled attention reduce artifacts identified by our metric. By optimizing model design systematically based on BSCT, the resulting MLIP simultaneously achieves a low conventional E/F regression error, stable MD simulations, and robust atomistic property predictions. Our results establish BSCT as both a validation metric and as an "in-the-loop" model design proxy that alerts MLIP developers to physical challenges that cannot be efficiently evaluated by current MLIP benchmarks.</description><author>Ryan Liu, Eric Qu, Tobias Kreiman, Samuel M. Blau, Aditi S. Krishnapriyan</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:50:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04861v1</guid></item><item><title>Combining Residual U-Net and Data Augmentation for Dense Temporal Segmentation of Spike Wave Discharges in Single-Channel EEG</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.00459v2</link><description>Manual annotation of spike-wave discharges (SWDs), the electrographic hallmark of absence seizures, is labor-intensive for long-term electroencephalography (EEG) monitoring studies. While machine learning approaches show promise for automated detection, they often struggle with cross-subject generalization due to high inter-individual variability in seizure morphology and signal characteristics. In this study we compare the performance of 15 machine learning classifiers on our own manually annotated dataset of 961 hours of EEG recordings from C3H/HeJ mice, including 22,637 labeled SWDs and find that a 1D U-Net performs the best. We then improve its performance by employing residual connections and data augmentation strategies combining amplitude scaling, Gaussian noise injection, and signal inversion during training to enhance cross-subject generalization. We also compare our method, named AugUNet1D, to a recently published time- and frequency-based algorithmic approach called "Twin Peaks" and show that AugUNet1D performs better on our dataset. AugUNet1D, pretrained on our manually annotated data or untrained, is made public for other users.</description><author>Saurav Sengupta, Scott Kilianski, Suchetha Sharma, Sakina Lashkeri, Ashley McHugh, Mark Beenhakker, Donald E. Brown</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:43:14 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.00459v2</guid></item><item><title>CoT is Not the Chain of Truth: An Empirical Internal Analysis of Reasoning LLMs for Fake News Generation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04856v1</link><description>From generating headlines to fabricating news, the Large Language Models (LLMs) are typically assessed by their final outputs, under the safety assumption that a refusal response signifies safe reasoning throughout the entire process. Challenging this assumption, our study reveals that during fake news generation, even when a model rejects a harmful request, its Chain-of-Thought (CoT) reasoning may still internally contain and propagate unsafe narratives. To analyze this phenomenon, we introduce a unified safety-analysis framework that systematically deconstructs CoT generation across model layers and evaluates the role of individual attention heads through Jacobian-based spectral metrics. Within this framework, we introduce three interpretable measures: stability, geometry, and energy to quantify how specific attention heads respond or embed deceptive reasoning patterns. Extensive experiments on multiple reasoning-oriented LLMs show that the generation risk rise significantly when the thinking mode is activated, where the critical routing decisions concentrated in only a few contiguous mid-depth layers. By precisely identifying the attention heads responsible for this divergence, our work challenges the assumption that refusal implies safety and provides a new understanding perspective for mitigating latent reasoning risks.</description><author>Zhao Tong, Chunlin Gong, Yiping Zhang, Qiang Liu, Xingcheng Xu, Shu Wu, Haichao Shi, Xiao-Yu Zhang</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:43:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04856v1</guid></item><item><title>Comparing statistical and deep learning techniques for parameter estimation of continuous-time stochastic differentiable equations</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.03980v2</link><description>Stochastic differential equations such as the Ornstein-Uhlenbeck process have long been used to model realworld probablistic events such as stock prices and temperature fluctuations. While statistical methods such as Maximum Likelihood Estimation (MLE), Kalman Filtering, Inverse Variable Method, and more have historically been used to estimate the parameters of stochastic differential equations, the recent explosion of deep learning technology suggests that models such as a Recurrent Neural Network (RNN) could produce more precise estimators. We present a series of experiments that compare the estimation accuracy and computational expensiveness of a statistical method (MLE) with a deep learning model (RNN) for the parameters of the Ornstein-Uhlenbeck process.</description><author>Aroon Sankoh, Victor Wickerhauser</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:42:42 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.03980v2</guid></item><item><title>Beyond Fixed Frames: Dynamic Character-Aligned Speech Tokenization</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.23174v2</link><description>Neural audio codecs are at the core of modern conversational speech technologies, converting continuous speech into sequences of discrete tokens that can be processed by LLMs. However, existing codecs typically operate at fixed frame rates, allocating tokens uniformly in time and producing unnecessarily long sequences. In this work, we introduce DyCAST, a Dynamic Character-Aligned Speech Tokenizer that enables variable-frame-rate tokenization through soft character-level alignment and explicit duration modeling. DyCAST learns to associate tokens with character-level linguistic units during training and supports alignment-free inference with direct control over token durations at decoding time. To improve speech resynthesis quality at low frame rates, we further introduce a retrieval-augmented decoding mechanism that enhances reconstruction fidelity without increasing bitrate. Experiments show that DyCAST achieves competitive speech resynthesis quality and downstream performance while using significantly fewer tokens than fixed-frame-rate codecs. Code and checkpoints will be released publicly at https://github.com/lucadellalib/dycast.</description><author>Luca Della Libera, Cem Subakan, Mirco Ravanelli</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:42:12 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.23174v2</guid></item><item><title>Decomposed Prompting Does Not Fix Knowledge Gaps, But Helps Models Say "I Don't Know"</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04853v1</link><description>Large language models often struggle to recognize their knowledge limits in closed-book question answering, leading to confident hallucinations. While decomposed prompting is typically used to improve accuracy, we investigate its impact on reliability. We evaluate three task-equivalent prompting regimes: Direct, Assistive, and Incremental, across different model scales and multi-hop QA benchmarks. We find that although accuracy gains from decomposition diminish in frontier models, disagreements between prompting regimes remain highly indicative of potential errors. Because factual knowledge is stable while hallucinations are stochastic, cross-regime agreement provides a precise signal of internal uncertainty. We leverage this signal to implement a training-free abstention policy that requires no retrieval or fine-tuning. Our results show that disagreement-based abstention outperforms standard uncertainty baselines as an error detector, improving both F1 and AUROC across settings. This demonstrates that decomposition-based prompting can serve as a practical diagnostic probe for model reliability in closed-book QA.</description><author>Dhruv Madhwal, Lyuxin David Zhang, Dan Roth, Tomer Wolfson, Vivek Gupta</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:39:58 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04853v1</guid></item><item><title>The Key to State Reduction in Linear Attention: A Rank-based Perspective</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04852v1</link><description>Linear attention offers a computationally efficient yet expressive alternative to softmax attention. However, recent empirical results indicate that the state of trained linear attention models often exhibits a low-rank structure, suggesting that these models underexploit their capacity in practice. To illuminate this phenomenon, we provide a theoretical analysis of the role of rank in linear attention, revealing that low effective rank can affect retrieval error by amplifying query noise. In addition to these theoretical insights, we conjecture that the low-rank states can be substantially reduced post-training with only minimal performance degradation, yielding faster and more memory-efficient models. To this end, we propose a novel hardware-aware approach that structurally prunes key and query matrices, reducing the state size while retaining compatibility with existing CUDA kernels. We adapt several existing pruning strategies to fit our framework and, building on our theoretical analysis, propose a novel structured pruning method based on a rank-revealing QR decomposition. Our empirical results, evaluated across models of varying sizes and on various downstream tasks, demonstrate the effectiveness of our state reduction framework. We highlight that our framework enables the removal of 50% of the query and key channels at only a marginal increase in perplexity. The code for this project can be found at https://github.com/camail-official/LinearAttentionPruning.</description><author>Philipp Nazari, T. Konstantin Rusch</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:39:38 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04852v1</guid></item><item><title>PDF-HR: Pose Distance Fields for Humanoid Robots</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04851v1</link><description>Pose and motion priors play a crucial role in humanoid robotics. Although such priors have been widely studied in human motion recovery (HMR) domain with a range of models, their adoption for humanoid robots remains limited, largely due to the scarcity of high-quality humanoid motion data. In this work, we introduce Pose Distance Fields for Humanoid Robots (PDF-HR), a lightweight prior that represents the robot pose distribution as a continuous and differentiable manifold. Given an arbitrary pose, PDF-HR predicts its distance to a large corpus of retargeted robot poses, yielding a smooth measure of pose plausibility that is well suited for optimization and control. PDF-HR can be integrated as a reward shaping term, a regularizer, or a standalone plausibility scorer across diverse pipelines. We evaluate PDF-HR on various humanoid tasks, including single-trajectory motion tracking, general motion tracking, style-based motion mimicry, and general motion retargeting. Experiments show that this plug-and-play prior consistently and substantially strengthens strong baselines. Code and models will be released.</description><author>Yi Gu, Yukang Gao, Yangchen Zhou, Xingyu Chen, Yixiao Feng, Mingle Zhao, Yunyang Mo, Zhaorui Wang, Lixin Xu, Renjing Xu</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:38:51 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04851v1</guid></item><item><title>El Agente Quntur: A research collaborator agent for quantum chemistry</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04850v1</link><description>Quantum chemistry is a foundational enabling tool for the fields of chemistry, materials science, computational biology and others. Despite of its power, the practical application of quantum chemistry simulations remains in the hands of qualified experts due to methodological complexity, software heterogeneity, and the need for informed interpretation of results. To bridge the accessibility gap for these tools and expand their reach to chemists with broader backgrounds, we introduce El Agente Quntur, a hierarchical, multi-agent AI system designed to operate not merely as an automation tool but as a research collaborator for computational quantum chemistry. Quntur was designed following three main strategies: i) elimination of hard-coded procedural policies in favour of reasoning-driven decisions, ii) construction of general and composable actions that facilitate generalization and efficiency, and iii) implementation of guided deep research to integrate abstract quantum-chemical reasoning across subdisciplines and a detailed understanding of the software's internal logic and syntax. Although instantiated in ORCA, these design principles are applicable to research agents more generally and easily expandable to additional quantum chemistry packages and beyond. Quntur supports the full range of calculations available in ORCA 6.0 and reasons over software documentation and scientific literature to plan, execute, adapt, and analyze in silico chemistry experiments following best practices. We discuss the advances and current bottlenecks in agentic systems operating at the research level in computational chemistry, and outline a roadmap toward a fully autonomous end-to-end computational chemistry research agent.</description><author>Juan B. Pérez-Sánchez, Yunheng Zou, Jorge A. Campos-Gonzalez-Angulo, Marcel Müller, Ignacio Gustin, Andrew Wang, Han Hao, Tsz Wai Ko, Changhyeok Choi, Eric S. Isbrandt, Mohammad Ghazi Vakili, Hanyong Xu, Chris Crebolder, Varinia Bernales, Alán Aspuru-Guzik</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:38:50 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04850v1</guid></item><item><title>El Agente Estructural: An Artificially Intelligent Molecular Editor</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04849v1</link><description>We present El Agente Estructural, a multimodal, natural-language-driven geometry-generation and manipulation agent for autonomous chemistry and molecular modelling. Unlike molecular generation or editing via generative models, Estructural mimics how human experts directly manipulate molecular systems in three dimensions by integrating a comprehensive set of domain-informed tools and vision-language models. This design enables precise control over atomic or functional group replacements, atomic connectivity, and stereochemistry without the need to rebuild extensive core molecular frameworks. Through a series of representative case studies, we demonstrate that Estructural enables chemically meaningful geometry manipulation across a wide range of real-world scenarios. These include site-selective functionalization, ligand binding, ligand exchange, stereochemically controlled structure construction, isomer interconversion, fragment-level structural analysis, image-guided generation of structures from schematic reaction mechanisms, and mechanism-driven geometry generation and modification. These examples illustrate how multimodal reasoning, when combined with specialized geometry-aware tools, supports interactive and context-aware molecular modelling beyond structure generation. Looking forward, the integration of Estructural into El Agente Quntur, an autonomous multi-agent quantum chemistry platform, enhances its capabilities by adding sophisticated tools for the generation and editing of three-dimensional structures.</description><author>Changhyeok Choi, Yunheng Zou, Marcel Müller, Han Hao, Yeonghun Kang, Juan B. Pérez-Sánchez, Ignacio Gustin, Hanyong Xu, Mohammad Ghazi Vakili, Chris Crebolder, Alán Aspuru-Guzik, Varinia Bernales</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:38:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04849v1</guid></item><item><title>Fluid Representations in Reasoning Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04843v1</link><description>Reasoning language models, which generate long chains of thought, dramatically outperform non-reasoning language models on abstract problems. However, the internal model mechanisms that allow this superior performance remain poorly understood. We present a mechanistic analysis of how QwQ-32B - a model specifically trained to produce extensive reasoning traces - process abstract structural information. On Mystery Blocksworld - a semantically obfuscated planning domain - we find that QwQ-32B gradually improves its internal representation of actions and concepts during reasoning. The model develops abstract encodings that focus on structure rather than specific action names. Through steering experiments, we establish causal evidence that these adaptations improve problem solving: injecting refined representations from successful traces boosts accuracy, while symbolic representations can replace many obfuscated encodings with minimal performance loss. We find that one of the factors driving reasoning model performance is in-context refinement of token representations, which we dub Fluid Reasoning Representations.</description><author>Dmitrii Kharlapenko, Alessandro Stolfo, Arthur Conmy, Mrinmaya Sachan, Zhijing Jin</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:34:50 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04843v1</guid></item><item><title>LitS: A novel Neighborhood Descriptor for Point Clouds</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04838v1</link><description>With the advancement of 3D scanning technologies, point clouds have become fundamental for representing 3D spatial data, with applications that span across various scientific and technological fields. Practical analysis of this data depends crucially on available neighborhood descriptors to accurately characterize the local geometries of the point cloud. This paper introduces LitS, a novel neighborhood descriptor for 2D and 3D point clouds. LitS are piecewise constant functions on the unit circle that allow points to keep track of their surroundings. Each element in LitS' domain represents a direction with respect to a local reference system. Once constructed, evaluating LitS at any given direction gives us information about the number of neighbors in a cone-like region centered around that same direction. Thus, LitS conveys a lot of information about the local neighborhood of a point, which can be leveraged to gain global structural understanding by analyzing how LitS changes between close points. In addition, LitS comes in two versions ('regular' and 'cumulative') and has two parameters, allowing them to adapt to various contexts and types of point clouds. Overall, they are a versatile neighborhood descriptor, capable of capturing the nuances of local point arrangements and resilient to common point cloud data issues such as variable density and noise.</description><author>Jonatan B. Bastos, Francisco F. Rivera, Oscar G. Lorenzo, David L. Vilariño, José C. Cabaleiro, Alberto M. Esmorís, Tomás F. Pena</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:31:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04838v1</guid></item><item><title>Personalized Image Generation via Human-in-the-loop Bayesian Optimization</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.02388v2</link><description>Imagine Alice has a specific image $x^\ast$ in her mind, say, the view of the street in which she grew up during her childhood. To generate that exact image, she guides a generative model with multiple rounds of prompting and arrives at an image $x^{p*}$. Although $x^{p*}$ is reasonably close to $x^\ast$, Alice finds it difficult to close that gap using language prompts. This paper aims to narrow this gap by observing that even after language has reached its limits, humans can still tell when a new image $x^+$ is closer to $x^\ast$ than $x^{p*}$. Leveraging this observation, we develop MultiBO (Multi-Choice Preferential Bayesian Optimization) that carefully generates $K$ new images as a function of $x^{p*}$, gets preferential feedback from the user, uses the feedback to guide the diffusion model, and ultimately generates a new set of $K$ images. We show that within $B$ rounds of user feedback, it is possible to arrive much closer to $x^\ast$, even though the generative model has no information about $x^\ast$. Qualitative scores from $30$ users, combined with quantitative metrics compared across $5$ baselines, show promising results, suggesting that multi-choice feedback from humans can be effectively harnessed for personalized image generation.</description><author>Rajalaxmi Rajagopalan, Debottam Dutta, Yu-Lin Wei, Romit Roy Choudhury</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:30:51 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.02388v2</guid></item><item><title>OverThink: Slowdown Attacks on Reasoning LLMs</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.02542v4</link><description>Most flagship language models generate explicit reasoning chains, enabling inference-time scaling. However, producing these reasoning chains increases token usage (i.e., reasoning tokens), which in turn increases latency and costs. Our OverThink attack increases overhead for applications that rely on reasoning language models (RLMs) and external context by forcing them to spend substantially more reasoning tokens while still producing contextually correct answers. An adversary mounts an attack by injecting decoy reasoning problems into public content that is consumed by RLM at inference time. Because our decoys (e.g., Markov decision processes, Sudokus, etc.) are benign, they evade safety filters. We evaluate OverThink on both closed-source and open-source reasoning models across the FreshQA, SQuAD, and MuSR datasets. We also explore the attack in multi-modal settings by creating images that cause excessive reasoning. We show that the resulting slowdown transfers across models. Finally, we explore both LLM-based and systems-level defenses, and discuss the societal, financial, and energy implications of the OverThink attacks.</description><author>Abhinav Kumar, Jaechul Roh, Ali Naseh, Marzena Karpinska, Mohit Iyyer, Amir Houmansadr, Eugene Bagdasarian</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:30:03 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.02542v4</guid></item><item><title>Group-Evolving Agents: Open-Ended Self-Improvement via Experience Sharing</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04837v1</link><description>Open-ended self-improving agents can autonomously modify their own structural designs to advance their capabilities and overcome the limits of pre-defined architectures, thus reducing reliance on human intervention. We introduce Group-Evolving Agents (GEA), a new paradigm for open-ended self-improvements, which treats a group of agents as the fundamental evolutionary unit, enabling explicit experience sharing and reuse within the group throughout evolution. Unlike existing open-ended self-evolving paradigms that adopt tree-structured evolution, GEA overcomes the limitation of inefficient utilization of exploratory diversity caused by isolated evolutionary branches. We evaluate GEA on challenging coding benchmarks, where it significantly outperforms state-of-the-art self-evolving methods (71.0% vs. 56.7% on SWE-bench Verified, 88.3% vs. 68.3% on Polyglot) and matches or exceeds top human-designed agent frameworks (71.8% and 52.0% on two benchmarks, respectively). Analysis reveals that GEA more effectively converts early-stage exploratory diversity into sustained, long-term progress, achieving stronger performance under the same number of evolved agents. Furthermore, GEA exhibits consistent transferability across different coding models and greater robustness, fixing framework-level bugs in 1.4 iterations on average, versus 5 for self-evolving methods.</description><author>Zhaotian Weng, Antonis Antoniades, Deepak Nathani, Zhen Zhang, Xiao Pu, Xin Eric Wang</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:29:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04837v1</guid></item><item><title>Grammatical Error Correction for Low-Resource Languages: The Case of Zarma</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.15539v3</link><description>Grammatical error correction (GEC) aims to improve text quality and readability. Previous work on the task focused primarily on high-resource languages, while low-resource languages lack robust tools. To address this shortcoming, we present a study on GEC for Zarma, a language spoken by over five million people in West Africa. We compare three approaches: rule-based methods, machine translation (MT) models, and large language models (LLMs). We evaluated GEC models using a dataset of more than 250,000 examples, including synthetic and human-annotated data. Our results showed that the MT-based approach using M2M100 outperforms others, with a detection rate of 95.82% and a suggestion accuracy of 78.90% in automatic evaluations (AE) and an average score of 3.0 out of 5.0 in manual evaluation (ME) from native speakers for grammar and logical corrections. The rule-based method was effective for spelling errors but failed on complex context-level errors. LLMs -- Gemma 2b and MT5-small -- showed moderate performance. Our work supports use of MT models to enhance GEC in low-resource settings, and we validated these results with Bambara, another West African language.</description><author>Mamadou K. Keita, Adwoa Bremang, Huy Le, Dennis Owusu, Christopher Homan, Marcos Zampieri</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:29:35 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.15539v3</guid></item><item><title>Group-Adaptive Adversarial Learning for Robust Fake News Detection Against Malicious Comments</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.09712v2</link><description>Online fake news profoundly distorts public judgment and erodes trust in social platforms. While existing detectors achieve competitive performance on benchmark datasets, they remain notably vulnerable to malicious comments designed specifically to induce misclassification. This evolving threat landscape necessitates detection systems that simultaneously prioritize predictive accuracy and structural robustness. However, current detectors often fail to generalize across diverse and novel comment attack patterns. To bridge this gap, we propose AdComment, an adaptive adversarial training framework for robustness enhancement against diverse malicious comments. Based on cognitive psychology, we categorize adversarial comments into Fact Distortion, Logical Confusion, and Emotional Manipulation, and leverage LLMs to synthesize diverse, category-specific perturbations. Central to our framework is an InfoDirichlet Resampling (IDR) mechanism that dynamically adjusts malicious comment proportions during training, thereby steering optimization toward the model's most susceptible regions. Experimental results demonstrate that our approach achieves state-of-the-art performance on three benchmark datasets, improving the F1 scores by 17.9%, 14.5% and 9.0%, respectively.</description><author>Zhao Tong, Chunlin Gong, Yimeng Gu, Haichao Shi, Qiang Liu, Shu Wu, Xiao-Yu Zhang</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:29:24 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.09712v2</guid></item><item><title>Are AI Capabilities Increasing Exponentially? A Competing Hypothesis</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04836v1</link><description>Rapidly increasing AI capabilities have substantial real-world consequences, ranging from AI safety concerns to labor market consequences. The Model Evaluation &amp; Threat Research (METR) report argues that AI capabilities have exhibited exponential growth since 2019. In this note, we argue that the data does not support exponential growth, even in shorter-term horizons. Whereas the METR study claims that fitting sigmoid/logistic curves results in inflection points far in the future, we fit a sigmoid curve to their current data and find that the inflection point has already passed. In addition, we propose a more complex model that decomposes AI capabilities into base and reasoning capabilities, exhibiting individual rates of improvement. We prove that this model supports our hypothesis that AI capabilities will exhibit an inflection point in the near future. Our goal is not to establish a rigorous forecast of our own, but to highlight the fragility of existing forecasts of exponential growth.</description><author>Haosen Ge, Hamsa Bastani, Osbert Bastani</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:28:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04836v1</guid></item><item><title>It's not a Lottery, it's a Race: Understanding How Gradient Descent Adapts the Network's Capacity to the Task</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04832v1</link><description>Our theoretical understanding of neural networks is lagging behind their empirical success. One of the important unexplained phenomena is why and how, during the process of training with gradient descent, the theoretical capacity of neural networks is reduced to an effective capacity that fits the task. We here investigate the mechanism by which gradient descent achieves this through analyzing the learning dynamics at the level of individual neurons in single hidden layer ReLU networks. We identify three dynamical principles -- mutual alignment, unlocking and racing -- that together explain why we can often successfully reduce capacity after training through the merging of equivalent neurons or the pruning of low norm weights. We specifically explain the mechanism behind the lottery ticket conjecture, or why the specific, beneficial initial conditions of some neurons lead them to obtain higher weight norms.</description><author>Hannah Pinson</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:22:40 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04832v1</guid></item><item><title>Guardrailed Uplift Targeting: A Causal Optimization Playbook for Marketing Strategy</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.19805v2</link><description>This paper introduces a marketing decision framework that optimizes customer targeting by integrating heterogeneous treatment effect estimation with explicit business guardrails. The objective is to maximize revenue and retention while adhering to constraints such as budget, revenue protection, and customer experience. The framework first estimates Conditional Average Treatment Effects (CATE) using uplift learners, then solves a constrained allocation problem to decide whom to target and which offer to deploy. It supports decisions in retention messaging, event rewards, and spend-threshold assignment. Validated through offline simulations and online A/B tests, the approach consistently outperforms propensity and static baselines, offering a reusable playbook for causal targeting at scale.</description><author>Deepit Sapru</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:18:31 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.19805v2</guid></item><item><title>Domain Generalization Under Posterior Drift</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.04441v2</link><description>Domain generalization (DG) is the problem of generalizing from several distributions (or domains), for which labeled training data are available, to a new test domain for which no labeled data is available. For the prevailing benchmark datasets in DG, there exists a single classifier that performs well across all domains. In this work, we study a fundamentally different regime where the domains satisfy a \emph{posterior drift} assumption, in which the optimal classifier might vary substantially with domain. We establish a decision-theoretic framework for DG under posterior drift, and investigate the practical implications of this framework through experiments on language and vision tasks.</description><author>Yilun Zhu, Naihao Deng, Naichen Shi, Aditya Gangrade, Clayton Scott</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:18:17 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.04441v2</guid></item><item><title>Attention Consistency Regularization for Interpretable Early-Exit Neural Networks</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.08891v2</link><description>Early-exit neural networks enable adaptive inference by allowing predictions at intermediate layers, reducing computational cost. However, early exits often lack interpretability and may focus on different features than deeper layers, limiting trust and explainability. This paper presents Explanation-Guided Training (EGT), a multi-objective framework that improves interpretability and consistency in early-exit networks through attention-based regularization. EGT introduces an attention consistency loss that aligns early-exit attention maps with the final exit. The framework jointly optimizes classification accuracy and attention consistency through a weighted combination of losses. Experiments on a real-world image classification dataset demonstrate that EGT achieves up to 98.97% overall accuracy (matching baseline performance) with a 1.97x inference speedup through early exits, while improving attention consistency by up to 18.5% compared to baseline models. The proposed method provides more interpretable and consistent explanations across all exit points, making early-exit networks more suitable for explainable AI applications in resource-constrained environments.</description><author>Yanhua Zhao</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:16:12 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.08891v2</guid></item><item><title>TRACE: Transparent Web Reliability Assessment with Contextual Explanations</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.12072v3</link><description>In an era of AI-generated misinformation flooding the web, existing tools struggle to empower users with nuanced, transparent assessments of content credibility. They often default to binary (true/false) classifications without contextual justifications, leaving users vulnerable to disinformation. We address this gap by introducing TRACE: Transparent Reliability Assessment with Contextual Explanations, a unified framework that performs two key tasks: (1) it assigns a fine-grained, continuous reliability score (from 0.1 to 1.0) to web content, and (2) it generates a contextual explanation for its assessment. The core of TRACE is the TrueGL-1B model, fine-tuned on a novel, large-scale dataset of over 140,000 articles. This dataset's primary contribution is its annotation with 35 distinct continuous reliability scores, created using a Human-LLM co-creation and data poisoning paradigm. This method overcomes the limitations of binary-labeled datasets by populating the mid-ranges of reliability. In our evaluation, TrueGL-1B consistently outperforms other small-scale LLM baselines and rule-based approaches on key regression metrics, including MAE, RMSE, and R2. The model's high accuracy and interpretable justifications make trustworthy information more accessible. To foster future research, our code and model are made publicly available here: github.com/zade90/TrueGL.</description><author>Joydeep Chandra, Aleksandr Algazinov, Satyam Kumar Navneet, Rim El Filali, Matt Laing, Andrew Hanna, Yong Zhang</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:13:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.12072v3</guid></item><item><title>Safe Urban Traffic Control via Uncertainty-Aware Conformal Prediction and World-Model Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04821v1</link><description>Urban traffic management demands systems that simultaneously predict future conditions, detect anomalies, and take safe corrective actions -- all while providing reliability guarantees. We present STREAM-RL, a unified framework that introduces three novel algorithmic contributions: (1) PU-GAT+, an Uncertainty-Guided Adaptive Conformal Forecaster that uses prediction uncertainty to dynamically reweight graph attention via confidence-monotonic attention, achieving distribution-free coverage guarantees; (2) CRFN-BY, a Conformal Residual Flow Network that models uncertainty-normalized residuals via normalizing flows with Benjamini-Yekutieli FDR control under arbitrary dependence; and (3) LyCon-WRL+, an Uncertainty-Guided Safe World-Model RL agent with Lyapunov stability certificates, certified Lipschitz bounds, and uncertainty-propagated imagination rollouts. To our knowledge, this is the first framework to propagate calibrated uncertainty from forecasting through anomaly detection to safe policy learning with end-to-end theoretical guarantees. Experiments on multiple real-world traffic trajectory data demonstrate that STREAM-RL achieves 91.4\% coverage efficiency, controls FDR at 4.1\% under verified dependence, and improves safety rate to 95.2\% compared to 69\% for standard PPO while achieving higher reward, with 23ms end-to-end inference latency.</description><author>Joydeep Chandra, Satyam Kumar Navneet, Aleksandr Algazinov, Yong Zhang</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:10:59 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04821v1</guid></item><item><title>Toward Reliable and Explainable Nail Disease Classification: Leveraging Adversarial Training and Grad-CAM Visualization</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04820v1</link><description>Human nail diseases are gradually observed over all age groups, especially among older individuals, often going ignored until they become severe. Early detection and accurate diagnosis of such conditions are important because they sometimes reveal our body's health problems. But it is challenging due to the inferred visual differences between disease types. This paper presents a machine learning-based model for automated classification of nail diseases based on a publicly available dataset, which contains 3,835 images scaling six categories. In 224x224 pixels, all images were resized to ensure consistency. To evaluate performance, four well-known CNN models-InceptionV3, DenseNet201, EfficientNetV2, and ResNet50 were trained and analyzed. Among these, InceptionV3 outperformed the others with an accuracy of 95.57%, while DenseNet201 came next with 94.79%. To make the model stronger and less likely to make mistakes on tricky or noisy images, we used adversarial training. To help understand how the model makes decisions, we used SHAP to highlight important features in the predictions. This system could be a helpful support for doctors, making nail disease diagnosis more accurate and faster.</description><author>Farzia Hossain, Samanta Ghosh, Shahida Begum, B. M. Shahria Alam, Mohammad Tahmid Noor, Md Parvez Mia, Nishat Tasnim Niloy</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:08:13 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04820v1</guid></item><item><title>XtraLight-MedMamba for Classification of Neoplastic Tubular Adenomas</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04819v1</link><description>Accurate risk stratification of precancerous polyps during routine colonoscopy screenings is essential for lowering the risk of developing colorectal cancer (CRC). However, assessment of low-grade dysplasia remains limited by subjective histopathologic interpretation. Advancements in digital pathology and deep learning provide new opportunities to identify subtle and fine morphologic patterns associated with malignant progression that may be imperceptible to the human eye. In this work, we propose XtraLight-MedMamba, an ultra-lightweight state-space-based deep learning framework for classifying neoplastic tubular adenomas from whole-slide images (WSIs). The architecture is a blend of ConvNext based shallow feature extractor with parallel vision mamba to efficiently model both long- and short-range dependencies and image generalization. An integration of Spatial and Channel Attention Bridge (SCAB) module enhances multiscale feature extraction, while Fixed Non-Negative Orthogonal Classifier (FNOClassifier) enables substantial parameter reduction and improved generalization. The model was evaluated on a curated dataset acquired from patients with low-grade tubular adenomas, stratified into case and control cohorts based on subsequent CRC development. XtraLight-MedMamba achieved an accuracy of 97.18% and an F1-score of 0.9767 using approximately 32,000 parameters, outperforming transformer-based and conventional Mamba architectures with significantly higher model complexity.</description><author>Aqsa Sultana, Rayan Afsar, Ahmed Rahu, Surendra P. Singh, Brian Shula, Brandon Combs, Derrick Forchetti, Vijayan K. Asari</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:07:51 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04819v1</guid></item><item><title>A Generalization Bound for a Family of Implicit Networks</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.07427v4</link><description>Implicit networks are a class of neural networks whose outputs are defined by the fixed point of a parameterized operator. They have enjoyed success in many applications including natural language processing, image processing, and numerous other applications. While they have found abundant empirical success, theoretical work on its generalization is still under-explored. In this work, we consider a large family of implicit networks defined parameterized contractive fixed point operators. We show a generalization bound for this class based on a covering number argument for the Rademacher complexity of these architectures.</description><author>Samy Wu Fung, Benjamin Berkels</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:05:18 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.07427v4</guid></item><item><title>Horizon-LM: A RAM-Centric Architecture for LLM Training</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04816v1</link><description>The rapid growth of large language models (LLMs) has outpaced the evolution of single-GPU hardware, making model scale increasingly constrained by memory capacity rather than computation. While modern training systems extend GPU memory through distributed parallelism and offloading across CPU and storage tiers, they fundamentally retain a GPU-centric execution paradigm in which GPUs host persistent model replicas and full autograd graphs. As a result, scaling large models remains tightly coupled to multi-GPU clusters, complex distributed runtimes, and unpredictable host memory consumption, creating substantial barriers for node-scale post-training workloads such as instruction tuning, alignment, and domain adaptation. We present Horizon-LM, a memory-centric training system that redefines the roles of CPU and GPU for large-model optimization. Horizon-LM treats host memory as the authoritative parameter store and uses GPUs solely as transient compute engines through a CPU-master, GPU-template execution model. By eliminating persistent GPU-resident modules and autograd graphs, employing explicit recomputation with manual gradient propagation, and introducing a pipelined double-buffered execution engine, Horizon-LM decouples model scale from GPU count and bounds memory usage to the theoretical parameter footprint. On a single H200 GPU with 1.5\,TB host RAM, Horizon-LM reliably trains models up to 120B parameters. On a standard single A100 machine, Horizon-LM achieves up to 12.2$\times$ higher training throughput than DeepSpeed ZeRO-3 with CPU offloading while preserving numerical correctness. Across platforms and scales, Horizon-LM sustains high device utilization and predictable memory growth, demonstrating that host memory, not GPU memory, defines the true feasibility boundary for node-scale large-model training.</description><author>Zhengqing Yuan, Lichao Sun, Yanfang, Ye</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:04:46 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04816v1</guid></item><item><title>DGS-Net: Distillation-Guided Gradient Surgery for CLIP Fine-Tuning in AI-Generated Image Detection</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.13108v2</link><description>The rapid progress of generative models such as GANs and diffusion models has led to the widespread proliferation of AI-generated images, raising concerns about misinformation, privacy violations, and trust erosion in digital media. Although large-scale multimodal models like CLIP offer strong transferable representations for detecting synthetic content, fine-tuning them often induces catastrophic forgetting, which degrades pre-trained priors and limits cross-domain generalization. To address this issue, we propose the Distillation-guided Gradient Surgery Network (DGS-Net), a novel framework that preserves transferable pre-trained priors while suppressing task-irrelevant components. Specifically, we introduce a gradient-space decomposition that separates harmful and beneficial descent directions during optimization. By projecting task gradients onto the orthogonal complement of harmful directions and aligning with beneficial ones distilled from a frozen CLIP encoder, DGS-Net achieves unified optimization of prior preservation and irrelevant suppression. Extensive experiments on 50 generative models demonstrate that our method outperforms state-of-the-art approaches by an average margin of 6.6, achieving superior detection performance and generalization across diverse generation techniques.</description><author>Jiazhen Yan, Ziqiang Li, Fan Wang, Boyu Wang, Ziwen He, Zhangjie Fu</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:02:11 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.13108v2</guid></item><item><title>X2HDR: HDR Image Generation in a Perceptually Uniform Space</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04814v1</link><description>High-dynamic-range (HDR) formats and displays are becoming increasingly prevalent, yet state-of-the-art image generators (e.g., Stable Diffusion and FLUX) typically remain limited to low-dynamic-range (LDR) output due to the lack of large-scale HDR training data. In this work, we show that existing pretrained diffusion models can be easily adapted to HDR generation without retraining from scratch. A key challenge is that HDR images are natively represented in linear RGB, whose intensity and color statistics differ substantially from those of sRGB-encoded LDR images. This gap, however, can be effectively bridged by converting HDR inputs into perceptually uniform encodings (e.g., using PU21 or PQ). Empirically, we find that LDR-pretrained variational autoencoders (VAEs) reconstruct PU21-encoded HDR inputs with fidelity comparable to LDR data, whereas linear RGB inputs cause severe degradations. Motivated by this finding, we describe an efficient adaptation strategy that freezes the VAE and finetunes only the denoiser via low-rank adaptation in a perceptually uniform space. This results in a unified computational method that supports both text-to-HDR synthesis and single-image RAW-to-HDR reconstruction. Experiments demonstrate that our perceptually encoded adaptation consistently improves perceptual fidelity, text-image alignment, and effective dynamic range, relative to previous techniques.</description><author>Ronghuan Wu, Wanchao Su, Kede Ma, Jing Liao, Rafał K. Mantiuk</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:59:51 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04814v1</guid></item><item><title>Agentic AI in Healthcare &amp; Medicine: A Seven-Dimensional Taxonomy for Empirical Evaluation of LLM-based Agents</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04813v1</link><description>Large Language Model (LLM)-based agents that plan, use tools and act has begun to shape healthcare and medicine. Reported studies demonstrate competence on various tasks ranging from EHR analysis and differential diagnosis to treatment planning and research workflows. Yet the literature largely consists of overviews which are either broad surveys or narrow dives into a single capability (e.g., memory, planning, reasoning), leaving healthcare work without a common frame. We address this by reviewing 49 studies using a seven-dimensional taxonomy: Cognitive Capabilities, Knowledge Management, Interaction Patterns, Adaptation &amp; Learning, Safety &amp; Ethics, Framework Typology and Core Tasks &amp; Subtasks with 29 operational sub-dimensions. Using explicit inclusion and exclusion criteria and a labeling rubric (Fully Implemented, Partially Implemented, Not Implemented), we map each study to the taxonomy and report quantitative summaries of capability prevalence and co-occurrence patterns. Our empirical analysis surfaces clear asymmetries. For instance, the External Knowledge Integration sub-dimension under Knowledge Management is commonly realized (~76% Fully Implemented) whereas Event-Triggered Activation sub-dimenison under Interaction Patterns is largely absent (~92% Not Implemented) and Drift Detection &amp; Mitigation sub-dimension under Adaptation &amp; Learning is rare (~98% Not Implemented). Architecturally, Multi-Agent Design sub-dimension under Framework Typology is the dominant pattern (~82% Fully Implemented) while orchestration layers remain mostly partial. Across Core Tasks &amp; Subtasks, information centric capabilities lead e.g., Medical Question Answering &amp; Decision Support and Benchmarking &amp; Simulation, while action and discovery oriented areas such as Treatment Planning &amp; Prescription still show substantial gaps (~59% Not Implemented).</description><author>Shubham Vatsal, Harsh Dubey, Aditi Singh</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:59:14 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04813v1</guid></item><item><title>Robust Generalizable Heterogeneous Legal Link Prediction</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04812v1</link><description>Recent work has applied link prediction to large heterogeneous legal citation networks \new{with rich meta-features}. We find that this approach can be improved by including edge dropout and feature concatenation for the learning of more robust representations, which reduces error rates by up to 45%. We also propose an approach based on multilingual node features with an improved asymmetric decoder for compatibility, which allows us to generalize and extend the prediction to more, geographically and linguistically disjoint, data from New Zealand. Our adaptations also improve inductive transferability between these disjoint legal systems.</description><author>Lorenz Wendlinger, Simon Alexander Nonn, Abdullah Al Zubaer, Michael Granitzer</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:59:13 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04812v1</guid></item><item><title>SE-Bench: Benchmarking Self-Evolution with Knowledge Internalization</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04811v1</link><description>True self-evolution requires agents to act as lifelong learners that internalize novel experiences to solve future problems. However, rigorously measuring this foundational capability is hindered by two obstacles: the entanglement of prior knowledge, where ``new'' knowledge may appear in pre-training data, and the entanglement of reasoning complexity, where failures may stem from problem difficulty rather than an inability to recall learned knowledge. We introduce SE-Bench, a diagnostic environment that obfuscates the NumPy library and its API doc into a pseudo-novel package with randomized identifiers. Agents are trained to internalize this package and evaluated on simple coding tasks without access to documentation, yielding a clean setting where tasks are trivial with the new API doc but impossible for base models without it. Our investigation reveals three insights: (1) the Open-Book Paradox, where training with reference documentation inhibits retention, requiring "Closed-Book Training" to force knowledge compression into weights; (2) the RL Gap, where standard RL fails to internalize new knowledge completely due to PPO clipping and negative gradients; and (3) the viability of Self-Play for internalization, proving models can learn from self-generated, noisy tasks when coupled with SFT, but not RL. Overall, SE-Bench establishes a rigorous diagnostic platform for self-evolution with knowledge internalization. Our code and dataset can be found at https://github.com/thunlp/SE-Bench.</description><author>Jiarui Yuan, Tailin Jin, Weize Chen, Zeyuan Liu, Zhiyuan Liu, Maosong Sun</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:58:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04811v1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Pyramid Network for Efficient Multimodal Large Language Model</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.20322v3</link><description>Multimodal large language models (MLLMs) have demonstrated impressive performance in various vision-language (VL) tasks, but their expensive computations still limit the real-world application. To address this issue, recent efforts aim to compress the visual features to save the computational costs of MLLMs. However, direct visual compression methods, e.g. efficient projectors, inevitably destroy the visual semantics in MLLM, especially in difficult samples. To overcome this shortcoming, we propose a novel dynamic pyramid network (DPN) for efficient MLLMs. Specifically, DPN formulates MLLM as a hierarchical structure where visual features are gradually compressed with increasing depth. In this case, even with a high compression ratio, fine-grained visual information can still be perceived in shallow layers. To maximize the benefit of DPN, we further propose an innovative Dynamic Pooling Experts (DPE) that can dynamically choose the optimal visual compression rate according to input features. With this design, harder samples will be assigned larger computations, thus preserving the model performance. To validate our approach, we conduct extensive experiments on two popular MLLMs and ten benchmarks. Experimental results show that DPN can save up to 56% average FLOPs on LLaVA while further achieving +0.74% performance gains. Besides, the generalization ability of DPN is also validated on the existing high-resolution MLLM called LLaVA-HR. The source code will be released at https://github.com/aihao2000/DPN-LLaVA.</description><author>Hao Ai, Kunyi Wang, Zezhou Wang, Hao Lu, Jin Tian, Yaxin Luo, Peng Xing, Jen-Yuan Huang, Huaxia Li, Gen luo</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:56:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.20322v3</guid></item><item><title>Beyond Rewards in Reinforcement Learning for Cyber Defence</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04809v1</link><description>Recent years have seen an explosion of interest in autonomous cyber defence agents trained to defend computer networks using deep reinforcement learning. These agents are typically trained in cyber gym environments using dense, highly engineered reward functions which combine many penalties and incentives for a range of (un)desirable states and costly actions. Dense rewards help alleviate the challenge of exploring complex environments but risk biasing agents towards suboptimal and potentially riskier solutions, a critical issue in complex cyber environments. We thoroughly evaluate the impact of reward function structure on learning and policy behavioural characteristics using a variety of sparse and dense reward functions, two well-established cyber gyms, a range of network sizes, and both policy gradient and value-based RL algorithms. Our evaluation is enabled by a novel ground truth evaluation approach which allows directly comparing between different reward functions, illuminating the nuanced inter-relationships between rewards, action space and the risks of suboptimal policies in cyber environments. Our results show that sparse rewards, provided they are goal aligned and can be encountered frequently, uniquely offer both enhanced training reliability and more effective cyber defence agents with lower-risk policies. Surprisingly, sparse rewards can also yield policies that are better aligned with cyber defender goals and make sparing use of costly defensive actions without explicit reward-based numerical penalties.</description><author>Elizabeth Bates, Chris Hicks, Vasilios Mavroudis</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:55:23 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04809v1</guid></item><item><title>Evolving Afferent Architectures: Biologically-inspired Models for Damage-Avoidance Learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04807v1</link><description>We introduce Afferent Learning, a framework that produces Computational Afferent Traces (CATs) as adaptive, internal risk signals for damage-avoidance learning. Inspired by biological systems, the framework uses a two-level architecture: evolutionary optimization (outer loop) discovers afferent sensing architectures that enable effective policy learning, while reinforcement learning (inner loop) trains damage-avoidance policies using these signals. This formalizes afferent sensing as providing an inductive bias for efficient learning: architectures are selected based on their ability to enable effective learning (rather than directly minimizing damage). We provide theoretical convergence guarantees under smoothness and bounded-noise assumptions. We illustrate the general approach in the challenging context of biomechanical digital twins operating over long time horizons (multiple decades of the life-course). Here, we find that CAT-based evolved architectures achieve significantly higher efficiency and better age-robustness than hand-designed baselines, enabling policies that exhibit age-dependent behavioral adaptation (23% reduction in high-risk actions). Ablation studies validate CAT signals, evolution, and predictive discrepancy as essential. We release code and data for reproducibility.</description><author>Wolfgang Maass, Sabine Janzen, Prajvi Saxena, Sach Mukherjee</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:53:28 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04807v1</guid></item><item><title>Skin Tokens: A Learned Compact Representation for Unified Autoregressive Rigging</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04805v1</link><description>The rapid proliferation of generative 3D models has created a critical bottleneck in animation pipelines: rigging. Existing automated methods are fundamentally limited by their approach to skinning, treating it as an ill-posed, high-dimensional regression task that is inefficient to optimize and is typically decoupled from skeleton generation. We posit this is a representation problem and introduce SkinTokens: a learned, compact, and discrete representation for skinning weights. By leveraging an FSQ-CVAE to capture the intrinsic sparsity of skinning, we reframe the task from continuous regression to a more tractable token sequence prediction problem. This representation enables TokenRig, a unified autoregressive framework that models the entire rig as a single sequence of skeletal parameters and SkinTokens, learning the complicated dependencies between skeletons and skin deformations. The unified model is then amenable to a reinforcement learning stage, where tailored geometric and semantic rewards improve generalization to complex, out-of-distribution assets. Quantitatively, the SkinTokens representation leads to a 98%-133% percents improvement in skinning accuracy over state-of-the-art methods, while the full TokenRig framework, refined with RL, enhances bone prediction by 17%-22%. Our work presents a unified, generative approach to rigging that yields higher fidelity and robustness, offering a scalable solution to a long-standing challenge in 3D content creation.</description><author>Jia-peng Zhang, Cheng-Feng Pu, Meng-Hao Guo, Yan-Pei Cao, Shi-Min Hu</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:52:17 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04805v1</guid></item><item><title>Y-Shaped Generative Flows</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.11955v3</link><description>Modern continuous-time generative models typically induce \emph{V-shaped} flows: each sample travels independently along a nearly straight trajectory from the prior to the data. Although effective, this independent movement overlooks the hierarchical structures that exist in real-world data. To address this, we introduce \emph{Y-shaped generative flows}, a framework in which samples travel together along shared pathways before branching off to target-specific endpoints. Our formulation is theoretically justified, yet remains practical, requiring only minimal modifications to standard velocity-driven models. We implement this through a scalable, neural network-based training objective. Experiments on synthetic, image, and biological datasets demonstrate that our method recovers hierarchy-aware structures, improves distributional metrics over strong flow-based baselines, and reaches targets in fewer steps.</description><author>Arip Asadulaev, Semyon Semenov, Abduragim Shtanchaev, Eric Moulines, Fakhri Karray, Martin Takac</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:51:14 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.11955v3</guid></item><item><title>OmniSIFT: Modality-Asymmetric Token Compression for Efficient Omni-modal Large Language Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04804v1</link><description>Omni-modal Large Language Models (Omni-LLMs) have demonstrated strong capabilities in audio-video understanding tasks. However, their reliance on long multimodal token sequences leads to substantial computational overhead. Despite this challenge, token compression methods designed for Omni-LLMs remain limited. To bridge this gap, we propose OmniSIFT (Omni-modal Spatio-temporal Informed Fine-grained Token compression), a modality-asymmetric token compression framework tailored for Omni-LLMs. Specifically, OmniSIFT adopts a two-stage compression strategy: (i) a spatio-temporal video pruning module that removes video redundancy arising from both intra-frame structure and inter-frame overlap, and (ii) a vision-guided audio selection module that filters audio tokens. The entire framework is optimized end-to-end via a differentiable straight-through estimator. Extensive experiments on five representative benchmarks demonstrate the efficacy and robustness of OmniSIFT. Notably, for Qwen2.5-Omni-7B, OmniSIFT introduces only 4.85M parameters while maintaining lower latency than training-free baselines such as OmniZip. With merely 25% of the original token context, OmniSIFT consistently outperforms all compression baselines and even surpasses the performance of the full-token model on several tasks.</description><author>Yue Ding, Yiyan Ji, Jungang Li, Xuyang Liu, Xinlong Chen, Junfei Wu, Bozhou Li, Bohan Zeng, Yang Shi, Yushuo Guan, Yuanxing Zhang, Jiaheng Liu, Qiang Liu, Pengfei Wan, Liang Wang</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:51:05 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04804v1</guid></item><item><title>VISTA-Bench: Do Vision-Language Models Really Understand Visualized Text as Well as Pure Text?</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04802v1</link><description>Vision-Language Models (VLMs) have achieved impressive performance in cross-modal understanding across textual and visual inputs, yet existing benchmarks predominantly focus on pure-text queries. In real-world scenarios, language also frequently appears as visualized text embedded in images, raising the question of whether current VLMs handle such input requests comparably. We introduce VISTA-Bench, a systematic benchmark from multimodal perception, reasoning, to unimodal understanding domains. It evaluates visualized text understanding by contrasting pure-text and visualized-text questions under controlled rendering conditions. Extensive evaluation of over 20 representative VLMs reveals a pronounced modality gap: models that perform well on pure-text queries often degrade substantially when equivalent semantic content is presented as visualized text. This gap is further amplified by increased perceptual difficulty, highlighting sensitivity to rendering variations despite unchanged semantics. Overall, VISTA-Bench provides a principled evaluation framework to diagnose this limitation and to guide progress toward more unified language representations across tokenized text and pixels. The source dataset is available at https://github.com/QingAnLiu/VISTA-Bench.</description><author>Qing'an Liu, Juntong Feng, Yuhao Wang, Xinzhe Han, Yujie Cheng, Yue Zhu, Haiwen Diao, Yunzhi Zhuge, Huchuan Lu</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:48:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04802v1</guid></item><item><title>Verification and Identification in ECG biometric on large-scale</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.02776v2</link><description>This work studies electrocardiogram (ECG) biometrics at large scale, directly addressing a critical gap in the literature: the scarcity of large-scale evaluations with operational metrics and protocols that enable meaningful standardization and comparison across studies. We show that identity information is already present in tabular representations (fiducial features): even a simple MLP-based embedding network yields non-trivial performance, establishing a strong baseline before waveform modeling. We then adopt embedding-based deep learning models (ArcFace), first on features and then on ECG waveforms, showing a clear performance jump when moving from tabular inputs to waveforms, and a further gain with larger training sets and consistent normalization across train/val/test. On a large-scale test set, verification achieves high TAR at strict FAR thresholds (TAR=0.908 @ FAR=1e-3; TAR=0.820 @ FAR=1e-4) with EER=2.53\% (all-vs-all); closed-set identification yields Rank@1=0.812 and Rank@10=0.910. In open-set, a two-stage pipeline (top-$K$ shortlist on embeddings + re-ranking) reaches DIR@FAR up to 0.976 at FAR=1e-3 and 1e-4. Overall, the results show that ECG carries a measurable individual signature and that large-scale testing is essential to obtain realistic, comparable metrics. The study provides an operationally grounded benchmark that helps standardize evaluation across protocols.</description><author>Scagnetto Arjuna</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:47:07 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.02776v2</guid></item><item><title>Score-Based Change-Point Detection and Region Localization for Spatio-Temporal Point Processes</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04798v1</link><description>We study sequential change-point detection for spatio-temporal point processes, where actionable detection requires not only identifying when a distributional change occurs but also localizing where it manifests in space. While classical quickest change detection methods provide strong guarantees on detection delay and false-alarm rates, existing approaches for point-process data predominantly focus on temporal changes and do not explicitly infer affected spatial regions. We propose a likelihood-free, score-based detection framework that jointly estimates the change time and the change region in continuous space-time without assuming parametric knowledge of the pre- or post-change dynamics. The method leverages a localized and conditionally weighted Hyvärinen score to quantify event-level deviations from nominal behavior and aggregates these scores using a spatio-temporal CUSUM-type statistic over a prescribed class of spatial regions. Operating sequentially, the procedure outputs both a stopping time and an estimated change region, enabling real-time detection with spatial interpretability. We establish theoretical guarantees on false-alarm control, detection delay, and spatial localization accuracy, and demonstrate the effectiveness of the proposed approach through simulations and real-world spatio-temporal event data.</description><author>Wenbin Zhou, Liyan Xie, Shixiang Zhu</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:44:41 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04798v1</guid></item><item><title>Maximum-Volume Nonnegative Matrix Factorization</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04795v1</link><description>Nonnegative matrix factorization (NMF) is a popular data embedding technique. Given a nonnegative data matrix $X$, it aims at finding two lower dimensional matrices, $W$ and $H$, such that $X\approx WH$, where the factors $W$ and $H$ are constrained to be element-wise nonnegative. The factor $W$ serves as a basis for the columns of $X$. In order to obtain more interpretable and unique solutions, minimum-volume NMF (MinVol NMF) minimizes the volume of $W$. In this paper, we consider the dual approach, where the volume of $H$ is maximized instead; this is referred to as maximum-volume NMF (MaxVol NMF). MaxVol NMF is identifiable under the same conditions as MinVol NMF in the noiseless case, but it behaves rather differently in the presence of noise. In practice, MaxVol NMF is much more effective to extract a sparse decomposition and does not generate rank-deficient solutions. In fact, we prove that the solutions of MaxVol NMF with the largest volume correspond to clustering the columns of $X$ in disjoint clusters, while the solutions of MinVol NMF with smallest volume are rank deficient. We propose two algorithms to solve MaxVol NMF. We also present a normalized variant of MaxVol NMF that exhibits better performance than MinVol NMF and MaxVol NMF, and can be interpreted as a continuum between standard NMF and orthogonal NMF. We illustrate our results in the context of hyperspectral unmixing.</description><author>Olivier Vu Thanh, Nicolas Gillis</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:43:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04795v1</guid></item><item><title>Light Forcing: Accelerating Autoregressive Video Diffusion via Sparse Attention</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04789v1</link><description>Advanced autoregressive (AR) video generation models have improved visual fidelity and interactivity, but the quadratic complexity of attention remains a primary bottleneck for efficient deployment. While existing sparse attention solutions have shown promise on bidirectional models, we identify that applying these solutions to AR models leads to considerable performance degradation for two reasons: isolated consideration of chunk generation and insufficient utilization of past informative context. Motivated by these observations, we propose \textsc{Light Forcing}, the \textit{first} sparse attention solution tailored for AR video generation models. It incorporates a \textit{Chunk-Aware Growth} mechanism to quantitatively estimate the contribution of each chunk, which determines their sparsity allocation. This progressive sparsity increase strategy enables the current chunk to inherit prior knowledge in earlier chunks during generation. Additionally, we introduce a \textit{Hierarchical Sparse Attention} to capture informative historical and local context in a coarse-to-fine manner. Such two-level mask selection strategy (\ie, frame and block level) can adaptively handle diverse attention patterns. Extensive experiments demonstrate that our method outperforms existing sparse attention in quality (\eg, 84.5 on VBench) and efficiency (\eg, $1.2{\sim}1.3\times$ end-to-end speedup). Combined with FP8 quantization and LightVAE, \textsc{Light Forcing} further achieves a $2.3\times$ speedup and 19.7\,FPS on an RTX~5090 GPU. Code will be released at \href{https://github.com/chengtao-lv/LightForcing}{https://github.com/chengtao-lv/LightForcing}.</description><author>Chengtao Lv, Yumeng Shi, Yushi Huang, Ruihao Gong, Shen Ren, Wenya Wang</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:41:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04789v1</guid></item><item><title>Accurate and scalable exchange-correlation with deep learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.14665v4</link><description>Density Functional Theory (DFT) is the most widely used electronic structure method for predicting the properties of molecules and materials. Although DFT is, in principle, an exact reformulation of the Schrödinger equation, practical applications rely on approximations to the unknown exchange-correlation (XC) functional. Most existing XC functionals are constructed using a limited set of increasingly complex, hand-crafted features that improve accuracy at the expense of computational efficiency. Yet, no current approximation achieves the accuracy and generality for predictive modeling of laboratory experiments at chemical accuracy -- typically defined as errors below 1 kcal/mol. In this work, we present Skala, a modern deep learning-based XC functional that bypasses expensive hand-designed features by learning representations directly from data. Skala achieves chemical accuracy for atomization energies of small molecules while retaining the computational efficiency typical of semi-local DFT. This performance is enabled by training on an unprecedented volume of high-accuracy reference data generated using computationally intensive wavefunction-based methods. Notably, Skala systematically improves with additional training data covering diverse chemistry. By incorporating a modest amount of additional high-accuracy data tailored to chemistry beyond atomization energies, Skala achieves accuracy competitive with the best-performing hybrid functionals across general main group chemistry, at the cost of semi-local DFT. As the training dataset continues to expand, Skala is poised to further enhance the predictive power of first-principles simulations.</description><author>Giulia Luise, Chin-Wei Huang, Thijs Vogels, Derk P. Kooi, Sebastian Ehlert, Stephanie Lanius, Klaas J. H. Giesbertz, Amir Karton, Deniz Gunceler, Megan Stanley, Wessel P. Bruinsma, Lin Huang, Xinran Wei, José Garrido Torres, Abylay Katbashev, Rodrigo Chavez Zavaleta, Bálint Máté, Sékou-Oumar Kaba, Roberto Sordillo, Yingrong Chen, David B. Williams-Young, Christopher M. Bishop, Jan Hermann, Rianne van den Berg, Paola Gori-Giorgi</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:40:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.14665v4</guid></item><item><title>UniReason 1.0: A Unified Reasoning Framework for World Knowledge Aligned Image Generation and Editing</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.02437v2</link><description>Unified multimodal models often struggle with complex synthesis tasks that demand deep reasoning, and typically treat text-to-image generation and image editing as isolated capabilities rather than interconnected reasoning steps. To address this, we propose UniReason, a unified framework that harmonizes these two tasks through two complementary reasoning paradigms. We incorporate world knowledge-enhanced textual reasoning into generation to infer implicit knowledge, and leverage editing capabilities for fine-grained editing-like visual refinement to further correct visual errors via self-reflection. This approach unifies generation and editing within a shared architecture, mirroring the human cognitive process of planning followed by refinement. We support this framework by systematically constructing a large-scale reasoning-centric dataset (~300k samples) covering five major knowledge domains (e.g., cultural commonsense, physics, etc.) for textual reasoning, alongside an agent-generated corpus for visual refinement. Extensive experiments demonstrate that UniReason achieves advanced performance on reasoning-intensive benchmarks such as WISE, KrisBench and UniREditBench, while maintaining superior general synthesis capabilities.</description><author>Dianyi Wang, Chaofan Ma, Feng Han, Size Wu, Wei Song, Yibin Wang, Zhixiong Zhang, Tianhang Wang, Siyuan Wang, Zhongyu Wei, Jiaqi Wang</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:38:12 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.02437v2</guid></item><item><title>GPU-Accelerated ANNS: Quantized for Speed, Built for Change</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.07048v3</link><description>Approximate nearest neighbor search (ANNS) is a core problem in machine learning and information retrieval applications. GPUs offer a promising path to high-performance ANNS: they provide massive parallelism for distance computations, are readily available, and can co-locate with downstream applications. Despite these advantages, current GPU-accelerated ANNS systems face three key limitations. First, real-world applications operate on evolving datasets that require fast batch updates, yet most GPU indices must be rebuilt from scratch when new data arrives. Second, high-dimensional vectors strain memory bandwidth, but current GPU systems lack efficient quantization techniques that reduce data movement without introducing costly random memory accesses. Third, the data-dependent memory accesses inherent to greedy search make overlapping compute and memory difficult, leading to reduced performance. We present Jasper, a GPU-native ANNS system with both high query throughput and updatability. Jasper builds on the Vamana graph index and overcomes existing bottlenecks via three contributions: (1) a CUDA batch-parallel construction algorithm that enables lock-free streaming insertions, (2) a GPU-efficient implementation of RaBitQ quantization that reduces memory footprint up to 8x without the random access penalties, and (3) an optimized greedy search kernel that increases compute utilization, resulting in better latency hiding and higher throughput. Our evaluation across five datasets shows that Jasper achieves up to 1.93x higher query throughput than CAGRA and achieves up to 80% peak utilization as measured by the roofline model. Jasper's construction scales efficiently and constructs indices an average of 2.4x faster than CAGRA while providing updatability that CAGRA lacks. Compared to BANG, the previous fastest GPU Vamana implementation, Jasper delivers 19-131x faster queries.</description><author>Hunter McCoy, Zikun Wang, Prashant Pandey</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:37:50 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.07048v3</guid></item><item><title>It's all In the (Exponential) Family: An Equivalence between Maximum Likelihood Estimation and Control Variates for Sketching Algorithms</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.22378v2</link><description>Maximum likelihood estimators (MLE) and control variate estimators (CVE) have been used in conjunction with known information across sketching algorithms and applications in machine learning. We prove that under certain conditions in an exponential family, an optimal CVE will achieve the same asymptotic variance as the MLE, giving an Expectation-Maximization (EM) algorithm for the MLE. Experiments show the EM algorithm is faster and numerically stable compared to other root finding algorithms for the MLE for the bivariate Normal distribution, and we expect this to hold across distributions satisfying these conditions. We show how the EM algorithm leads to reproducibility for algorithms using MLE / CVE, and demonstrate how the EM algorithm leads to finding the MLE when the CV weights are known.</description><author>Keegan Kang, Kerong Wang, Ding Zhang, Rameshwar Pratap, Bhisham Dev Verma, Benedict H. W. Wong</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:35:28 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.22378v2</guid></item><item><title>MixGRPO: Unlocking Flow-based GRPO Efficiency with Mixed ODE-SDE</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.21802v5</link><description>Although GRPO substantially enhances flow matching models in human preference alignment of image generation, methods such as FlowGRPO and DanceGRPO still exhibit inefficiency due to the necessity of sampling and optimizing over all denoising steps specified by the Markov Decision Process (MDP). In this paper, we propose $\textbf{MixGRPO}$, a novel framework that leverages the flexibility of mixed sampling strategies through the integration of stochastic differential equations (SDE) and ordinary differential equations (ODE). This streamlines the optimization process within the MDP to improve efficiency and boost performance. Specifically, MixGRPO introduces a sliding window mechanism, using SDE sampling and GRPO-guided optimization only within the window, while applying ODE sampling outside. This design confines sampling randomness to the time-steps within the window, thereby reducing the optimization overhead, and allowing for more focused gradient updates to accelerate convergence. Additionally, as time-steps beyond the sliding window are not involved in optimization, higher-order solvers are supported for faster sampling. So we present a faster variant, termed $\textbf{MixGRPO-Flash}$, which further improves training efficiency while achieving comparable performance. MixGRPO exhibits substantial gains across multiple dimensions of human preference alignment, outperforming DanceGRPO in both effectiveness and efficiency, with nearly 50% lower training time. Notably, MixGRPO-Flash further reduces training time by 71%.</description><author>Junzhe Li, Yutao Cui, Tao Huang, Yinping Ma, Chun Fan, Miles Yang, Zhao Zhong, Liefeng Bo</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:35:17 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.21802v5</guid></item><item><title>Multi-Excitation Projective Simulation with a Many-Body Physics Inspired Inductive Bias</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.10192v4</link><description>With the impressive progress of deep learning, applications relying on machine learning are increasingly being integrated into daily life. However, most deep learning models have an opaque, oracle-like nature making it difficult to interpret and understand their decisions. This problem led to the development of the field known as eXplainable Artificial Intelligence (XAI). One method in this field known as Projective Simulation (PS) models a chain-of-thought as a random walk of a particle on a graph with vertices that have concepts attached to them. While this description has various benefits, including the possibility of quantization, it cannot be naturally used to model thoughts that combine several concepts simultaneously. To overcome this limitation, we introduce Multi-Excitation Projective Simulation (mePS), a generalization that considers a chain-of-thought to be a random walk of several particles on a hypergraph. A definition for a dynamic hypergraph is put forward to describe the agent's training history along with applications to AI and hypergraph visualization. An inductive bias inspired by the remarkably successful few-body interaction models used in quantum many-body physics is formalized for our classical mePS framework and employed to tackle the exponential complexity associated with naive implementations of hypergraphs. We prove that our inductive bias reduces the complexity from exponential to polynomial, with the exponent representing the cutoff on how many particles can interact. We numerically apply our method to two toy environments and a more complex scenario modelling the diagnosis of a broken computer. These environments demonstrate the resource savings provided by an appropriate choice of inductive bias, as well as showcasing aspects of interpretability. A quantum model for mePS is also briefly outlined and some future directions for it are discussed.</description><author>Philip A. LeMaitre, Marius Krumm, Hans J. Briegel</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:34:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.10192v4</guid></item><item><title>Mugi: Value Level Parallelism For Efficient LLMs</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.10823v2</link><description>Value level parallelism (VLP) has been proposed to improve the efficiency of large-batch, low-precision general matrix multiply (GEMM) between symmetric activations and weights. In transformer based large language models (LLMs), there exist more sophisticated operations beyond activation-weight GEMM. In this paper, we explore how VLP benefits LLMs. First, we generalize VLP for nonlinear approximations, outperforming existing nonlinear approximations in end-to-end LLM accuracy, performance, and efficiency. Our VLP approximation follows a value-centric approach, where important values are assigned with greater accuracy. Second, we optimize VLP for small-batch GEMMs with asymmetric inputs efficiently, which leverages timely LLM optimizations, including weight-only quantization, key-value (KV) cache quantization, and group query attention. Finally, we design a new VLP architecture, Mugi, to encapsulate the innovations above and support full LLM workloads, while providing better performance, efficiency and sustainability. Our experimental results show that Mugi can offer significant improvements on throughput and energy efficiency, up to $45\times$ and $668\times$ for nonlinear softmax operations, and $2.07\times$ and $3.11\times$ for LLMs, and also decrease operational carbon for LLM operation by $1.45\times$ and embodied carbon by $1.48\times$.</description><author>Daniel Price, Prabhu Vellaisamy, John Shen, Di Wu</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:34:41 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.10823v2</guid></item><item><title>Team, Then Trim: An Assembly-Line LLM Framework for High-Quality Tabular Data Generation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04785v1</link><description>While tabular data is fundamental to many real-world machine learning (ML) applications, acquiring high-quality tabular data is usually labor-intensive and expensive. Limited by the scarcity of observations, tabular datasets often exhibit critical deficiencies, such as class imbalance, selection bias, and low fidelity. To address these challenges, building on recent advances in Large Language Models (LLMs), this paper introduces Team-then-Trim (T$^2$), a framework that synthesizes high-quality tabular data through a collaborative team of LLMs, followed by a rigorous three-stage plug-in data quality control (QC) pipeline. In T$^2$, tabular data generation is conceptualized as a manufacturing process: specialized LLMs, guided by domain knowledge, are tasked with generating different data components sequentially, and the resulting products, i.e., the synthetic data, are systematically evaluated across multiple dimensions of QC. Empirical results on both simulated and real-world datasets demonstrate that T$^2$ outperforms state-of-the-art methods in producing high-quality tabular data, highlighting its potential to support downstream models when direct data collection is practically infeasible.</description><author>Congjing Zhang, Ryan Feng Lin, Ruoxuan Bao, Shuai Huang</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:34:41 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04785v1</guid></item><item><title>From independent patches to coordinated attention: Controlling information flow in vision transformers</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04784v1</link><description>We make the information transmitted by attention an explicit, measurable quantity in vision transformers. By inserting variational information bottlenecks on all attention-mediated writes to the residual stream -- without other architectural changes -- we train models with an explicit information cost and obtain a controllable spectrum from independent patch processing to fully expressive global attention. On ImageNet-100, we characterize how classification behavior and information routing evolve across this spectrum, and provide initial insights into how global visual representations emerge from local patch processing by analyzing the first attention heads that transmit information. By biasing learning toward solutions with constrained internal communication, our approach yields models that are more tractable for mechanistic analysis and more amenable to control.</description><author>Kieran A. Murphy</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:33:24 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04784v1</guid></item><item><title>Self-Improving Pretraining: using post-trained models to pretrain better models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.21343v2</link><description>Ensuring safety, factuality and overall quality in the generations of large language models is a critical challenge, especially as these models are increasingly deployed in real-world applications. The prevailing approach to addressing these issues involves collecting expensive, carefully curated datasets and applying multiple stages of fine-tuning and alignment. However, even this complex pipeline cannot guarantee the correction of patterns learned during pretraining. Therefore, addressing these issues during pretraining is crucial, as it shapes a model's core behaviors and prevents unsafe or hallucinated outputs from becoming deeply embedded. To tackle this issue, we introduce a new pretraining method that streams documents and uses reinforcement learning (RL) to improve the next K generated tokens at each step. A strong, post-trained model judges candidate generations -- including model rollouts, the original suffix, and a rewritten suffix -- for quality, safety, and factuality. Early in training, the process relies on the original and rewritten suffixes; as the model improves, RL rewards high-quality rollouts. This approach builds higher quality, safer, and more factual models from the ground up. In experiments, our method gives 36.2% and 18.5% relative improvements over standard pretraining in terms of factuality and safety, and up to 86.3% win rate improvements in overall generation quality.</description><author>Ellen Xiaoqing Tan, Shehzaad Dhuliawala, Jing Xu, Ping Yu, Sainbayar Sukhbaatar, Jason Weston, Olga Golovneva</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:31:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.21343v2</guid></item><item><title>Legendre Memory Unit with A Multi-Slice Compensation Model for Short-Term Wind Speed Forecasting Based on Wind Farm Cluster Data</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04782v1</link><description>With more wind farms clustered for integration, the short-term wind speed prediction of such wind farm clusters is critical for normal operation of power systems. This paper focuses on achieving accurate, fast, and robust wind speed prediction by full use of cluster data with spatial-temporal correlation. First, weighted mean filtering (WMF) is applied to denoise wind speed data at the single-farm level. The Legendre memory unit (LMU) is then innovatively applied for the wind speed prediction, in combination with the Compensating Parameter based on Kendall rank correlation coefficient (CPK) of wind farm cluster data, to construct the multi-slice LMU (MSLMU). Finally, an innovative ensemble model WMF-CPK-MSLMU is proposed herein, with three key blocks: data pre-processing, forecasting, and multi-slice compensation. Advantages include: 1) LMU jointly models linear and nonlinear dependencies among farms to capture spatial-temporal correlations through backpropagation; 2) MSLMU enhances forecasting by using CPK-derived weights instead of random initialization, allowing spatial correlations to fully activate hidden nodes across clustered wind farms.; 3) CPK adaptively weights the compensation model in MSLMU and complements missing data spatially, to facilitate the whole model highly accurate and robust. Test results on different wind farm clusters indicate the effectiveness and superiority of proposed ensemble model WMF-CPK-MSLMU in the short-term prediction of wind farm clusters compared to the existing models.</description><author>Mumin Zhang, Haochen Zhang, Xin Zhi Khoo, Yilin Zhang, Nuo Chen, Ting Zhang, Junjie Tang</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:28:42 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04782v1</guid></item><item><title>Unifying Re-Identification, Attribute Inference, and Data Reconstruction Risks in Differential Privacy</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.06969v4</link><description>Differentially private (DP) mechanisms are difficult to interpret and calibrate because existing methods for mapping standard privacy parameters to concrete privacy risks -- re-identification, attribute inference, and data reconstruction -- are both overly pessimistic and inconsistent. In this work, we use the hypothesis-testing interpretation of DP ($f$-DP), and determine that bounds on attack success can take the same unified form across re-identification, attribute inference, and data reconstruction risks. Our unified bounds are (1) consistent across a multitude of attack settings, and (2) tunable, enabling practitioners to evaluate risk with respect to arbitrary, including worst-case, levels of baseline risk. Empirically, our results are tighter than prior methods using $\varepsilon$-DP, Rényi DP, and concentrated DP. As a result, calibrating noise using our bounds can reduce the required noise by 20% at the same risk level, which yields, e.g., an accuracy increase from 52% to 70% in a text classification task. Overall, this unifying perspective provides a principled framework for interpreting and calibrating the degree of protection in DP against specific levels of re-identification, attribute inference, or data reconstruction risk.</description><author>Bogdan Kulynych, Juan Felipe Gomez, Georgios Kaissis, Jamie Hayes, Borja Balle, Flavio P. Calmon, Jean Louis Raisaro</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:28:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.06969v4</guid></item><item><title>Dynamical Regimes of Multimodal Diffusion Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04780v1</link><description>Diffusion based generative models have achieved unprecedented fidelity in synthesizing high dimensional data, yet the theoretical mechanisms governing multimodal generation remain poorly understood. Here, we present a theoretical framework for coupled diffusion models, using coupled Ornstein-Uhlenbeck processes as a tractable model. By using the nonequilibrium statistical physics of dynamical phase transitions, we demonstrate that multimodal generation is governed by a spectral hierarchy of interaction timescales rather than simultaneous resolution. A key prediction is the ``synchronization gap'', a temporal window during the reverse generative process where distinct eigenmodes stabilize at different rates, providing a theoretical explanation for common desynchronization artifacts. We derive analytical conditions for speciation and collapse times under both symmetric and anisotropic coupling regimes, establishing strict bounds for coupling strength to avoid unstable symmetry breaking. We show that the coupling strength acts as a spectral filter that enforces a tunable temporal hierarchy on generation. We support these predictions through controlled experiments with diffusion models trained on MNIST datasets and exact score samplers. These results motivate time dependent coupling schedules that target mode specific timescales, offering a potential alternative to ad hoc guidance tuning.</description><author>Emil Albrychiewicz, Andrés Franco Valiente, Li-Ching Chen</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:16:12 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04780v1</guid></item><item><title>Minimax and Bayes Optimal Best-Arm Identification</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.24007v4</link><description>This study investigates minimax and Bayes optimal strategies for fixed-budget best-arm identification. We consider an adaptive procedure consisting of a sampling phase followed by a recommendation phase, and we design an adaptive experiment within this framework to efficiently identify the best arm, defined as the one with the highest expected outcome. In our proposed strategy, the sampling phase consists of two stages. The first stage is a pilot phase, in which we allocate samples uniformly across arms to eliminate clearly suboptimal arms and to estimate outcome variances. Before entering the second stage, we solve a Gaussian minimax game, which yields a sampling ratio and a decision rule. In the second stage, samples are allocated according to this sampling ratio. After the sampling phase, the procedure enters the recommendation phase, where we select an arm using the decision rule. We prove that this single strategy is simultaneously asymptotically minimax and Bayes optimal for the simple regret, and we establish upper bounds that coincide exactly with our lower bounds, including the constant terms.</description><author>Masahiro Kato</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:13:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.24007v4</guid></item><item><title>Speaker-Aware Simulation Improves Conversational Speech Recognition</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04776v1</link><description>Automatic speech recognition (ASR) for conversational speech remains challenging due to the limited availability of large-scale, well-annotated multi-speaker dialogue data and the complex temporal dynamics of natural interactions. Speaker-aware simulated conversations (SASC) offer an effective data augmentation strategy by transforming single-speaker recordings into realistic multi-speaker dialogues. However, prior work has primarily focused on English data, leaving questions about the applicability to lower-resource languages. In this paper, we adapt and implement the SASC framework for Hungarian conversational ASR. We further propose C-SASC, an extended variant that incorporates pause modeling conditioned on utterance duration, enabling a more faithful representation of local temporal dependencies observed in human conversation while retaining the simplicity and efficiency of the original approach. We generate synthetic Hungarian dialogues from the BEA-Large corpus and combine them with real conversational data for ASR training. Both SASC and C-SASC are evaluated extensively under a wide range of simulation configurations, using conversational statistics derived from CallHome, BEA-Dialogue, and GRASS corpora. Experimental results show that speaker-aware conversational simulation consistently improves recognition performance over naive concatenation-based augmentation. While the additional duration conditioning in C-SASC yields modest but systematic gains--most notably in character-level error rates--its effectiveness depends on the match between source conversational statistics and the target domain. Overall, our findings confirm the robustness of speaker-aware conversational simulation for Hungarian ASR and highlight the benefits and limitations of increasingly detailed temporal modeling in synthetic dialogue generation.</description><author>Máté Gedeon, Péter Mihajlik</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:12:09 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04776v1</guid></item><item><title>Interval-Based AUC (iAUC): Extending ROC Analysis to Uncertainty-Aware Classification</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04775v1</link><description>In high-stakes risk prediction, quantifying uncertainty through interval-valued predictions is essential for reliable decision-making. However, standard evaluation tools like the receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curve and the area under the curve (AUC) are designed for point scores and fail to capture the impact of predictive uncertainty on ranking performance. We propose an uncertainty-aware ROC framework specifically for interval-valued predictions, introducing two new measures: $AUC_L$ and $AUC_U$. This framework enables an informative three-region decomposition of the ROC plane, partitioning pairwise rankings into correct, incorrect, and uncertain orderings. This approach naturally supports selective prediction by allowing models to abstain from ranking cases with overlapping intervals, thereby optimizing the trade-off between abstention rate and discriminative reliability. We prove that under valid class-conditional coverage, $AUC_L$ and $AUC_U$ provide formal lower and upper bounds on the theoretical optimal AUC ($AUC^*$), characterizing the physical limit of achievable discrimination. The proposed framework applies broadly to interval-valued prediction models, regardless of the interval construction method. Experiments on real-world benchmark datasets, using bootstrap-based intervals as one instantiation, validate the framework's correctness and demonstrate its practical utility for uncertainty-aware evaluation and decision-making.</description><author>Yuqi Li, Matthew M. Engelhard</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:12:04 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04775v1</guid></item><item><title>Theory of Optimal Learning Rate Schedules and Scaling Laws for a Random Feature Model</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04774v1</link><description>Setting the learning rate for a deep learning model is a critical part of successful training, yet choosing this hyperparameter is often done empirically with trial and error. In this work, we explore a solvable model of optimal learning rate schedules for a powerlaw random feature model trained with stochastic gradient descent (SGD). We consider the optimal schedule $η_T^\star(t)$ where $t$ is the current iterate and $T$ is the total training horizon. This schedule is computed both numerically and analytically (when possible) using optimal control methods. Our analysis reveals two regimes which we term the easy phase and hard phase. In the easy phase the optimal schedule is a polynomial decay $η_T^\star(t) \simeq T^{-ξ} (1-t/T)^δ$ where $ξ$ and $δ$ depend on the properties of the features and task. In the hard phase, the optimal schedule resembles warmup-stable-decay with constant (in $T$) initial learning rate and annealing performed over a vanishing (in $T$) fraction of training steps. We investigate joint optimization of learning rate and batch size, identifying a degenerate optimality condition. Our model also predicts the compute-optimal scaling laws (where model size and training steps are chosen optimally) in both easy and hard regimes. Going beyond SGD, we consider optimal schedules for the momentum $β(t)$, where speedups in the hard phase are possible. We compare our optimal schedule to various benchmarks in our task including (1) optimal constant learning rates $η_T(t) \sim T^{-ξ}$ (2) optimal power laws $η_T(t) \sim T^{-ξ} t^{-χ}$, finding that our schedule achieves better rates than either of these. Our theory suggests that learning rate transfer across training horizon depends on the structure of the model and task. We explore these ideas in simple experimental pretraining setups.</description><author>Blake Bordelon, Francesco Mori</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:11:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04774v1</guid></item><item><title>DEBATE: A Large-Scale Benchmark for Evaluating Opinion Dynamics in Role-Playing LLM Agents</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.25110v3</link><description>Accurately modeling opinion change through social interactions is crucial for understanding and mitigating polarization, misinformation, and societal conflict. Recent work simulates opinion dynamics with role-playing LLM agents (RPLAs), but multi-agent simulations often display unnatural group behavior (e.g., premature convergence) and lack empirical benchmarks for assessing alignment with real human group interactions. We introduce DEBATE, a large-scale benchmark for evaluating the authenticity of opinion dynamics in multi-agent RPLA simulations. DEBATE contains 36,383 messages from 2,832 U.S.-based participants across 708 groups and 107 topics, with both public messages and private Likert-scale beliefs, enabling evaluation at the utterance and group levels (and supporting future individual-level analyses). We instantiate "digital twin" RPLAs with seven LLMs and evaluate across two settings: next-message prediction and full conversation rollout, using stance-alignment and opinion-convergence metrics. In zero-shot settings, RPLA groups exhibit strong opinion convergence relative to human groups. Post-training via supervised fine-tuning (SFT) and Direct Preference Optimization (DPO) improves stance alignment and brings group-level convergence closer to human behavior, though discrepancies in opinion change and belief updating remain. DEBATE enables rigorous benchmarking of simulated opinion dynamics and supports future research on aligning multi-agent RPLAs with realistic human interactions.</description><author>Yun-Shiuan Chuang, Ruixuan Tu, Chengtao Dai, Smit Vasani, You Li, Binwei Yao, Michael Henry Tessler, Sijia Yang, Dhavan Shah, Robert Hawkins, Junjie Hu, Timothy T. Rogers</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:09:34 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.25110v3</guid></item><item><title>Generative Modeling via Drifting</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04770v1</link><description>Generative modeling can be formulated as learning a mapping f such that its pushforward distribution matches the data distribution. The pushforward behavior can be carried out iteratively at inference time, for example in diffusion and flow-based models. In this paper, we propose a new paradigm called Drifting Models, which evolve the pushforward distribution during training and naturally admit one-step inference. We introduce a drifting field that governs the sample movement and achieves equilibrium when the distributions match. This leads to a training objective that allows the neural network optimizer to evolve the distribution. In experiments, our one-step generator achieves state-of-the-art results on ImageNet at 256 x 256 resolution, with an FID of 1.54 in latent space and 1.61 in pixel space. We hope that our work opens up new opportunities for high-quality one-step generation.</description><author>Mingyang Deng, He Li, Tianhong Li, Yilun Du, Kaiming He</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:06:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04770v1</guid></item><item><title>NeuroCanvas: VLLM-Powered Robust Seizure Detection by Reformulating Multichannel EEG as Image</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04769v1</link><description>Accurate and timely seizure detection from Electroencephalography (EEG) is critical for clinical intervention, yet manual review of long-term recordings is labor-intensive. Recent efforts to encode EEG signals into large language models (LLMs) show promise in handling neural signals across diverse patients, but two significant challenges remain: (1) multi-channel heterogeneity, as seizure-relevant information varies substantially across EEG channels, and (2) computing inefficiency, as the EEG signals need to be encoded into a massive number of tokens for the prediction. To address these issues, we draw the EEG signal and propose the novel NeuroCanvas framework. Specifically, NeuroCanvas consists of two modules: (i) The Entropy-guided Channel Selector (ECS) selects the seizure-relevant channels input to LLM and (ii) the following Canvas of Neuron Signal (CNS) converts selected multi-channel heterogeneous EEG signals into structured visual representations. The ECS module alleviates the multi-channel heterogeneity issue, and the CNS uses compact visual tokens to represent the EEG signals that improve the computing efficiency. We evaluate NeuroCanvas across multiple seizure detection datasets, demonstrating a significant improvement of $20\%$ in F1 score and reductions of $88\%$ in inference latency. These results highlight NeuroCanvas as a scalable and effective solution for real-time and resource-efficient seizure detection in clinical practice.The code will be released at https://github.com/Yanchen30247/seizure_detect.</description><author>Yan Chen, Jie Peng, Moajjem Hossain Chowdhury, Tianlong Chen, Yunmei Liu</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:06:38 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04769v1</guid></item><item><title>Causal-Adapter: Taming Text-to-Image Diffusion for Faithful Counterfactual Generation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.24798v5</link><description>We present Causal-Adapter, a modular framework that adapts frozen text-to-image diffusion backbones for counterfactual image generation. Our method supports causal interventions on target attributes and consistently propagates their effects to causal dependents while preserving the core identity of the image. Unlike prior approaches that rely on prompt engineering without explicit causal structure, Causal-Adapter leverages structural causal modeling with two attribute-regularization strategies: (i) prompt-aligned injection, which aligns causal attributes with textual embeddings for precise semantic control, and (ii) a conditioned token contrastive loss that disentangles attribute factors and reduces spurious correlations. Causal-Adapter achieves state-of-the-art performance on both synthetic and real-world datasets, including up to a 91% reduction in MAE on Pendulum for accurate attribute control and up to an 87% reduction in FID on ADNI for high-fidelity MRI generation. These results demonstrate robust, generalizable counterfactual editing with faithful attribute modification and strong identity preservation. Code and models will be released at: https://leitong02.github.io/causaladapter/.</description><author>Lei Tong, Zhihua Liu, Chaochao Lu, Dino Oglic, Tom Diethe, Philip Teare, Sotirios A. Tsaftaris, Chen Jin</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:04:57 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.24798v5</guid></item><item><title>Billion-Scale Graph Foundation Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04768v1</link><description>Graph-structured data underpins many critical applications. While foundation models have transformed language and vision via large-scale pretraining and lightweight adaptation, extending this paradigm to general, real-world graphs is challenging. In this work, we present Graph Billion- Foundation-Fusion (GraphBFF): the first end-to-end recipe for building billion-parameter Graph Foundation Models (GFMs) for arbitrary heterogeneous, billion-scale graphs. Central to the recipe is the GraphBFF Transformer, a flexible and scalable architecture designed for practical billion-scale GFMs. Using the GraphBFF, we present the first neural scaling laws for general graphs and show that loss decreases predictably as either model capacity or training data scales, depending on which factor is the bottleneck. The GraphBFF framework provides concrete methodologies for data batching, pretraining, and fine-tuning for building GFMs at scale. We demonstrate the effectiveness of the framework with an evaluation of a 1.4 billion-parameter GraphBFF Transformer pretrained on one billion samples. Across ten diverse, real-world downstream tasks on graphs unseen during training, spanning node- and link-level classification and regression, GraphBFF achieves remarkable zero-shot and probing performance, including in few-shot settings, with large margins of up to 31 PRAUC points. Finally, we discuss key challenges and open opportunities for making GFMs a practical and principled foundation for graph learning at industrial scale.</description><author>Maya Bechler-Speicher, Yoel Gottlieb, Andrey Isakov, David Abensur, Ami Tavory, Daniel Haimovich, Ido Guy, Udi Weinsberg</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:03:51 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04768v1</guid></item><item><title>Optimization, Generalization and Differential Privacy Bounds for Gradient Descent on Kolmogorov-Arnold Networks</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.22409v2</link><description>Kolmogorov--Arnold Networks (KANs) have recently emerged as a structured alternative to standard MLPs, yet a principled theory for their training dynamics, generalization, and privacy properties remains limited. In this paper, we analyze gradient descent (GD) for training two-layer KANs and derive general bounds that characterize their training dynamics, generalization, and utility under differential privacy (DP). As a concrete instantiation, we specialize our analysis to logistic loss under an NTK-separable assumption, where we show that polylogarithmic network width suffices for GD to achieve an optimization rate of order $1/T$ and a generalization rate of order $1/n$, with $T$ denoting the number of GD iterations and $n$ the sample size. In the private setting, we characterize the noise required for $(ε,δ)$-DP and obtain a utility bound of order $\sqrt{d}/(nε)$ (with $d$ the input dimension), matching the classical lower bound for general convex Lipschitz problems. Our results imply that polylogarithmic width is not only sufficient but also necessary under differential privacy, revealing a qualitative gap between non-private (sufficiency only) and private (necessity also emerges) training regimes. Experiments further illustrate how these theoretical insights can guide practical choices, including network width selection and early stopping.</description><author>Puyu Wang, Junyu Zhou, Philipp Liznerski, Marius Kloft</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:03:18 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.22409v2</guid></item><item><title>Beyond Many-Shot Translation: Scaling In-Context Demonstrations For Low-Resource Machine Translation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04764v1</link><description>Building machine translation (MT) systems for low-resource languages is notably difficult due to the scarcity of high-quality data. Although Large Language Models (LLMs) have improved MT system performance, adapting them to lesser-represented languages remains challenging. In-context learning (ICL) may offer novel ways to adapt LLMs for low-resource MT by conditioning models on demonstration at inference time. In this study, we explore scaling low-resource machine translation ICL beyond the few-shot setting to thousands of examples with long-context models. We scale in-context token budget to 1M tokens and compare three types of training corpora used as in-context supervision: monolingual unsupervised data, instruction-style data, and parallel data (English--target and Indonesian--target). Our experiments on Javanese and Sundanese show that gains from additional context saturate quickly and can degrade near the maximum context window, with scaling behavior strongly dependent on corpus type. Notably, some forms of monolingual supervision can be competitive with parallel data, despite the latter offering additional supervision. Overall, our results characterize the effective limits and corpus-type sensitivity of long-context ICL for low-resource MT, highlighting that larger context windows do not necessarily yield proportional quality gains.</description><author>Luis Frentzen Salim, Esteban Carlin, Alexandre Morinvil, Xi Ai, Lun-Wei Ku</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:02:22 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04764v1</guid></item><item><title>Active Asymmetric Multi-Agent Multimodal Learning under Uncertainty</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04763v1</link><description>Multi-agent systems are increasingly equipped with heterogeneous multimodal sensors, enabling richer perception but introducing modality-specific and agent-dependent uncertainty. Existing multi-agent collaboration frameworks typically reason at the agent level, assume homogeneous sensing, and handle uncertainty implicitly, limiting robustness under sensor corruption. We propose Active Asymmetric Multi-Agent Multimodal Learning under Uncertainty (A2MAML), a principled approach for uncertainty-aware, modality-level collaboration. A2MAML models each modality-specific feature as a stochastic estimate with uncertainty prediction, actively selects reliable agent-modality pairs, and aggregates information via Bayesian inverse-variance weighting. This formulation enables fine-grained, modality-level fusion, supports asymmetric modality availability, and provides a principled mechanism to suppress corrupted or noisy modalities. Extensive experiments on connected autonomous driving scenarios for collaborative accident detection demonstrate that A2MAML consistently outperforms both single-agent and collaborative baselines, achieving up to 18.7% higher accident detection rate.</description><author>Rui Liu, Pratap Tokekar, Ming Lin</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:01:31 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04763v1</guid></item><item><title>Backward Conformal Prediction</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.13732v4</link><description>We introduce $\textit{Backward Conformal Prediction}$, a method that guarantees conformal coverage while providing flexible control over the size of prediction sets. Unlike standard conformal prediction, which fixes the coverage level and allows the conformal set size to vary, our approach defines a rule that constrains how prediction set sizes behave based on the observed data, and adapts the coverage level accordingly. Our method builds on two key foundations: (i) recent results by Gauthier et al. [2025] on post-hoc validity using e-values, which ensure marginal coverage of the form $\mathbb{P}(Y_{\rm test} \in \hat C_n^{\tildeα}(X_{\rm test})) \ge 1 - \mathbb{E}[\tildeα]$ for any data-dependent miscoverage $\tildeα$, and (ii) a novel leave-one-out estimator $\hatα^{\rm LOO}$ of the marginal miscoverage $\mathbb{E}[\tildeα]$ based on the calibration set, ensuring that the theoretical guarantees remain computable in practice. This approach is particularly useful in applications where large prediction sets are impractical such as medical diagnosis. We provide theoretical results and empirical evidence supporting the validity of our method, demonstrating that it maintains computable coverage guarantees while ensuring interpretable, well-controlled prediction set sizes.</description><author>Etienne Gauthier, Francis Bach, Michael I. Jordan</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:59:22 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.13732v4</guid></item><item><title>Improved Dimension Dependence for Bandit Convex Optimization with Gradient Variations</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04761v1</link><description>Gradient-variation online learning has drawn increasing attention due to its deep connections to game theory, optimization, etc. It has been studied extensively in the full-information setting, but is underexplored with bandit feedback. In this work, we focus on gradient variation in Bandit Convex Optimization (BCO) with two-point feedback. By proposing a refined analysis on the non-consecutive gradient variation, a fundamental quantity in gradient variation with bandits, we improve the dimension dependence for both convex and strongly convex functions compared with the best known results (Chiang et al., 2013). Our improved analysis for the non-consecutive gradient variation also implies other favorable problem-dependent guarantees, such as gradient-variance and small-loss regrets. Beyond the two-point setup, we demonstrate the versatility of our technique by achieving the first gradient-variation bound for one-point bandit linear optimization over hyper-rectangular domains. Finally, we validate the effectiveness of our results in more challenging tasks such as dynamic/universal regret minimization and bandit games, establishing the first gradient-variation dynamic and universal regret bounds for two-point BCO and fast convergence rates in bandit games.</description><author>Hang Yu, Yu-Hu Yan, Peng Zhao</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:58:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04761v1</guid></item><item><title>A Dual-TransUNet Deep Learning Framework for Multi-Source Precipitation Merging and Improving Seasonal and Extreme Estimates</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04757v1</link><description>Multi-source precipitation products (MSPs) from satellite retrievals and reanalysis are widely used for hydroclimatic monitoring, yet spatially heterogeneous biases and limited skill for extremes still constrain their hydrologic utility. Here we develop a dual-stage TransUNet-based multi-source precipitation merging framework (DDL-MSPMF) that integrates six MSPs with four ERA5 near-surface physical predictors. A first-stage classifier estimates daily precipitation occurrence probability, and a second-stage regressor fuses the classifier outputs together with all predictors to estimate daily precipitation amount at 0.25 degree resolution over China for 2001-2020. Benchmarking against multiple deep learning and hybrid baselines shows that the TransUNet - TransUNet configuration yields the best seasonal performance (R = 0.75; RMSE = 2.70 mm/day) and improves robustness relative to a single-regressor setting. For heavy precipitation (&gt;25 mm/day), DDL-MSPMF increases equitable threat scores across most regions of eastern China and better reproduces the spatial pattern of the July 2021 Zhengzhou rainstorm, indicating enhanced extreme-event detection beyond seasonal-mean corrections. Independent evaluation over the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau using TPHiPr further supports its applicability in data-scarce regions. SHAP analysis highlights the importance of precipitation occurrence probabilities and surface pressure, providing physically interpretable diagnostics. The proposed framework offers a scalable and explainable approach for precipitation fusion and extreme-event assessment.</description><author>Yuchen Ye, Zixuan Qi, Shixuan Li, Wei Qi, Yanpeng Cai, Chaoxia Yuan</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:55:43 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04757v1</guid></item><item><title>Non-Intrusive Graph-Based Bot Detection for E-Commerce Using Inductive Graph Neural Networks</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.22579v3</link><description>Malicious bots pose a growing threat to e-commerce platforms by scraping data, hoarding inventory, and perpetrating fraud. Traditional bot mitigation techniques, including IP blacklists and CAPTCHA-based challenges, are increasingly ineffective or intrusive, as modern bots leverage proxies, botnets, and AI-assisted evasion strategies. This work proposes a non-intrusive graph-based bot detection framework for e-commerce that models user session behavior through a graph representation and applies an inductive graph neural network for classification. The approach captures both relational structure and behavioral semantics, enabling accurate identification of subtle automated activity that evades feature-based methods. Experiments on real-world e-commerce traffic demonstrate that the proposed inductive graph model outperforms a strong session-level multilayer perceptron baseline in terms of AUC and F1 score. Additional adversarial perturbation and cold-start simulations show that the model remains robust under moderate graph modifications and generalizes effectively to previously unseen sessions and URLs. The proposed framework is deployment-friendly, integrates with existing systems without client-side instrumentation, and supports real-time inference and incremental updates, making it suitable for practical e-commerce security deployments.</description><author>Sichen Zhao, Zhiming Xue, Yalun Qi, Xianling Zeng, Zihan Yu</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:55:42 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.22579v3</guid></item><item><title>When Silence Is Golden: Can LLMs Learn to Abstain in Temporal QA and Beyond?</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04755v1</link><description>Large language models (LLMs) rarely admit uncertainty, often producing fluent but misleading answers, rather than abstaining (i.e., refusing to answer). This weakness is even evident in temporal question answering, where models frequently ignore time-sensitive evidence and conflate facts across different time-periods. In this paper, we present the first empirical study of training LLMs with an abstention ability while reasoning about temporal QA. Existing approaches such as calibration might be unreliable in capturing uncertainty in complex reasoning. We instead frame abstention as a teachable skill and introduce a pipeline that couples Chain-of-Thought (CoT) supervision with Reinforcement Learning (RL) guided by abstention-aware rewards. Our goal is to systematically analyze how different information types and training techniques affect temporal reasoning with abstention behavior in LLMs. Through extensive experiments studying various methods, we find that RL yields strong empirical gains on reasoning: a model initialized by Qwen2.5-1.5B-Instruct surpasses GPT-4o by $3.46\%$ and $5.80\%$ in Exact Match on TimeQA-Easy and Hard, respectively. Moreover, it improves the True Positive rate on unanswerable questions by $20\%$ over a pure supervised fine-tuned (SFT) variant. Beyond performance, our analysis shows that SFT induces overconfidence and harms reliability, while RL improves prediction accuracy but exhibits similar risks. Finally, by comparing implicit reasoning cues (e.g., original context, temporal sub-context, knowledge graphs) with explicit CoT supervision, we find that implicit information provides limited benefit for reasoning with abstention. Our study provides new insights into how abstention and reasoning can be jointly optimized, providing a foundation for building more reliable LLMs.</description><author>Xinyu Zhou, Chang Jin, Carsten Eickhoff, Zhijiang Guo, Seyed Ali Bahrainian</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:54:47 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04755v1</guid></item><item><title>TxRay: Agentic Postmortem of Live Blockchain Attacks</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.01317v2</link><description>Decentralized Finance (DeFi) has turned blockchains into financial infrastructure, allowing anyone to trade, lend, and build protocols without intermediaries, but this openness exposes pools of value controlled by code. Within five years, the DeFi ecosystem has lost over 15.75B USD to reported exploits. Many exploits arise from permissionless opportunities that any participant can trigger using only public state and standard interfaces, which we call Anyone-Can-Take (ACT) opportunities. Despite on-chain transparency, postmortem analysis remains slow and manual: investigations start from limited evidence, sometimes only a single transaction hash, and must reconstruct the exploit lifecycle by recovering related transactions, contract code, and state dependencies. We present TxRay, a Large Language Model (LLM) agentic postmortem system that uses tool calls to reconstruct live ACT attacks from limited evidence. Starting from one or more seed transactions, TxRay recovers the exploit lifecycle, derives an evidence-backed root cause, and generates a runnable, self-contained Proof of Concept (PoC) that deterministically reproduces the incident. TxRay self-checks postmortems by encoding incident-specific semantic oracles as executable assertions. To evaluate PoC correctness and quality, we develop PoCEvaluator, an independent agentic execution-and-review evaluator. On 114 incidents from DeFiHackLabs, TxRay produces an expert-aligned root cause and an executable PoC for 105 incidents, achieving 92.11% end-to-end reproduction. Under PoCEvaluator, 98.1% of TxRay PoCs avoid hard-coding attacker addresses, a +22.9pp lift over DeFiHackLabs. In a live deployment, TxRay delivers validated root causes in 40 minutes and PoCs in 59 minutes at median latency. TxRay's oracle-validated PoCs enable attack imitation, improving coverage by 15.6% and 65.5% over STING and APE.</description><author>Ziyue Wang, Jiangshan Yu, Kaihua Qin, Dawn Song, Arthur Gervais, Liyi Zhou</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:54:43 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.01317v2</guid></item><item><title>Unlocking hidden biomolecular conformational landscapes in diffusion models at inference time</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03312v2</link><description>The function of biomolecules such as proteins depends on their ability to interconvert between a wide range of structures or "conformations." Researchers have endeavored for decades to develop computational methods to predict the distribution of conformations, which is far harder to determine experimentally than a static folded structure. We present ConforMix, an inference-time algorithm that enhances sampling of conformational distributions using a combination of classifier guidance, filtering, and free energy estimation. Our approach upgrades diffusion models -- whether trained for static structure prediction or conformational generation -- to enable more efficient discovery of conformational variability without requiring prior knowledge of major degrees of freedom. ConforMix is orthogonal to improvements in model pretraining and would benefit even a hypothetical model that perfectly reproduced the Boltzmann distribution. Remarkably, when applied to a diffusion model trained for static structure prediction, ConforMix captures structural changes including domain motion, cryptic pocket flexibility, and transporter cycling, while avoiding unphysical states. Case studies of biologically critical proteins demonstrate the scalability, accuracy, and utility of this method.</description><author>Daniel D. Richman, Jessica Karaguesian, Carl-Mikael Suomivuori, Ron O. Dror</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:54:34 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03312v2</guid></item><item><title>Comparative Insights on Adversarial Machine Learning from Industry and Academia: A User-Study Approach</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04753v1</link><description>An exponential growth of Machine Learning and its Generative AI applications brings with it significant security challenges, often referred to as Adversarial Machine Learning (AML). In this paper, we conducted two comprehensive studies to explore the perspectives of industry professionals and students on different AML vulnerabilities and their educational strategies. In our first study, we conducted an online survey with professionals revealing a notable correlation between cybersecurity education and concern for AML threats. For our second study, we developed two CTF challenges that implement Natural Language Processing and Generative AI concepts and demonstrate a poisoning attack on the training data set. The effectiveness of these challenges was evaluated by surveying undergraduate and graduate students at Carnegie Mellon University, finding that a CTF-based approach effectively engages interest in AML threats. Based on the responses of the participants in our research, we provide detailed recommendations emphasizing the critical need for integrated security education within the ML curriculum.</description><author>Vishruti Kakkad, Paul Chung, Hanan Hibshi, Maverick Woo</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:51:50 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04753v1</guid></item><item><title>Decomposing Query-Key Feature Interactions Using Contrastive Covariances</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04752v1</link><description>Despite the central role of attention heads in Transformers, we lack tools to understand why a model attends to a particular token. To address this, we study the query-key (QK) space -- the bilinear joint embedding space between queries and keys. We present a contrastive covariance method to decompose the QK space into low-rank, human-interpretable components. It is when features in keys and queries align in these low-rank subspaces that high attention scores are produced. We first study our method both analytically and empirically in a simplified setting. We then apply our method to large language models to identify human-interpretable QK subspaces for categorical semantic features and binding features. Finally, we demonstrate how attention scores can be attributed to our identified features.</description><author>Andrew Lee, Yonatan Belinkov, Fernanda Viégas, Martin Wattenberg</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:50:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04752v1</guid></item><item><title>UNO: Unifying One-stage Video Scene Graph Generation via Object-Centric Visual Representation Learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.06165v5</link><description>Video Scene Graph Generation (VidSGG) aims to represent dynamic visual content by detecting objects and modeling their temporal interactions as structured graphs. Prior studies typically target either coarse-grained box-level or fine-grained panoptic pixel-level VidSGG, often requiring task-specific architectures and multi-stage training pipelines. In this paper, we present UNO (UNified Object-centric VidSGG), a single-stage, unified framework that jointly addresses both tasks within an end-to-end architecture. UNO is designed to minimize task-specific modifications and maximize parameter sharing, enabling generalization across different levels of visual granularity. The core of UNO is an extended slot attention mechanism that decomposes visual features into object and relation slots. To ensure robust temporal modeling, we introduce object temporal consistency learning, which enforces consistent object representations across frames without relying on explicit tracking modules. Additionally, a dynamic triplet prediction module links relation slots to corresponding object pairs, capturing evolving interactions over time. We evaluate UNO on standard box-level and pixel-level VidSGG benchmarks. Results demonstrate that UNO not only achieves competitive performance across both tasks but also offers improved efficiency through a unified, object-centric design. Code is available at: https://github.com/Fsoft-AIC/UNO</description><author>Huy Le, Nhat Chung, Tung Kieu, Jingkang Yang, Ngan Le</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:49:45 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.06165v5</guid></item><item><title>Exploiting contextual information to improve stance detection in informal political discourse with LLMs</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04750v1</link><description>This study investigates the use of Large Language Models (LLMs) for political stance detection in informal online discourse, where language is often sarcastic, ambiguous, and context-dependent. We explore whether providing contextual information, specifically user profile summaries derived from historical posts, can improve classification accuracy. Using a real-world political forum dataset, we generate structured profiles that summarize users' ideological leaning, recurring topics, and linguistic patterns. We evaluate seven state-of-the-art LLMs across baseline and context-enriched setups through a comprehensive cross-model evaluation. Our findings show that contextual prompts significantly boost accuracy, with improvements ranging from +17.5\% to +38.5\%, achieving up to 74\% accuracy that surpasses previous approaches. We also analyze how profile size and post selection strategies affect performance, showing that strategically chosen political content yields better results than larger, randomly selected contexts. These findings underscore the value of incorporating user-level context to enhance LLM performance in nuanced political classification tasks.</description><author>Arman Engin Sucu, Yixiang Zhou, Mario A. Nascimento, Tony Mullen</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:49:26 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04750v1</guid></item><item><title>Mitigating Long-Tail Bias via Prompt-Controlled Diffusion Augmentation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04749v1</link><description>Semantic segmentation of high-resolution remote-sensing imagery is critical for urban mapping and land-cover monitoring, yet training data typically exhibits severe long-tailed pixel imbalance. In the dataset LoveDA, this challenge is compounded by an explicit Urban/Rural split with distinct appearance and inconsistent class-frequency statistics across domains. We present a prompt-controlled diffusion augmentation framework that synthesizes paired label--image samples with explicit control of both domain and semantic composition. Stage~A uses a domain-aware, masked ratio-conditioned discrete diffusion model to generate layouts that satisfy user-specified class-ratio targets while respecting learned co-occurrence structure. Stage~B translates layouts into photorealistic, domain-consistent images using Stable Diffusion with ControlNet guidance. Mixing the resulting ratio and domain-controlled synthetic pairs with real data yields consistent improvements across multiple segmentation backbones, with gains concentrated on minority classes and improved Urban and Rural generalization, demonstrating controllable augmentation as a practical mechanism to mitigate long-tail bias in remote-sensing segmentation. Source codes, pretrained models, and synthetic datasets are available at \href{https://github.com/Buddhi19/SyntheticGen.git}{Github}</description><author>Buddhi Wijenayake, Nichula Wasalathilake, Roshan Godaliyadda, Vijitha Herath, Parakrama Ekanayake, Vishal M. Patel</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:49:16 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04749v1</guid></item><item><title>Impact of diversity on bounded archives for multi-objective local search</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04745v1</link><description>This work tackles two critical challenges related to the development of metaheuristics for Multi-Objective Optimization Problems (MOOPs): the exponential growth of non-dominated solutions and the tendency of metaheuristics to disproportionately concentrate their search on a subset of the Pareto Front. To counteract the first, bounded archives are employed as a strategic mechanism for effectively managing the increasing number of non-dominated solutions. Addressing the second challenge involves an in-depth exploration of solution diversity algorithms found in existing literature. Upon recognizing that current approaches predominantly center on diversity within the objective space, this research introduces innovative methods specifically designed to enhance diversity in the solution space. Results demonstrate the efficacy of the Hamming Distance Archiving Algorithm, one of the newly proposed algorithms for multi-objective local search, surpassing the performance of the Adaptive Grid Archiving and the Hypervolume Archiving, both drawn from the literature. This outcome suggests a promising avenue for enhancing the overall efficiency of metaheuristics employed for solving MOOPs.</description><author>Amadeu A. Coco, Cyprien Borée, Julien Baste, Laetitia Jourdan, Lucien Mousin</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:47:14 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04745v1</guid></item><item><title>Graph Persistence goes Spectral</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.06571v3</link><description>Including intricate topological information (e.g., cycles) provably enhances the expressivity of message-passing graph neural networks (GNNs) beyond the Weisfeiler-Leman (WL) hierarchy. Consequently, Persistent Homology (PH) methods are increasingly employed for graph representation learning. In this context, recent works have proposed decorating classical PH diagrams with vertex and edge features for improved expressivity. However, these methods still fail to capture basic graph structural information. In this paper, we propose SpectRe -- a new topological descriptor for graphs that integrates spectral information into PH diagrams. Notably, SpectRe is strictly more expressive than PH and spectral information on graphs alone. We also introduce notions of global and local stability to analyze existing descriptors and establish that SpectRe is locally stable. Finally, experiments on synthetic and real-world datasets demonstrate the effectiveness of SpectRe and its potential to enhance the capabilities of graph models in relevant learning tasks. Code is available at https://github.com/Aalto-QuML/SpectRe/.</description><author>Mattie Ji, Amauri H. Souza, Vikas Garg</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:44:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.06571v3</guid></item><item><title>M^3-Bench: Multi-Modal, Multi-Hop, Multi-Threaded Tool-Using MLLM Agent Benchmark</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17729v4</link><description>We present M^3-Bench, the first benchmark for evaluating multimodal tool use under the Model Context Protocol. The benchmark targets realistic, multi-hop and multi-threaded workflows that require visual grounding and textual reasoning, cross-tool dependencies, and persistence of intermediate resources across steps. We introduce a similarity-driven alignment that serializes each tool call, embeds signatures with a sentence encoder, and performs similarity-bucketed Hungarian matching to obtain auditable one-to-one correspondences. On top of this alignment, we report interpretable metrics that decouple semantic fidelity from workflow consistency. The benchmark spans 28 servers with 231 tools, and provides standardized trajectories curated through an Executor &amp; Judge pipeline with human verification; an auxiliary four large language models (LLMs) judge ensemble reports end-task Task Completion and information grounding. Evaluations of representative state-of-the-art Multimodal LLMs (MLLMs) reveal persistent gaps in multimodal MCP tool use, particularly in argument fidelity and structure consistency, underscoring the need for methods that jointly reason over images, text, and tool graphs. Our Benchmark's anonymous repository is at https://github.com/EtaYang10th/Open-M3-Bench</description><author>Yang Zhou, Mingyu Zhao, Zhenting Wang, Difei Gu, Bangwei Guo, Ruosong Ye, Ligong Han, Can Jin, Dimitris N. Metaxas</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:44:31 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17729v4</guid></item><item><title>Inference-Time Reasoning Selectively Reduces Implicit Social Bias in Large Language Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04742v1</link><description>Drawing on constructs from psychology, prior work has identified a distinction between explicit and implicit bias in large language models (LLMs). While many LLMs undergo post-training alignment and safety procedures to avoid expressions of explicit social bias, they still exhibit significant implicit biases on indirect tasks resembling the Implicit Association Test (IAT). Recent work has further shown that inference-time reasoning can impair LLM performance on tasks that rely on implicit statistical learning. Motivated by a theoretical link between implicit associations and statistical learning in human cognition, we examine how reasoning-enabled inference affects implicit bias in LLMs. We find that enabling reasoning significantly reduces measured implicit bias on an IAT-style evaluation for some model classes across fifteen stereotype topics. This effect appears specific to social bias domains, as we observe no corresponding reduction for non-social implicit associations. As reasoning is increasingly enabled by default in deployed LLMs, these findings suggest that it can meaningfully alter fairness evaluation outcomes in some systems, while also raising questions about how alignment procedures interact with inference-time reasoning to drive variation in bias reduction across model types. More broadly, this work highlights how theory from cognitive science and psychology can complement AI evaluation research by providing methodological and interpretive frameworks that reveal new insights into model behavior.</description><author>Molly Apsel, Michael N. Jones</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:44:23 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04742v1</guid></item><item><title>Improved Bag-of-Words Image Retrieval with Geometric Constraints for Ground Texture Localization</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.11620v2</link><description>Ground texture localization using a downward-facing camera offers a low-cost, high-precision localization solution that is robust to dynamic environments and requires no environmental modification. We present a significantly improved bag-of-words (BoW) image retrieval system for ground texture localization, achieving substantially higher accuracy for global localization and higher precision and recall for loop closure detection in SLAM. Our approach leverages an approximate $k$-means (AKM) vocabulary with soft assignment, and exploits the consistent orientation and constant scale constraints inherent to ground texture localization. Identifying the different needs of global localization vs. loop closure detection for SLAM, we present both high-accuracy and high-speed versions of our algorithm. We test the effect of each of our proposed improvements through an ablation study and demonstrate our method's effectiveness for both global localization and loop closure detection. With numerous ground texture localization systems already using BoW, our method can readily replace other generic BoW systems in their pipeline and immediately improve their results.</description><author>Aaron Wilhelm, Nils Napp</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:43:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.11620v2</guid></item><item><title>Alignment Drift in Multimodal LLMs: A Two-Phase, Longitudinal Evaluation of Harm Across Eight Model Releases</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04739v1</link><description>Multimodal large language models (MLLMs) are increasingly deployed in real-world systems, yet their safety under adversarial prompting remains underexplored. We present a two-phase evaluation of MLLM harmlessness using a fixed benchmark of 726 adversarial prompts authored by 26 professional red teamers. Phase 1 assessed GPT-4o, Claude Sonnet 3.5, Pixtral 12B, and Qwen VL Plus; Phase 2 evaluated their successors (GPT-5, Claude Sonnet 4.5, Pixtral Large, and Qwen Omni) yielding 82,256 human harm ratings. Large, persistent differences emerged across model families: Pixtral models were consistently the most vulnerable, whereas Claude models appeared safest due to high refusal rates. Attack success rates (ASR) showed clear alignment drift: GPT and Claude models exhibited increased ASR across generations, while Pixtral and Qwen showed modest decreases. Modality effects also shifted over time: text-only prompts were more effective in Phase 1, whereas Phase 2 produced model-specific patterns, with GPT-5 and Claude 4.5 showing near-equivalent vulnerability across modalities. These findings demonstrate that MLLM harmlessness is neither uniform nor stable across updates, underscoring the need for longitudinal, multimodal benchmarks to track evolving safety behaviour.</description><author>Casey Ford, Madison Van Doren, Emily Dix</author><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:42:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04739v1</guid></item></channel></rss>