<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Arxivfresh papers</title><link></link><description>Arxiv paper</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 05:40:57 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.0.0</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>SemanticGen: Video Generation in Semantic Space</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20619v1</link><description>State-of-the-art video generative models typically learn the distribution of video latents in the VAE space and map them to pixels using a VAE decoder. While this approach can generate high-quality videos, it suffers from slow convergence and is computationally expensive when generating long videos. In this paper, we introduce SemanticGen, a novel solution to address these limitations by generating videos in the semantic space. Our main insight is that, due to the inherent redundancy in videos, the generation process should begin in a compact, high-level semantic space for global planning, followed by the addition of high-frequency details, rather than directly modeling a vast set of low-level video tokens using bi-directional attention. SemanticGen adopts a two-stage generation process. In the first stage, a diffusion model generates compact semantic video features, which define the global layout of the video. In the second stage, another diffusion model generates VAE latents conditioned on these semantic features to produce the final output. We observe that generation in the semantic space leads to faster convergence compared to the VAE latent space. Our method is also effective and computationally efficient when extended to long video generation. Extensive experiments demonstrate that SemanticGen produces high-quality videos and outperforms state-of-the-art approaches and strong baselines.</description><author>Jianhong Bai, Xiaoshi Wu, Xintao Wang, Fu Xiao, Yuanxing Zhang, Qinghe Wang, Xiaoyu Shi, Menghan Xia, Zuozhu Liu, Haoji Hu, Pengfei Wan, Kun Gai</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:59:56 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20619v1</guid></item><item><title>LongVideoAgent: Multi-Agent Reasoning with Long Videos</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20618v1</link><description>Recent advances in multimodal LLMs and systems that use tools for long-video QA point to the promise of reasoning over hour-long episodes. However, many methods still compress content into lossy summaries or rely on limited toolsets, weakening temporal grounding and missing fine-grained cues. We propose a multi-agent framework in which a master LLM coordinates a grounding agent to localize question-relevant segments and a vision agent to extract targeted textual observations. The master agent plans with a step limit, and is trained with reinforcement learning to encourage concise, correct, and efficient multi-agent cooperation. This design helps the master agent focus on relevant clips via grounding, complements subtitles with visual detail, and yields interpretable trajectories. On our proposed LongTVQA and LongTVQA+ which are episode-level datasets aggregated from TVQA/TVQA+, our multi-agent system significantly outperforms strong non-agent baselines. Experiments also show reinforcement learning further strengthens reasoning and planning for the trained agent. Code and data will be shared at https://longvideoagent.github.io/.</description><author>Runtao Liu, Ziyi Liu, Jiaqi Tang, Yue Ma, Renjie Pi, Jipeng Zhang, Qifeng Chen</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:59:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20618v1</guid></item><item><title>SpatialTree: How Spatial Abilities Branch Out in MLLMs</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20617v1</link><description>Cognitive science suggests that spatial ability develops progressively-from perception to reasoning and interaction. Yet in multimodal LLMs (MLLMs), this hierarchy remains poorly understood, as most studies focus on a narrow set of tasks. We introduce SpatialTree, a cognitive-science-inspired hierarchy that organizes spatial abilities into four levels: low-level perception (L1), mental mapping (L2), simulation (L3), and agentic competence (L4). Based on this taxonomy, we construct the first capability-centric hierarchical benchmark, thoroughly evaluating mainstream MLLMs across 27 sub-abilities. The evaluation results reveal a clear structure: L1 skills are largely orthogonal, whereas higher-level skills are strongly correlated, indicating increasing interdependency. Through targeted supervised fine-tuning, we uncover a surprising transfer dynamic-negative transfer within L1, but strong cross-level transfer from low- to high-level abilities with notable synergy. Finally, we explore how to improve the entire hierarchy. We find that naive RL that encourages extensive "thinking" is unreliable: it helps complex reasoning but hurts intuitive perception. We propose a simple auto-think strategy that suppresses unnecessary deliberation, enabling RL to consistently improve performance across all levels. By building SpatialTree, we provide a proof-of-concept framework for understanding and systematically scaling spatial abilities in MLLMs.</description><author>Yuxi Xiao, Longfei Li, Shen Yan, Xinhang Liu, Sida Peng, Yunchao Wei, Xiaowei Zhou, Bingyi Kang</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:59:46 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20617v1</guid></item><item><title>Active Intelligence in Video Avatars via Closed-loop World Modeling</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20615v1</link><description>Current video avatar generation methods excel at identity preservation and motion alignment but lack genuine agency, they cannot autonomously pursue long-term goals through adaptive environmental interaction. We address this by introducing L-IVA (Long-horizon Interactive Visual Avatar), a task and benchmark for evaluating goal-directed planning in stochastic generative environments, and ORCA (Online Reasoning and Cognitive Architecture), the first framework enabling active intelligence in video avatars. ORCA embodies Internal World Model (IWM) capabilities through two key innovations: (1) a closed-loop OTAR cycle (Observe-Think-Act-Reflect) that maintains robust state tracking under generative uncertainty by continuously verifying predicted outcomes against actual generations, and (2) a hierarchical dual-system architecture where System 2 performs strategic reasoning with state prediction while System 1 translates abstract plans into precise, model-specific action captions. By formulating avatar control as a POMDP and implementing continuous belief updating with outcome verification, ORCA enables autonomous multi-step task completion in open-domain scenarios. Extensive experiments demonstrate that ORCA significantly outperforms open-loop and non-reflective baselines in task success rate and behavioral coherence, validating our IWM-inspired design for advancing video avatar intelligence from passive animation to active, goal-oriented behavior.</description><author>Xuanhua He, Tianyu Yang, Ke Cao, Ruiqi Wu, Cheng Meng, Yong Zhang, Zhuoliang Kang, Xiaoming Wei, Qifeng Chen</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:59:16 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20615v1</guid></item><item><title>Making Large Language Models Efficient Dense Retrievers</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20612v1</link><description>Recent work has shown that directly fine-tuning large language models (LLMs) for dense retrieval yields strong performance, but their substantial parameter counts make them computationally inefficient. While prior studies have revealed significant layer redundancy in LLMs for generative tasks, it remains unclear whether similar redundancy exists when these models are adapted for retrieval tasks, which require encoding entire sequences into fixed representations rather than generating tokens iteratively. To this end, we conduct a comprehensive analysis of layer redundancy in LLM-based dense retrievers. We find that, in contrast to generative settings, MLP layers are substantially more prunable, while attention layers remain critical for semantic aggregation. Building on this insight, we propose EffiR, a framework for developing efficient retrievers that performs large-scale MLP compression through a coarse-to-fine strategy (coarse-grained depth reduction followed by fine-grained width reduction), combined with retrieval-specific fine-tuning. Across diverse BEIR datasets and LLM backbones, EffiR achieves substantial reductions in model size and inference cost while preserving the performance of full-size models.</description><author>Yibin Lei, Shwai He, Ang Li, Andrew Yates</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:58:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20612v1</guid></item><item><title>FedPOD: the deployable units of training for federated learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20610v1</link><description>This paper proposes FedPOD (Proportionally Orchestrated Derivative) for optimizing learning efficiency and communication cost in federated learning among multiple clients. Inspired by FedPIDAvg, we define a round-wise task for FedPOD to enhance training efficiency. FedPIDAvg achieved performance improvement by incorporating the training loss reduction for prediction entropy as weights using differential terms. Furthermore, by modeling data distribution with a Poisson distribution and using a PID controller, it reduced communication costs even in skewed data distribution. However, excluding participants classified as outliers based on the Poisson distribution can limit data utilization. Additionally, PID controller requires the same participants to be maintained throughout the federated learning process as it uses previous rounds' learning information in the current round. In our approach, FedPOD addresses these issues by including participants excluded as outliers, eliminating dependency on previous rounds' learning information, and applying a method for calculating validation loss at each round. In this challenge, FedPOD presents comparable performance to FedPIDAvg in metrics of Dice score, 0.78, 0.71 and 0.72 for WT, ET and TC in average, and projected convergence score, 0.74 in average. Furthermore, the concept of FedPOD draws inspiration from Kubernetes' smallest computing unit, POD, designed to be compatible with Kubernetes auto-scaling. Extending round-wise tasks of FedPOD to POD units allows flexible design by applying scale-out similar to Kubernetes' auto-scaling. This work demonstrated the potentials of FedPOD to enhance federated learning by improving efficiency, flexibility, and performance in metrics.</description><author>Daewoon Kim, Si Young Yie, Jae Sung Lee</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:57:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20610v1</guid></item><item><title>Saddle-to-Saddle Dynamics Explains A Simplicity Bias Across Neural Network Architectures</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20607v1</link><description>Neural networks trained with gradient descent often learn solutions of increasing complexity over time, a phenomenon known as simplicity bias. Despite being widely observed across architectures, existing theoretical treatments lack a unifying framework. We present a theoretical framework that explains a simplicity bias arising from saddle-to-saddle learning dynamics for a general class of neural networks, incorporating fully-connected, convolutional, and attention-based architectures. Here, simple means expressible with few hidden units, i.e., hidden neurons, convolutional kernels, or attention heads. Specifically, we show that linear networks learn solutions of increasing rank, ReLU networks learn solutions with an increasing number of kinks, convolutional networks learn solutions with an increasing number of convolutional kernels, and self-attention models learn solutions with an increasing number of attention heads. By analyzing fixed points, invariant manifolds, and dynamics of gradient descent learning, we show that saddle-to-saddle dynamics operates by iteratively evolving near an invariant manifold, approaching a saddle, and switching to another invariant manifold. Our analysis also illuminates the effects of data distribution and weight initialization on the duration and number of plateaus in learning, dissociating previously confounding factors. Overall, our theory offers a framework for understanding when and why gradient descent progressively learns increasingly complex solutions.</description><author>Yedi Zhang, Andrew Saxe, Peter E. Latham</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:55:30 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20607v1</guid></item><item><title>Repurposing Video Diffusion Transformers for Robust Point Tracking</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20606v1</link><description>Point tracking aims to localize corresponding points across video frames, serving as a fundamental task for 4D reconstruction, robotics, and video editing. Existing methods commonly rely on shallow convolutional backbones such as ResNet that process frames independently, lacking temporal coherence and producing unreliable matching costs under challenging conditions. Through systematic analysis, we find that video Diffusion Transformers (DiTs), pre-trained on large-scale real-world videos with spatio-temporal attention, inherently exhibit strong point tracking capability and robustly handle dynamic motions and frequent occlusions. We propose DiTracker, which adapts video DiTs through: (1) query-key attention matching, (2) lightweight LoRA tuning, and (3) cost fusion with a ResNet backbone. Despite training with 8 times smaller batch size, DiTracker achieves state-of-the-art performance on challenging ITTO benchmark and matches or outperforms state-of-the-art models on TAP-Vid benchmarks. Our work validates video DiT features as an effective and efficient foundation for point tracking.</description><author>Soowon Son, Honggyu An, Chaehyun Kim, Hyunah Ko, Jisu Nam, Dahyun Chung, Siyoon Jin, Jung Yi, Jaewon Min, Junhwa Hur, Seungryong Kim</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:54:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20606v1</guid></item><item><title>Emergent temporal abstractions in autoregressive models enable hierarchical reinforcement learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20605v1</link><description>Large-scale autoregressive models pretrained on next-token prediction and finetuned with reinforcement learning (RL) have achieved unprecedented success on many problem domains. During RL, these models explore by generating new outputs, one token at a time. However, sampling actions token-by-token can result in highly inefficient learning, particularly when rewards are sparse. Here, we show that it is possible to overcome this problem by acting and exploring within the internal representations of an autoregressive model. Specifically, to discover temporally-abstract actions, we introduce a higher-order, non-causal sequence model whose outputs control the residual stream activations of a base autoregressive model. On grid world and MuJoCo-based tasks with hierarchical structure, we find that the higher-order model learns to compress long activation sequence chunks onto internal controllers. Critically, each controller executes a sequence of behaviorally meaningful actions that unfold over long timescales and are accompanied with a learned termination condition, such that composing multiple controllers over time leads to efficient exploration on novel tasks. We show that direct internal controller reinforcement, a process we term "internal RL", enables learning from sparse rewards in cases where standard RL finetuning fails. Our results demonstrate the benefits of latent action generation and reinforcement in autoregressive models, suggesting internal RL as a promising avenue for realizing hierarchical RL within foundation models.</description><author>Seijin Kobayashi, Yanick Schimpf, Maximilian Schlegel, Angelika Steger, Maciej Wolczyk, Johannes von Oswald, Nino Scherre, Kaitlin Maile, Guillaume Lajoie, Blake A. Richards, Rif A. Saurous, James Manyika, Blaise Agüera y Arcas, Alexander Meulemans, João Sacramento</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:51:50 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20605v1</guid></item><item><title>MoE-DiffuSeq: Enhancing Long-Document Diffusion Models with Sparse Attention and Mixture of Experts</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20604v1</link><description>We present MoE-DiffuSeq, a mixture of experts based framework for enhancing diffusion models in long document generation. Existing diffusion based text generation models, such as DiffuSeq, suffer from high computational cost and memory overhead when applied to extended sequences. To address these challenges, MoE-DiffuSeq integrates sparse attention with a mixture of experts architecture, enabling efficient and scalable long sequence modeling. Our approach introduces a customized sparse attention mechanism designed to reduce computational complexity while preserving text quality and coherence. In addition, we incorporate a soft absorbing state within the diffusion process to accelerate sequence reconstruction and improve generation precision. Extensive experiments demonstrate that MoE-DiffuSeq significantly improves training efficiency and sampling speed compared to existing diffusion models. These advantages are particularly effective for long document scenarios, including scientific article generation, code repository modeling, and long form dialogue generation. Benchmark results further show that MoE-DiffuSeq improves efficiency, speed, accuracy, and expressiveness, advancing the practical applicability of diffusion models for high quality long form text generation.</description><author>Alexandros Christoforos, Chadbourne Davis</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:50:54 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20604v1</guid></item><item><title>Reinforcement Learning From State and Temporal Differences</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.08855v2</link><description>TD($λ$) with function approximation has proved empirically successful for some complex reinforcement learning problems. For linear approximation, TD($λ$) has been shown to minimise the squared error between the approximate value of each state and the true value. However, as far as policy is concerned, it is error in the relative ordering of states that is critical, rather than error in the state values. We illustrate this point, both in simple two-state and three-state systems in which TD($λ$)--starting from an optimal policy--converges to a sub-optimal policy, and also in backgammon. We then present a modified form of TD($λ$), called STD($λ$), in which function approximators are trained with respect to relative state values on binary decision problems. A theoretical analysis, including a proof of monotonic policy improvement for STD($λ$) in the context of the two-state system, is presented, along with a comparison with Bertsekas' differential training method [1]. This is followed by successful demonstrations of STD($λ$) on the two-state system and a variation on the well known acrobot problem.</description><author>Lex Weaver, Jonathan Baxter</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:50:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.08855v2</guid></item><item><title>Learning Informative Attention Weights for Person Re-Identification</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.08961v2</link><description>Attention mechanisms have been widely used in deep learning, and recent efforts have been devoted to incorporating attention modules into deep neural networks (DNNs) for person Re-Identification (Re-ID) to enhance their discriminative feature learning capabilities. Existing attention modules, including self-attention and channel attention, learn attention weights that quantify the importance of feature tokens or feature channels. However, existing attention methods do not explicitly ensure that the attention weights are informative for predicting the identity of the person in the input image, and may consequently introduce noisy information from the input image. To address this issue, we propose a novel method termed Reduction of Information Bottleneck loss (RIB), motivated by the principle of the Information Bottleneck (IB). A novel distribution-free and efficient variational upper bound for the IB loss (IBB), which can be optimized by standard SGD, is derived and incorporated into the training loss of the RIB models. RIB is applied to DNNs with self-attention modules through a novel Differentiable Channel Selection Attention module, or DCS-Attention, that selects the most informative channels for computing attention weights, leading to competitive models termed RIB-DCS. RIB is also incorporated into DNNs with existing channel attention modules to promote the learning of informative channel attention weights, leading to models termed RIB-CA. Both RIB-DCS and RIB-CA are applied to fixed neural network backbones and learnable backbones with Differentiable Neural Architecture Search (DNAS). Extensive experiments on multiple person Re-ID benchmarks show that RIB significantly enhances the prediction accuracy of DNNs for person Re-ID, even for the occluded person Re-ID.</description><author>Yancheng Wang, Nebojsa Jojic, Yingzhen Yang</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:50:46 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.08961v2</guid></item><item><title>Cube Bench: A Benchmark for Spatial Visual Reasoning in MLLMs</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20595v1</link><description>We introduce Cube Bench, a Rubik's-cube benchmark for evaluating spatial and sequential reasoning in multimodal large language models (MLLMs). The benchmark decomposes performance into five skills: (i) reconstructing cube faces from images and text, (ii) choosing the optimal next move, (iii) predicting the outcome of a candidate move without applying it, (iv) executing multi-step plans while recovering from mistakes, and (v) detecting and revising one's own errors. Using a shared set of scrambled cube states, identical prompts and parsers, and a single distance-to-solved metric, we compare recent MLLMs side by side as a function of scramble depth. Across seven MLLMs, accuracy drops sharply with depth; once a trajectory stalls or diverges, models rarely recover, and high face-reconstruction accuracy does not guarantee competent action selection or multi-step execution. A pronounced closed- vs open-source gap emerges: the strongest closed model leads on both single-step perception tasks and multi-step control tasks, while open-weight models cluster near chance on the hardest settings; yet even the best MLLM degrades at higher cube complexity. A simple self-correction via reflective thinking yields modest gains but can also introduce overthinking. Cube Bench offers a compact, reproducible probe of sequential spatial reasoning in MLLMs.</description><author>Dhruv Anand, Ehsan Shareghi</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:43:05 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20595v1</guid></item><item><title>Leveraging High-Fidelity Digital Models and Reinforcement Learning for Mission Engineering: A Case Study of Aerial Firefighting Under Perfect Information</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20589v1</link><description>As systems engineering (SE) objectives evolve from design and operation of monolithic systems to complex System of Systems (SoS), the discipline of Mission Engineering (ME) has emerged which is increasingly being accepted as a new line of thinking for the SE community. Moreover, mission environments are uncertain, dynamic, and mission outcomes are a direct function of how the mission assets will interact with this environment. This proves static architectures brittle and calls for analytically rigorous approaches for ME. To that end, this paper proposes an intelligent mission coordination methodology that integrates digital mission models with Reinforcement Learning (RL), that specifically addresses the need for adaptive task allocation and reconfiguration. More specifically, we are leveraging a Digital Engineering (DE) based infrastructure that is composed of a high-fidelity digital mission model and agent-based simulation; and then we formulate the mission tactics management problem as a Markov Decision Process (MDP), and employ an RL agent trained via Proximal Policy Optimization. By leveraging the simulation as a sandbox, we map the system states to actions, refining the policy based on realized mission outcomes. The utility of the RL-based intelligent mission coordinator is demonstrated through an aerial firefighting case study. Our findings indicate that the RL-based intelligent mission coordinator not only surpasses baseline performance but also significantly reduces the variability in mission performance. Thus, this study serves as a proof of concept demonstrating that DE-enabled mission simulations combined with advanced analytical tools offer a mission-agnostic framework for improving ME practice; which can be extended to more complicated fleet design and selection problems in the future from a mission-first perspective.</description><author>İbrahim Oğuz Çetinkaya, Sajad Khodadadian, Taylan G. Topçu</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:36:07 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20589v1</guid></item><item><title>Automated stereotactic radiosurgery planning using a human-in-the-loop reasoning large language model agent</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20586v1</link><description>Stereotactic radiosurgery (SRS) demands precise dose shaping around critical structures, yet black-box AI systems have limited clinical adoption due to opacity concerns. We tested whether chain-of-thought reasoning improves agentic planning in a retrospective cohort of 41 patients with brain metastases treated with 18 Gy single-fraction SRS. We developed SAGE (Secure Agent for Generative Dose Expertise), an LLM-based planning agent for automated SRS treatment planning. Two variants generated plans for each case: one using a non-reasoning model, one using a reasoning model. The reasoning variant showed comparable plan dosimetry relative to human planners on primary endpoints (PTV coverage, maximum dose, conformity index, gradient index; all p &gt; 0.21) while reducing cochlear dose below human baselines (p = 0.022). When prompted to improve conformity, the reasoning model demonstrated systematic planning behaviors including prospective constraint verification (457 instances) and trade-off deliberation (609 instances), while the standard model exhibited none of these deliberative processes (0 and 7 instances, respectively). Content analysis revealed that constraint verification and causal explanation concentrated in the reasoning agent. The optimization traces serve as auditable logs, offering a path toward transparent automated planning.</description><author>Humza Nusrat, Luke Francisco, Bing Luo, Hassan Bagher-Ebadian, Joshua Kim, Karen Chin-Snyder, Salim Siddiqui, Mira Shah, Eric Mellon, Mohammad Ghassemi, Anthony Doemer, Benjamin Movsas, Kundan Thind</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:32:17 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20586v1</guid></item><item><title>Relu and softplus neural nets as zero-sum turn-based games</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20582v1</link><description>We show that the output of a ReLU neural network can be interpreted as the value of a zero-sum, turn-based, stopping game, which we call the ReLU net game. The game runs in the direction opposite to that of the network, and the input of the network serves as the terminal reward of the game. In fact, evaluating the network is the same as running the Shapley-Bellman backward recursion for the value of the game. Using the expression of the value of the game as an expected total payoff with respect to the path measure induced by the transition probabilities and a pair of optimal policies, we derive a discrete Feynman-Kac-type path-integral formula for the network output. This game-theoretic representation can be used to derive bounds on the output from bounds on the input, leveraging the monotonicity of Shapley operators, and to verify robustness properties using policies as certificates. Moreover, training the neural network becomes an inverse game problem: given pairs of terminal rewards and corresponding values, one seeks transition probabilities and rewards of a game that reproduces them. Finally, we show that a similar approach applies to neural networks with Softplus activation functions, where the ReLU net game is replaced by its entropic regularization.</description><author>Stephane Gaubert, Yiannis Vlassopoulos</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:27:41 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20582v1</guid></item><item><title>Behavioral Machine Learning? Regularization and Forecast Bias</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2303.16158v4</link><description>Standard forecast efficiency tests interpret violations as evidence of behavioral bias. We show theoretically and empirically that rational forecasters using optimal regularization systematically violate these tests. Machine learning forecasts show near zero bias at one year horizon, but strong overreaction at two years, consistent with predictions from a model of regularization and measurement noise. We provide three complementary tests: experimental variation in regularization parameters, cross-sectional heterogeneity in firm signal quality, and quasi-experimental evidence from ML adoption around 2013. Technically trained analysts shift sharply toward overreaction post-2013. Our findings suggest reported violations may reflect statistical sophistication rather than cognitive failure.</description><author>Murray Z. Frank, Jing Gao, Keer Yang</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:23:14 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2303.16158v4</guid></item><item><title>Can LLMs Predict Their Own Failures? Self-Awareness via Internal Circuits</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20578v1</link><description>Large language models (LLMs) generate fluent and complex outputs but often fail to recognize their own mistakes and hallucinations. Existing approaches typically rely on external judges, multi-sample consistency, or text-based self-critique, which incur additional compute or correlate weakly with true correctness. We ask: can LLMs predict their own failures by inspecting internal states during inference? We introduce Gnosis, a lightweight self-awareness mechanism that enables frozen LLMs to perform intrinsic self-verification by decoding signals from hidden states and attention patterns. Gnosis passively observes internal traces, compresses them into fixed-budget descriptors, and predicts correctness with negligible inference cost, adding only ~5M parameters and operating independently of sequence length. Across math reasoning, open-domain question answering, and academic knowledge benchmarks, and over frozen backbones ranging from 1.7B to 20B parameters, Gnosis consistently outperforms strong internal baselines and large external judges in both accuracy and calibration. Moreover, it generalizes zero-shot to partial generations, enabling early detection of failing trajectories and compute-aware control. These results show that reliable correctness cues are intrinsic to generation process and can be extracted efficiently without external supervision.</description><author>Amirhosein Ghasemabadi, Di Niu</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:21:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20578v1</guid></item><item><title>Improving ML Training Data with Gold-Standard Quality Metrics</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20577v1</link><description>Hand-tagged training data is essential to many machine learning tasks. However, training data quality control has received little attention in the literature, despite data quality varying considerably with the tagging exercise. We propose methods to evaluate and enhance the quality of hand-tagged training data using statistical approaches to measure tagging consistency and agreement. We show that agreement metrics give more reliable results if recorded over multiple iterations of tagging, where declining variance in such recordings is an indicator of increasing data quality. We also show one way a tagging project can collect high-quality training data without requiring multiple tags for every work item, and that a tagger burn-in period may not be sufficient for minimizing tagger errors.</description><author>Leslie Barrett, Michael W. Sherman</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:21:24 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20577v1</guid></item><item><title>Performative Policy Gradient: Optimality in Performative Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20576v1</link><description>Post-deployment machine learning algorithms often influence the environments they act in, and thus shift the underlying dynamics that the standard reinforcement learning (RL) methods ignore. While designing optimal algorithms in this performative setting has recently been studied in supervised learning, the RL counterpart remains under-explored. In this paper, we prove the performative counterparts of the performance difference lemma and the policy gradient theorem in RL, and further introduce the Performative Policy Gradient algorithm (PePG). PePG is the first policy gradient algorithm designed to account for performativity in RL. Under softmax parametrisation, and also with and without entropy regularisation, we prove that PePG converges to performatively optimal policies, i.e. policies that remain optimal under the distribution shifts induced by themselves. Thus, PePG significantly extends the prior works in Performative RL that achieves performative stability but not optimality. Furthermore, our empirical analysis on standard performative RL environments validate that PePG outperforms standard policy gradient algorithms and the existing performative RL algorithms aiming for stability.</description><author>Debabrota Basu, Udvas Das, Brahim Driss, Uddalak Mukherjee</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:20:06 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20576v1</guid></item><item><title>Fail Fast, Win Big: Rethinking the Drafting Strategy in Speculative Decoding via Diffusion LLMs</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20573v1</link><description>Diffusion Large Language Models (dLLMs) offer fast, parallel token generation, but their standalone use is plagued by an inherent efficiency-quality tradeoff. We show that, if carefully applied, the attributes of dLLMs can actually be a strength for drafters in speculative decoding with autoregressive (AR) verifiers. Our core insight is that dLLM's speed from parallel decoding drastically lowers the risk of costly rejections, providing a practical mechanism to effectively realize the (elusive) lengthy drafts that lead to large speedups with speculative decoding. We present FailFast, a dLLM-based speculative decoding framework that realizes this approach by dynamically adapting its speculation length. It "fails fast" by spending minimal compute in hard-to-speculate regions to shrink speculation latency and "wins big" by aggressively extending draft lengths in easier regions to reduce verification latency (in many cases, speculating and accepting 70 tokens at a time!). Without any fine-tuning, FailFast delivers lossless acceleration of AR LLMs and achieves up to 4.9$\times$ speedup over vanilla decoding, 1.7$\times$ over the best naive dLLM drafter, and 1.4$\times$ over EAGLE-3 across diverse models and workloads. We open-source FailFast at https://github.com/ruipeterpan/failfast.</description><author>Rui Pan, Zhuofu Chen, Ravi Netravali</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:16:58 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20573v1</guid></item><item><title>Distilling to Hybrid Attention Models via KL-Guided Layer Selection</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20569v1</link><description>Distilling pretrained softmax attention Transformers into more efficient hybrid architectures that interleave softmax and linear attention layers is a promising approach for improving the inference efficiency of LLMs without requiring expensive pretraining from scratch. A critical factor in the conversion process is layer selection, i.e., deciding on which layers to convert to linear attention variants. This paper describes a simple and efficient recipe for layer selection that uses layer importance scores derived from a small amount of training on generic text data. Once the layers have been selected we use a recent pipeline for the distillation process itself \citep[RADLADS;][]{goldstein2025radlads}, which consists of attention weight transfer, hidden state alignment, KL-based distribution matching, followed by a small amount of finetuning. We find that this approach is more effective than existing approaches for layer selection, including heuristics that uniformly interleave linear attentions based on a fixed ratio, as well as more involved approaches that rely on specialized diagnostic datasets.</description><author>Yanhong Li, Songlin Yang, Shawn Tan, Mayank Mishra, Rameswar Panda, Jiawei Zhou, Yoon Kim</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:12:22 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20569v1</guid></item><item><title>Similarity Field Theory: A Mathematical Framework for Intelligence</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.18218v4</link><description>We posit that persisting and transforming similarity relations form the structural basis of any comprehensible dynamic system. This paper introduces Similarity Field Theory, a mathematical framework that formalizes the principles governing similarity values among entities and their evolution. We define: (1) a similarity field $S: U \times U \to [0,1]$ over a universe of entities $U$, satisfying reflexivity $S(E,E)=1$ and treated as a directed relational field (asymmetry and non-transitivity are allowed); (2) the evolution of a system through a sequence $Z_p=(X_p,S^{(p)})$ indexed by $p=0,1,2,\ldots$; (3) concepts $K$ as entities that induce fibers $F_α(K)={E\in U \mid S(E,K)\ge α}$, i.e., superlevel sets of the unary map $S_K(E):=S(E,K)$; and (4) a generative operator $G$ that produces new entities. Within this framework, we formalize a generative definition of intelligence: an operator $G$ is intelligent with respect to a concept $K$ if, given a system containing entities belonging to the fiber of $K$, it generates new entities that also belong to that fiber. Similarity Field Theory thus offers a foundational language for characterizing, comparing, and constructing intelligent systems. At a high level, this framework reframes intelligence and interpretability as geometric problems on similarity fields--preserving and composing level-set fibers--rather than purely statistical ones. We prove two theorems: (i) asymmetry blocks mutual inclusion; and (ii) stability implies either an anchor coordinate or asymptotic confinement to the target level (up to arbitrarily small tolerance). Together, these results constrain similarity-field evolution and motivate an interpretive lens that can be applied to large language models.</description><author>Kei-Sing Ng</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:09:51 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.18218v4</guid></item><item><title>LEAD: Minimizing Learner-Expert Asymmetry in End-to-End Driving</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20563v1</link><description>Simulators can generate virtually unlimited driving data, yet imitation learning policies in simulation still struggle to achieve robust closed-loop performance. Motivated by this gap, we empirically study how misalignment between privileged expert demonstrations and sensor-based student observations can limit the effectiveness of imitation learning. More precisely, experts have significantly higher visibility (e.g., ignoring occlusions) and far lower uncertainty (e.g., knowing other vehicles' actions), making them difficult to imitate reliably. Furthermore, navigational intent (i.e., the route to follow) is under-specified in student models at test time via only a single target point. We demonstrate that these asymmetries can measurably limit driving performance in CARLA and offer practical interventions to address them. After careful modifications to narrow the gaps between expert and student, our TransFuser v6 (TFv6) student policy achieves a new state of the art on all major publicly available CARLA closed-loop benchmarks, reaching 95 DS on Bench2Drive and more than doubling prior performances on Longest6~v2 and Town13. Additionally, by integrating perception supervision from our dataset into a shared sim-to-real pipeline, we show consistent gains on the NAVSIM and Waymo Vision-Based End-to-End driving benchmarks. Our code, data, and models are publicly available at https://github.com/autonomousvision/lead.</description><author>Long Nguyen, Micha Fauth, Bernhard Jaeger, Daniel Dauner, Maximilian Igl, Andreas Geiger, Kashyap Chitta</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:07:43 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20563v1</guid></item><item><title>Shallow Neural Networks Learn Low-Degree Spherical Polynomials with Learnable Channel Attention</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20562v1</link><description>We study the problem of learning a low-degree spherical polynomial of degree $\ell_0 = Θ(1) \ge 1$ defined on the unit sphere in $\RR^d$ by training an over-parameterized two-layer neural network (NN) with channel attention in this paper. Our main result is the significantly improved sample complexity for learning such low-degree polynomials. We show that, for any regression risk $\eps \in (0,1)$, a carefully designed two-layer NN with channel attention and finite width of $m \ge Θ({n^4 \log (2n/δ)}/{d^{2\ell_0}})$ trained by the vanilla gradient descent (GD) requires the lowest sample complexity of $n \asymp Θ(d^{\ell_0}/\eps)$ with probability $1-δ$ for every $δ\in (0,1)$, in contrast with the representative sample complexity $Θ\pth{d^{\ell_0} \max\set{\eps^{-2},\log d}}$, where $n$ is the training daata size. Moreover, such sample complexity is not improvable since the trained network renders a sharp rate of the nonparametric regression risk of the order $Θ(d^{\ell_0}/{n})$ with probability at least $1-δ$. On the other hand, the minimax optimal rate for the regression risk with a kernel of rank $Θ(d^{\ell_0})$ is $Θ(d^{\ell_0}/{n})$, so that the rate of the nonparametric regression risk of the network trained by GD is minimax optimal. The training of the two-layer NN with channel attention consists of two stages. In Stage 1, a provable learnable channel selection algorithm identifies the ground-truth channel number $\ell_0$ from the initial $L \ge \ell_0$ channels in the first-layer activation, with high probability. This learnable selection is achieved by an efficient one-step GD update on both layers, enabling feature learning for low-degree polynomial targets. In Stage 2, the second layer is trained by standard GD using the activation function with the selected channels.</description><author>Yingzhen Yang</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:05:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20562v1</guid></item><item><title>FlashVLM: Text-Guided Visual Token Selection for Large Multimodal Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20561v1</link><description>Large vision-language models (VLMs) typically process hundreds or thousands of visual tokens per image or video frame, incurring quadratic attention cost and substantial redundancy. Existing token reduction methods often ignore the textual query or rely on deep attention maps, whose instability under aggressive pruning leads to degraded semantic alignment. We propose FlashVLM, a text guided visual token selection framework that dynamically adapts visual inputs to the query. Instead of relying on noisy attention weights, FlashVLM computes an explicit cross modal similarity between projected image tokens and normalized text embeddings in the language model space. This extrinsic relevance is fused with intrinsic visual saliency using log domain weighting and temperature controlled sharpening. In addition, a diversity preserving partition retains a minimal yet representative set of background tokens to maintain global context. Under identical token budgets and evaluation protocols, FlashVLM achieves beyond lossless compression, slightly surpassing the unpruned baseline while pruning up to 77.8 percent of visual tokens on LLaVA 1.5, and maintaining 92.8 percent accuracy even under 94.4 percent compression. Extensive experiments on 14 image and video benchmarks demonstrate that FlashVLM delivers state of the art efficiency performance trade offs while maintaining strong robustness and generalization across mainstream VLMs.</description><author>Kaitong Cai, Jusheng Zhang, Jing Yang, Yijia Fan, Pengtao Xie, Jian Wang, Keze Wang</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:05:43 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20561v1</guid></item><item><title>Compute-in-Memory Implementation of State Space Models for Event Sequence Processing</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.13912v2</link><description>State space models (SSMs) have recently emerged as a powerful framework for long sequence processing, outperforming traditional methods on diverse benchmarks. Fundamentally, SSMs can generalize both recurrent and convolutional networks and have been shown to even capture key functions of biological systems. Here we report an approach to implement SSMs in energy-efficient compute-in-memory (CIM) hardware to achieve real-time, event-driven processing. Our work re-parameterizes the model to function with real-valued coefficients and shared decay constants, reducing the complexity of model mapping onto practical hardware systems. By leveraging device dynamics and diagonalized state transition parameters, the state evolution can be natively implemented in crossbar-based CIM systems combined with memristors exhibiting short-term memory effects. Through this algorithm and hardware co-design, we show the proposed system offers both high accuracy and high energy efficiency while supporting fully asynchronous processing for event-based vision and audio tasks.</description><author>Xiaoyu Zhang, Mingtao Hu, Sen Lu, Soohyeon Kim, Eric Yeu-Jer Lee, Yuyang Liu, Wei D. Lu</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:00:52 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.13912v2</guid></item><item><title>Learning to Reason in 4D: Dynamic Spatial Understanding for Vision Language Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20557v1</link><description>Vision-language models (VLM) excel at general understanding yet remain weak at dynamic spatial reasoning (DSR), i.e., reasoning about the evolvement of object geometry and relationship in 3D space over time, largely due to the scarcity of scalable 4D-aware training resources. To bridge this gap across aspects of dataset, benchmark and model, we introduce DSR Suite. First, we propose an automated pipeline that generates multiple-choice question-answer pairs from in-the-wild videos for DSR. By leveraging modern vision foundation models, the pipeline extracts rich geometric and motion information, including camera poses, local point clouds, object masks, orientations, and 3D trajectories. These geometric cues enable the construction of DSR-Train for learning and further human-refined DSR-Bench for evaluation. Compared with previous works, our data emphasize (i) in-the-wild video sources, (ii) object- and scene-level 3D requirements, (iii) viewpoint transformations, (iv) multi-object interactions, and (v) fine-grained, procedural answers. Beyond data, we propose a lightweight Geometry Selection Module (GSM) to seamlessly integrate geometric priors into VLMs, which condenses question semantics and extracts question-relevant knowledge from pretrained 4D reconstruction priors into a compact set of geometry tokens. This targeted extraction avoids overwhelming the model with irrelevant knowledge. Experiments show that integrating DSR-Train and GSM into Qwen2.5-VL-7B significantly enhances its dynamic spatial reasoning capability, while maintaining accuracy on general video understanding benchmarks.</description><author>Shengchao Zhou, Yuxin Chen, Yuying Ge, Wei Huang, Jiehong Lin, Ying Shan, Xiaojuan Qi</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:56:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20557v1</guid></item><item><title>Multi-Grained Text-Guided Image Fusion for Multi-Exposure and Multi-Focus Scenarios</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20556v1</link><description>Image fusion aims to synthesize a single high-quality image from a pair of inputs captured under challenging conditions, such as differing exposure levels or focal depths. A core challenge lies in effectively handling disparities in dynamic range and focus depth between the inputs. With the advent of vision-language models, recent methods incorporate textual descriptions as auxiliary guidance to enhance fusion quality. However, simply incorporating coarse-grained descriptions hampers the understanding of fine-grained details and poses challenges for precise cross-modal alignment. To address these limitations, we propose Multi-grained Text-guided Image Fusion (MTIF), a novel fusion paradigm with three key designs. First, it introduces multi-grained textual descriptions that separately capture fine details, structural cues, and semantic content, guiding image fusion through a hierarchical cross-modal modulation module. Second, it involves supervision signals at each granularity to facilitate alignment between visual and textual features and enhance the utility of auxiliary text. Third, it adopts a saliency-driven enrichment module to augment training data with dense semantic content, further strengthening the cross-modal modulation and alignment. Extensive experiments show that MTIF consistently outperforms previous methods on both multi-exposure and multi-focus image fusion tasks.</description><author>Mingwei Tang, Jiahao Nie, Guang Yang, Ziqing Cui, Jie Li</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:55:35 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20556v1</guid></item><item><title>Information-theoretic signatures of causality in Bayesian networks and hypergraphs</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20552v1</link><description>Analyzing causality in multivariate systems involves establishing how information is generated, distributed and combined, and thus requires tools that capture interactions beyond pairwise relations. Higher-order information theory provides such tools. In particular, Partial Information Decomposition (PID) allows the decomposition of the information that a set of sources provides about a target into redundant, unique, and synergistic components. Yet the mathematical connection between such higher-order information-theoretic measures and causal structure remains undeveloped. Here we establish the first theoretical correspondence between PID components and causal structure in both Bayesian networks and hypergraphs. We first show that in Bayesian networks unique information precisely characterizes direct causal neighbors, while synergy identifies collider relationships. This establishes a localist causal discovery paradigm in which the structure surrounding each variable can be recovered from its immediate informational footprint, eliminating the need for global search over graph space. Extending these results to higher-order systems, we prove that PID signatures in Bayesian hypergraphs differentiate parents, children, co-heads, and co-tails, revealing a higher-order collider effect unique to multi-tail hyperedges. We also present procedures by which our results can be used to characterize systematically the causal structure of Bayesian networks and hypergraphs. Our results position PID as a rigorous, model-agnostic foundation for inferring both pairwise and higher-order causal structure, and introduce a fundamentally local information-theoretic viewpoint on causal discovery.</description><author>Sung En Chiang, Zhaolu Liu, Robert L. Peach, Mauricio Barahona</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:46:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20552v1</guid></item><item><title>Resolution scaling governs DINOv3 transfer performance in chest radiograph classification</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.07191v2</link><description>Self-supervised learning (SSL) has advanced visual representation learning, but its value in chest radiography, a high-volume imaging modality with fine-grained findings, remains unclear. Meta's DINOv3 extends earlier SSL models through Gram-anchored self-distillation. Whether these design choices improve transfer learning for chest radiography has not been systematically tested. We benchmarked DINOv3 against DINOv2 and ImageNet initialization across seven datasets (n&gt;814,000). Two representative backbones were evaluated: ViT-B/16 and ConvNeXt-B. Images were analyzed at 224x224, 512x512, and 1024x1024 pixels. We additionally assessed frozen features from a 7B model. The primary outcome was mean AUROC across labels. At 224x224, DINOv3 and DINOv2 achieved comparable performance on adult datasets. Increasing resolution to 512x512 yielded consistent improvements for DINOv3 over both DINOv2 and ImageNet. In contrast, results in pediatric cohort showed no differences across initializations. Across all settings, ConvNeXt-B outperformed ViT-B/16. Models using frozen DINOv3-7B features underperformed relative to fully finetuned 86-89M-parameter backbones, highlighting the importance of domain adaptation. Scaling to 1024x1024 did not further improve accuracy. Resolution-related gains were most evident for boundary-dependent and small focal abnormalities. In chest radiography, higher input resolution is critical for leveraging the benefits of modern self-supervised models. 512x512 pixels represent a practical upper limit where DINOv3-initialized ConvNeXt-B networks provide the strongest performance, while larger inputs offer minimal return on cost. Clinically, these findings support use of finetuned, mid-sized backbones at 512x512 for chest radiograph interpretation, with the greatest gains expected in detecting subtle or boundary-centered lesions relevant to emergency and critical care settings.</description><author>Soroosh Tayebi Arasteh, Mina Shaigan, Christiane Kuhl, Jakob Nikolas Kather, Sven Nebelung, Daniel Truhn</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:45:29 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.07191v2</guid></item><item><title>Advancing Multimodal Teacher Sentiment Analysis:The Large-Scale T-MED Dataset &amp; The Effective AAM-TSA Model</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20548v1</link><description>Teachers' emotional states are critical in educational scenarios, profoundly impacting teaching efficacy, student engagement, and learning achievements. However, existing studies often fail to accurately capture teachers' emotions due to the performative nature and overlook the critical impact of instructional information on emotional expression.In this paper, we systematically investigate teacher sentiment analysis by building both the dataset and the model accordingly. We construct the first large-scale teacher multimodal sentiment analysis dataset, T-MED.To ensure labeling accuracy and efficiency, we employ a human-machine collaborative labeling process.The T-MED dataset includes 14,938 instances of teacher emotional data from 250 real classrooms across 11 subjects ranging from K-12 to higher education, integrating multimodal text, audio, video, and instructional information.Furthermore, we propose a novel asymmetric attention-based multimodal teacher sentiment analysis model, AAM-TSA.AAM-TSA introduces an asymmetric attention mechanism and hierarchical gating unit to enable differentiated cross-modal feature fusion and precise emotional classification. Experimental results demonstrate that AAM-TSA significantly outperforms existing state-of-the-art methods in terms of accuracy and interpretability on the T-MED dataset.</description><author>Zhiyi Duan, Xiangren Wang, Hongyu Yuan, Qianli Xing</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:42:16 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20548v1</guid></item><item><title>Seedance 1.5 pro: A Native Audio-Visual Joint Generation Foundation Model</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.13507v3</link><description>Recent strides in video generation have paved the way for unified audio-visual generation. In this work, we present Seedance 1.5 pro, a foundational model engineered specifically for native, joint audio-video generation. Leveraging a dual-branch Diffusion Transformer architecture, the model integrates a cross-modal joint module with a specialized multi-stage data pipeline, achieving exceptional audio-visual synchronization and superior generation quality. To ensure practical utility, we implement meticulous post-training optimizations, including Supervised Fine-Tuning (SFT) on high-quality datasets and Reinforcement Learning from Human Feedback (RLHF) with multi-dimensional reward models. Furthermore, we introduce an acceleration framework that boosts inference speed by over 10X. Seedance 1.5 pro distinguishes itself through precise multilingual and dialect lip-syncing, dynamic cinematic camera control, and enhanced narrative coherence, positioning it as a robust engine for professional-grade content creation. Seedance 1.5 pro is now accessible on Volcano Engine at https://console.volcengine.com/ark/region:ark+cn-beijing/experience/vision?type=GenVideo.</description><author>Team Seedance, Heyi Chen, Siyan Chen, Xin Chen, Yanfei Chen, Ying Chen, Zhuo Chen, Feng Cheng, Tianheng Cheng, Xinqi Cheng, Xuyan Chi, Jian Cong, Jing Cui, Qinpeng Cui, Qide Dong, Junliang Fan, Jing Fang, Zetao Fang, Chengjian Feng, Han Feng, Mingyuan Gao, Yu Gao, Dong Guo, Qiushan Guo, Boyang Hao, Qingkai Hao, Bibo He, Qian He, Tuyen Hoang, Ruoqing Hu, Xi Hu, Weilin Huang, Zhaoyang Huang, Zhongyi Huang, Donglei Ji, Siqi Jiang, Wei Jiang, Yunpu Jiang, Zhuo Jiang, Ashley Kim, Jianan Kong, Zhichao Lai, Shanshan Lao, Yichong Leng, Ai Li, Feiya Li, Gen Li, Huixia Li, JiaShi Li, Liang Li, Ming Li, Shanshan Li, Tao Li, Xian Li, Xiaojie Li, Xiaoyang Li, Xingxing Li, Yameng Li, Yifu Li, Yiying Li, Chao Liang, Han Liang, Jianzhong Liang, Ying Liang, Zhiqiang Liang, Wang Liao, Yalin Liao, Heng Lin, </author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:38:46 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.13507v3</guid></item><item><title>AlignPose: Generalizable 6D Pose Estimation via Multi-view Feature-metric Alignment</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20538v1</link><description>Single-view RGB model-based object pose estimation methods achieve strong generalization but are fundamentally limited by depth ambiguity, clutter, and occlusions. Multi-view pose estimation methods have the potential to solve these issues, but existing works rely on precise single-view pose estimates or lack generalization to unseen objects. We address these challenges via the following three contributions. First, we introduce AlignPose, a 6D object pose estimation method that aggregates information from multiple extrinsically calibrated RGB views and does not require any object-specific training or symmetry annotation. Second, the key component of this approach is a new multi-view feature-metric refinement specifically designed for object pose. It optimizes a single, consistent world-frame object pose minimizing the feature discrepancy between on-the-fly rendered object features and observed image features across all views simultaneously. Third, we report extensive experiments on four datasets (YCB-V, T-LESS, ITODD-MV, HouseCat6D) using the BOP benchmark evaluation and show that AlignPose outperforms other published methods, especially on challenging industrial datasets where multiple views are readily available in practice.</description><author>Anna Šárová Mikeštíková, Médéric Fourmy, Martin Cífka, Josef Sivic, Vladimir Petrik</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:29:08 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20538v1</guid></item><item><title>Over-the-Air Goal-Oriented Communications</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20533v1</link><description>Goal-oriented communications offer an attractive alternative to the Shannon-based communication paradigm, where the data is never reconstructed at the Receiver (RX) side. Rather, focusing on the case of edge inference, the Transmitter (TX) and the RX cooperate to exchange features of the input data that will be used to predict an unseen attribute of them, leveraging information from collected data sets. This chapter demonstrates that the wireless channel can be used to perform computations over the data, when equipped with programmable metasurfaces. The end-to-end system of the TX, RX, and MS-based channel is treated as a single deep neural network which is trained through backpropagation to perform inference on unseen data. Using Stacked Intelligent Metasurfaces (SIM), it is shown that this Metasurfaces-Integrated Neural Network (MINN) can achieve performance comparable to fully digital neural networks under various system parameters and data sets. By offloading computations onto the channel itself, important benefits may be achieved in terms of energy consumption, arising from reduced computations at the transceivers and smaller transmission power required for successful inference.</description><author>Kyriakos Stylianopoulos, Paolo Di Lorenzo, George C. Alexandropoulos</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:24:39 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20533v1</guid></item><item><title>SirenPose: Dynamic Scene Reconstruction via Geometric Supervision</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20531v1</link><description>We introduce SirenPose, a geometry-aware loss formulation that integrates the periodic activation properties of sinusoidal representation networks with keypoint-based geometric supervision, enabling accurate and temporally consistent reconstruction of dynamic 3D scenes from monocular videos. Existing approaches often struggle with motion fidelity and spatiotemporal coherence in challenging settings involving fast motion, multi-object interaction, occlusion, and rapid scene changes. SirenPose incorporates physics inspired constraints to enforce coherent keypoint predictions across both spatial and temporal dimensions, while leveraging high frequency signal modeling to capture fine grained geometric details. We further expand the UniKPT dataset to 600,000 annotated instances and integrate graph neural networks to model keypoint relationships and structural correlations. Extensive experiments on benchmarks including Sintel, Bonn, and DAVIS demonstrate that SirenPose consistently outperforms state-of-the-art methods. On DAVIS, SirenPose achieves a 17.8 percent reduction in FVD, a 28.7 percent reduction in FID, and a 6.0 percent improvement in LPIPS compared to MoSCA. It also improves temporal consistency, geometric accuracy, user score, and motion smoothness. In pose estimation, SirenPose outperforms Monst3R with lower absolute trajectory error as well as reduced translational and rotational relative pose error, highlighting its effectiveness in handling rapid motion, complex dynamics, and physically plausible reconstruction.</description><author>Kaitong Cai, Jensen Zhang, Jing Yang, Keze Wang</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:23:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20531v1</guid></item><item><title>ScoreMatchingRiesz: Auto-DML with Infinitesimal Classification</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20523v1</link><description>This study proposes Riesz representer estimation methods based on score matching. The Riesz representer is a key component in debiased machine learning for constructing $\sqrt{n}$-consistent and efficient estimators in causal inference and structural parameter estimation. To estimate the Riesz representer, direct approaches have garnered attention, such as Riesz regression and the covariate balancing propensity score. These approaches can also be interpreted as variants of direct density ratio estimation (DRE) in several applications such as average treatment effect estimation. In DRE, it is well known that flexible models can easily overfit the observed data due to the estimand and the form of the loss function. To address this issue, recent work has proposed modeling the density ratio as a product of multiple intermediate density ratios and estimating it using score-matching techniques, which are often used in the diffusion model literature. We extend score-matching-based DRE methods to Riesz representer estimation. Our proposed method not only mitigates overfitting but also provides insights for causal inference by bridging marginal effects and average policy effects through time score functions.</description><author>Masahiro Kato</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:14:14 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20523v1</guid></item><item><title>Benchmarking LLMs for Predictive Applications in the Intensive Care Units</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20520v1</link><description>With the advent of LLMs, various tasks across the natural language processing domain have been transformed. However, their application in predictive tasks remains less researched. This study compares large language models, including GatorTron-Base (trained on clinical data), Llama 8B, and Mistral 7B, against models like BioBERT, DocBERT, BioClinicalBERT, Word2Vec, and Doc2Vec, setting benchmarks for predicting Shock in critically ill patients. Timely prediction of shock can enable early interventions, thus improving patient outcomes. Text data from 17,294 ICU stays of patients in the MIMIC III database were scored for length of stay &gt; 24 hours and shock index (SI) &gt; 0.7 to yield 355 and 87 patients with normal and abnormal SI-index, respectively. Both focal and cross-entropy losses were used during finetuning to address class imbalances. Our findings indicate that while GatorTron Base achieved the highest weighted recall of 80.5%, the overall performance metrics were comparable between SLMs and LLMs. This suggests that LLMs are not inherently superior to SLMs in predicting future clinical events despite their strong performance on text-based tasks. To achieve meaningful clinical outcomes, future efforts in training LLMs should prioritize developing models capable of predicting clinical trajectories rather than focusing on simpler tasks such as named entity recognition or phenotyping.</description><author>Chehak Malhotra, Mehak Gopal, Akshaya Devadiga, Pradeep Singh, Ridam Pal, Ritwik Kashyap, Tavpritesh Sethi</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:08:31 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20520v1</guid></item><item><title>Deep Reinforcement Learning Optimization for Uncertain Nonlinear Systems via Event-Triggered Robust Adaptive Dynamic Programming</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.15735v3</link><description>This work proposes a unified control architecture that couples a Reinforcement Learning (RL)-driven controller with a disturbance-rejection Extended State Observer (ESO), complemented by an Event-Triggered Mechanism (ETM) to limit unnecessary computations. The ESO is utilized to estimate the system states and the lumped disturbance in real time, forming the foundation for effective disturbance compensation. To obtain near-optimal behavior without an accurate system description, a value-iteration-based Adaptive Dynamic Programming (ADP) method is adopted for policy approximation. The inclusion of the ETM ensures that parameter updates of the learning module are executed only when the state deviation surpasses a predefined bound, thereby preventing excessive learning activity and substantially reducing computational load. A Lyapunov-oriented analysis is used to characterize the stability properties of the resulting closed-loop system. Numerical experiments further confirm that the developed approach maintains strong control performance and disturbance tolerance, while achieving a significant reduction in sampling and processing effort compared with standard time-triggered ADP schemes.</description><author>Ningwei Bai, Chi Pui Chan, Qichen Yin, Tengyang Gong, Yunda Yan, Zezhi Tang</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:06:16 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.15735v3</guid></item><item><title>Explainable time-series forecasting with sampling-free SHAP for Transformers</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20514v1</link><description>Time-series forecasts are essential for planning and decision-making in many domains. Explainability is key to building user trust and meeting transparency requirements. Shapley Additive Explanations (SHAP) is a popular explainable AI framework, but it lacks efficient implementations for time series and often assumes feature independence when sampling counterfactuals. We introduce SHAPformer, an accurate, fast and sampling-free explainable time-series forecasting model based on the Transformer architecture. It leverages attention manipulation to make predictions based on feature subsets. SHAPformer generates explanations in under one second, several orders of magnitude faster than the SHAP Permutation Explainer. On synthetic data with ground truth explanations, SHAPformer provides explanations that are true to the data. Applied to real-world electrical load data, it achieves competitive predictive performance and delivers meaningful local and global insights, such as identifying the past load as the key predictor and revealing a distinct model behavior during the Christmas period.</description><author>Matthias Hertel, Sebastian Pütz, Ralf Mikut, Veit Hagenmeyer, Benjamin Schäfer</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:02:35 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20514v1</guid></item><item><title>Recurrent Off-Policy Deep Reinforcement Learning Doesn't Have to be Slow</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20513v1</link><description>Recurrent off-policy deep reinforcement learning models achieve state-of-the-art performance but are often sidelined due to their high computational demands. In response, we introduce RISE (Recurrent Integration via Simplified Encodings), a novel approach that can leverage recurrent networks in any image-based off-policy RL setting without significant computational overheads via using both learnable and non-learnable encoder layers. When integrating RISE into leading non-recurrent off-policy RL algorithms, we observe a 35.6% human-normalized interquartile mean (IQM) performance improvement across the Atari benchmark. We analyze various implementation strategies to highlight the versatility and potential of our proposed framework.</description><author>Tyler Clark, Christine Evers, Jonathon Hare</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:02:17 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20513v1</guid></item><item><title>Memorize-and-Generate: Towards Long-Term Consistency in Real-Time Video Generation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.18741v2</link><description>Frame-level autoregressive (frame-AR) models have achieved significant progress, enabling real-time video generation comparable to bidirectional diffusion models and serving as a foundation for interactive world models and game engines. However, current approaches in long video generation typically rely on window attention, which naively discards historical context outside the window, leading to catastrophic forgetting and scene inconsistency; conversely, retaining full history incurs prohibitive memory costs. To address this trade-off, we propose Memorize-and-Generate (MAG), a framework that decouples memory compression and frame generation into distinct tasks. Specifically, we train a memory model to compress historical information into a compact KV cache, and a separate generator model to synthesize subsequent frames utilizing this compressed representation. Furthermore, we introduce MAG-Bench to strictly evaluate historical memory retention. Extensive experiments demonstrate that MAG achieves superior historical scene consistency while maintaining competitive performance on standard video generation benchmarks.</description><author>Tianrui Zhu, Shiyi Zhang, Zhirui Sun, Jingqi Tian, Yansong Tang</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:47:46 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.18741v2</guid></item><item><title>Bridging Modalities and Transferring Knowledge: Enhanced Multimodal Understanding and Recognition</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20501v1</link><description>This manuscript explores multimodal alignment, translation, fusion, and transference to enhance machine understanding of complex inputs. We organize the work into five chapters, each addressing unique challenges in multimodal machine learning. Chapter 3 introduces Spatial-Reasoning Bert for translating text-based spatial relations into 2D arrangements between clip-arts. This enables effective decoding of spatial language into visual representations, paving the way for automated scene generation aligned with human spatial understanding. Chapter 4 presents a method for translating medical texts into specific 3D locations within an anatomical atlas. We introduce a loss function leveraging spatial co-occurrences of medical terms to create interpretable mappings, significantly enhancing medical text navigability. Chapter 5 tackles translating structured text into canonical facts within knowledge graphs. We develop a benchmark for linking natural language to entities and predicates, addressing ambiguities in text extraction to provide clearer, actionable insights. Chapter 6 explores multimodal fusion methods for compositional action recognition. We propose a method fusing video frames and object detection representations, improving recognition robustness and accuracy. Chapter 7 investigates multimodal knowledge transference for egocentric action recognition. We demonstrate how multimodal knowledge distillation enables RGB-only models to mimic multimodal fusion-based capabilities, reducing computational requirements while maintaining performance. These contributions advance methodologies for spatial language understanding, medical text interpretation, knowledge graph enrichment, and action recognition, enhancing computational systems' ability to process complex, multimodal inputs across diverse applications.</description><author>Gorjan Radevski</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:46:58 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20501v1</guid></item><item><title>Deep Research Comparator: A Platform For Fine-grained Human Annotations of Deep Research Agents</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.05495v2</link><description>Effectively evaluating deep research agents that autonomously search the web, analyze information, and generate reports remains a major challenge, particularly when it comes to assessing long reports and giving detailed feedback on their intermediate steps. To address these gaps, we introduce Deep Research Comparator, a platform that offers a holistic framework for deep research agent hosting, side-by-side comparison, fine-grained human feedback collection, and ranking calculation. Given a user query, our platform displays the final reports from two different agents along with their intermediate steps during generation. Annotators can evaluate the overall quality of final reports based on side-by-side comparison, and also provide detailed feedback separately by assessing intermediate steps or specific text spans within the final report. Furthermore, we develop Simple Deepresearch, an end-to-end agent scaffold. This scaffold serves as a baseline that facilitates the easy integration of various large language models to transform them into deep research agents for evaluation. To demonstrate the platform's utility for deep research agent development, we have collected real user preference data from 17 annotators on three deep research agents. A demo video of our platform can be found at https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g4d2dnbdseg.</description><author>Prahaladh Chandrahasan, Jiahe Jin, Zhihan Zhang, Tevin Wang, Andy Tang, Lucy Mo, Morteza Ziyadi, Leonardo F. R. Ribeiro, Zimeng Qiu, Markus Dreyer, Akari Asai, Chenyan Xiong</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:43:12 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.05495v2</guid></item><item><title>Step-DeepResearch Technical Report</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20491v1</link><description>As LLMs shift toward autonomous agents, Deep Research has emerged as a pivotal metric. However, existing academic benchmarks like BrowseComp often fail to meet real-world demands for open-ended research, which requires robust skills in intent recognition, long-horizon decision-making, and cross-source verification. To address this, we introduce Step-DeepResearch, a cost-effective, end-to-end agent. We propose a Data Synthesis Strategy Based on Atomic Capabilities to reinforce planning and report writing, combined with a progressive training path from agentic mid-training to SFT and RL. Enhanced by a Checklist-style Judger, this approach significantly improves robustness. Furthermore, to bridge the evaluation gap in the Chinese domain, we establish ADR-Bench for realistic deep research scenarios. Experimental results show that Step-DeepResearch (32B) scores 61.4% on Scale AI Research Rubrics. On ADR-Bench, it significantly outperforms comparable models and rivals SOTA closed-source models like OpenAI and Gemini DeepResearch. These findings prove that refined training enables medium-sized models to achieve expert-level capabilities at industry-leading cost-efficiency.</description><author>Chen Hu, Haikuo Du, Heng Wang, Lin Lin, Mingrui Chen, Peng Liu, Ruihang Miao, Tianchi Yue, Wang You, Wei Ji, Wei Yuan, Wenjin Deng, Xiaojian Yuan, Xiaoyun Zhang, Xiangyu Liu, Xikai Liu, Yanming Xu, Yicheng Cao, Yifei Zhang, Yongyao Wang, Yubo Shu, Yurong Zhang, Yuxiang Zhang, Zheng Gong, Zhichao Chang, Binyan Li, Dan Ma, Furong Jia, Hongyuan Wang, Jiayu Liu, Jing Bai, Junlan Liu, Manjiao Liu, Na Wang, Qiuping Wu, Qinxin Du, Shiwei Li, Wen Sun, Yifeng Gong, Yonglin Chen, Yuling Zhao, Yuxuan Lin, Ziqi Ren, Zixuan Wang, Aihu Zhang, Brian Li, Buyun Ma, Kang An, Li Xie, Mingliang Li, Pan Li, Shidong Yang, Xi Chen, Xiaojia Liu, Yuchu Luo, Yuan Song, YuanHao Ding, Yuanwei Liang, Zexi Li, Zhaoning Zhang, Zixin Zhang, Binxing Jiao, Daxin Jiang, Jiansheng Chen, Jing Li, Xiangyu Zhang, Yibo Zhu</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:32:27 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20491v1</guid></item><item><title>Spectral Bottleneck in Sinusoidal Representation Networks: Noise is All You Need</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.09719v2</link><description>This work identifies and attempts to address a fundamental limitation of implicit neural representations with sinusoidal activation. The fitting error of SIRENs is highly sensitive to the target frequency content and to the choice of initialization. In extreme cases, this sensitivity leads to a spectral bottleneck that can result in a zero-valued output. This phenomenon is characterized by analyzing the evolution of activation spectra and the empirical neural tangent kernel (NTK) during the training process. An unfavorable distribution of energy across frequency modes was noted to give rise to this failure mode. Furthermore, the effect of Gaussian perturbations applied to the baseline uniformly initialized weights is examined, showing how these perturbations influence activation spectra and the NTK eigenbasis of SIREN. Overall, initialization emerges as a central factor governing the evolution of SIRENs, indicating the need for adaptive, target-aware strategies as the target length increases and fine-scale detail becomes essential. The proposed weight initialization scheme (WINNER) represents a simple ad hoc step in this direction and demonstrates that fitting accuracy can be significantly improved by modifying the spectral profile of network activations through a target-aware initialization. The approach achieves state-of-the-art performance on audio fitting tasks and yields notable improvements in image fitting tasks.</description><author>Hemanth Chandravamsi, Dhanush V. Shenoy, Itay Zinn, Ziv Chen, Shimon Pisnoy, Steven H. Frankel</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:32:05 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.09719v2</guid></item><item><title>Multi-temporal Adaptive Red-Green-Blue and Long-Wave Infrared Fusion for You Only Look Once-Based Landmine Detection from Unmanned Aerial Systems</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20487v1</link><description>Landmines remain a persistent humanitarian threat, with 110 million actively deployed mines across 60 countries, claiming 26,000 casualties annually. This research evaluates adaptive Red-Green-Blue (RGB) and Long-Wave Infrared (LWIR) fusion for Unmanned Aerial Systems (UAS)-based detection of surface-laid landmines, leveraging the thermal contrast between the ordnance and the surrounding soil to enhance feature extraction. Using You Only Look Once (YOLO) architectures (v8, v10, v11) across 114 test images, generating 35,640 model-condition evaluations, YOLOv11 achieved optimal performance (86.8% mAP), with 10 to 30% thermal fusion at 5 to 10m altitude identified as the optimal detection parameters. A complementary architectural comparison revealed that while RF-DETR achieved the highest accuracy (69.2% mAP), followed by Faster R-CNN (67.6%), YOLOv11 (64.2%), and RetinaNet (50.2%), YOLOv11 trained 17.7 times faster than the transformer-based RF-DETR (41 minutes versus 12 hours), presenting a critical accuracy-efficiency tradeoff for operational deployment. Aggregated multi-temporal training datasets outperformed season-specific approaches by 1.8 to 9.6%, suggesting that models benefit from exposure to diverse thermal conditions. Anti-Tank (AT) mines achieved 61.9% detection accuracy, compared with 19.2% for Anti-Personnel (AP) mines, reflecting both the size differential and thermal-mass differences between these ordnance classes. As this research examined surface-laid mines where thermal contrast is maximized, future research should quantify thermal contrast effects for mines buried at varying depths across heterogeneous soil types.</description><author>James E. Gallagher, Edward J. Oughton, Jana Kosecka</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:26:47 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20487v1</guid></item><item><title>Toward Storage-Aware Learning with Compressed Data An Empirical Exploratory Study on JPEG</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.12833v2</link><description>On-device machine learning is often constrained by limited storage, particularly in continuous data collection scenarios. This paper presents an empirical study on storage-aware learning, focusing on the trade-off between data quantity and quality via compression. We demonstrate that naive strategies, such as uniform data dropping or one-size-fits-all compression, are suboptimal. Our findings further reveal that data samples exhibit varying sensitivities to compression, supporting the feasibility of a sample-wise adaptive compression strategy. These insights provide a foundation for developing a new class of storage-aware learning systems. The primary contribution of this work is the systematic characterization of this under-explored challenge, offering valuable insights that advance the understanding of storage-aware learning.</description><author>Kichang Lee, Songkuk Kim, JaeYeon Park, JeongGil Ko</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:25:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.12833v2</guid></item><item><title>Improving Local Training in Federated Learning via Temperature Scaling</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09986v3</link><description>Federated learning is inherently hampered by data heterogeneity: non-i.i.d. training data over local clients. We propose a novel model training approach for federated learning, FLex&amp;Chill, which exploits the Logit Chilling method. Through extensive evaluations, we demonstrate that, in the presence of non-i.i.d. data characteristics inherent in federated learning systems, this approach can expedite model convergence and improve inference accuracy. Quantitatively, from our experiments, we observe up to 6X improvement in the global federated learning model convergence time, and up to 3.37% improvement in inference accuracy.</description><author>Kichang Lee, Pei Zhang, Songkuk Kim, JeongGil Ko</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:22:09 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09986v3</guid></item><item><title>mLaSDI: Multi-stage latent space dynamics identification</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.09207v3</link><description>Accurately solving partial differential equations (PDEs) is essential across many scientific disciplines. However, high-fidelity solvers can be computationally prohibitive, motivating the development of reduced-order models (ROMs). Recently, Latent Space Dynamics Identification (LaSDI) was proposed as a data-driven, non-intrusive ROM framework. LaSDI compresses the training data via an autoencoder and learns user-specified ordinary differential equations (ODEs), governing the latent dynamics, enabling rapid predictions for unseen parameters. While LaSDI has produced effective ROMs for numerous problems, the autoencoder must simultaneously reconstruct the training data and satisfy the imposed latent dynamics, which are often competing objectives that limit accuracy, particularly for complex or high-frequency phenomena. To address this limitation, we propose multi-stage Latent Space Dynamics Identification (mLaSDI). With mLaSDI, we train LaSDI sequentially in stages. After training the initial autoencoder, we train additional decoders which map the latent trajectories to residuals from previous stages. This staged residual learning, combined with periodic activation functions, enables recovery of high-frequency content without sacrificing interpretability of the latent dynamics. Numerical experiments on a multiscale oscillating system, unsteady wake flow, and the 1D-1V Vlasov equation demonstrate that mLaSDI achieves significantly lower reconstruction and prediction errors, often by an order of magnitude, while requiring less training time and reduced hyperparameter tuning compared to standard LaSDI.</description><author>William Anderson, Seung Whan Chung, Robert Stephany, Youngsoo Choi</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:20:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.09207v3</guid></item><item><title>SweRank+: Multilingual, Multi-Turn Code Ranking for Software Issue Localization</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20482v1</link><description>Maintaining large-scale, multilingual codebases hinges on accurately localizing issues, which requires mapping natural-language error descriptions to the relevant functions that need to be modified. However, existing ranking approaches are often Python-centric and perform a single-pass search over the codebase. This work introduces SweRank+, a framework that couples SweRankMulti, a cross-lingual code ranking tool, with SweRankAgent, an agentic search setup, for iterative, multi-turn reasoning over the code repository. SweRankMulti comprises a code embedding retriever and a listwise LLM reranker, and is trained using a carefully curated large-scale issue localization dataset spanning multiple popular programming languages. SweRankAgent adopts an agentic search loop that moves beyond single-shot localization with a memory buffer to reason and accumulate relevant localization candidates over multiple turns. Our experiments on issue localization benchmarks spanning various languages demonstrate new state-of-the-art performance with SweRankMulti, while SweRankAgent further improves localization over single-pass ranking.</description><author>Revanth Gangi Reddy, Ye Liu, Wenting Zhao, JaeHyeok Doo, Tarun Suresh, Daniel Lee, Caiming Xiong, Yingbo Zhou, Semih Yavuz, Shafiq Joty</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:18:39 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20482v1</guid></item><item><title>Coherence in the brain unfolds across separable temporal regimes</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20481v1</link><description>Coherence in language requires the brain to satisfy two competing temporal demands: gradual accumulation of meaning across extended context and rapid reconfiguration of representations at event boundaries. Despite their centrality to language and thought, how these processes are implemented in the human brain during naturalistic listening remains unclear. Here, we tested whether these two processes can be captured by annotation-free drift and shift signals and whether their neural expression dissociates across large-scale cortical systems. These signals were derived from a large language model (LLM) and formalized contextual drift and event shifts directly from the narrative input. To enable high-precision voxelwise encoding models with stable parameter estimates, we densely sampled one healthy adult across more than 7 hours of listening to thirteen crime stories while collecting ultra high-field (7T) BOLD data. We then modeled the feature-informed hemodynamic response using a regularized encoding framework validated on independent stories. Drift predictions were prevalent in default-mode network hubs, whereas shift predictions were evident bilaterally in the primary auditory cortex and language association cortex. Furthermore, activity in default-mode and parietal networks was best explained by a signal capturing how meaning accumulates and gradually fades over the course of the narrative. Together, these findings show that coherence during language comprehension is implemented through dissociable neural regimes of slow contextual integration and rapid event-driven reconfiguration, offering a mechanistic entry point for understanding disturbances of language coherence in psychiatric disorders.</description><author>Davide Stauba, Finn Rabe, Akhil Misra, Yves Pauli, Roya Hüppi, Nils Lang, Lars Michels, Victoria Edkins, Sascha Frühholz, Iris Sommer, Wolfram Hinzen, Philipp Homan</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:16:42 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20481v1</guid></item><item><title>UTDesign: A Unified Framework for Stylized Text Editing and Generation in Graphic Design Images</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20479v1</link><description>AI-assisted graphic design has emerged as a powerful tool for automating the creation and editing of design elements such as posters, banners, and advertisements. While diffusion-based text-to-image models have demonstrated strong capabilities in visual content generation, their text rendering performance, particularly for small-scale typography and non-Latin scripts, remains limited. In this paper, we propose UTDesign, a unified framework for high-precision stylized text editing and conditional text generation in design images, supporting both English and Chinese scripts. Our framework introduces a novel DiT-based text style transfer model trained from scratch on a synthetic dataset, capable of generating transparent RGBA text foregrounds that preserve the style of reference glyphs. We further extend this model into a conditional text generation framework by training a multi-modal condition encoder on a curated dataset with detailed text annotations, enabling accurate, style-consistent text synthesis conditioned on background images, prompts, and layout specifications. Finally, we integrate our approach into a fully automated text-to-design (T2D) pipeline by incorporating pre-trained text-to-image (T2I) models and an MLLM-based layout planner. Extensive experiments demonstrate that UTDesign achieves state-of-the-art performance among open-source methods in terms of stylistic consistency and text accuracy, and also exhibits unique advantages compared to proprietary commercial approaches. Code and data for this paper are available at https://github.com/ZYM-PKU/UTDesign.</description><author>Yiming Zhao, Yuanpeng Gao, Yuxuan Luo, Jiwei Duan, Shisong Lin, Longfei Xiong, Zhouhui Lian</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:13:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20479v1</guid></item><item><title>Bohrium + SciMaster: Building the Infrastructure and Ecosystem for Agentic Science at Scale</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20469v1</link><description>AI agents are emerging as a practical way to run multi-step scientific workflows that interleave reasoning with tool use and verification, pointing to a shift from isolated AI-assisted steps toward \emph{agentic science at scale}. This shift is increasingly feasible, as scientific tools and models can be invoked through stable interfaces and verified with recorded execution traces, and increasingly necessary, as AI accelerates scientific output and stresses the peer-review and publication pipeline, raising the bar for traceability and credible evaluation. However, scaling agentic science remains difficult: workflows are hard to observe and reproduce; many tools and laboratory systems are not agent-ready; execution is hard to trace and govern; and prototype AI Scientist systems are often bespoke, limiting reuse and systematic improvement from real workflow signals. We argue that scaling agentic science requires an infrastructure-and-ecosystem approach, instantiated in Bohrium+SciMaster. Bohrium acts as a managed, traceable hub for AI4S assets -- akin to a HuggingFace of AI for Science -- that turns diverse scientific data, software, compute, and laboratory systems into agent-ready capabilities. SciMaster orchestrates these capabilities into long-horizon scientific workflows, on which scientific agents can be composed and executed. Between infrastructure and orchestration, a \emph{scientific intelligence substrate} organizes reusable models, knowledge, and components into executable building blocks for workflow reasoning and action, enabling composition, auditability, and improvement through use. We demonstrate this stack with eleven representative master agents in real workflows, achieving orders-of-magnitude reductions in end-to-end scientific cycle time and generating execution-grounded signals from real workloads at multi-million scale.</description><author>Linfeng Zhang, Siheng Chen, Yuzhu Cai, Jingyi Chai, Junhan Chang, Kun Chen, Zhi X. Chen, Zhaohan Ding, Yuwen Du, Yuanpeng Gao, Yuan Gao, Jing Gao, Zhifeng Gao, Qiangqiang Gu, Yanhui Hong, Yuan Huang, Xi Fang, Xiaohong Ji, Guolin Ke, Zixing Lei, Xinyu Li, Yongge Li, Ruoxue Liao, Hang Lin, Xiaolu Lin, Yuxiang Liu, Xinzijian Liu, Zexi Liu, Jintan Lu, Tingjia Miao, Haohui Que, Weijie Sun, Yanfeng Wang, Bingyang Wu, Tianju Xue, Rui Ye, Jinzhe Zeng, Duo Zhang, Jiahui Zhang, Linfeng Zhang, Tianhan Zhang, Wenchang Zhang, Yuzhi Zhang, Zezhong Zhang, Hang Zheng, Hui Zhou, Tong Zhu, Xinyu Zhu, Qingguo Zhou, Weinan E</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:04:41 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20469v1</guid></item><item><title>Snapshot 3D image projection using a diffractive decoder</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20464v1</link><description>3D image display is essential for next-generation volumetric imaging; however, dense depth multiplexing for 3D image projection remains challenging because diffraction-induced cross-talk rapidly increases as the axial image planes get closer. Here, we introduce a 3D display system comprising a digital encoder and a diffractive optical decoder, which simultaneously projects different images onto multiple target axial planes with high axial resolution. By leveraging multi-layer diffractive wavefront decoding and deep learning-based end-to-end optimization, the system achieves high-fidelity depth-resolved 3D image projection in a snapshot, enabling axial plane separations on the order of a wavelength. The digital encoder leverages a Fourier encoder network to capture multi-scale spatial and frequency-domain features from input images, integrates axial position encoding, and generates a unified phase representation that simultaneously encodes all images to be axially projected in a single snapshot through a jointly-optimized diffractive decoder. We characterized the impact of diffractive decoder depth, output diffraction efficiency, spatial light modulator resolution, and axial encoding density, revealing trade-offs that govern axial separation and 3D image projection quality. We further demonstrated the capability to display volumetric images containing 28 axial slices, as well as the ability to dynamically reconfigure the axial locations of the image planes, performed on demand. Finally, we experimentally validated the presented approach, demonstrating close agreement between the measured results and the target images. These results establish the diffractive 3D display system as a compact and scalable framework for depth-resolved snapshot 3D image projection, with potential applications in holographic displays, AR/VR interfaces, and volumetric optical computing.</description><author>Cagatay Isil, Alexander Chen, Yuhang Li, F. Onuralp Ardic, Shiqi Chen, Che-Yung Shen, Aydogan Ozcan</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:57:08 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20464v1</guid></item><item><title>The Aligned Economic Index &amp; The State Switching Model</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20460v1</link><description>A growing empirical literature suggests that equity-premium predictability is state dependent, with much of the forecasting power concentrated around recessionary periods \parencite{Henkel2011,DanglHalling2012,Devpura2018}. I study U.S. stock return predictability across economic regimes and document strong evidence of time-varying expected returns across both expansionary and contractionary states. I contribute in two ways. First, I introduce a state-switching predictive regression in which the market state is defined in real time using the slope of the yield curve. Relative to the standard one-state predictive regression, the state-switching specification increases both in-sample and out-of-sample performance for the set of popular predictors considered by \textcite{WelchGoyal2008}, improving the out-of-sample performance of most predictors in economically meaningful ways. Second, I propose a new aggregate predictor, the Aligned Economic Index, constructed via partial least squares (PLS). Under the state-switching model, the Aligned Economic Index exhibits statistically and economically significant predictive power in sample and out of sample, and it outperforms widely used benchmark predictors and alternative predictor-combination methods.</description><author>Ilias Aarab</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:55:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20460v1</guid></item><item><title>Explaining Tournament Solutions with Minimal Supports</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.09312v4</link><description>Tournaments are widely used models to represent pairwise dominance between candidates, alternatives, or teams. We study the problem of providing certified explanations for why a candidate appears among the winners under various tournament rules. To this end, we identify minimal supports, minimal sub-tournaments in which the candidate is guaranteed to win regardless of how the rest of the tournament is completed (that is, the candidate is a necessary winner of the sub-tournament). This notion corresponds to an abductive explanation for the question,"Why does the winner win the tournament?", a central concept in formal explainable AI. We focus on common tournament solutions: the top cycle, the uncovered set, the Copeland rule, the Borda rule, the maximin rule, and the weighted uncovered set. For each rule we determine the size of the smallest minimal supports, and we present polynomial-time algorithms to compute them for all solutions except for the weighted uncovered set, for which the problem is NP-complete. Finally, we show how minimal supports can serve to produce compact, certified, and intuitive explanations for tournament solutions.</description><author>Clément Contet, Umberto Grandi, Jérôme Mengin</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:52:27 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.09312v4</guid></item><item><title>Stochastic activations</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.22358v2</link><description>We introduce stochastic activations. This novel strategy randomly selects between several non-linear functions in the feed-forward layer of a large language model. In particular, we choose between SILU or RELU depending on a Bernoulli draw. This strategy circumvents the optimization problem associated with RELU, namely, the constant shape for negative inputs that prevents the gradient flow. We leverage this strategy in two ways: (1) We use stochastic activations during pre-training and fine-tune the model with RELU, which is used at inference time to provide sparse latent vectors. This reduces the inference FLOPs and translates into a significant speedup in the CPU. Interestingly, this leads to much better results than training from scratch with the RELU activation function. (2) We evaluate stochastic activations for generation. This strategy performs reasonably well: it is only slightly inferior to the best deterministic non-linearity, namely SILU combined with temperature scaling. This offers an alternative to existing strategies by providing a controlled way to increase the diversity of the generated text.</description><author>Maria Lomeli, Matthijs Douze, Gergely Szilvasy, Loic Cabannes, Jade Copet, Sainbayar Sukhbaatar, Jason Weston, Gabriel Synnaeve, Pierre-Emmanuel Mazaré, Hervé Jégou</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:51:07 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.22358v2</guid></item><item><title>Beyond Motion Pattern: An Empirical Study of Physical Forces for Human Motion Understanding</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20451v1</link><description>Human motion understanding has advanced rapidly through vision-based progress in recognition, tracking, and captioning. However, most existing methods overlook physical cues such as joint actuation forces that are fundamental in biomechanics. This gap motivates our study: if and when do physically inferred forces enhance motion understanding? By incorporating forces into established motion understanding pipelines, we systematically evaluate their impact across baseline models on 3 major tasks: gait recognition, action recognition, and fine-grained video captioning. Across 8 benchmarks, incorporating forces yields consistent performance gains; for example, on CASIA-B, Rank-1 gait recognition accuracy improved from 89.52% to 90.39% (+0.87), with larger gain observed under challenging conditions: +2.7% when wearing a coat and +3.0% at the side view. On Gait3D, performance also increases from 46.0% to 47.3% (+1.3). In action recognition, CTR-GCN achieved +2.00% on Penn Action, while high-exertion classes like punching/slapping improved by +6.96%. Even in video captioning, Qwen2.5-VL's ROUGE-L score rose from 0.310 to 0.339 (+0.029), indicating that physics-inferred forces enhance temporal grounding and semantic richness. These results demonstrate that force cues can substantially complement visual and kinematic features under dynamic, occluded, or appearance-varying conditions.</description><author>Anh Dao, Manh Tran, Yufei Zhang, Xiaoming Liu, Zijun Cui</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:43:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20451v1</guid></item><item><title>Binarization-Aware Adjuster for Discrete Decision Learning with an Application to Edge Detection</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.12460v3</link><description>Discrete decision tasks in machine learning exhibit a fundamental misalignment between training and inference: models are optimized with continuous-valued outputs but evaluated using discrete predictions. This misalignment arises from the discontinuity of discretization operations, which prevents decision behavior from being directly incorporated into gradient-based optimization. To address this issue, we propose a theoretically grounded framework termed the Binarization-Aware Adjuster (BAA), which embeds binarization characteristics into continuous optimization. The framework is built upon the Distance Weight Function (DWF), which modulates loss contributions according to prediction correctness and proximity to the decision threshold, thereby aligning optimization emphasis with decision-critical regions while remaining compatible with standard learning pipelines. We apply the proposed BAA framework to the edge detection (ED) task, a representative binary decision problem. Experimental results on representative models and datasets show that incorporating BAA into optimization leads to consistent performance improvements, supporting its effectiveness. Overall, this work establishes a principled approach for aligning continuous optimization with discrete decision behavior, with its effectiveness demonstrated in a concrete application setting.</description><author>Hao Shu</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:42:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.12460v3</guid></item><item><title>Machine Learning to Predict Digital Frustration from Clickstream Data</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20438v1</link><description>Many businesses depend on their mobile apps and websites, so user frustration while trying to complete a task on these channels can cause lost sales and complaints. In this research, I use clickstream data from a real e-commerce site to predict whether a session is frustrated or not. Frustration is defined using certain rules based on rage bursts, back and forth navigation (U turns), cart churn, search struggle, and long wandering sessions, and applies these rules to 5.4 million raw clickstream events (304,881 sessions). From each session, I build tabular features and train standard classifier models. I also use the full event sequence to train a discriminative LSTM classifier. XGBoost reaches about 90% accuracy, ROC AUC of 0.9579, while the LSTM performs best with about 91% accuracy and a ROC AUC of 0.9705. Finally, the research shows that with only the first 20 to 30 interactions, the LSTM already predicts frustration reliably.</description><author>Jibin Joseph</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:27:28 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20438v1</guid></item><item><title>Boosted Control Functions: Distribution generalization and invariance in confounded models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.05805v3</link><description>Modern machine learning methods and the availability of large-scale data have significantly advanced our ability to predict target quantities from large sets of covariates. However, these methods often struggle under distributional shifts, particularly in the presence of hidden confounding. While the impact of hidden confounding is well-studied in causal effect estimation, e.g., instrumental variables, its implications for prediction tasks under shifting distributions remain underexplored. This work addresses this gap by introducing a strong notion of invariance that, unlike existing weaker notions, allows for distribution generalization even in the presence of nonlinear, non-identifiable structural functions. Central to this framework is the Boosted Control Function (BCF), a novel, identifiable target of inference that satisfies the proposed strong invariance notion and is provably worst-case optimal under distributional shifts. The theoretical foundation of our work lies in Simultaneous Equation Models for Distribution Generalization (SIMDGs), which bridge machine learning with econometrics by describing data-generating processes under distributional shifts. To put these insights into practice, we propose the ControlTwicing algorithm to estimate the BCF using nonparametric machine-learning techniques and study its generalization performance on synthetic and real-world datasets compared to robust and empirical risk minimization approaches.</description><author>Nicola Gnecco, Jonas Peters, Sebastian Engelke, Niklas Pfister</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:25:13 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.05805v3</guid></item><item><title>Dual-Encoder Transformer-Based Multimodal Learning for Ischemic Stroke Lesion Segmentation Using Diffusion MRI</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20436v1</link><description>Accurate segmentation of ischemic stroke lesions from diffusion magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) is essential for clinical decision-making and outcome assessment. Diffusion-Weighted Imaging (DWI) and Apparent Diffusion Coefficient (ADC) scans provide complementary information on acute and sub-acute ischemic changes; however, automated lesion delineation remains challenging due to variability in lesion appearance. In this work, we study ischemic stroke lesion segmentation using multimodal diffusion MRI from the ISLES 2022 dataset. Several state-of-the-art convolutional and transformer-based architectures, including U-Net variants, Swin-UNet, and TransUNet, are benchmarked. Based on performance, a dual-encoder TransUNet architecture is proposed to learn modality-specific representations from DWI and ADC inputs. To incorporate spatial context, adjacent slice information is integrated using a three-slice input configuration. All models are trained under a unified framework and evaluated using the Dice Similarity Coefficient (DSC). Results show that transformer-based models outperform convolutional baselines, and the proposed dual-encoder TransUNet achieves the best performance, reaching a Dice score of 85.4% on the test set. The proposed framework offers a robust solution for automated ischemic stroke lesion segmentation from diffusion MRI.</description><author>Muhammad Usman, Azka Rehman, Muhammad Mutti Ur Rehman, Abd Ur Rehman, Muhammad Umar Farooq</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:24:31 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20436v1</guid></item><item><title>Efficient Low-Tubal-Rank Tensor Estimation via Alternating Preconditioned Gradient Descent</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.07490v3</link><description>The problem of low-tubal-rank tensor estimation is a fundamental task with wide applications across high-dimensional signal processing, machine learning, and image science. Traditional approaches tackle such a problem by performing tensor singular value decomposition, which is computationally expensive and becomes infeasible for large-scale tensors. Recent approaches address this issue by factorizing the tensor into two smaller factor tensors and solving the resulting problem using gradient descent. However, this kind of approach requires an accurate estimate of the tensor rank, and when the rank is overestimated, the convergence of gradient descent and its variants slows down significantly or even diverges. To address this problem, we propose an Alternating Preconditioned Gradient Descent (APGD) algorithm, which accelerates convergence in the over-parameterized setting by adding a preconditioning term to the original gradient and updating these two factors alternately. Based on certain geometric assumptions on the objective function, we establish linear convergence guarantees for more general low-tubal-rank tensor estimation problems. Then we further analyze the specific cases of low-tubal-rank tensor factorization and low-tubal-rank tensor recovery. Our theoretical results show that APGD achieves linear convergence even under over-parameterization, and the convergence rate is independent of the tensor condition number. Extensive simulations on synthetic data are carried out to validate our theoretical assertions.</description><author>Zhiyu Liu, Zhi Han, Yandong Tang, Jun Fan, Yao Wang</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:22:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.07490v3</guid></item><item><title>High Dimensional Data Decomposition for Anomaly Detection of Textured Images</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20432v1</link><description>In the realm of diverse high-dimensional data, images play a significant role across various processes of manufacturing systems where efficient image anomaly detection has emerged as a core technology of utmost importance. However, when applied to textured defect images, conventional anomaly detection methods have limitations including non-negligible misidentification, low robustness, and excessive reliance on large-scale and structured datasets. This paper proposes a texture basis integrated smooth decomposition (TBSD) approach, which is targeted at efficient anomaly detection in textured images with smooth backgrounds and sparse anomalies. Mathematical formulation of quasi-periodicity and its theoretical properties are investigated for image texture estimation. TBSD method consists of two principal processes: the first process learns the texture basis functions to effectively extract quasi-periodic texture patterns; the subsequent anomaly detection process utilizes that texture basis as prior knowledge to prevent texture misidentification and capture potential anomalies with high accuracy.The proposed method surpasses benchmarks with less misidentification, smaller training dataset requirement, and superior anomaly detection performance on both simulation and real-world datasets.</description><author>Ji Song, Xing Wang, Jianguo Wu, Xiaowei Yue</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:21:18 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20432v1</guid></item><item><title>Skin Lesion Classification Using a Soft Voting Ensemble of Convolutional Neural Networks</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20431v1</link><description>Skin cancer can be identified by dermoscopic examination and ocular inspection, but early detection significantly increases survival chances. Artificial intelligence (AI), using annotated skin images and Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs), improves diagnostic accuracy. This paper presents an early skin cancer classification method using a soft voting ensemble of CNNs. In this investigation, three benchmark datasets, namely HAM10000, ISIC 2016, and ISIC 2019, were used. The process involved rebalancing, image augmentation, and filtering techniques, followed by a hybrid dual encoder for segmentation via transfer learning. Accurate segmentation focused classification models on clinically significant features, reducing background artifacts and improving accuracy. Classification was performed through an ensemble of MobileNetV2, VGG19, and InceptionV3, balancing accuracy and speed for real-world deployment. The method achieved lesion recognition accuracies of 96.32\%, 90.86\%, and 93.92\% for the three datasets. The system performance was evaluated using established skin lesion detection metrics, yielding impressive results.</description><author>Abdullah Al Shafi, Abdul Muntakim, Pintu Chandra Shill, Rowzatul Zannat, Abdullah Al-Amin</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:20:47 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20431v1</guid></item><item><title>Video Generation Models Are Good Latent Reward Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.21541v2</link><description>Reward feedback learning (ReFL) has proven effective for aligning image generation with human preferences. However, its extension to video generation faces significant challenges. Existing video reward models rely on vision-language models designed for pixel-space inputs, confining ReFL optimization to near-complete denoising steps after computationally expensive VAE decoding. This pixel-space approach incurs substantial memory overhead and increased training time, and its late-stage optimization lacks early-stage supervision, refining only visual quality rather than fundamental motion dynamics and structural coherence. In this work, we show that pre-trained video generation models are naturally suited for reward modeling in the noisy latent space, as they are explicitly designed to process noisy latent representations at arbitrary timesteps and inherently preserve temporal information through their sequential modeling capabilities. Accordingly, we propose Process Reward Feedback Learning~(PRFL), a framework that conducts preference optimization entirely in latent space, enabling efficient gradient backpropagation throughout the full denoising chain without VAE decoding. Extensive experiments demonstrate that PRFL significantly improves alignment with human preferences, while achieving substantial reductions in memory consumption and training time compared to RGB ReFL.</description><author>Xiaoyue Mi, Wenqing Yu, Jiesong Lian, Shibo Jie, Ruizhe Zhong, Zijun Liu, Guozhen Zhang, Zixiang Zhou, Zhiyong Xu, Yuan Zhou, Qinglin Lu, Fan Tang</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:17:06 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.21541v2</guid></item><item><title>Towards Dataset Copyright Evasion Attack against Personalized Text-to-Image Diffusion Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.02824v2</link><description>Text-to-image (T2I) diffusion models enable high-quality image generation conditioned on textual prompts. However, fine-tuning these pre-trained models for personalization raises concerns about unauthorized dataset usage. To address this issue, dataset ownership verification (DOV) has recently been proposed, which embeds watermarks into fine-tuning datasets via backdoor techniques. These watermarks remain dormant on benign samples but produce owner-specified outputs when triggered. Despite its promise, the robustness of DOV against copyright evasion attacks (CEA) remains unexplored. In this paper, we investigate how adversaries can circumvent these mechanisms, enabling models trained on watermarked datasets to bypass ownership verification. We begin by analyzing the limitations of potential attacks achieved by backdoor removal, including TPD and T2IShield. In practice, TPD suffers from inconsistent effectiveness due to randomness, while T2IShield fails when watermarks are embedded as local image patches. To this end, we introduce CEAT2I, the first CEA specifically targeting DOV in T2I diffusion models. CEAT2I consists of three stages: (1) motivated by the observation that T2I models converge faster on watermarked samples with respect to intermediate features rather than training loss, we reliably detect watermarked samples; (2) we iteratively ablate tokens from the prompts of detected samples and monitor feature shifts to identify trigger tokens; and (3) we apply a closed-form concept erasure method to remove the injected watermarks. Extensive experiments demonstrate that CEAT2I effectively evades state-of-the-art DOV mechanisms while preserving model performance. The code is available at https://github.com/csyufei/CEAT2I.</description><author>Kuofeng Gao, Yufei Zhu, Yiming Li, Jiawang Bai, Yong Yang, Zhifeng Li, Shu-Tao Xia</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:15:42 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.02824v2</guid></item><item><title>Learning Safe Autonomous Driving Policies Using Predictive Safety Representations</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.17586v2</link><description>Safe reinforcement learning (SafeRL) is a prominent paradigm for autonomous driving, where agents are required to optimize performance under strict safety requirements. This dual objective creates a fundamental tension, as overly conservative policies limit driving efficiency while aggressive exploration risks safety violations. The Safety Representations for Safer Policy Learning (SRPL) framework addresses this challenge by equipping agents with a predictive model of future constraint violations and has shown promise in controlled environments. This paper investigates whether SRPL extends to real-world autonomous driving scenarios. Systematic experiments on the Waymo Open Motion Dataset (WOMD) and NuPlan demonstrate that SRPL can improve the reward-safety tradeoff, achieving statistically significant improvements in success rate (effect sizes r = 0.65-0.86) and cost reduction (effect sizes r = 0.70-0.83), with p &lt; 0.05 for observed improvements. However, its effectiveness depends on the underlying policy optimizer and the dataset distribution. The results further show that predictive safety representations play a critical role in improving robustness to observation noise. Additionally, in zero-shot cross-dataset evaluation, SRPL-augmented agents demonstrate improved generalization compared to non-SRPL methods. These findings collectively demonstrate the potential of predictive safety representations to strengthen SafeRL for autonomous driving.</description><author>Mahesh Keswani, Raunak Bhattacharyya</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:11:27 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.17586v2</guid></item><item><title>Evasion-Resilient Detection of DNS-over-HTTPS Data Exfiltration: A Practical Evaluation and Toolkit</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20423v1</link><description>The purpose of this project is to assess how well defenders can detect DNS-over-HTTPS (DoH) file exfiltration, and which evasion strategies can be used by attackers. While providing a reproducible toolkit to generate, intercept and analyze DoH exfiltration, and comparing Machine Learning vs threshold-based detection under adversarial scenarios. The originality of this project is the introduction of an end-to-end, containerized pipeline that generates configurable file exfiltration over DoH using several parameters (e.g., chunking, encoding, padding, resolver rotation). It allows for file reconstruction at the resolver side, while extracting flow-level features using a fork of DoHLyzer. The pipeline contains a prediction side, which allows the training of machine learning models based on public labelled datasets and then evaluates them side-by-side with threshold-based detection methods against malicious and evasive DNS-Over-HTTPS traffic. We train Random Forest, Gradient Boosting and Logistic Regression classifiers on a public DoH dataset and benchmark them against evasive DoH exfiltration scenarios. The toolkit orchestrates traffic generation, file capture, feature extraction, model training and analysis. The toolkit is then encapsulated into several Docker containers for easy setup and full reproducibility regardless of the platform it is run on. Future research regarding this project is directed at validating the results on mixed enterprise traffic, extending the protocol coverage to HTTP/3/QUIC request, adding a benign traffic generation, and working on real-time traffic evaluation. A key objective is to quantify when stealth constraints make DoH exfiltration uneconomical and unworthy for the attacker.</description><author>Adam Elaoumari</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:07:17 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20423v1</guid></item><item><title>Training Deep Morphological Neural Networks as Universal Approximators</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.09710v3</link><description>We investigate deep morphological neural networks (DMNNs). We demonstrate that despite their inherent non-linearity, "linear" activations are essential for DMNNs. To preserve their inherent sparsity, we propose architectures that constraint the parameters of the "linear" activations: For the first (resp. second) architecture, we work under the constraint that the majority of parameters (resp. learnable parameters) should be part of morphological operations. We improve the generalization ability of our networks via residual connections and weight dropout. Our proposed networks can be successfully trained, and are more prunable than linear networks. To the best of our knowledge, we are the first to successfully train DMNNs under such constraints. Finally, we propose a hybrid network architecture combining linear and morphological layers, showing empirically that the inclusion of morphological layers significantly accelerates the convergence of gradient descent with large batches.</description><author>Konstantinos Fotopoulos, Petros Maragos</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:03:59 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.09710v3</guid></item><item><title>Scaling Laws for Energy Efficiency of Local LLMs</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.16531v3</link><description>Deploying local large language models and vision-language models on edge devices requires balancing accuracy with constrained computational and energy budgets. Although graphics processors dominate modern artificial-intelligence deployment, most consumer hardware--including laptops, desktops, industrial controllers, and embedded systems--relies on central processing units. Despite this, the computational laws governing central-processing-unit-only inference for local language and vision-language workloads remain largely unexplored. We systematically benchmark large language and vision-language models on two representative central-processing-unit tiers widely used for local inference: a MacBook Pro M2, reflecting mainstream laptop-class deployment, and a Raspberry Pi 5, representing constrained, low-power embedded settings. Using a unified methodology based on continuous sampling of processor and memory usage together with area-under-curve integration, we characterize how computational load scales with input text length for language models and with image resolution for vision-language models. We uncover two empirical scaling laws: (1) computational cost for language-model inference scales approximately linearly with token length; and (2) vision-language models exhibit a preprocessing-driven "resolution knee", where compute remains constant above an internal resolution clamp and decreases sharply below it. Beyond these laws, we show that quantum-inspired compression reduces processor and memory usage by up to 71.9% and energy consumption by up to 62%, while preserving or improving semantic accuracy. These results provide a systematic quantification of multimodal central-processing-unit-only scaling for local language and vision-language workloads, and they identify model compression and input-resolution preprocessing as effective, low-cost levers for sustainable edge inference.</description><author>Ander Alvarez, Alessandro Genuardi, Nilotpal Sinha, Antonio Tiene, Mikail Okyay, Bakbergen Ryskulov, David Montero, Samuel Mugel, Román Orús</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:02:39 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.16531v3</guid></item><item><title>Simplifying Multi-Task Architectures Through Task-Specific Normalization</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20420v1</link><description>Multi-task learning (MTL) aims to leverage shared knowledge across tasks to improve generalization and parameter efficiency, yet balancing resources and mitigating interference remain open challenges. Architectural solutions often introduce elaborate task-specific modules or routing schemes, increasing complexity and overhead. In this work, we show that normalization layers alone are sufficient to address many of these challenges. Simply replacing shared normalization with task-specific variants already yields competitive performance, questioning the need for complex designs. Building on this insight, we propose Task-Specific Sigmoid Batch Normalization (TS$σ$BN), a lightweight mechanism that enables tasks to softly allocate network capacity while fully sharing feature extractors. TS$σ$BN improves stability across CNNs and Transformers, matching or exceeding performance on NYUv2, Cityscapes, CelebA, and PascalContext, while remaining highly parameter-efficient. Moreover, its learned gates provide a natural framework for analyzing MTL dynamics, offering interpretable insights into capacity allocation, filter specialization, and task relationships. Our findings suggest that complex MTL architectures may be unnecessary and that task-specific normalization offers a simple, interpretable, and efficient alternative.</description><author>Mihai Suteu, Ovidiu Serban</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:02:12 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20420v1</guid></item><item><title>Regressor-Guided Generative Image Editing Balances User Emotions to Reduce Time Spent Online</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.12289v2</link><description>Internet overuse is a widespread phenomenon in today's digital society. Existing interventions, such as time limits or grayscaling, often rely on restrictive controls that provoke psychological reactance and are frequently circumvented. Building on prior work showing that emotional responses mediate the relationship between content consumption and online engagement, we investigate whether regulating the emotional impact of images can reduce online use in a non-coercive manner. We introduce and systematically analyze three regressor-guided image-editing approaches: (i) global optimization of emotion-related image attributes, (ii) optimization in a style latent space, and (iii) a diffusion-based method using classifier and classifier-free guidance. While the first two approaches modify low-level visual features (e.g., contrast, color), the diffusion-based method enables higher-level changes (e.g., adjusting clothing, facial features). Results from a controlled image-rating study and a social media experiment show that diffusion-based edits balance emotional responses and are associated with lower usage duration while preserving visual quality.</description><author>Christoph Gebhardt, Robin Willardt, Seyedmorteza Sadat, Chih-Wei Ning, Andreas Brombach, Jie Song, Otmar Hilliges, Christian Holz</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:02:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.12289v2</guid></item><item><title>Chain-of-Anomaly Thoughts with Large Vision-Language Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20417v1</link><description>Automated video surveillance with Large Vision-Language Models is limited by their inherent bias towards normality, often failing to detect crimes. While Chain-of-Thought reasoning strategies show significant potential for improving performance in language tasks, the lack of inductive anomaly biases in their reasoning further steers the models towards normal interpretations. To address this, we propose Chain-of-Anomaly-Thoughts (CoAT), a multi-agent reasoning framework that introduces inductive criminal bias in the reasoning process through a final, anomaly-focused classification layer. Our method significantly improves Anomaly Detection, boosting F1-score by 11.8 p.p. on challenging low-resolution footage and Anomaly Classification by 3.78 p.p. in high-resolution videos.</description><author>Pedro Domingos, João Pereira, Vasco Lopes, João Neves, David Semedo</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:01:05 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20417v1</guid></item><item><title>DETACH : Decomposed Spatio-Temporal Alignment for Exocentric Video and Ambient Sensors with Staged Learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20409v1</link><description>Aligning egocentric video with wearable sensors have shown promise for human action recognition, but face practical limitations in user discomfort, privacy concerns, and scalability. We explore exocentric video with ambient sensors as a non-intrusive, scalable alternative. While prior egocentric-wearable works predominantly adopt Global Alignment by encoding entire sequences into unified representations, this approach fails in exocentric-ambient settings due to two problems: (P1) inability to capture local details such as subtle motions, and (P2) over-reliance on modality-invariant temporal patterns, causing misalignment between actions sharing similar temporal patterns with different spatio-semantic contexts. To resolve these problems, we propose DETACH, a decomposed spatio-temporal framework. This explicit decomposition preserves local details, while our novel sensor-spatial features discovered via online clustering provide semantic grounding for context-aware alignment. To align the decomposed features, our two-stage approach establishes spatial correspondence through mutual supervision, then performs temporal alignment via a spatial-temporal weighted contrastive loss that adaptively handles easy negatives, hard negatives, and false negatives. Comprehensive experiments with downstream tasks on Opportunity++ and HWU-USP datasets demonstrate substantial improvements over adapted egocentric-wearable baselines.</description><author>Junho Yoon, Jaemo Jung, Hyunju Kim, Dongman Lee</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:55:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20409v1</guid></item><item><title>AUDRON: A Deep Learning Framework with Fused Acoustic Signatures for Drone Type Recognition</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20407v1</link><description>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs), commonly known as drones, are increasingly used across diverse domains, including logistics, agriculture, surveillance, and defense. While these systems provide numerous benefits, their misuse raises safety and security concerns, making effective detection mechanisms essential. Acoustic sensing offers a low-cost and non-intrusive alternative to vision or radar-based detection, as drone propellers generate distinctive sound patterns. This study introduces AUDRON (AUdio-based Drone Recognition Network), a hybrid deep learning framework for drone sound detection, employing a combination of Mel-Frequency Cepstral Coefficients (MFCC), Short-Time Fourier Transform (STFT) spectrograms processed with convolutional neural networks (CNNs), recurrent layers for temporal modeling, and autoencoder-based representations. Feature-level fusion integrates complementary information before classification. Experimental evaluation demonstrates that AUDRON effectively differentiates drone acoustic signatures from background noise, achieving high accuracy while maintaining generalizability across varying conditions. AUDRON achieves 98.51 percent and 97.11 percent accuracy in binary and multiclass classification. The results highlight the advantage of combining multiple feature representations with deep learning for reliable acoustic drone detection, suggesting the framework's potential for deployment in security and surveillance applications where visual or radar sensing may be limited.</description><author>Rajdeep Chatterjee, Sudip Chakrabarty, Trishaani Acharjee, Deepanjali Mishra</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:55:08 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20407v1</guid></item><item><title>Sentiment-Aware Extractive and Abstractive Summarization for Unstructured Text Mining</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20404v1</link><description>With the rapid growth of unstructured data from social media, reviews, and forums, text mining has become essential in Information Systems (IS) for extracting actionable insights. Summarization can condense fragmented, emotion-rich posts, but existing methods-optimized for structured news-struggle with noisy, informal content. Emotional cues are critical for IS tasks such as brand monitoring and market analysis, yet few studies integrate sentiment modeling into summarization of short user-generated texts. We propose a sentiment-aware framework extending extractive (TextRank) and abstractive (UniLM) approaches by embedding sentiment signals into ranking and generation processes. This dual design improves the capture of emotional nuances and thematic relevance, producing concise, sentiment-enriched summaries that enhance timely interventions and strategic decision-making in dynamic online environments.</description><author>Junyi Liu, Stanley Kok</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:48:42 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20404v1</guid></item><item><title>BRIDGE: Budget-aware Reasoning via Intermediate Distillation with Guided Examples</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20403v1</link><description>Distilling knowledge from large proprietary models (e.g., GPT-4) to tiny deployable models (less than 1B parameters) faces a critical capacity-budget trap: the 1000x capacity gap between teachers and students prevents effective direct transfer, while API costs prohibit extensive data collection. We introduce BRIDGE (Budget-Aware Reasoning via Intermediate Distillation), a two-phase framework that resolves these constraints through strategic intermediation and budget asymmetry. In Phase 1, a mid-sized Teacher Assistant (TA; e.g., about 7B) learns from the black-box teacher on a strictly limited subset of data (e.g., 3-5%), selected via a zero-API-cost pipeline that balances entropic difficulty and semantic diversity using only local TA inference. In Phase 2, we exploit this asymmetry-teacher queries are expensive, whereas TA inference is free to amplify supervision: the refined TA generates synthetic rationales for the full dataset to train the tiny student. Crucially, we apply an instruction-tuning curriculum to establish behavioral alignment in the tiny student before transferring reasoning. Our theoretical analysis shows that BRIDGE yields tighter generalization bounds than direct distillation when data is abundant. Experiments across medical, legal, and financial benchmarks demonstrate consistent improvements: BRIDGE delivers student performance gains of 28-41%, closing the capability gap with proprietary teachers by 12-16% while using 10x fewer teacher queries. Notably, BRIDGE defies the conventional cost-performance frontier, surpassing direct distillation baselines that use 100% of the budget while consuming only 5% of the resources.</description><author>Xuan-An Le, Minh-Nam Tran, Son Nguyen</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:46:43 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20403v1</guid></item><item><title>Fusion of Multiscale Features Via Centralized Sparse-attention Network for EEG Decoding</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.18689v2</link><description>Electroencephalography (EEG) signal decoding is a key technology that translates brain activity into executable commands, laying the foundation for direct brain-machine interfacing and intelligent interaction. To address the inherent spatiotemporal heterogeneity of EEG signals, this paper proposes a multi-branch parallel architecture, where each temporal scale is equipped with an independent spatial feature extraction module. To further enhance multi-branch feature fusion, we propose a Fusion of Multiscale Features via Centralized Sparse-attention Network (EEG-CSANet), a centralized sparse-attention network. It employs a main-auxiliary branch architecture, where the main branch models core spatiotemporal patterns via multiscale self-attention, and the auxiliary branch facilitates efficient local interactions through sparse cross-attention. Experimental results show that EEG-CSANet achieves state-of-the-art (SOTA) performance across five public datasets (BCIC-IV-2A, BCIC-IV-2B, HGD, SEED, and SEED-VIG), with accuracies of 88.54%, 91.09%, 99.43%, 96.03%, and 90.56%, respectively. Such performance demonstrates its strong adaptability and robustness across various EEG decoding tasks. Moreover, extensive ablation studies are conducted to enhance the interpretability of EEG-CSANet. In the future, we hope that EEG-CSANet could serve as a promising baseline model in the field of EEG signal decoding. The source code is publicly available at: https://github.com/Xiangrui-Cai/EEG-CSANet</description><author>Xiangrui Cai, Shaocheng Ma, Lei Cao, Jie Li, Tianyu Liu, Yilin Dong</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:46:41 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.18689v2</guid></item><item><title>Multiscale Corrections by Continuous Super-Resolution</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.07576v2</link><description>Finite element methods typically require a high resolution to satisfactorily approximate micro and even macro patterns of an underlying physical model. This issue can be circumvented by appropriate multiscale strategies that are able to obtain reasonable approximations on under-resolved scales. In this paper, we study the implicit neural representation and propose a continuous super-resolution network as a correction strategy for multiscale effects. It can take coarse finite element data to learn both in-distribution and out-of-distribution high-resolution finite element predictions. Our highlight is the design of a local implicit transformer, which is able to learn multiscale features. We also propose Gabor wavelet-based coordinate encodings, which can overcome the bias of neural networks learning low-frequency features. Finally, perception is often preferred over distortion, so scientists can recognize the visual pattern for further investigation. However, implicit neural representation is known for its lack of local pattern supervision. We propose to use stochastic cosine similarities to compare the local feature differences between prediction and ground truth. It shows better performance on structural alignments. Our experiments show that our proposed strategy achieves superior performance as an in-distribution and out-of-distribution super-resolution strategy.</description><author>Zhi-Song Liu, Roland Maier, Andreas Rupp</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:44:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.07576v2</guid></item><item><title>GeoTransolver: Learning Physics on Irregumar Domains Using Multi-scale Geometry Aware Physics Attention Transformer</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20399v1</link><description>We present GeoTransolver, a Multiscale Geometry-Aware Physics Attention Transformer for CAE that replaces standard attention with GALE, coupling physics-aware self-attention on learned state slices with cross-attention to a shared geometry/global/boundary-condition context computed from multi-scale ball queries (inspired by DoMINO) and reused in every block. Implemented and released in NVIDIA PhysicsNeMo, GeoTransolver persistently projects geometry, global and boundary condition parameters into physical state spaces to anchor latent computations to domain structure and operating regimes. We benchmark GeoTransolver on DrivAerML, Luminary SHIFT-SUV, and Luminary SHIFT-Wing, comparing against Domino, Transolver (as released in PhysicsNeMo), and literature-reported AB-UPT, and evaluate drag/lift R2 and Relative L1 errors for field variables. GeoTransolver delivers better accuracy, improved robustness to geometry/regime shifts, and favorable data efficiency; we include ablations on DrivAerML and qualitative results such as contour plots and design trends for the best GeoTransolver models. By unifying multiscale geometry-aware context with physics-based attention in a scalable transformer, GeoTransolver advances operator learning for high-fidelity surrogate modeling across complex, irregular domains and non-linear physical regimes.</description><author>Corey Adams, Rishikesh Ranade, Ram Cherukuri, Sanjay Choudhry</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:40:08 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20399v1</guid></item><item><title>LAMIC: Layout-Aware Multi-Image Composition via Scalability of Multimodal Diffusion Transformer</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.00477v2</link><description>In controllable image synthesis, generating coherent and consistent images from multiple references with spatial layout awareness remains an open challenge. We present LAMIC, a Layout-Aware Multi-Image Composition framework that, for the first time, extends single-reference diffusion models to multi-reference scenarios in a training-free manner. Built upon the MMDiT model, LAMIC introduces two plug-and-play attention mechanisms: 1) Group Isolation Attention (GIA) to enhance entity disentanglement; and 2) Region-Modulated Attention (RMA) to enable layout-aware generation. To comprehensively evaluate model capabilities, we further introduce three metrics: 1) Inclusion Ratio (IN-R) and Fill Ratio (FI-R) for assessing layout control; and 2) Background Similarity (BG-S) for measuring background consistency. Extensive experiments show that LAMIC achieves state-of-the-art performance across most major metrics: it consistently outperforms existing multi-reference baselines in ID-S, BG-S, IN-R and AVG scores across all settings, and achieves the best DPG in complex composition tasks. These results demonstrate LAMIC's superior abilities in identity keeping, background preservation, layout control, and prompt-following, all achieved without any training or fine-tuning, showcasing strong zero-shot generalization ability. By inheriting the strengths of advanced single-reference models and enabling seamless extension to multi-image scenarios, LAMIC establishes a new training-free paradigm for controllable multi-image composition. As foundation models continue to evolve, LAMIC's performance is expected to scale accordingly. Our implementation is available at: https://github.com/Suchenl/LAMIC.</description><author>Yuzhuo Chen, Zehua Ma, Jianhua Wang, Kai Kang, Shunyu Yao, Weiming Zhang</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:27:42 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.00477v2</guid></item><item><title>Generative Digital Twins: Vision-Language Simulation Models for Executable Industrial Systems</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20387v1</link><description>We propose a Vision-Language Simulation Model (VLSM) that unifies visual and textual understanding to synthesize executable FlexScript from layout sketches and natural-language prompts, enabling cross-modal reasoning for industrial simulation systems. To support this new paradigm, the study constructs the first large-scale dataset for generative digital twins, comprising over 120,000 prompt-sketch-code triplets that enable multimodal learning between textual descriptions, spatial structures, and simulation logic. In parallel, three novel evaluation metrics, Structural Validity Rate (SVR), Parameter Match Rate (PMR), and Execution Success Rate (ESR), are proposed specifically for this task to comprehensively evaluate structural integrity, parameter fidelity, and simulator executability. Through systematic ablation across vision encoders, connectors, and code-pretrained language backbones, the proposed models achieve near-perfect structural accuracy and high execution robustness. This work establishes a foundation for generative digital twins that integrate visual reasoning and language understanding into executable industrial simulation systems.</description><author>YuChe Hsu, AnJui Wang, TsaiChing Ni, YuanFu Yang</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:22:26 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20387v1</guid></item><item><title>Identifying Appropriately-Sized Services with Deep Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20381v1</link><description>Service-based architecture (SBA) has gained attention in industry and academia as a means to modernize legacy systems. It refers to a design style that enables systems to be developed as suites of small, loosely coupled, and autonomous components (services) that encapsulate functionality and communicate via language-agnostic APIs. However, defining appropriately sized services that capture cohesive subsets of system functionality remains challenging. Existing work often relies on the availability of documentation, access to project personnel, or a priori knowledge of the target number of services, assumptions that do not hold in many real-world scenarios. Our work addresses these limitations using a deep reinforcement learning-based approach to identify appropriately sized services directly from implementation artifacts. We present Rake, a reinforcement learning-based technique that leverages available system documentation and source code to guide service decomposition at the level of implementation methods. Rake does not require specific documentation or access to project personnel and is language-agnostic. It also supports a customizable objective function that balances modularization quality and business capability alignment, i.e., the degree to which a service covers the targeted business capability. We applied Rake to four open-source legacy projects and compared it with two state-of-the-art techniques. On average, Rake achieved 7-14 percent higher modularization quality and 18-22 percent stronger business capability alignment. Our results further show that optimizing solely for business context can degrade decomposition quality in tightly coupled systems, highlighting the need for balanced objectives.</description><author>Syeda Tasnim Fabiha, Saad Shafiq, Wesley Klewerton Guez Assunção, Nenad Medvidović</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:12:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20381v1</guid></item><item><title>Reinforcement Learning for Large Model: A Survey</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.08189v3</link><description>Recent advances at the intersection of reinforcement learning (RL) and visual intelligence have enabled agents that not only perceive complex visual scenes but also reason, generate, and act within them. This survey offers a critical and up-to-date synthesis of the field. We first formalize visual RL problems and trace the evolution of policy-optimization strategies from RLHF to verifiable reward paradigms, and from Proximal Policy Optimization to Group Relative Policy Optimization. We then organize more than 200 representative works into four thematic pillars: multi-modal large language models, visual generation, unified model frameworks, and vision-language-action models. For each pillar we examine algorithmic design, reward engineering, benchmark progress, and we distill trends such as curriculum-driven training, preference-aligned diffusion, and unified reward modeling. Finally, we review evaluation protocols spanning set-level fidelity, sample-level preference, and state-level stability, and we identify open challenges that include sample efficiency, generalization, and safe deployment. Our goal is to provide researchers and practitioners with a coherent map of the rapidly expanding landscape of visual RL and to highlight promising directions for future inquiry. Resources are available at: https://github.com/weijiawu/Awesome-Visual-Reinforcement-Learning.</description><author>Weijia Wu, Chen Gao, Joya Chen, Kevin Qinghong Lin, Qingwei Meng, Yiming Zhang, Yuke Qiu, Hong Zhou, Mike Zheng Shou</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:03:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.08189v3</guid></item><item><title>Thematic Dispersion in Arabic Applied Linguistics: A Bibliometric Analysis using Brookes' Measure</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.15328v2</link><description>This study applies Brookes' Measure of Categorical Dispersion (Δ) to analyze the thematic structure of contemporary Arabic Applied Linguistics research. Using a comprehensive, real-world dataset of 1,564 publications from 2019 to 2025, classified into eight core sub-disciplines, we calculate a dispersion index of Δ = 0.194. This remarkably low value indicates extreme thematic dispersion, revealing that the field is characterized by pronounced heterogeneity rather than concentration. The analysis identifies Computational Linguistics as a dominant but non-hegemonic force, coexisting with robust research in Sociolinguistics, Language Teaching, and other subfields. This study clarifies the correct application of Brookes' original formula, demonstrates its utility for field characterization, and provides a replicable bibliometric methodology for assessing disciplinary structure across domains.</description><author>Ayman Eddakrouri, Amani Ramadan</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:00:56 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.15328v2</guid></item><item><title>SmartSplat: Feature-Smart Gaussians for Scalable Compression of Ultra-High-Resolution Images</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20377v1</link><description>Recent advances in generative AI have accelerated the production of ultra-high-resolution visual content, posing significant challenges for efficient compression and real-time decoding on end-user devices. Inspired by 3D Gaussian Splatting, recent 2D Gaussian image models improve representation efficiency, yet existing methods struggle to balance compression ratio and reconstruction fidelity in ultra-high-resolution scenarios. To address this issue, we propose SmartSplat, a highly adaptive and feature-aware GS-based image compression framework that supports arbitrary image resolutions and compression ratios. SmartSplat leverages image-aware features such as gradients and color variances, introducing a Gradient-Color Guided Variational Sampling strategy together with an Exclusion-based Uniform Sampling scheme to improve the non-overlapping coverage of Gaussian primitives in pixel space. In addition, we propose a Scale-Adaptive Gaussian Color Sampling method to enhance color initialization across scales. Through joint optimization of spatial layout, scale, and color initialization, SmartSplat efficiently captures both local structures and global textures using a limited number of Gaussians, achieving high reconstruction quality under strong compression. Extensive experiments on DIV8K and a newly constructed 16K dataset demonstrate that SmartSplat consistently outperforms state-of-the-art methods at comparable compression ratios and exceeds their compression limits, showing strong scalability and practical applicability. The code is publicly available at https://github.com/lif314/SmartSplat.</description><author>Linfei Li, Lin Zhang, Zhong Wang, Ying Shen</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:00:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20377v1</guid></item><item><title>STEP: A Unified Spiking Transformer Evaluation Platform for Fair and Reproducible Benchmarking</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.11151v2</link><description>Spiking Transformers have recently emerged as promising architectures for combining the efficiency of spiking neural networks with the representational power of self-attention. However, the lack of standardized implementations, evaluation pipelines, and consistent design choices has hindered fair comparison and principled analysis. In this paper, we introduce STEP a unified benchmark framework for Spiking Transformers that supports a wide range of tasks, including classification, segmentation, and detection across static, event-based, and sequential datasets. STEP provides modular support for diverse components such as spiking neurons, input encodings, surrogate gradients, and multiple backends (e.g., SpikingJelly, BrainCog). Using STEP, we reproduce and evaluate several representative models, and conduct systematic ablation studies on attention design, neuron types, encoding schemes, and temporal modeling capabilities. We also propose a unified analytical model for energy estimation, accounting for spike sparsity, bitwidth, and memory access, and show that quantized ANNs may offer comparable or better energy efficiency. Our results suggest that current Spiking Transformers rely heavily on convolutional frontends and lack strong temporal modeling, underscoring the need for spike-native architectural innovations. The full code is available at: https://github.com/Fancyssc/STEP</description><author>Sicheng Shen, Dongcheng Zhao, Linghao Feng, Zeyang Yue, Jindong Li, Tenglong Li, Guobin Shen, Yi Zeng</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:00:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.11151v2</guid></item><item><title>Linking Faces and Voices Across Languages: Insights from the FAME 2026 Challenge</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20376v1</link><description>Over half of the world's population is bilingual and people often communicate under multilingual scenarios. The Face-Voice Association in Multilingual Environments (FAME) 2026 Challenge, held at ICASSP 2026, focuses on developing methods for face-voice association that are effective when the language at test-time is different than the training one. This report provides a brief summary of the challenge.</description><author>Marta Moscati, Ahmed Abdullah, Muhammad Saad Saeed, Shah Nawaz, Rohan Kumar Das, Muhammad Zaigham Zaheer, Junaid Mir, Muhammad Haroon Yousaf, Khalid Mahmood Malik, Markus Schedl</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:00:34 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20376v1</guid></item><item><title>CLIP Based Region-Aware Feature Fusion for Automated BBPS Scoring in Colonoscopy Images</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20374v1</link><description>Accurate assessment of bowel cleanliness is essential for effective colonoscopy procedures. The Boston Bowel Preparation Scale (BBPS) offers a standardized scoring system but suffers from subjectivity and inter-observer variability when performed manually. In this paper, to support robust training and evaluation, we construct a high-quality colonoscopy dataset comprising 2,240 images from 517 subjects, annotated with expert-agreed BBPS scores. We propose a novel automated BBPS scoring framework that leverages the CLIP model with adapter-based transfer learning and a dedicated fecal-feature extraction branch. Our method fuses global visual features with stool-related textual priors to improve the accuracy of bowel cleanliness evaluation without requiring explicit segmentation. Extensive experiments on both our dataset and the public NERTHU dataset demonstrate the superiority of our approach over existing baselines, highlighting its potential for clinical deployment in computer-aided colonoscopy analysis.</description><author>Yujia Fu, Zhiyu Dong, Tianwen Qian, Chenye Zheng, Danian Ji, Linhai Zhuo</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:58:12 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20374v1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-Population White Matter Atlas Creation for Concurrent Mapping of Brain Connections in Neonates and Adults with Diffusion MRI Tractography</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20370v1</link><description>Comparing white matter (WM) connections between adults and neonates using diffusion MRI (dMRI) can advance our understanding of typical brain development and potential biomarkers for neurological disorders. However, existing WM atlases are population-specific (adult or neonatal) and reside in separate spaces, preventing direct cross-population comparisons. A unified WM atlas spanning both neonates and adults is still lacking. In this study, we propose a neonatal/adult brain atlas (NABA), a WM tractography atlas built from dMRI data of both neonates and adults. NABA is constructed using a robust, data-driven fiber clustering pipeline, enabling group-wise WM atlasing across populations despite substantial anatomical variability. The atlas provides a standardized template for WM parcellation, allowing direct comparison of WM tracts between neonates and adults. Using NABA, we conduct four analyses: (1) evaluating the feasibility of joint WM mapping across populations, (2) characterizing WM development across neonatal ages relative to adults, (3) assessing sex-related differences in neonatal WM development, and (4) examining the effects of preterm birth. Our results show that NABA robustly identifies WM tracts in both populations. We observe rapid fractional anisotropy (FA) development in long-range association tracts, including the arcuate fasciculus and superior longitudinal fasciculus II, whereas intra-cerebellar tracts develop more slowly. Neonatal females exhibit faster overall FA development than males. Although preterm neonates show lower overall FA development rates, they demonstrate relatively higher FA growth in specific tracts, including the corticospinal tract, corona radiata-pontine pathway, and intracerebellar tracts. These findings demonstrate that NABA is a useful tool for investigating WM development across neonates and adults.</description><author>Wei Zhang, Yijie Li, Ruixi Zheng, Nir A. Sochen, Yuqian Chen, Leo R. Zekelman, Ofer Pasternak, Jarrett Rushmore, Yogesh Rathi, Nikos Makris, Lauren J. O'Donnell, Fan Zhang</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:54:11 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20370v1</guid></item><item><title>Avoiding the Price of Adaptivity: Inference in Linear Contextual Bandits via Stability</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20368v1</link><description>Statistical inference in contextual bandits is complicated by the adaptive, non-i.i.d. nature of the data. A growing body of work has shown that classical least-squares inference may fail under adaptive sampling, and that constructing valid confidence intervals for linear functionals of the model parameter typically requires paying an unavoidable inflation of order $\sqrt{d \log T}$. This phenomenon -- often referred to as the price of adaptivity -- highlights the inherent difficulty of reliable inference under general contextual bandit policies. A key structural property that circumvents this limitation is the \emph{stability} condition of Lai and Wei, which requires the empirical feature covariance to concentrate around a deterministic limit. When stability holds, the ordinary least-squares estimator satisfies a central limit theorem, and classical Wald-type confidence intervals -- designed for i.i.d. data -- become asymptotically valid even under adaptation, \emph{without} incurring the $\sqrt{d \log T}$ price of adaptivity. In this paper, we propose and analyze a penalized EXP4 algorithm for linear contextual bandits. Our first main result shows that this procedure satisfies the Lai--Wei stability condition and therefore admits valid Wald-type confidence intervals for linear functionals. Our second result establishes that the same algorithm achieves regret guarantees that are minimax optimal up to logarithmic factors, demonstrating that stability and statistical efficiency can coexist within a single contextual bandit method. Finally, we complement our theory with simulations illustrating the empirical normality of the resulting estimators and the sharpness of the corresponding confidence intervals.</description><author>Samya Praharaj, Koulik Khamaru</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:53:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20368v1</guid></item><item><title>Clust-PSI-PFL: A Population Stability Index Approach for Clustered Non-IID Personalized Federated Learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20363v1</link><description>Federated learning (FL) supports privacy-preserving, decentralized machine learning (ML) model training by keeping data on client devices. However, non-independent and identically distributed (non-IID) data across clients biases updates and degrades performance. To alleviate these issues, we propose Clust-PSI-PFL, a clustering-based personalized FL framework that uses the Population Stability Index (PSI) to quantify the level of non-IID data. We compute a weighted PSI metric, $WPSI^L$, which we show to be more informative than common non-IID metrics (Hellinger, Jensen-Shannon, and Earth Mover's distance). Using PSI features, we form distributionally homogeneous groups of clients via K-means++; the number of optimal clusters is chosen by a systematic silhouette-based procedure, typically yielding few clusters with modest overhead. Across six datasets (tabular, image, and text modalities), two partition protocols (Dirichlet with parameter $α$ and Similarity with parameter S), and multiple client sizes, Clust-PSI-PFL delivers up to 18% higher global accuracy than state-of-the-art baselines and markedly improves client fairness by a relative improvement of 37% under severe non-IID data. These results establish PSI-guided clustering as a principled, lightweight mechanism for robust PFL under label skew.</description><author>Daniel M. Jimenez-Gutierrez, Mehrdad Hassanzadeh, Aris Anagnostopoulos, Ioannis Chatzigiannakis, Andrea Vitaletti</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:46:38 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20363v1</guid></item><item><title>CRAFT: Continuous Reasoning and Agentic Feedback Tuning for Multimodal Text-to-Image Generation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20362v1</link><description>Recent work has shown that inference-time reasoning and reflection can improve text-to-image generation without retraining. However, existing approaches often rely on implicit, holistic critiques or unconstrained prompt rewrites, making their behavior difficult to interpret, control, or stop reliably. In contrast, large language models have benefited from explicit, structured forms of **thinking** based on verification, targeted correction, and early stopping. We introduce CRAFT (Continuous Reasoning and Agentic Feedback Tuning), a training-free, model-agnostic framework that brings this structured reasoning paradigm to multimodal image generation. CRAFT decomposes a prompt into dependency-structured visual questions, veries generated images using a vision-language model, and applies targeted prompt edits through an LLM agent only where constraints fail. The process iterates with an explicit stopping criterion once all constraints are satised, yielding an interpretable and controllable inference-time renement loop. Across multiple model families and challenging benchmarks, CRAFT consistently improves compositional accuracy, text rendering, and preference-based evaluations, with particularly strong gains for lightweight generators. Importantly, these improvements incur only a negligible inference-time overhead, allowing smaller or cheaper models to approach the quality of substantially more expensive systems. Our results suggest that explicitly structured, constraint-driven inference-time reasoning is a key ingredient for improving the reliability of multimodal generative models.</description><author>V. Kovalev, A. Kuvshinov, A. Buzovkin, D. Pokidov, D. Timonin</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:44:41 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20362v1</guid></item><item><title>Scalable Temporal Anomaly Causality Discovery in Large Systems: Achieving Computational Efficiency with Binary Anomaly Flag Data</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.11800v3</link><description>Extracting anomaly causality facilitates diagnostics once monitoring systems detect system faults. Identifying anomaly causes in large systems involves investigating a broader set of monitoring variables across multiple subsystems. However, learning graphical causal models (GCMs) comes with a significant computational burden that restrains the applicability of most existing methods in real-time and large-scale deployments. In addition, modern monitoring applications for large systems often generate large amounts of binary alarm flags, and the distinct characteristics of binary anomaly data -- the meaning of state transition and data sparsity -- challenge existing causality learning mechanisms. This study proposes an anomaly causal discovery approach (AnomalyCD), addressing the accuracy and computational challenges of generating GCMs from temporal binary flag datasets. The AnomalyCD presents several strategies, such as anomaly data-aware causality testing, sparse data and prior link compression, and edge pruning adjustment approaches. We validate the performance of the approach on two datasets: monitoring sensor data from the readout-box system of the Compact Muon Solenoid experiment at CERN, and a public dataset from an information technology monitoring system. The results on temporal GCMs demonstrate a considerable reduction of computation overhead and a moderate enhancement of accuracy on the binary anomaly datasets Source code: https://github.com/muleina/AnomalyCD .</description><author>Mulugeta Weldezgina Asres, Christian Walter Omlin, The CMS-HCAL Collaboration</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:43:57 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.11800v3</guid></item><item><title>Multi-LLM Thematic Analysis with Dual Reliability Metrics: Combining Cohen's Kappa and Semantic Similarity for Qualitative Research Validation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20352v1</link><description>Qualitative research faces a critical reliability challenge: traditional inter-rater agreement methods require multiple human coders, are time-intensive, and often yield moderate consistency. We present a multi-perspective validation framework for LLM-based thematic analysis that combines ensemble validation with dual reliability metrics: Cohen's Kappa ($κ$) for inter-rater agreement and cosine similarity for semantic consistency. Our framework enables configurable analysis parameters (1-6 seeds, temperature 0.0-2.0), supports custom prompt structures with variable substitution, and provides consensus theme extraction across any JSON format. As proof-of-concept, we evaluate three leading LLMs (Gemini 2.5 Pro, GPT-4o, Claude 3.5 Sonnet) on a psychedelic art therapy interview transcript, conducting six independent runs per model. Results demonstrate Gemini achieves highest reliability ($κ= 0.907$, cosine=95.3%), followed by GPT-4o ($κ= 0.853$, cosine=92.6%) and Claude ($κ= 0.842$, cosine=92.1%). All three models achieve a high agreement ($κ&gt; 0.80$), validating the multi-run ensemble approach. The framework successfully extracts consensus themes across runs, with Gemini identifying 6 consensus themes (50-83% consistency), GPT-4o identifying 5 themes, and Claude 4 themes. Our open-source implementation provides researchers with transparent reliability metrics, flexible configuration, and structure-agnostic consensus extraction, establishing methodological foundations for reliable AI-assisted qualitative research.</description><author>Nilesh Jain, Seyi Adeyinka, Leor Roseman, Aza Allsop</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:32:43 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20352v1</guid></item><item><title>BConformeR: A Conformer Based on Mutual Sampling for Unified Prediction of Continuous and Discontinuous Antibody Binding Sites</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.12029v3</link><description>Accurate prediction of antibody-binding sites (epitopes) on antigens is crucial for vaccine design, immunodiagnostics, therapeutic antibody development, antibody engineering, research into autoimmune and allergic diseases, and advancing our understanding of immune responses. Despite in silico methods that have been proposed to predict both linear (continuous) and conformational (discontinuous) epitopes, they consistently underperform in predicting conformational epitopes. In this work, we propose Conformer-based models trained separately on AlphaFold-predicted structures and experimentally determined structures, leveraging convolutional neural networks (CNNs) to extract local features and Transformers to capture long-range dependencies within antigen sequences. Ablation studies demonstrate that CNN enhances the prediction of linear epitopes, and the Transformer module improves the prediction of conformational epitopes. Experimental results show that our model outperforms existing baselines in terms of MCC, ROC-AUC, PR-AUC, and F1 scores on both linear and conformational epitopes.</description><author>Zhangyu You, Jiahao Ma, Hongzong Li, Ye-Fan Hu, Jian-Dong Huang</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:32:11 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.12029v3</guid></item><item><title>Field-Space Attention for Structure-Preserving Earth System Transformers</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20350v1</link><description>Accurate and physically consistent modeling of Earth system dynamics requires machine-learning architectures that operate directly on continuous geophysical fields and preserve their underlying geometric structure. Here we introduce Field-Space attention, a mechanism for Earth system Transformers that computes attention in the physical domain rather than in a learned latent space. By maintaining all intermediate representations as continuous fields on the sphere, the architecture enables interpretable internal states and facilitates the enforcement of scientific constraints. The model employs a fixed, non-learned multiscale decomposition and learns structure-preserving deformations of the input field, allowing coherent integration of coarse and fine-scale information while avoiding the optimization instabilities characteristic of standard single-scale Vision Transformers. Applied to global temperature super-resolution on a HEALPix grid, Field-Space Transformers converge more rapidly and stably than conventional Vision Transformers and U-Net baselines, while requiring substantially fewer parameters. The explicit preservation of field structure throughout the network allows physical and statistical priors to be embedded directly into the architecture, yielding improved fidelity and reliability in data-driven Earth system modeling. These results position Field-Space Attention as a compact, interpretable, and physically grounded building block for next-generation Earth system prediction and generative modeling frameworks.</description><author>Maximilian Witte, Johannes Meuer, Étienne Plésiat, Christopher Kadow</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:31:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20350v1</guid></item><item><title>C3RL: Rethinking the Combination of Channel-independence and Channel-mixing from Representation Learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.17454v2</link><description>Multivariate time series forecasting has drawn increasing attention due to its practical importance. Existing approaches typically adopt either channel-mixing (CM) or channel-independence (CI) strategies. CM strategy can capture inter-variable dependencies but fails to discern variable-specific temporal patterns. CI strategy improves this aspect but fails to fully exploit cross-variable dependencies like CM. Hybrid strategies based on feature fusion offer limited generalization and interpretability. To address these issues, we propose C3RL, a novel representation learning framework that jointly models both CM and CI strategies. Motivated by contrastive learning in computer vision, C3RL treats the inputs of the two strategies as transposed views and builds a siamese network architecture: one strategy serves as the backbone, while the other complements it. By jointly optimizing contrastive and prediction losses with adaptive weighting, C3RL balances representation and forecasting performance. Extensive experiments on seven models show that C3RL boosts the best-case performance rate to 81.4% for models based on CI strategy and to 76.3% for models based on CM strategy, demonstrating strong generalization and effectiveness.</description><author>Shusen Ma, Yun-Bo Zhao, Yu Kang</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:29:56 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.17454v2</guid></item></channel></rss>