<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Arxivfresh papers</title><link></link><description>Arxiv paper</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 12:01:13 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.0.0</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Biases in the Blind Spot: Detecting What LLMs Fail to Mention</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10117v1</link><description>Large Language Models (LLMs) often provide chain-of-thought (CoT) reasoning traces that appear plausible, but may hide internal biases. We call these *unverbalized biases*. Monitoring models via their stated reasoning is therefore unreliable, and existing bias evaluations typically require predefined categories and hand-crafted datasets. In this work, we introduce a fully automated, black-box pipeline for detecting task-specific unverbalized biases. Given a task dataset, the pipeline uses LLM autoraters to generate candidate bias concepts. It then tests each concept on progressively larger input samples by generating positive and negative variations, and applies statistical techniques for multiple testing and early stopping. A concept is flagged as an unverbalized bias if it yields statistically significant performance differences while not being cited as justification in the model's CoTs. We evaluate our pipeline across six LLMs on three decision tasks (hiring, loan approval, and university admissions). Our technique automatically discovers previously unknown biases in these models (e.g., Spanish fluency, English proficiency, writing formality). In the same run, the pipeline also validates biases that were manually identified by prior work (gender, race, religion, ethnicity). More broadly, our proposed approach provides a practical, scalable path to automatic task-specific bias discovery.</description><author>Iván Arcuschin, David Chanin, Adrià Garriga-Alonso, Oana-Maria Camburu</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:59:56 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10117v1</guid></item><item><title>SAGE: Scalable Agentic 3D Scene Generation for Embodied AI</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10116v1</link><description>Real-world data collection for embodied agents remains costly and unsafe, calling for scalable, realistic, and simulator-ready 3D environments. However, existing scene-generation systems often rely on rule-based or task-specific pipelines, yielding artifacts and physically invalid scenes. We present SAGE, an agentic framework that, given a user-specified embodied task (e.g., "pick up a bowl and place it on the table"), understands the intent and automatically generates simulation-ready environments at scale. The agent couples multiple generators for layout and object composition with critics that evaluate semantic plausibility, visual realism, and physical stability. Through iterative reasoning and adaptive tool selection, it self-refines the scenes until meeting user intent and physical validity. The resulting environments are realistic, diverse, and directly deployable in modern simulators for policy training. Policies trained purely on this data exhibit clear scaling trends and generalize to unseen objects and layouts, demonstrating the promise of simulation-driven scaling for embodied AI. Code, demos, and the SAGE-10k dataset can be found on the project page here: https://nvlabs.github.io/sage.</description><author>Hongchi Xia, Xuan Li, Zhaoshuo Li, Qianli Ma, Jiashu Xu, Ming-Yu Liu, Yin Cui, Tsung-Yi Lin, Wei-Chiu Ma, Shenlong Wang, Shuran Song, Fangyin Wei</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:59:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10116v1</guid></item><item><title>Quantum Multiple Rotation Averaging</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10115v1</link><description>Multiple rotation averaging (MRA) is a fundamental optimization problem in 3D vision and robotics that aims to recover globally consistent absolute rotations from noisy relative measurements. Established classical methods, such as L1-IRLS and Shonan, face limitations including local minima susceptibility and reliance on convex relaxations that fail to preserve the exact manifold geometry, leading to reduced accuracy in high-noise scenarios. We introduce IQARS (Iterative Quantum Annealing for Rotation Synchronization), the first algorithm that reformulates MRA as a sequence of local quadratic non-convex sub-problems executable on quantum annealers after binarization, to leverage inherent hardware advantages. IQARS removes convex relaxation dependence and better preserves non-Euclidean rotation manifold geometry while leveraging quantum tunneling and parallelism for efficient solution space exploration. We evaluate IQARS's performance on synthetic and real-world datasets. While current annealers remain in their nascent phase and only support solving problems of limited scale with constrained performance, we observed that IQARS on D-Wave annealers can already achieve ca. 12% higher accuracy than Shonan, i.e., the best-performing classical method evaluated empirically.</description><author>Shuteng Wang, Natacha Kuete Meli, Michael Möller, Vladislav Golyanik</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:59:54 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10115v1</guid></item><item><title>ConsID-Gen: View-Consistent and Identity-Preserving Image-to-Video Generation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10113v1</link><description>Image-to-Video generation (I2V) animates a static image into a temporally coherent video sequence following textual instructions, yet preserving fine-grained object identity under changing viewpoints remains a persistent challenge. Unlike text-to-video models, existing I2V pipelines often suffer from appearance drift and geometric distortion, artifacts we attribute to the sparsity of single-view 2D observations and weak cross-modal alignment. Here we address this problem from both data and model perspectives. First, we curate ConsIDVid, a large-scale object-centric dataset built with a scalable pipeline for high-quality, temporally aligned videos, and establish ConsIDVid-Bench, where we present a novel benchmarking and evaluation framework for multi-view consistency using metrics sensitive to subtle geometric and appearance deviations. We further propose ConsID-Gen, a view-assisted I2V generation framework that augments the first frame with unposed auxiliary views and fuses semantic and structural cues via a dual-stream visual-geometric encoder as well as a text-visual connector, yielding unified conditioning for a Diffusion Transformer backbone. Experiments across ConsIDVid-Bench demonstrate that ConsID-Gen consistently outperforms in multiple metrics, with the best overall performance surpassing leading video generation models like Wan2.1 and HunyuanVideo, delivering superior identity fidelity and temporal coherence under challenging real-world scenarios. We will release our model and dataset at https://myangwu.github.io/ConsID-Gen.</description><author>Mingyang Wu, Ashirbad Mishra, Soumik Dey, Shuo Xing, Naveen Ravipati, Hansi Wu, Binbin Li, Zhengzhong Tu</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:59:51 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10113v1</guid></item><item><title>Olaf-World: Orienting Latent Actions for Video World Modeling</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10104v1</link><description>Scaling action-controllable world models is limited by the scarcity of action labels. While latent action learning promises to extract control interfaces from unlabeled video, learned latents often fail to transfer across contexts: they entangle scene-specific cues and lack a shared coordinate system. This occurs because standard objectives operate only within each clip, providing no mechanism to align action semantics across contexts. Our key insight is that although actions are unobserved, their semantic effects are observable and can serve as a shared reference. We introduce Seq$Δ$-REPA, a sequence-level control-effect alignment objective that anchors integrated latent action to temporal feature differences from a frozen, self-supervised video encoder. Building on this, we present Olaf-World, a pipeline that pretrains action-conditioned video world models from large-scale passive video. Extensive experiments demonstrate that our method learns a more structured latent action space, leading to stronger zero-shot action transfer and more data-efficient adaptation to new control interfaces than state-of-the-art baselines.</description><author>Yuxin Jiang, Yuchao Gu, Ivor W. Tsang, Mike Zheng Shou</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:58:41 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10104v1</guid></item><item><title>VideoWorld 2: Learning Transferable Knowledge from Real-world Videos</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10102v1</link><description>Learning transferable knowledge from unlabeled video data and applying it in new environments is a fundamental capability of intelligent agents. This work presents VideoWorld 2, which extends VideoWorld and offers the first investigation into learning transferable knowledge directly from raw real-world videos. At its core, VideoWorld 2 introduces a dynamic-enhanced Latent Dynamics Model (dLDM) that decouples action dynamics from visual appearance: a pretrained video diffusion model handles visual appearance modeling, enabling the dLDM to learn latent codes that focus on compact and meaningful task-related dynamics. These latent codes are then modeled autoregressively to learn task policies and support long-horizon reasoning. We evaluate VideoWorld 2 on challenging real-world handcraft making tasks, where prior video generation and latent-dynamics models struggle to operate reliably. Remarkably, VideoWorld 2 achieves up to 70% improvement in task success rate and produces coherent long execution videos. In robotics, we show that VideoWorld 2 can acquire effective manipulation knowledge from the Open-X dataset, which substantially improves task performance on CALVIN. This study reveals the potential of learning transferable world knowledge directly from raw videos, with all code, data, and models to be open-sourced for further research.</description><author>Zhongwei Ren, Yunchao Wei, Xiao Yu, Guixun Luo, Yao Zhao, Bingyi Kang, Jiashi Feng, Xiaojie Jin</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:58:19 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10102v1</guid></item><item><title>Towards Explainable Federated Learning: Understanding the Impact of Differential Privacy</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10100v1</link><description>Data privacy and eXplainable Artificial Intelligence (XAI) are two important aspects for modern Machine Learning systems. To enhance data privacy, recent machine learning models have been designed as a Federated Learning (FL) system. On top of that, additional privacy layers can be added, via Differential Privacy (DP). On the other hand, to improve explainability, ML must consider more interpretable approaches with reduced number of features and less complex internal architecture. In this context, this paper aims to achieve a machine learning (ML) model that combines enhanced data privacy with explainability. So, we propose a FL solution, called Federated EXplainable Trees with Differential Privacy (FEXT-DP), that: (i) is based on Decision Trees, since they are lightweight and have superior explainability than neural networks-based FL systems; (ii) provides additional layer of data privacy protection applying Differential Privacy (DP) to the Tree-Based model. However, there is a side effect adding DP: it harms the explainability of the system. So, this paper also presents the impact of DP protection on the explainability of the ML model. The carried out performance assessment shows improvements of FEXT-DP in terms of a faster training, i.e., numbers of rounds, Mean Squared Error and explainability.</description><author>Júlio Oliveira, Rodrigo Ferreira, André Riker, Glaucio H. S. Carvalho, Eirini Eleni Tsilopoulou</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:58:11 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10100v1</guid></item><item><title>Learning on the Manifold: Unlocking Standard Diffusion Transformers with Representation Encoders</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10099v1</link><description>Leveraging representation encoders for generative modeling offers a path for efficient, high-fidelity synthesis. However, standard diffusion transformers fail to converge on these representations directly. While recent work attributes this to a capacity bottleneck proposing computationally expensive width scaling of diffusion transformers we demonstrate that the failure is fundamentally geometric. We identify Geometric Interference as the root cause: standard Euclidean flow matching forces probability paths through the low-density interior of the hyperspherical feature space of representation encoders, rather than following the manifold surface. To resolve this, we propose Riemannian Flow Matching with Jacobi Regularization (RJF). By constraining the generative process to the manifold geodesics and correcting for curvature-induced error propagation, RJF enables standard Diffusion Transformer architectures to converge without width scaling. Our method RJF enables the standard DiT-B architecture (131M parameters) to converge effectively, achieving an FID of 3.37 where prior methods fail to converge. Code: https://github.com/amandpkr/RJF</description><author>Amandeep Kumar, Vishal M. Patel</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:58:04 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10099v1</guid></item><item><title>VLA-JEPA: Enhancing Vision-Language-Action Model with Latent World Model</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10098v1</link><description>Pretraining Vision-Language-Action (VLA) policies on internet-scale video is appealing, yet current latent-action objectives often learn the wrong thing: they remain anchored to pixel variation rather than action-relevant state transitions, making them vulnerable to appearance bias, nuisance motion, and information leakage. We introduce VLA-JEPA, a JEPA-style pretraining framework that sidesteps these pitfalls by design. The key idea is \emph{leakage-free state prediction}: a target encoder produces latent representations from future frames, while the student pathway sees only the current observation -- future information is used solely as supervision targets, never as input. By predicting in latent space rather than pixel space, VLA-JEPA learns dynamics abstractions that are robust to camera motion and irrelevant background changes. This yields a simple two-stage recipe -- JEPA pretraining followed by action-head fine-tuning -- without the multi-stage complexity of prior latent-action pipelines. Experiments on LIBERO, LIBERO-Plus, SimplerEnv and real-world manipulation tasks show that VLA-JEPA achieves consistent gains in generalization and robustness over existing methods.</description><author>Jingwen Sun, Wenyao Zhang, Zekun Qi, Shaojie Ren, Zezhi Liu, Hanxin Zhu, Guangzhong Sun, Xin Jin, Zhibo Chen</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:58:01 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10098v1</guid></item><item><title>Step-resolved data attribution for looped transformers</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10097v1</link><description>We study how individual training examples shape the internal computation of looped transformers, where a shared block is applied for $τ$ recurrent iterations to enable latent reasoning. Existing training-data influence estimators such as TracIn yield a single scalar score that aggregates over all loop iterations, obscuring when during the recurrent computation a training example matters. We introduce \textit{Step-Decomposed Influence (SDI)}, which decomposes TracIn into a length-$τ$ influence trajectory by unrolling the recurrent computation graph and attributing influence to specific loop iterations. To make SDI practical at transformer scale, we propose a TensorSketch implementation that never materialises per-example gradients. Experiments on looped GPT-style models and algorithmic reasoning tasks show that SDI scales excellently, matches full-gradient baselines with low error and supports a broad range of data attribution and interpretability tasks with per-step insights into the latent reasoning process.</description><author>Georgios Kaissis, David Mildenberger, Juan Felipe Gomez, Martin J. Menten, Eleni Triantafillou</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:57:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10097v1</guid></item><item><title>Causality in Video Diffusers is Separable from Denoising</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10095v1</link><description>Causality -- referring to temporal, uni-directional cause-effect relationships between components -- underlies many complex generative processes, including videos, language, and robot trajectories. Current causal diffusion models entangle temporal reasoning with iterative denoising, applying causal attention across all layers, at every denoising step, and over the entire context. In this paper, we show that the causal reasoning in these models is separable from the multi-step denoising process. Through systematic probing of autoregressive video diffusers, we uncover two key regularities: (1) early layers produce highly similar features across denoising steps, indicating redundant computation along the diffusion trajectory; and (2) deeper layers exhibit sparse cross-frame attention and primarily perform intra-frame rendering. Motivated by these findings, we introduce Separable Causal Diffusion (SCD), a new architecture that explicitly decouples once-per-frame temporal reasoning, via a causal transformer encoder, from multi-step frame-wise rendering, via a lightweight diffusion decoder. Extensive experiments on both pretraining and post-training tasks across synthetic and real benchmarks show that SCD significantly improves throughput and per-frame latency while matching or surpassing the generation quality of strong causal diffusion baselines.</description><author>Xingjian Bai, Guande He, Zhengqi Li, Eli Shechtman, Xun Huang, Zongze Wu</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:57:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10095v1</guid></item><item><title>4RC: 4D Reconstruction via Conditional Querying Anytime and Anywhere</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10094v1</link><description>We present 4RC, a unified feed-forward framework for 4D reconstruction from monocular videos. Unlike existing approaches that typically decouple motion from geometry or produce limited 4D attributes such as sparse trajectories or two-view scene flow, 4RC learns a holistic 4D representation that jointly captures dense scene geometry and motion dynamics. At its core, 4RC introduces a novel encode-once, query-anywhere and anytime paradigm: a transformer backbone encodes the entire video into a compact spatio-temporal latent space, from which a conditional decoder can efficiently query 3D geometry and motion for any query frame at any target timestamp. To facilitate learning, we represent per-view 4D attributes in a minimally factorized form by decomposing them into base geometry and time-dependent relative motion. Extensive experiments demonstrate that 4RC outperforms prior and concurrent methods across a wide range of 4D reconstruction tasks.</description><author>Yihang Luo, Shangchen Zhou, Yushi Lan, Xingang Pan, Chen Change Loy</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:57:04 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10094v1</guid></item><item><title>Noisy-Pair Robust Representation Alignment for Positive-Unlabeled Learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.01278v2</link><description>Positive-Unlabeled (PU) learning aims to train a binary classifier (positive vs. negative) where only limited positive data and abundant unlabeled data are available. While widely applicable, state-of-the-art PU learning methods substantially underperform their supervised counterparts on complex datasets, especially without auxiliary negatives or pre-estimated parameters (e.g., a 14.26% gap on CIFAR-100 dataset). We identify the primary bottleneck as the challenge of learning discriminative representations under unreliable supervision. To tackle this challenge, we propose NcPU, a non-contrastive PU learning framework that requires no auxiliary information. NcPU combines a noisy-pair robust supervised non-contrastive loss (NoiSNCL), which aligns intra-class representations despite unreliable supervision, with a phantom label disambiguation (PLD) scheme that supplies conservative negative supervision via regret-based label updates. Theoretically, NoiSNCL and PLD can iteratively benefit each other from the perspective of the Expectation-Maximization framework. Empirically, extensive experiments demonstrate that: (1) NoiSNCL enables simple PU methods to achieve competitive performance; and (2) NcPU achieves substantial improvements over state-of-the-art PU methods across diverse datasets, including challenging datasets on post-disaster building damage mapping, highlighting its promise for real-world applications. Code: Code will be open-sourced after review.</description><author>Hengwei Zhao, Zhengzhong Tu, Zhuo Zheng, Wei Wang, Junjue Wang, Rusty Feagin, Wenzhe Jiao</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:56:09 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.01278v2</guid></item><item><title>Quantum-Audit: Evaluating the Reasoning Limits of LLMs on Quantum Computing</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10092v1</link><description>Language models have become practical tools for quantum computing education and research, from summarizing technical papers to explaining theoretical concepts and answering questions about recent developments in the field. While existing benchmarks evaluate quantum code generation and circuit design, their understanding of quantum computing concepts has not been systematically measured. Quantum-Audit addresses this gap with 2,700 questions covering core quantum computing topics. We evaluate 26 models from leading organizations. Our benchmark comprises 1,000 expert-written questions, 1,000 questions extracted from research papers using LLMs and validated by experts, plus an additional 700 questions including 350 open-ended questions and 350 questions with false premises to test whether models can correct erroneous assumptions. Human participants scored between 23% and 86%, with experts averaging 74%. Top-performing models exceeded the expert average, with Claude Opus 4.5 reaching 84% accuracy, though top models showed an average 12-point accuracy drop on expert-written questions compared to LLM-generated ones. Performance declined further on advanced topics, dropping to 73% on security questions. Additionally, models frequently accepted and reinforced false premises embedded in questions instead of identifying them, with accuracy below 66% on these critical reasoning tasks.</description><author>Mohamed Afane, Kayla Laufer, Wenqi Wei, Ying Mao, Junaid Farooq, Ying Wang, Juntao Chen</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:56:04 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10092v1</guid></item><item><title>Agent World Model: Infinity Synthetic Environments for Agentic Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10090v1</link><description>Recent advances in large language model (LLM) have empowered autonomous agents to perform complex tasks that require multi-turn interactions with tools and environments. However, scaling such agent training is limited by the lack of diverse and reliable environments. In this paper, we propose Agent World Model (AWM), a fully synthetic environment generation pipeline. Using this pipeline, we scale to 1,000 environments covering everyday scenarios, in which agents can interact with rich toolsets (35 tools per environment on average) and obtain high-quality observations. Notably, these environments are code-driven and backed by databases, providing more reliable and consistent state transitions than environments simulated by LLMs. Moreover, they enable more efficient agent interaction compared with collecting trajectories from realistic environments. To demonstrate the effectiveness of this resource, we perform large-scale reinforcement learning for multi-turn tool-use agents. Thanks to the fully executable environments and accessible database states, we can also design reliable reward functions. Experiments on three benchmarks show that training exclusively in synthetic environments, rather than benchmark-specific ones, yields strong out-of-distribution generalization. The code is available at https://github.com/Snowflake-Labs/agent-world-model.</description><author>Zhaoyang Wang, Canwen Xu, Boyi Liu, Yite Wang, Siwei Han, Zhewei Yao, Huaxiu Yao, Yuxiong He</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:55:41 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10090v1</guid></item><item><title>Story-Iter: A Training-free Iterative Paradigm for Long Story Visualization</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.06244v2</link><description>This paper introduces Story-Iter, a new training-free iterative paradigm to enhance long-story generation. Unlike existing methods that rely on fixed reference images to construct a complete story, our approach features a novel external iterative paradigm, extending beyond the internal iterative denoising steps of diffusion models, to continuously refine each generated image by incorporating all reference images from the previous round. To achieve this, we propose a plug-and-play, training-free global reference cross-attention (GRCA) module, modeling all reference frames with global embeddings, ensuring semantic consistency in long sequences. By progressively incorporating holistic visual context and text constraints, our iterative paradigm enables precise generation with fine-grained interactions, optimizing the story visualization step-by-step. Extensive experiments in the official story visualization dataset and our long story benchmark demonstrate that Story-Iter's state-of-the-art performance in long-story visualization (up to 100 frames) excels in both semantic consistency and fine-grained interactions.</description><author>Jiawei Mao, Xiaoke Huang, Yunfei Xie, Yuanqi Chang, Mude Hui, Bingjie Xu, Zeyu Zheng, Zirui Wang, Cihang Xie, Yuyin Zhou</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:53:34 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.06244v2</guid></item><item><title>CODE-SHARP: Continuous Open-ended Discovery and Evolution of Skills as Hierarchical Reward Programs</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10085v1</link><description>Developing agents capable of open-endedly discovering and learning novel skills is a grand challenge in Artificial Intelligence. While reinforcement learning offers a powerful framework for training agents to master complex skills, it typically relies on hand-designed reward functions. This is infeasible for open-ended skill discovery, where the set of meaningful skills is not known a priori. While recent methods have shown promising results towards automating reward function design, they remain limited to refining rewards for pre-defined tasks. To address this limitation, we introduce Continuous Open-ended Discovery and Evolution of Skills as Hierarchical Reward Programs (CODE-SHARP), a novel framework leveraging Foundation Models (FM) to open-endedly expand and refine a hierarchical skill archive, structured as a directed graph of executable reward functions in code. We show that a goal-conditioned agent trained exclusively on the rewards generated by the discovered SHARP skills learns to solve increasingly long-horizon goals in the Craftax environment. When composed by a high-level FM-based planner, the discovered skills enable a single goal-conditioned agent to solve complex, long-horizon tasks, outperforming both pretrained agents and task-specific expert policies by over $134$% on average. We will open-source our code and provide additional videos $\href{https://sites.google.com/view/code-sharp/homepage}{here}$.</description><author>Richard Bornemann, Pierluigi Vito Amadori, Antoine Cully</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:51:39 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10085v1</guid></item><item><title>CyberExplorer: Benchmarking LLM Offensive Security Capabilities in a Real-World Attacking Simulation Environment</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.08023v2</link><description>Real-world offensive security operations are inherently open-ended: attackers explore unknown attack surfaces, revise hypotheses under uncertainty, and operate without guaranteed success. Existing LLM-based offensive agent evaluations rely on closed-world settings with predefined goals and binary success criteria. To address this gap, we introduce CyberExplorer, an evaluation suite with two core components: (1) an open-environment benchmark built on a virtual machine hosting 40 vulnerable web services derived from real-world CTF challenges, where agents autonomously perform reconnaissance, target selection, and exploitation without prior knowledge of vulnerability locations; and (2) a reactive multi-agent framework supporting dynamic exploration without predefined plans. CyberExplorer enables fine-grained evaluation beyond flag recovery, capturing interaction dynamics, coordination behavior, failure modes, and vulnerability discovery signals-bridging the gap between benchmarks and realistic multi-target attack scenarios.</description><author>Nanda Rani, Kimberly Milner, Minghao Shao, Meet Udeshi, Haoran Xi, Venkata Sai Charan Putrevu, Saksham Aggarwal, Sandeep K. Shukla, Prashanth Krishnamurthy, Farshad Khorrami, Muhammad Shafique, Ramesh Karri</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:48:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.08023v2</guid></item><item><title>Anagent For Enhancing Scientific Table &amp; Figure Analysis</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10081v1</link><description>In scientific research, analysis requires accurately interpreting complex multimodal knowledge, integrating evidence from different sources, and drawing inferences grounded in domain-specific knowledge. However, current artificial intelligence (AI) systems struggle to consistently demonstrate such capabilities. The complexity and variability of scientific tables and figures, combined with heterogeneous structures and long-context requirements, pose fundamental obstacles to scientific table \&amp; figure analysis. To quantify these challenges, we introduce AnaBench, a large-scale benchmark featuring $63,178$ instances from nine scientific domains, systematically categorized along seven complexity dimensions. To tackle these challenges, we propose Anagent, a multi-agent framework for enhanced scientific table \&amp; figure analysis through four specialized agents: Planner decomposes tasks into actionable subtasks, Expert retrieves task-specific information through targeted tool execution, Solver synthesizes information to generate coherent analysis, and Critic performs iterative refinement through five-dimensional quality assessment. We further develop modular training strategies that leverage supervised finetuning and specialized reinforcement learning to optimize individual capabilities while maintaining effective collaboration. Comprehensive evaluation across 170 subdomains demonstrates that Anagent achieves substantial improvements, up to $\uparrow 13.43\%$ in training-free settings and $\uparrow 42.12\%$ with finetuning, while revealing that task-oriented reasoning and context-aware problem-solving are essential for high-quality scientific table \&amp; figure analysis. Our project page: https://xhguo7.github.io/Anagent/.</description><author>Xuehang Guo, Zhiyong Lu, Tom Hope, Qingyun Wang</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:46:28 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10081v1</guid></item><item><title>Can Image Splicing and Copy-Move Forgery Be Detected by the Same Model? Forensim: An Attention-Based State-Space Approach</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10079v1</link><description>We introduce Forensim, an attention-based state-space framework for image forgery detection that jointly localizes both manipulated (target) and source regions. Unlike traditional approaches that rely solely on artifact cues to detect spliced or forged areas, Forensim is designed to capture duplication patterns crucial for understanding context. In scenarios such as protest imagery, detecting only the forged region, for example a duplicated act of violence inserted into a peaceful crowd, can mislead interpretation, highlighting the need for joint source-target localization. Forensim outputs three-class masks (pristine, source, target) and supports detection of both splicing and copy-move forgeries within a unified architecture. We propose a visual state-space model that leverages normalized attention maps to identify internal similarities, paired with a region-based block attention module to distinguish manipulated regions. This design enables end-to-end training and precise localization. Forensim achieves state-of-the-art performance on standard benchmarks. We also release CMFD-Anything, a new dataset addressing limitations of existing copy-move forgery datasets.</description><author>Soumyaroop Nandi, Prem Natarajan</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:46:04 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10079v1</guid></item><item><title>Designing Multi-Robot Ground Video Sensemaking with Public Safety Professionals</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.08882v2</link><description>Videos from fleets of ground robots can advance public safety by providing scalable situational awareness and reducing professionals' burden. Yet little is known about how to design and integrate multi-robot videos into public safety workflows. Collaborating with six police agencies, we examined how such videos could be made practical. In Study 1, we presented the first testbed for multi-robot ground video sensemaking. The testbed includes 38 events-of-interest (EoI) relevant to public safety, a dataset of 20 robot patrol videos (10 day/night pairs) covering EoI types, and 6 design requirements aimed at improving current video sensemaking practices. In Study 2, we built MRVS, a tool that augments multi-robot patrol video streams with a prompt-engineered video understanding model. Participants reported reduced manual workload and greater confidence with LLM-based explanations, while noting concerns about false alarms and privacy. We conclude with implications for designing future multi-robot video sensemaking tools.</description><author>Puqi Zhou, Ali Asgarov, Aafiya Hussain, Wonjoon Park, Amit Paudyal, Sameep Shrestha, Chia-wei Tang, Michael F. Lighthiser, Michael R. Hieb, Xuesu Xiao, Chris Thomas, Sungsoo Ray Hong</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:41:40 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.08882v2</guid></item><item><title>CAPID: Context-Aware PII Detection for Question-Answering Systems</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10074v1</link><description>Detecting personally identifiable information (PII) in user queries is critical for ensuring privacy in question-answering systems. Current approaches mainly redact all PII, disregarding the fact that some of them may be contextually relevant to the user's question, resulting in a degradation of response quality. Large language models (LLMs) might be able to help determine which PII are relevant, but due to their closed source nature and lack of privacy guarantees, they are unsuitable for sensitive data processing. To achieve privacy-preserving PII detection, we propose CAPID, a practical approach that fine-tunes a locally owned small language model (SLM) that filters sensitive information before it is passed to LLMs for QA. However, existing datasets do not capture the context-dependent relevance of PII needed to train such a model effectively. To fill this gap, we propose a synthetic data generation pipeline that leverages LLMs to produce a diverse, domain-rich dataset spanning multiple PII types and relevance levels. Using this dataset, we fine-tune an SLM to detect PII spans, classify their types, and estimate contextual relevance. Our experiments show that relevance-aware PII detection with a fine-tuned SLM substantially outperforms existing baselines in span, relevance and type accuracy while preserving significantly higher downstream utility under anonymization.</description><author>Mariia Ponomarenko, Sepideh Abedini, Masoumeh Shafieinejad, D. B. Emerson, Shubhankar Mohapatra, Xi He</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:41:31 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10074v1</guid></item><item><title>Data-efficient and Interpretable Inverse Materials Design using a Disentangled Variational Autoencoder</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.06740v3</link><description>Inverse materials design has proven successful in accelerating novel material discovery. Many inverse materials design methods use unsupervised learning where a latent space is learned to offer a compact description of materials representations. A latent space learned this way is likely to be entangled, in terms of the target property and other properties of the materials. This makes the inverse design process ambiguous. Here, we present a semi-supervised learning approach based on a disentangled variational autoencoder to learn a probabilistic relationship between features, latent variables and target properties. This approach is data efficient because it combines all labelled and unlabelled data in a coherent manner, and it uses expert-informed prior distributions to improve model robustness even with limited labelled data. It is in essence interpretable, as the learnable target property is disentangled out of the other properties of the materials, and an extra layer of interpretability can be provided by a post-hoc analysis of the classification head of the model. We demonstrate this new approach on an experimental high-entropy alloy dataset with chemical compositions as input and single-phase formation as the single target property. High-entropy alloys were chosen as example materials because of the vast chemical space of their possible combinations of compositions and atomic configurations. While single property is used in this work, the disentangled model can be extended to customize for inverse design of materials with multiple target properties.</description><author>Cheng Zeng, Zulqarnain Khan, Nathan L. Post</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:34:17 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.06740v3</guid></item><item><title>Features as Rewards: Scalable Supervision for Open-Ended Tasks via Interpretability</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10067v1</link><description>Language models trained on large-scale datasets have been shown to learn features that encode abstract concepts such as factuality or intent. Such features are traditionally used for test-time monitoring or steering. We present an alternative affordance: features as scalable supervision for open-ended tasks. We consider the case of hallucination-reduction as a desirable, yet open-ended behavior and design a reinforcement learning (RL) pipeline, titled RLFR (Reinforcement Learning from Feature Rewards), that uses features as reward functions. Grounded in a novel probing framework that identifies candidate hallucinated claims, our pipeline teaches a model to intervene and correct its completions when it is uncertain of their factuality. Furthermore, the pipeline enables scalable test-time compute, guided once more by our reward features. This end-to-end process operationalized on Gemma-3-12B-IT results in a policy that is 58% less likely to hallucinate compared to the original model, while preserving performance on standard benchmarks. Taken together, by grounding supervision in the language of features, this paper introduces a novel paradigm in the use of interpretability for learning open-ended tasks.</description><author>Aaditya Vikram Prasad, Connor Watts, Jack Merullo, Dhruvil Gala, Owen Lewis, Thomas McGrath, Ekdeep Singh Lubana</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:33:45 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10067v1</guid></item><item><title>Variational Sparse Paired Autoencoders (vsPAIR) for Inverse Problems and Uncertainty Quantification</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.02948v2</link><description>Inverse problems are fundamental to many scientific and engineering disciplines; they arise when one seeks to reconstruct hidden, underlying quantities from noisy measurements. Many applications demand not just point estimates but interpretable uncertainty. Providing fast inference alongside uncertainty estimates remains challenging yet desirable in numerous applications. We propose the Variational Sparse Paired Autoencoder (vsPAIR) to address this challenge. The architecture pairs a standard VAE encoding observations with a sparse VAE encoding quantities of interest, connected through a learned latent mapping. The variational structure enables uncertainty estimation, the paired architecture encourages interpretability by anchoring QoI representations to clean data, and sparse encodings provide structure by concentrating information into identifiable factors rather than diffusing across all dimensions. To validate the effectiveness of our proposed architecture, we conduct experiments on blind inpainting and computed tomography, demonstrating that vsPAIR is a capable inverse problem solver that can provide interpretable and structured uncertainty estimates.</description><author>Jack Michael Solomon, Rishi Leburu, Matthias Chung</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:33:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.02948v2</guid></item><item><title>From Spatial to Actions: Grounding Vision-Language-Action Model in Spatial Foundation Priors</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.17439v2</link><description>Existing vision-language-action (VLA) models act in 3D real-world but are typically built on 2D encoders, leaving a spatial reasoning gap that limits generalization and adaptability. Recent 3D integration techniques for VLAs either require specialized sensors and transfer poorly across modalities, or inject weak cues that lack geometry and degrade vision-language alignment. In this work, we introduce FALCON (From Spatial to Action), a novel paradigm that injects rich 3D spatial tokens into the action head. FALCON leverages spatial foundation models to deliver strong geometric priors from RGB alone, and includes an Embodied Spatial Model that can optionally fuse depth, or pose for higher fidelity when available, without retraining or architectural changes. To preserve language reasoning, spatial tokens are consumed by a Spatial-Enhanced Action Head rather than being concatenated into the vision-language backbone. These designs enable FALCON to address limitations in spatial representation, modality transferability, and alignment. In comprehensive evaluations across three simulation benchmarks and eleven real-world tasks, our proposed FALCON achieves state-of-the-art performance, consistently surpasses competitive baselines, and remains robust under clutter, spatial-prompt conditioning, and variations in object scale and height.</description><author>Zhengshen Zhang, Hao Li, Yalun Dai, Zhengbang Zhu, Lei Zhou, Chenchen Liu, Dong Wang, Francis E. H. Tay, Sijin Chen, Ziwei Liu, Yuxiao Liu, Xinghang Li, Pan Zhou</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:32:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.17439v2</guid></item><item><title>Chain of Mindset: Reasoning with Adaptive Cognitive Modes</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10063v1</link><description>Human problem-solving is never the repetition of a single mindset, by which we mean a distinct mode of cognitive processing. When tackling a specific task, we do not rely on a single mindset; instead, we integrate multiple mindsets within the single solution process. However, existing LLM reasoning methods fall into a common trap: they apply the same fixed mindset across all steps, overlooking that different stages of solving the same problem require fundamentally different mindsets. This single-minded assumption prevents models from reaching the next level of intelligence. To address this limitation, we propose Chain of Mindset (CoM), a training-free agentic framework that enables step-level adaptive mindset orchestration. CoM decomposes reasoning into four functionally heterogeneous mindsets: Spatial, Convergent, Divergent, and Algorithmic. A Meta-Agent dynamically selects the optimal mindset based on the evolving reasoning state, while a bidirectional Context Gate filters cross-module information flow to maintain effectiveness and efficiency. Experiments across six challenging benchmarks spanning mathematics, code generation, scientific QA, and spatial reasoning demonstrate that CoM achieves state-of-the-art performance, outperforming the strongest baseline by 4.96\% and 4.72\% in overall accuracy on Qwen3-VL-32B-Instruct and Gemini-2.0-Flash, while balancing reasoning efficiency. Our code is publicly available at \href{https://github.com/QuantaAlpha/chain-of-mindset}{https://github.com/QuantaAlpha/chain-of-mindset}.</description><author>Tianyi Jiang, Arctanx An, Hengyi Feng, Naixin Zhai, Haodong Li, Xiaomin Yu, Jiahui Liu, Hanwen Du, Shuo Zhang, Zhi Yang, Jie Huang, Yuhua Li, Yongxin Ni, Huacan Wang, Ronghao Chen</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:31:47 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10063v1</guid></item><item><title>Vendi Novelty Scores for Out-of-Distribution Detection</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10062v1</link><description>Out-of-distribution (OOD) detection is critical for the safe deployment of machine learning systems. Existing post-hoc detectors typically rely on model confidence scores or likelihood estimates in feature space, often under restrictive distributional assumptions. In this work, we introduce a third paradigm and formulate OOD detection from a diversity perspective. We propose the Vendi Novelty Score (VNS), an OOD detector based on the Vendi Scores (VS), a family of similarity-based diversity metrics. VNS quantifies how much a test sample increases the VS of the in-distribution feature set, providing a principled notion of novelty that does not require density modeling. VNS is linear-time, non-parametric, and naturally combines class-conditional (local) and dataset-level (global) novelty signals. Across multiple image classification benchmarks and network architectures, VNS achieves state-of-the-art OOD detection performance. Remarkably, VNS retains this performance when computed using only 1% of the training data, enabling deployment in memory- or access-constrained settings.</description><author>Amey P. Pasarkar, Adji Bousso Dieng</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:30:29 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10062v1</guid></item><item><title>Evaluating Disentangled Representations for Controllable Music Generation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10058v1</link><description>Recent approaches in music generation rely on disentangled representations, often labeled as structure and timbre or local and global, to enable controllable synthesis. Yet the underlying properties of these embeddings remain underexplored. In this work, we evaluate such disentangled representations in a set of music audio models for controllable generation using a probing-based framework that goes beyond standard downstream tasks. The selected models reflect diverse unsupervised disentanglement strategies, including inductive biases, data augmentations, adversarial objectives, and staged training procedures. We further isolate specific strategies to analyze their effect. Our analysis spans four key axes: informativeness, equivariance, invariance, and disentanglement, which are assessed across datasets, tasks, and controlled transformations. Our findings reveal inconsistencies between intended and actual semantics of the embeddings, suggesting that current strategies fall short of producing truly disentangled representations, and prompting a re-examination of how controllability is approached in music generation.</description><author>Laura Ibáñez-Martínez, Chukwuemeka Nkama, Andrea Poltronieri, Xavier Serra, Martín Rocamora</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:25:04 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10058v1</guid></item><item><title>WildCat: Near-Linear Attention in Theory and Practice</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10056v1</link><description>We introduce WildCat, a high-accuracy, low-cost approach to compressing the attention mechanism in neural networks. While attention is a staple of modern network architectures, it is also notoriously expensive to deploy due to resource requirements that scale quadratically with the input sequence length $n$. WildCat avoids these quadratic costs by only attending over a small weighted coreset. Crucially, we select the coreset using a fast but spectrally-accurate subsampling algorithm -- randomly pivoted Cholesky -- and weight the elements optimally to minimise reconstruction error. Remarkably, given bounded inputs, WildCat approximates exact attention with super-polynomial $O(n^{-\sqrt{\log(\log(n))}})$ error decay while running in near-linear $O(n^{1+o(1)})$ time. In contrast, prior practical approximations either lack error guarantees or require quadratic runtime to guarantee such high fidelity. We couple this advance with a GPU-optimized PyTorch implementation and a suite of benchmark experiments demonstrating the benefits of WildCat for image generation, image classification, and language model KV cache compression.</description><author>Tobias Schröder, Lester Mackey</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:22:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10056v1</guid></item><item><title>Universal computation is intrinsic to language model decoding</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.08061v2</link><description>Language models now provide an interface to express and often solve general problems in natural language, yet their ultimate computational capabilities remain a major topic of scientific debate. Unlike a formal computer, a language model is trained to autoregressively predict successive elements in human-generated text. We prove that chaining a language model's autoregressive output is sufficient to perform universal computation. That is, a language model can simulate the execution of any algorithm on any input. The challenge of eliciting desired computational behaviour can thus be reframed in terms of programmability: the ease of finding a suitable prompt. Strikingly, we demonstrate that even randomly initialized language models are capable of universal computation before training. This implies that training does not give rise to computational expressiveness -- rather, it improves programmability, enabling a natural language interface for accessing these intrinsic capabilities.</description><author>Alex Lewandowski, Marlos C. Machado, Dale Schuurmans</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:21:22 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.08061v2</guid></item><item><title>From Moderation to Mediation: Can LLMs Serve as Mediators in Online Flame Wars?</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03005v3</link><description>The rapid advancement of large language models (LLMs) has opened new possibilities for AI for good applications. As LLMs increasingly mediate online communication, their potential to foster empathy and constructive dialogue becomes an important frontier for responsible AI research. This work explores whether LLMs can serve not only as moderators that detect harmful content, but as mediators capable of understanding and de-escalating online conflicts. Our framework decomposes mediation into two subtasks: judgment, where an LLM evaluates the fairness and emotional dynamics of a conversation, and steering, where it generates empathetic, de-escalatory messages to guide participants toward resolution. To assess mediation quality, we construct a large Reddit-based dataset and propose a multi-stage evaluation pipeline combining principle-based scoring, user simulation, and human comparison. Experiments show that API-based models outperform open-source counterparts in both reasoning and intervention alignment when doing mediation. Our findings highlight both the promise and limitations of current LLMs as emerging agents for online social mediation.</description><author>Dawei Li, Abdullah Alnaibari, Arslan Bisharat, Manny Sandoval, Deborah Hall, Yasin Silva, Huan Liu</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:19:05 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.03005v3</guid></item><item><title>Spatio-Temporal Attention for Consistent Video Semantic Segmentation in Automated Driving</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10052v1</link><description>Deep neural networks, especially transformer-based architectures, have achieved remarkable success in semantic segmentation for environmental perception. However, existing models process video frames independently, thus failing to leverage temporal consistency, which could significantly improve both accuracy and stability in dynamic scenes. In this work, we propose a Spatio-Temporal Attention (STA) mechanism that extends transformer attention blocks to incorporate multi-frame context, enabling robust temporal feature representations for video semantic segmentation. Our approach modifies standard self-attention to process spatio-temporal feature sequences while maintaining computational efficiency and requiring minimal changes to existing architectures. STA demonstrates broad applicability across diverse transformer architectures and remains effective across both lightweight and larger-scale models. A comprehensive evaluation on the Cityscapes and BDD100k datasets shows substantial improvements of 9.20 percentage points in temporal consistency metrics and up to 1.76 percentage points in mean intersection over union compared to single-frame baselines. These results demonstrate STA as an effective architectural enhancement for video-based semantic segmentation applications.</description><author>Serin Varghese, Kevin Ross, Fabian Hueger, Kira Maag</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:18:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10052v1</guid></item><item><title>Knowledge-Guided Masked Autoencoder with Linear Spectral Mixing and Spectral-Angle-Aware Reconstruction</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.12445v2</link><description>Integrating domain knowledge into deep learning has emerged as a promising direction for improving model interpretability, generalization, and data efficiency. In this work, we present a novel knowledge-guided ViT-based Masked Autoencoder that embeds scientific domain knowledge within the self-supervised reconstruction process. Instead of relying solely on data-driven optimization, our proposed approach incorporates the Linear Spectral Mixing Model (LSMM) as a physical constraint and physically-based Spectral Angle Mapper (SAM), ensuring that learned representations adhere to known structural relationships between observed signals and their latent components. The framework jointly optimizes LSMM and SAM loss with a conventional Huber loss objective, promoting both numerical accuracy and geometric consistency in the feature space. This knowledge-guided design enhances reconstruction fidelity, stabilizes training under limited supervision, and yields interpretable latent representations grounded in physical principles. The experimental findings indicate that the proposed model substantially enhances reconstruction quality and improves downstream task performance, highlighting the promise of embedding physics-informed inductive biases within transformer-based self-supervised learning.</description><author>Abdul Matin, Rupasree Dey, Tanjim Bin Faruk, Shrideep Pallickara, Sangmi Lee Pallickara</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:18:19 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.12445v2</guid></item><item><title>Long Chain-of-Thought Compression via Fine-Grained Group Policy Optimization</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10048v1</link><description>Large Language Models (LLMs) often generate unnecessarily verbose Chain-of-Thought (CoT) reasoning that increases computational costs and latency without proportional performance gains. In this paper, we propose \textbf{F}ine-grained \textbf{G}roup policy \textbf{O}ptimization (\textbf{FGO}), a Reinforcement Learning (RL) algorithm that refines group responses by subdividing them and assigning appropriate weights based on length and entropy, thereby enabling effective CoT compression. Meanwhile, as an enhanced variant of Group Relative Policy Optimization (GRPO), FGO successfully addresses two major limitations of the GRPO: inefficient data utilization and entropy collapse. We evaluate FGO on multiple reasoning LLMs and benchmarks, including MATH500, AIME24, AMC23, and Minerva. Experimental results show that FGO achieves efficient CoT compression without degrading performance, and simultaneously resolves the key limitations of GRPO.</description><author>Xinchen Han, Hossam Afifi, Michel Marot, Xilu Wang, Lu Yin</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:15:58 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10048v1</guid></item><item><title>Conformal Prediction Sets for Instance Segmentation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10045v1</link><description>Current instance segmentation models achieve high performance on average predictions, but lack principled uncertainty quantification: their outputs are not calibrated, and there is no guarantee that a predicted mask is close to the ground truth. To address this limitation, we introduce a conformal prediction algorithm to generate adaptive confidence sets for instance segmentation. Given an image and a pixel coordinate query, our algorithm generates a confidence set of instance predictions for that pixel, with a provable guarantee for the probability that at least one of the predictions has high Intersection-Over-Union (IoU) with the true object instance mask. We apply our algorithm to instance segmentation examples in agricultural field delineation, cell segmentation, and vehicle detection. Empirically, we find that our prediction sets vary in size based on query difficulty and attain the target coverage, outperforming existing baselines such as Learn Then Test, Conformal Risk Control, and morphological dilation-based methods. We provide versions of the algorithm with asymptotic and finite sample guarantees.</description><author>Kerri Lu, Dan M. Kluger, Stephen Bates, Sherrie Wang</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:15:06 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10045v1</guid></item><item><title>How to Purchase Labels? A Cost-Effective Approach Using Active Learning Markets</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.20605v3</link><description>We introduce and analyse active learning markets as a way to purchase labels, in situations where analysts aim to acquire additional data to improve model fitting, or to better train models for predictive analytics applications. This comes in contrast to the many proposals that already exist to purchase features and examples. By originally formalising the market clearing as an optimisation problem, we integrate budget constraints and improvement thresholds into the label acquisition process. We focus on a single-buyer-multiple-seller setup and propose the use of two active learning strategies (variance based and query-by-committee based), paired with distinct pricing mechanisms. They are compared to benchmark baselines including random sampling and a greedy knapsack heuristic. The proposed strategies are validated on real-world datasets from two critical application domains: real estate pricing and energy forecasting. Results demonstrate the robustness of our approach, consistently achieving superior performance with fewer labels acquired compared to conventional methods. Our proposal comprises an easy-to-implement practical solution for optimising data acquisition in resource-constrained environments.</description><author>Xiwen Huang, Pierre Pinson</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:12:04 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.20605v3</guid></item><item><title>Optimistic World Models: Efficient Exploration in Model-Based Deep Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10044v1</link><description>Efficient exploration remains a central challenge in reinforcement learning (RL), particularly in sparse-reward environments. We introduce Optimistic World Models (OWMs), a principled and scalable framework for optimistic exploration that brings classical reward-biased maximum likelihood estimation (RBMLE) from adaptive control into deep RL. In contrast to upper confidence bound (UCB)-style exploration methods, OWMs incorporate optimism directly into model learning by augmentation with an optimistic dynamics loss that biases imagined transitions toward higher-reward outcomes. This fully gradient-based loss requires neither uncertainty estimates nor constrained optimization. Our approach is plug-and-play with existing world model frameworks, preserving scalability while requiring only minimal modifications to standard training procedures. We instantiate OWMs within two state-of-the-art world model architectures, leading to Optimistic DreamerV3 and Optimistic STORM, which demonstrate significant improvements in sample efficiency and cumulative return compared to their baseline counterparts.</description><author>Akshay Mete, Shahid Aamir Sheikh, Tzu-Hsiang Lin, Dileep Kalathil, P. R. Kumar</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:11:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10044v1</guid></item><item><title>In-Context Learning Without Copying</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.05743v2</link><description>Induction heads are attention heads that perform inductive copying by matching patterns from earlier context and copying their continuations verbatim. As models develop induction heads, they experience a sharp drop in training loss, a phenomenon cited as evidence that induction heads may underlie a wide range of in-context learning (ICL) capabilities. In this work, we investigate whether induction heads are a necessary building block for learning abstractive ICL capabilities (i.e., tasks where the answer is not contained in the input context), or whether such capabilities can emerge independently. We propose Hapax, a training regime that omits the loss contribution of tokens predictable by induction heads. Despite a significant reduction in inductive copying, abstractive ICL capabilities are preserved, with the model achieving higher accuracy than the vanilla model on 13 out of 21 tasks, even though 31.7% of tokens are omitted from the loss. Furthermore, our model achieves lower loss values on token positions that induction heads cannot predict. Mechanistic analysis shows that models trained with Hapax develop fewer and weaker induction heads despite preserving abstractive ICL capabilities. Our findings suggest that the developmental link between induction heads and abstractive ICL capabilities is weaker than previously hypothesized.</description><author>Kerem Sahin, Sheridan Feucht, Adam Belfki, Jannik Brinkmann, Aaron Mueller, David Bau, Chris Wendler</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:10:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.05743v2</guid></item><item><title>Simple Image Processing and Similarity Measures Can Link Data Samples across Databases through Brain MRI</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10043v1</link><description>Head Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) is routinely collected and shared for research under strict regulatory frameworks. These frameworks require removing potential identifiers before sharing. But, even after skull stripping, the brain parenchyma contains unique signatures that can match other MRIs from the same participants across databases, posing a privacy risk if additional data features are available. Current regulatory frameworks often mandate evaluating such risks based on the assessment of a certain level of reasonableness. Prior studies have already suggested that a brain MRI could enable participant linkage, but they have relied on training-based or computationally intensive methods. Here, we demonstrate that linking an individual's skull-stripped T1-weighted MRI, which may lead to re-identification if other identifiers are available, is possible using standard preprocessing followed by image similarity computation. Nearly perfect linkage accuracy was achieved in matching data samples across various time intervals, scanner types, spatial resolutions, and acquisition protocols, despite potential cognitive decline, simulating MRI matching across databases. These results aim to contribute meaningfully to the development of thoughtful, forward-looking policies in medical data sharing.</description><author>Gaurang Sharma, Harri Polonen, Juha Pajula, Jutta Suksi, Jussi Tohka</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:10:12 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10043v1</guid></item><item><title>Fake-HR1: Rethinking reasoning of vision language model for synthetic image detection</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10042v1</link><description>Recent studies have demonstrated that incorporating Chain-of-Thought (CoT) reasoning into the detection process can enhance a model's ability to detect synthetic images. However, excessively lengthy reasoning incurs substantial resource overhead, including token consumption and latency, which is particularly redundant when handling obviously generated forgeries. To address this issue, we propose Fake-HR1, a large-scale hybrid-reasoning model that, to the best of our knowledge, is the first to adaptively determine whether reasoning is necessary based on the characteristics of the generative detection task. To achieve this, we design a two-stage training framework: we first perform Hybrid Fine-Tuning (HFT) for cold-start initialization, followed by online reinforcement learning with Hybrid-Reasoning Grouped Policy Optimization (HGRPO) to implicitly learn when to select an appropriate reasoning mode. Experimental results show that Fake-HR1 adaptively performs reasoning across different types of queries, surpassing existing LLMs in both reasoning ability and generative detection performance, while significantly improving response efficiency.</description><author>Changjiang Jiang, Xinkuan Sha, Fengchang Yu, Jingjing Liu, Jian Liu, Mingqi Fang, Chenfeng Zhang, Wei Lu</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:10:08 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10042v1</guid></item><item><title>LIBMoE: A Library for comprehensive benchmarking Mixture of Experts in Large Language Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.00918v4</link><description>Mixture of experts (MoE) architectures have become a cornerstone for scaling up and are a key component in most large language models such as GPT-OSS, DeepSeek-V3, Llama-4, and Gemini-2.5. However, systematic research on MoE remains severely constrained by the prohibitive computational costs of training and evaluation, restricting large-scale studies accessible to most researchers. We introduce LibMoE, a unified framework for reproducible, efficient, and extensible MoE research that supports both pretraining and sparse-upcycling regimes. Beyond unified implementations, the framework provides transparent analytical tools for probing routing and expert dynamics. Leveraging this foundation, we conduct a comprehensive analysis along three dimensions: (i) routing dynamics, covering expert selection patterns, routing stability and optimality, and how routing entropy reveals task specialization and expert diversity; (ii) the effect of lightweight initialization on load balancing, demonstrating how subtle changes in router initialization shape early expert utilization; and (iii) training regime differences, revealing how sparse upcycling and full pretraining exhibit distinct routing patterns and stability profiles. By lowering the barrier to entry and standardizing evaluation, along with our comprehensive analysis, LibMoE broadens access to MoE research and establishes a reliable benchmark to guide future innovations. GitHub: \href{https://github.com/Fsoft-AIC/LibMoE}{https://github.com/Fsoft-AIC/LibMoE}.</description><author>Nam V. Nguyen, Thong T. Doan, Luong Tran, Van Nguyen, Quang Pham</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:09:04 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.00918v4</guid></item><item><title>Effectiveness of Binary Autoencoders for QUBO-Based Optimization Problems</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10037v1</link><description>In black-box combinatorial optimization, objective evaluations are often expensive, so high quality solutions must be found under a limited budget. Factorization machine with quantum annealing (FMQA) builds a quadratic surrogate model from evaluated samples and optimizes it on an Ising machine. However, FMQA requires binary decision variables, and for nonbinary structures such as integer permutations, the choice of binary encoding strongly affects search efficiency. If the encoding fails to reflect the original neighborhood structure, small Hamming moves may not correspond to meaningful modifications in the original solution space, and constrained problems can yield many infeasible candidates that waste evaluations. Recent work combines FMQA with a binary autoencoder (bAE) that learns a compact binary latent code from feasible solutions, yet the mechanism behind its performance gains is unclear. Using a small traveling salesman problem as an interpretable testbed, we show that the bAE reconstructs feasible tours accurately and, compared with manually designed encodings at similar compression, better aligns tour distances with latent Hamming distances, yields smoother neighborhoods under small bit flips, and produces fewer local optima. These geometric properties explain why bAE+FMQA improves the approximation ratio faster while maintaining feasibility throughout optimization, and they provide guidance for designing latent representations for black-box optimization.</description><author>Tetsuro Abe, Masashi Yamashita, Shu Tanaka</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:59:29 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10037v1</guid></item><item><title>Perception with Guarantees: Certified Pose Estimation via Reachability Analysis</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10032v1</link><description>Agents in cyber-physical systems are increasingly entrusted with safety-critical tasks. Ensuring safety of these agents often requires localizing the pose for subsequent actions. Pose estimates can, e.g., be obtained from various combinations of lidar sensors, cameras, and external services such as GPS. Crucially, in safety-critical domains, a rough estimate is insufficient to formally determine safety, i.e., guaranteeing safety even in the worst-case scenario, and external services might additionally not be trustworthy. We address this problem by presenting a certified pose estimation in 3D solely from a camera image and a well-known target geometry. This is realized by formally bounding the pose, which is computed by leveraging recent results from reachability analysis and formal neural network verification. Our experiments demonstrate that our approach efficiently and accurately localizes agents in both synthetic and real-world experiments.</description><author>Tobias Ladner, Yasser Shoukry, Matthias Althoff</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:55:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10032v1</guid></item><item><title>ALIVE: Animate Your World with Lifelike Audio-Video Generation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.08682v2</link><description>Video generation is rapidly evolving towards unified audio-video generation. In this paper, we present ALIVE, a generation model that adapts a pretrained Text-to-Video (T2V) model to Sora-style audio-video generation and animation. In particular, the model unlocks the Text-to-Video&amp;Audio (T2VA) and Reference-to-Video&amp;Audio (animation) capabilities compared to the T2V foundation models. To support the audio-visual synchronization and reference animation, we augment the popular MMDiT architecture with a joint audio-video branch which includes TA-CrossAttn for temporally-aligned cross-modal fusion and UniTemp-RoPE for precise audio-visual alignment. Meanwhile, a comprehensive data pipeline consisting of audio-video captioning, quality control, etc., is carefully designed to collect high-quality finetuning data. Additionally, we introduce a new benchmark to perform a comprehensive model test and comparison. After continue pretraining and finetuning on million-level high-quality data, ALIVE demonstrates outstanding performance, consistently outperforming open-source models and matching or surpassing state-of-the-art commercial solutions. With detailed recipes and benchmarks, we hope ALIVE helps the community develop audio-video generation models more efficiently. Official page: https://github.com/FoundationVision/Alive.</description><author>Ying Guo, Qijun Gan, Yifu Zhang, Jinlai Liu, Yifei Hu, Pan Xie, Dongjun Qian, Yu Zhang, Ruiqi Li, Yuqi Zhang, Ruibiao Lu, Xiaofeng Mei, Bo Han, Xiang Yin, Bingyue Peng, Zehuan Yuan</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:53:52 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.08682v2</guid></item><item><title>Position: Message-passing and spectral GNNs are two sides of the same coin</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10031v1</link><description>Graph neural networks (GNNs) are commonly divided into message-passing neural networks (MPNNs) and spectral graph neural networks, reflecting two largely separate research traditions in machine learning and signal processing. This paper argues that this divide is mostly artificial, hindering progress in the field. We propose a viewpoint in which both MPNNs and spectral GNNs are understood as different parametrizations of permutation-equivariant operators acting on graph signals. From this perspective, many popular architectures are equivalent in expressive power, while genuine gaps arise only in specific regimes. We further argue that MPNNs and spectral GNNs offer complementary strengths. That is, MPNNs provide a natural language for discrete structure and expressivity analysis using tools from logic and graph isomorphism research, while the spectral perspective provides principled tools for understanding smoothing, bottlenecks, stability, and community structure. Overall, we posit that progress in graph learning will be accelerated by clearly understanding the key similarities and differences between these two types of GNNs, and by working towards unifying these perspectives within a common theoretical and conceptual framework rather than treating them as competing paradigms.</description><author>Antonis Vasileiou, Juan Cervino, Pascal Frossard, Charilaos I. Kanatsoulis, Christopher Morris, Michael T. Schaub, Pierre Vandergheynst, Zhiyang Wang, Guy Wolf, Ron Levie</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:53:40 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10031v1</guid></item><item><title>Overview of the TREC 2025 RAGTIME Track</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10024v1</link><description>The principal goal of the RAG TREC Instrument for Multilingual Evaluation (RAGTIME) track at TREC is to study report generation from multilingual source documents. The track has created a document collection containing Arabic, Chinese, English, and Russian news stories. RAGTIME includes three task types: Multilingual Report Generation, English Report Generation, and Multilingual Information Retrieval (MLIR). A total of 125 runs were submitted by 13 participating teams (and as baselines by the track coordinators) for three tasks. This overview describes these three tasks and presents the available results.</description><author>Dawn Lawrie, Sean MacAvaney, James Mayfield, Luca Soldaini, Eugene Yang, Andrew Yates</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:47:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10024v1</guid></item><item><title>MEVER: Multi-Modal and Explainable Claim Verification with Graph-based Evidence Retrieval</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10023v1</link><description>Verifying the truthfulness of claims usually requires joint multi-modal reasoning over both textual and visual evidence, such as analyzing both textual caption and chart image for claim verification. In addition, to make the reasoning process transparent, a textual explanation is necessary to justify the verification result. However, most claim verification works mainly focus on the reasoning over textual evidence only or ignore the explainability, resulting in inaccurate and unconvincing verification. To address this problem, we propose a novel model that jointly achieves evidence retrieval, multi-modal claim verification, and explanation generation. For evidence retrieval, we construct a two-layer multi-modal graph for claims and evidence, where we design image-to-text and text-to-image reasoning for multi-modal retrieval. For claim verification, we propose token- and evidence-level fusion to integrate claim and evidence embeddings for multi-modal verification. For explanation generation, we introduce multi-modal Fusion-in-Decoder for explainability. Finally, since almost all the datasets are in general domain, we create a scientific dataset, AIChartClaim, in AI domain to complement claim verification community. Experiments show the strength of our model.</description><author>Delvin Ce Zhang, Suhan Cui, Zhelin Chu, Xianren Zhang, Dongwon Lee</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:44:57 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10023v1</guid></item><item><title>Decoupled Reasoning with Implicit Fact Tokens (DRIFT): A Dual-Model Framework for Efficient Long-Context Inference</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10021v1</link><description>The integration of extensive, dynamic knowledge into Large Language Models (LLMs) remains a significant challenge due to the inherent entanglement of factual data and reasoning patterns. Existing solutions, ranging from non-parametric Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) to parametric knowledge editing, are often constrained in practice by finite context windows, retriever noise, or the risk of catastrophic forgetting. In this paper, we propose DRIFT, a novel dual-model architecture designed to explicitly decouple knowledge extraction from the reasoning process. Unlike static prompt compression, DRIFT employs a lightweight knowledge model to dynamically compress document chunks into implicit fact tokens conditioned on the query. These dense representations are projected into the reasoning model's embedding space, replacing raw, redundant text while maintaining inference accuracy. Extensive experiments show that DRIFT significantly improves performance on long-context tasks, outperforming strong baselines among comparably sized models. Our approach provides a scalable and efficient paradigm for extending the effective context window and reasoning capabilities of LLMs. Our code is available at https://github.com/Lancelot-Xie/DRIFT.</description><author>Wenxuan Xie, Yujia Wang, Xin Tan, Chaochao Lu, Xia Hu, Xuhong Wang</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:42:31 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10021v1</guid></item><item><title>ADORA: Training Reasoning Models with Dynamic Advantage Estimation on Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10019v1</link><description>Reinforcement learning has become a cornerstone technique for developing reasoning models in complex tasks, ranging from mathematical problem-solving to imaginary reasoning. The optimization of these models typically relies on policy gradient methods, whose efficacy hinges on the accurate estimation of an advantage function. However, prevailing methods typically employ static advantage estimation, a practice that leads to inefficient credit assignment by neglecting the dynamic utility of training samples over time. This limitation results in suboptimal policy updates, which in turn manifest as slower convergence rates and increased learning instability, as models fail to adapt to evolving sample utilities effectively. To address this problem, we introduce \textbf{ADORA} (\textbf{A}dvantage \textbf{D}ynamics via \textbf{O}nline \textbf{R}ollout \textbf{A}daptation), a novel framework for policy optimization. ADORA dynamically adjusts the advantage function's weighting by adaptively categorizing training data into temporarily advantageous and disadvantageous samples, based on their evolving utility during online model rollouts. This tailored data differentiation strategy allows ADORA to be seamlessly integrated into existing policy optimization algorithms without significant architectural modifications, enabling the policy to prioritize learning from more informative experiences and thereby achieve more efficient policy updates. Extensive evaluations across diverse model families and varying data scales demonstrate that ADORA is a robust and efficient framework. It significantly enhances long reasoning in both geometric and mathematical tasks, consistently achieving notable performance gains without requiring sensitive hyperparameter tuning.</description><author>Qingnan Ren, Shiting Huang, Zhen Fang, Zehui Chen, Lin Chen, Lijun Li, Feng Zhao</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:40:39 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10019v1</guid></item><item><title>Online Selective Conformal Prediction with Asymmetric Rules: A Permutation Test Approach</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10018v1</link><description>Selective conformal prediction aims to construct prediction sets with valid coverage for a test unit conditional on it being selected by a data-driven mechanism. While existing methods in the offline setting handle any selection mechanism that is permutation invariant to the labeled data, their extension to the online setting -- where data arrives sequentially and later decisions depend on earlier ones -- is challenged by the fact that the selection mechanism is naturally asymmetric. As such, existing methods only address a limited collection of selection mechanisms. In this paper, we propose PErmutation-based Mondrian Conformal Inference (PEMI), a general permutation-based framework for selective conformal prediction with arbitrary asymmetric selection rules. Motivated by full and Mondrian conformal prediction, PEMI identifies all permutations of the observed data (or a Monte-Carlo subset thereof) that lead to the same selection event, and calibrates a prediction set using conformity scores over this selection-preserving reference set. Under standard exchangeability conditions, our prediction sets achieve finite-sample exact selection-conditional coverage for any asymmetric selection mechanism and any prediction model. PEMI naturally incorporates additional offline labeled data, extends to selection mechanisms with multiple test samples, and achieves FCR control with fine-grained selection taxonomies. We further work out several efficient instantiations for commonly-used online selection rules, including covariate-based rules, conformal p/e-values-based procedures, and selection based on earlier outcomes. Finally, we demonstrate the efficacy of our methods across various selection rules on a real drug discovery dataset and investigate their performance via simulations.</description><author>Mingyi Zheng, Ying Jin</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:39:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10018v1</guid></item><item><title>SCORE: Specificity, Context Utilization, Robustness, and Relevance for Reference-Free LLM Evaluation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10017v1</link><description>Large language models (LLMs) are increasingly used to support question answering and decision-making in high-stakes, domain-specific settings such as natural hazard response and infrastructure planning, where effective answers must convey fine-grained, decision-critical details. However, existing evaluation frameworks for retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) and open-ended question answering primarily rely on surface-level similarity, factual consistency, or semantic relevance, and often fail to assess whether responses provide the specific information required for domain-sensitive decisions. To address this gap, we propose a multi-dimensional, reference-free evaluation framework that assesses LLM outputs along four complementary dimensions: specificity, robustness to paraphrasing and semantic perturbations, answer relevance, and context utilization. We introduce a curated dataset of 1,412 domain-specific question-answer pairs spanning 40 professional roles and seven natural hazard types to support systematic evaluation. We further conduct human evaluation to assess inter-annotator agreement and alignment between model outputs and human judgments, which highlights the inherent subjectivity of open-ended, domain-specific evaluation. Our results show that no single metric sufficiently captures answer quality in isolation and demonstrate the need for structured, multi-metric evaluation frameworks when deploying LLMs in high-stakes applications.</description><author>Homaira Huda Shomee, Rochana Chaturvedi, Yangxinyu Xie, Tanwi Mallick</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:39:17 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10017v1</guid></item><item><title>Kunlun: Establishing Scaling Laws for Massive-Scale Recommendation Systems through Unified Architecture Design</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10016v1</link><description>Deriving predictable scaling laws that govern the relationship between model performance and computational investment is crucial for designing and allocating resources in massive-scale recommendation systems. While such laws are established for large language models, they remain challenging for recommendation systems, especially those processing both user history and context features. We identify poor scaling efficiency as the main barrier to predictable power-law scaling, stemming from inefficient modules with low Model FLOPs Utilization (MFU) and suboptimal resource allocation. We introduce Kunlun, a scalable architecture that systematically improves model efficiency and resource allocation. Our low-level optimizations include Generalized Dot-Product Attention (GDPA), Hierarchical Seed Pooling (HSP), and Sliding Window Attention. Our high-level innovations feature Computation Skip (CompSkip) and Event-level Personalization. These advances increase MFU from 17% to 37% on NVIDIA B200 GPUs and double scaling efficiency over state-of-the-art methods. Kunlun is now deployed in major Meta Ads models, delivering significant production impact.</description><author>Bojian Hou, Xiaolong Liu, Xiaoyi Liu, Jiaqi Xu, Yasmine Badr, Mengyue Hang, Sudhanshu Chanpuriya, Junqing Zhou, Yuhang Yang, Han Xu, Qiuling Suo, Laming Chen, Yuxi Hu, Jiasheng Zhang, Huaqing Xiong, Yuzhen Huang, Chao Chen, Yue Dong, Yi Yang, Shuo Chang, Xiaorui Gan, Wenlin Chen, Santanu Kolay, Darren Liu, Jade Nie, Chunzhi Yang, Jiyan Yang, Huayu Li</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:37:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10016v1</guid></item><item><title>RoboSubtaskNet: Temporal Sub-task Segmentation for Human-to-Robot Skill Transfer in Real-World Environments</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10015v1</link><description>Temporally locating and classifying fine-grained sub-task segments in long, untrimmed videos is crucial to safe human-robot collaboration. Unlike generic activity recognition, collaborative manipulation requires sub-task labels that are directly robot-executable. We present RoboSubtaskNet, a multi-stage human-to-robot sub-task segmentation framework that couples attention-enhanced I3D features (RGB plus optical flow) with a modified MS-TCN employing a Fibonacci dilation schedule to capture better short-horizon transitions such as reach-pick-place. The network is trained with a composite objective comprising cross-entropy and temporal regularizers (truncated MSE and a transition-aware term) to reduce over-segmentation and to encourage valid sub-task progressions. To close the gap between vision benchmarks and control, we introduce RoboSubtask, a dataset of healthcare and industrial demonstrations annotated at the sub-task level and designed for deterministic mapping to manipulator primitives. Empirically, RoboSubtaskNet outperforms MS-TCN and MS-TCN++ on GTEA and our RoboSubtask benchmark (boundary-sensitive and sequence metrics), while remaining competitive on the long-horizon Breakfast benchmark. Specifically, RoboSubtaskNet attains F1 @ 50 = 79.5%, Edit = 88.6%, Acc = 78.9% on GTEA; F1 @ 50 = 30.4%, Edit = 52.0%, Acc = 53.5% on Breakfast; and F1 @ 50 = 94.2%, Edit = 95.6%, Acc = 92.2% on RoboSubtask. We further validate the full perception-to-execution pipeline on a 7-DoF Kinova Gen3 manipulator, achieving reliable end-to-end behavior in physical trials (overall task success approx 91.25%). These results demonstrate a practical path from sub-task level video understanding to deployed robotic manipulation in real-world settings.</description><author>Dharmendra Sharma, Archit Sharma, John Reberio, Vaibhav Kesharwani, Peeyush Thakur, Narendra Kumar Dhar, Laxmidhar Behera</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:37:35 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10015v1</guid></item><item><title>A Task-Centric Theory for Iterative Self-Improvement with Easy-to-Hard Curricula</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10014v1</link><description>Iterative self-improvement fine-tunes an autoregressive large language model (LLM) on reward-verified outputs generated by the LLM itself. In contrast to the empirical success of self-improvement, the theoretical foundation of this generative, iterative procedure in a practical, finite-sample setting remains limited. We make progress toward this goal by modeling each round of self-improvement as maximum-likelihood fine-tuning on a reward-filtered distribution and deriving finite-sample guarantees for the expected reward. Our analysis reveals an explicit feedback loop where better models accept more data per iteration, supporting sustained self-improvement while explaining eventual saturation of such improvement. Adopting a task-centric view by considering reasoning tasks with multiple difficulty levels, we further prove quantifiable conditions on model initialization, task difficulty, and sample budget where easy-to-hard curricula provably achieve better guarantees than training on fixed mixtures of tasks. Our analyses are validated via Monte-Carlo simulations and controlled experiments on graph-based reasoning tasks.</description><author>Chenruo Liu, Yijun Dong, Yiqiu Shen, Qi Lei</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:36:41 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10014v1</guid></item><item><title>Discovering High Level Patterns from Simulation Traces</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10009v1</link><description>Artificial intelligence (AI) agents embedded in environments with physics-based interaction face many challenges including reasoning, planning, summarization, and question answering. This problem is exacerbated when a human user wishes to either guide or interact with the agent in natural language. Although the use of Language Models (LMs) is the default choice, as an AI tool, they struggle with tasks involving physics. The LM's capability for physical reasoning is learned from observational data, rather than being grounded in simulation. A common approach is to include simulation traces as context, but this suffers from poor scalability as simulation traces contain larger volumes of fine-grained numerical and semantic data. In this paper, we propose a natural language guided method to discover coarse-grained patterns (e.g., 'rigid-body collision', 'stable support', etc.) from detailed simulation logs. Specifically, we synthesize programs that operate on simulation logs and map them to a series of high level activated patterns. We show, through two physics benchmarks, that this annotated representation of the simulation log is more amenable to natural language reasoning about physical systems. We demonstrate how this method enables LMs to generate effective reward programs from goals specified in natural language, which may be used within the context of planning or supervised learning.</description><author>Sean Memery, Kartic Subr</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:31:39 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10009v1</guid></item><item><title>A Collaborative Safety Shield for Safe and Efficient CAV Lane Changes in Congested On-Ramp Merging</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10007v1</link><description>Lane changing in dense traffic is a significant challenge for Connected and Autonomous Vehicles (CAVs). Existing lane change controllers primarily either ensure safety or collaboratively improve traffic efficiency, but do not consider these conflicting objectives together. To address this, we propose the Multi-Agent Safety Shield (MASS), designed using Control Barrier Functions (CBFs) to enable safe and collaborative lane changes. The MASS enables collaboration by capturing multi-agent interactions among CAVs through interaction topologies constructed as a graph using a simple algorithm. Further, a state-of-the-art Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning (MARL) lane change controller is extended by integrating MASS to ensure safety and defining a customised reward function to prioritise efficiency improvements. As a result, we propose a lane change controller, known as MARL-MASS, and evaluate it in a congested on-ramp merging simulation. The results demonstrate that MASS enables collaborative lane changes with safety guarantees by strictly respecting the safety constraints. Moreover, the proposed custom reward function improves the stability of MARL policies trained with a safety shield. Overall, by encouraging the exploration of a collaborative lane change policy while respecting safety constraints, MARL-MASS effectively balances the trade-off between ensuring safety and improving traffic efficiency in congested traffic. The code for MARL-MASS is available with an open-source licence at https://github.com/hkbharath/MARL-MASS</description><author>Bharathkumar Hegde, Melanie Bouroche</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:30:09 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10007v1</guid></item><item><title>Answer First, Reason Later: Aligning Search Relevance via Mode-Balanced Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10006v1</link><description>Building a search relevance model that achieves both low latency and high performance is a long-standing challenge in the search industry. To satisfy the millisecond-level response requirements of online systems while retaining the interpretable reasoning traces of Large Language Models (LLMs), we propose a novel \textbf{Answer-First, Reason Later (AFRL)} paradigm. This paradigm requires the model to output the definitive relevance score in the very first token, followed by a structured logical explanation. Inspired by the success of reasoning models, we adopt a "Supervised Fine-Tuning (SFT) + Reinforcement Learning (RL)" pipeline to achieve AFRL. However, directly applying existing RL training often leads to \textbf{mode collapse} in the search relevance task, where the model forgets complex long-tail rules in pursuit of high rewards. From an information theory perspective: RL inherently minimizes the \textbf{Reverse KL divergence}, which tends to seek probability peaks (mode-seeking) and is prone to "reward hacking." On the other hand, SFT minimizes the \textbf{Forward KL divergence}, forcing the model to cover the data distribution (mode-covering) and effectively anchoring expert rules. Based on this insight, we propose a \textbf{Mode-Balanced Optimization} strategy, incorporating an SFT auxiliary loss into Stepwise-GRPO training to balance these two properties. Furthermore, we construct an automated instruction evolution system and a multi-stage curriculum to ensure expert-level data quality. Extensive experiments demonstrate that our 32B teacher model achieves state-of-the-art performance. Moreover, the AFRL architecture enables efficient knowledge distillation, successfully transferring expert-level logic to a 0.6B model, thereby reconciling reasoning depth with deployment latency.</description><author>Shijie Zhang, Xiang Guo, Rujun Guo, Shaoyu Liu, Xiaozhao Wang, Guanjun Jiang, Kevin Zhang</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:28:12 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10006v1</guid></item><item><title>ESTAR: Early-Stopping Token-Aware Reasoning For Efficient Inference</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10004v1</link><description>Large reasoning models (LRMs) achieve state-of-the-art performance by generating long chains-of-thought, but often waste computation on redundant reasoning after the correct answer has already been reached. We introduce Early-Stopping for Token-Aware Reasoning (ESTAR), which detects and reduces such reasoning redundancy to improve efficiency without sacrificing accuracy. Our method combines (i) a trajectory-based classifier that identifies when reasoning can be safely stopped, (ii) supervised fine-tuning to teach LRMs to propose self-generated &lt;stop&gt; signals, and (iii) &lt;stop&gt;-aware reinforcement learning that truncates rollouts at self-generated stop points with compute-aware rewards. Experiments on four reasoning datasets show that ESTAR reduces reasoning length by about 3.7x (from 4,799 to 1,290) while preserving accuracy (74.9% vs. 74.2%), with strong cross-domain generalization. These results highlight early stopping as a simple yet powerful mechanism for improving reasoning efficiency in LRMs.</description><author>Junda Wang, Zhichao Yang, Dongxu Zhang, Sanjit Singh Batra, Robert E. Tillman</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:27:26 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10004v1</guid></item><item><title>ViSpeechFormer: A Phonemic Approach for Vietnamese Automatic Speech Recognition</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10003v1</link><description>Vietnamese has a phonetic orthography, where each grapheme corresponds to at most one phoneme and vice versa. Exploiting this high grapheme-phoneme transparency, we propose ViSpeechFormer (\textbf{Vi}etnamese \textbf{Speech} Trans\textbf{Former}), a phoneme-based approach for Vietnamese Automatic Speech Recognition (ASR). To the best of our knowledge, this is the first Vietnamese ASR framework that explicitly models phonemic representations. Experiments on two publicly available Vietnamese ASR datasets show that ViSpeechFormer achieves strong performance, generalizes better to out-of-vocabulary words, and is less affected by training bias. This phoneme-based paradigm is also promising for other languages with phonetic orthographies. The code will be released upon acceptance of this paper.</description><author>Khoa Anh Nguyen, Long Minh Hoang, Nghia Hieu Nguyen, Luan Thanh Nguyen, Ngan Luu-Thuy Nguyen</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:26:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.10003v1</guid></item><item><title>Faster-GS: Analyzing and Improving Gaussian Splatting Optimization</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09999v1</link><description>Recent advances in 3D Gaussian Splatting (3DGS) have focused on accelerating optimization while preserving reconstruction quality. However, many proposed methods entangle implementation-level improvements with fundamental algorithmic modifications or trade performance for fidelity, leading to a fragmented research landscape that complicates fair comparison. In this work, we consolidate and evaluate the most effective and broadly applicable strategies from prior 3DGS research and augment them with several novel optimizations. We further investigate underexplored aspects of the framework, including numerical stability, Gaussian truncation, and gradient approximation. The resulting system, Faster-GS, provides a rigorously optimized algorithm that we evaluate across a comprehensive suite of benchmarks. Our experiments demonstrate that Faster-GS achieves up to 5$\times$ faster training while maintaining visual quality, establishing a new cost-effective and resource efficient baseline for 3DGS optimization. Furthermore, we demonstrate that optimizations can be applied to 4D Gaussian reconstruction, leading to efficient non-rigid scene optimization.</description><author>Florian Hahlbohm, Linus Franke, Martin Eisemann, Marcus Magnor</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:22:59 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09999v1</guid></item><item><title>Does Memory Need Graphs? A Unified Framework and Empirical Analysis for Long-Term Dialog Memory</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.01280v3</link><description>Graph structures are increasingly used in dialog memory systems, but empirical findings on their effectiveness remain inconsistent, making it unclear which design choices truly matter. We present an experimental, system-oriented analysis of long-term dialog memory architectures. We introduce a unified framework that decomposes dialog memory systems into core components and supports both graph-based and non-graph approaches. Under this framework, we conduct controlled, stage-wise experiments on LongMemEval and HaluMem, comparing common design choices in memory representation, organization, maintenance, and retrieval. Our results show that many performance differences are driven by foundational system settings rather than specific architectural innovations. Based on these findings, we identify stable and reliable strong baselines for future dialog memory research. Code are available at https://github.com/AvatarMemory/UnifiedMem</description><author>Sen Hu, Yuxiang Wei, Jiaxin Ran, Zhiyuan Yao, Xueran Han, Huacan Wang, Ronghao Chen, Lei Zou</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:21:43 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.01280v3</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of LLMs on Online News Consumption and Production</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24968v3</link><description>Large language models (LLMs) change how consumers acquire information online; their bots also crawl news publishers' websites for training data and to answer consumer queries; and they provide tools that can lower the cost of content creation. These changes lead to predictions of adverse impact on news publishers in the form of lowered consumer demand, reduced demand for newsroom employees, and an increase in news "slop." Consequently, some publishers strategically responded by blocking LLM access to their websites using the robots.txt file standard. Using high-frequency granular data, we document four effects related to the predicted shifts in news publishing following the introduction of generative AI (GenAI). First, we find a moderate decline in traffic to news publishers occurring after August 2024. Second, using a difference-in-differences approach, we find that blocking GenAI bots can be associated with a reduction of total website traffic to large publishers compared to not blocking. Third, on the hiring side, we do not find evidence that LLMs are replacing editorial or content-production jobs yet. The share of new editorial and content-production job listings increases over time. Fourth, regarding content production, we find no evidence that large publishers increased text volume; instead, they significantly increased rich content and use more advertising and targeting technologies. Together, these findings provide early evidence of some unforeseen impacts of the introduction of LLMs on news production and consumption.</description><author>Hangcheng Zhao, Ron Berman</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:18:09 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.24968v3</guid></item><item><title>A Unified Assessment of the Poverty of the Stimulus Argument for Neural Language Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09992v1</link><description>How can children acquire native-level syntax from limited input? According to the Poverty of the Stimulus Hypothesis (PoSH), the linguistic input children receive is insufficient to explain certain generalizations that are robustly learned; innate linguistic constraints, many have argued, are thus necessary to explain language learning. Neural language models, which lack such language-specific constraints in their design, offer a computational test of this longstanding (but controversial) claim. We introduce \poshbench, a training-and-evaluation suite targeting question formation, islands to movement, and other English phenomena at the center of the PoSH arguments. Training Transformer models on 10--50M words of developmentally plausible text, we find indications of generalization on all phenomena even without direct positive evidence -- yet neural models remain less data-efficient and their generalizations are weaker than those of children. We further enhance our models with three recently proposed cognitively motivated inductive biases. We find these biases improve general syntactic competence but not \poshbench performance. Our findings challenge the claim that innate syntax is the only possible route to generalization, while suggesting that human-like data efficiency requires inductive biases beyond those tested here.</description><author>Xiulin Yang, Arianna Bisazza, Nathan Schneider, Ethan Gotlieb Wilcox</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:16:29 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09992v1</guid></item><item><title>Stochastic Optimization with Optimal Importance Sampling</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.03560v3</link><description>Importance Sampling (IS) is a widely used variance reduction technique for enhancing the efficiency of Monte Carlo methods, particularly in rare-event simulation and related applications. Despite its effectiveness, the performance of IS is highly sensitive to the choice of the proposal distribution and often requires stochastic calibration. While the design and analysis of IS have been extensively studied in estimation settings, applying IS within stochastic optimization introduces a lesser-known fundamental challenge: the decision variable and the importance sampling distribution are mutually dependent, creating a circular optimization structure. This interdependence complicates both convergence analysis and variance control. In this paper, we consider the generic setting of convex stochastic optimization with linear constraints. We propose a single-loop stochastic approximation algorithm, based on a variant of Nesterov's dual averaging, that jointly updates the decision variable and the importance sampling distribution, notably without time-scale separation or nested optimization. The method is globally convergent and achieves the minimal asymptotic variance among stochastic gradient schemes, which moreover matches the performance of an oracle sampler adapted to the optimal solution and thus effectively resolves the circular optimization challenge.</description><author>Liviu Aolaritei, Bart P. G. Van Parys, Henry Lam, Michael I. Jordan</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:15:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.03560v3</guid></item><item><title>Efficient Special Stain Classification</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09989v1</link><description>Stains are essential in histopathology to visualize specific tissue characteristics, with Haematoxylin and Eosin (H&amp;E) serving as the clinical standard. However, pathologists frequently utilize a variety of special stains for the diagnosis of specific morphologies. Maintaining accurate metadata for these slides is critical for quality control in clinical archives and for the integrity of computational pathology datasets. In this work, we compare two approaches for automated classification of stains using whole slide images, covering the 14 most commonly used special stains in our institute alongside standard and frozen-section H&amp;E. We evaluate a Multi-Instance Learning (MIL) pipeline and a proposed lightweight thumbnail-based approach. On internal test data, MIL achieved the highest performance (macro F1: 0.941 for 16 classes; 0.969 for 14 merged classes), while the thumbnail approach remained competitive (0.897 and 0.953, respectively). On external TCGA data, the thumbnail model generalized best (weighted F1: 0.843 vs. 0.807 for MIL). The thumbnail approach also increased throughput by two orders of magnitude (5.635 vs. 0.018 slides/s for MIL with all patches). We conclude that thumbnail-based classification provides a scalable and robust solution for routine visual quality control in digital pathology workflows.</description><author>Oskar Thaeter, Christian Grashei, Anette Haas, Elisa Schmoeckel, Han Li, Peter J. Schüffler</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:15:13 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09989v1</guid></item><item><title>Empirical Stability Analysis of Kolmogorov-Arnold Networks in Hard-Constrained Recurrent Physics-Informed Discovery</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09988v1</link><description>We investigate the integration of Kolmogorov-Arnold Networks (KANs) into hard-constrained recurrent physics-informed architectures (HRPINN) to evaluate the fidelity of learned residual manifolds in oscillatory systems. Motivated by the Kolmogorov-Arnold representation theorem and preliminary gray-box results, we hypothesized that KANs would enable efficient recovery of unknown terms compared to MLPs. Through initial sensitivity analysis on configuration sensitivity, parameter scale, and training paradigm, we found that while small KANs are competitive on univariate polynomial residuals (Duffing), they exhibit severe hyperparameter fragility, instability in deeper configurations, and consistent failure on multiplicative terms (Van der Pol), generally outperformed by standard MLPs. These empirical challenges highlight limitations of the additive inductive bias in the original KAN formulation for state coupling and provide preliminary empirical evidence of inductive bias limitations for future hybrid modeling.</description><author>Enzo Nicolas Spotorno, Josafat Leal Filho, Antonio Augusto Medeiros Frohlich</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:13:51 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09988v1</guid></item><item><title>Infusion: Shaping Model Behavior by Editing Training Data via Influence Functions</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09987v1</link><description>Influence functions are commonly used to attribute model behavior to training documents. We explore the reverse: crafting training data that induces model behavior. Our framework, Infusion, uses scalable influence-function approximations to compute small perturbations to training documents that induce targeted changes in model behavior through parameter shifts. We evaluate Infusion on data poisoning tasks across vision and language domains. On CIFAR-10, we show that making subtle edits via Infusion to just 0.2% (100/45,000) of the training documents can be competitive with the baseline of inserting a small number of explicit behavior examples. We also find that Infusion transfers across architectures (ResNet $\leftrightarrow$ CNN), suggesting a single poisoned corpus can affect multiple independently trained models. In preliminary language experiments, we characterize when our approach increases the probability of target behaviors and when it fails, finding it most effective at amplifying behaviors the model has already learned. Taken together, these results show that small, subtle edits to training data can systematically shape model behavior, underscoring the importance of training data interpretability for adversaries and defenders alike. We provide the code here: https://github.com/jrosseruk/infusion.</description><author>J Rosser, Robert Kirk, Edward Grefenstette, Jakob Foerster, Laura Ruis</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:13:42 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09987v1</guid></item><item><title>Online Monitoring Framework for Automotive Time Series Data using JEPA Embeddings</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09985v1</link><description>As autonomous vehicles are rolled out, measures must be taken to ensure their safe operation. In order to supervise a system that is already in operation, monitoring frameworks are frequently employed. These run continuously online in the background, supervising the system status and recording anomalies. This work proposes an online monitoring framework to detect anomalies in object state representations. Thereby, a key challenge is creating a framework for anomaly detection without anomaly labels, which are usually unavailable for unknown anomalies. To address this issue, this work applies a self-supervised embedding method to translate object data into a latent representation space. For this, a JEPA-based self-supervised prediction task is constructed, allowing training without anomaly labels and the creation of rich object embeddings. The resulting expressive JEPA embeddings serve as input for established anomaly detection methods, in order to identify anomalies within object state representations. This framework is particularly useful for applications in real-world environments, where new or unknown anomalies may occur during operation for which there are no labels available. Experiments performed on the publicly available, real-world nuScenes dataset illustrate the framework's capabilities.</description><author>Alexander Fertig, Karthikeyan Chandra Sekaran, Lakshman Balasubramanian, Michael Botsch</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:10:29 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09985v1</guid></item><item><title>Coupled Inference in Diffusion Models for Semantic Decomposition</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09983v1</link><description>Many visual scenes can be described as compositions of latent factors. Effective recognition, reasoning, and editing often require not only forming such compositional representations, but also solving the decomposition problem. One popular choice for constructing these representations is through the binding operation. Resonator networks, which can be understood as coupled Hopfield networks, were proposed as a way to perform decomposition on such bound representations. Recent works have shown notable similarities between Hopfield networks and diffusion models. Motivated by these observations, we introduce a framework for semantic decomposition using coupled inference in diffusion models. Our method frames semantic decomposition as an inverse problem and couples the diffusion processes using a reconstruction-driven guidance term that encourages the composition of factor estimates to match the bound vector. We also introduce a novel iterative sampling scheme that improves the performance of our model. Finally, we show that attention-based resonator networks are a special case of our framework. Empirically, we demonstrate that our coupled inference framework outperforms resonator networks across a range of synthetic semantic decomposition tasks.</description><author>Calvin Yeung, Ali Zakeri, Zhuowen Zou, Mohsen Imani</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:10:05 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09983v1</guid></item><item><title>Bridging Past and Future: Distribution-Aware Alignment for Time Series Forecasting</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14181v3</link><description>Although contrastive and other representation-learning methods have long been explored in vision and NLP, their adoption in modern time series forecasters remains limited. We believe they hold strong promise for this domain. To unlock this potential, we explicitly align past and future representations, thereby bridging the distributional gap between input histories and future targets. To this end, we introduce TimeAlign, a lightweight, plug-and-play framework that establishes a new representation paradigm, distinct from contrastive learning, by aligning auxiliary features via a simple reconstruction task and feeding them back into any base forecaster. Extensive experiments across eight benchmarks verify its superior performance. Further studies indicate that the gains arise primarily from correcting frequency mismatches between historical inputs and future outputs. Additionally, we provide two theoretical justifications for how reconstruction improves forecasting generalization and how alignment increases the mutual information between learned representations and predicted targets. The code is available at https://github.com/TROUBADOUR000/TimeAlign.</description><author>Yifan Hu, Jie Yang, Tian Zhou, Peiyuan Liu, Yujin Tang, Rong Jin, Liang Sun</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:08:41 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14181v3</guid></item><item><title>Supervised Metric Regularization Through Alternating Optimization for Multi-Regime Physics-Informed Neural Networks</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09980v1</link><description>Standard Physics-Informed Neural Networks (PINNs) often face challenges when modeling parameterized dynamical systems with sharp regime transitions, such as bifurcations. In these scenarios, the continuous mapping from parameters to solutions can result in spectral bias or "mode collapse", where the network averages distinct physical behaviors. We propose a Topology-Aware PINN (TAPINN) that aims to mitigate this challenge by structuring the latent space via Supervised Metric Regularization. Unlike standard parametric PINNs that map physical parameters directly to solutions, our method conditions the solver on a latent state optimized to reflect the metric-based separation between regimes, showing ~49% lower physics residual (0.082 vs. 0.160). We train this architecture using a phase-based Alternating Optimization (AO) schedule to manage gradient conflicts between the metric and physics objectives. Preliminary experiments on the Duffing Oscillator demonstrate that while standard baselines suffer from spectral bias and high-capacity Hypernetworks overfit (memorizing data while violating physics), our approach achieves stable convergence with 2.18x lower gradient variance than a multi-output Sobolev Error baseline, and 5x fewer parameters than a hypernetwork-based alternative.</description><author>Enzo Nicolas Spotorno, Josafat Ribeiro Leal, Antonio Augusto Frohlich</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:06:57 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09980v1</guid></item><item><title>Learning to Detect Baked Goods with Limited Supervision</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09979v1</link><description>Monitoring leftover products provides valuable insights that can be used to optimize future production. This is especially important for German bakeries because freshly baked goods have a very short shelf life. Automating this process can reduce labor costs, improve accuracy, and streamline operations. We propose automating this process using an object detection model to identify baked goods from images. However, the large diversity of German baked goods makes fully supervised training prohibitively expensive and limits scalability. Although open-vocabulary detectors (e.g., OWLv2, Grounding DINO) offer lexibility, we demonstrate that they are insufficient for our task. While motivated by bakeries, our work addresses the broader challenges of deploying computer vision in industries, where tasks are specialized and annotated datasets are scarce. We compile dataset splits with varying supervision levels, covering 19 classes of baked goods. We propose two training workflows to train an object detection model with limited supervision. First, we combine OWLv2 and Grounding DINO localization with image-level supervision to train the model in a weakly supervised manner. Second, we improve viewpoint robustness by fine-tuning on video frames annotated using Segment Anything 2 as a pseudo-label propagation model. Using these workflows, we train YOLOv11 for our detection task due to its favorable speed accuracy tradeoff. Relying solely on image-level supervision, the model achieves a mean Average Precision (mAP) of 0.91. Finetuning with pseudo-labels raises model performance by 19.3% under non-ideal deployment conditions. Combining these workflows trains a model that surpasses our fully-supervised baseline model under non-ideal deployment conditions, despite relying only on image-level supervision.</description><author>Thomas H. Schmitt, Maximilian Bundscherer, Tobias Bocklet</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:06:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09979v1</guid></item><item><title>Stopping Rules for SGD via Anytime-Valid Confidence Sequences</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.13123v4</link><description>Deciding when to stop stochastic gradient descent (SGD) has long remained unresolved in a statistically rigorous sense. While SGD is routinely monitored as it runs, the classical theory of SGD provides guarantees only at pre-specified iteration horizons and offers no valid way to decide, based on the observed trajectory, when further computation is justified. We address this gap by developing anytime-valid confidence sequences for stochastic gradient methods, which remain valid under continuous monitoring and directly induce statistically valid, trajectory-dependent stopping rules: stop as soon as the current upper confidence bound on an appropriate performance measure falls below a user-specified tolerance. The confidence sequences are constructed using nonnegative supermartingales, are time-uniform, and depend only on observable quantities along the SGD trajectory, without requiring prior knowledge of the optimization horizon. In convex optimization, this yields anytime-valid certificates for weighted suboptimality of projected SGD under general stepsize schedules, without assuming smoothness or strong convexity. In nonconvex optimization, it yields time-uniform certificates for weighted first-order stationarity under smoothness assumptions. We further characterize the stopping-time complexity of the resulting stopping rules under standard stepsize schedules. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first framework that provides statistically valid, time-uniform stopping rules for SGD across both convex and nonconvex settings based solely on its observed trajectory.</description><author>Liviu Aolaritei, Michael I. Jordan</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:04:47 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.13123v4</guid></item><item><title>Among Us: A Sandbox for Measuring and Detecting Agentic Deception</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.04072v3</link><description>Prior studies on deception in language-based AI agents typically assess whether the agent produces a false statement about a topic, or makes a binary choice prompted by a goal, rather than allowing open-ended deceptive behavior to emerge in pursuit of a longer-term goal. To fix this, we introduce Among Us, a sandbox social deception game where LLM-agents exhibit long-term, open-ended deception as a consequence of the game objectives. While most benchmarks saturate quickly, Among Us can be expected to last much longer, because it is a multi-player game far from equilibrium. Using the sandbox, we evaluate 18 proprietary and open-weight LLMs and uncover a general trend: models trained with RL are comparatively much better at producing deception than detecting it. We evaluate the effectiveness of methods to detect lying and deception: logistic regression on the activations and sparse autoencoders (SAEs). We find that probes trained on a dataset of "pretend you're a dishonest model:.." generalize extremely well out-of-distribution, consistently obtaining AUROCs over 95% even when evaluated just on the deceptive statement, without the chain of thought. We also find two SAE features that work well at deception detection but are unable to steer the model to lie less. We hope our open-sourced sandbox, game logs, and probes serve to anticipate and mitigate deceptive behavior and capabilities in language-based agents.</description><author>Satvik Golechha, Adrià Garriga-Alonso</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:00:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.04072v3</guid></item><item><title>Causal Identification in Multi-Task Demand Learning with Confounding</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09969v1</link><description>We study a canonical multi-task demand learning problem motivated by retail pricing, in which a firm seeks to estimate heterogeneous linear price-response functions across a large collection of decision contexts. Each context is characterized by rich observable covariates yet typically exhibits only limited historical price variation, motivating the use of multi-task learning to borrow strength across tasks. A central challenge in this setting is endogeneity: historical prices are chosen by managers or algorithms and may be arbitrarily correlated with unobserved, task-level demand determinants. Under such confounding by latent fundamentals, commonly used approaches, such as pooled regression and meta-learning, fail to identify causal price effects. We propose a new estimation framework that achieves causal identification despite arbitrary dependence between prices and latent task structure. Our approach, Decision-Conditioned Masked-Outcome Meta-Learning (DCMOML), involves carefully designing the information set of a meta-learner to leverage cross-task heterogeneity while accounting for endogenous decision histories. Under a mild restriction on price adaptivity in each task, we establish that this method identifies the conditional mean of the task-specific causal parameters given the designed information set. Our results provide guarantees for large-scale demand estimation with endogenous prices and small per-task samples, offering a principled foundation for deploying causal, data-driven pricing models in operational environments.</description><author>Varun Gupta, Vijay Kamble</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:58:50 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09969v1</guid></item><item><title>Scalable Dynamic Origin-Destination Demand Estimation Enhanced by High-Resolution Satellite Imagery Data</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.22499v2</link><description>This study presents a novel integrated framework for dynamic origin-destination demand estimation (DODE) in multi-class mesoscopic network models, incorporating high-resolution satellite imagery together with conventional traffic data from local sensors. Unlike sparse local detectors, satellite imagery offers consistent, city-wide road and traffic information of both parking and moving vehicles, overcoming data availability limitations. To extract information from imagery data, we design a computer vision pipeline for class-specific vehicle detection and map matching, generating link-level traffic density observations by vehicle class. Building upon this information, we formulate a computational graph-based DODE framework that calibrates dynamic network states by jointly matching observed traffic counts/speeds from local sensors with density measurements derived from satellite imagery. To assess the accuracy and robustness of the proposed framework, we conduct a series of numerical experiments using both synthetic and real-world data. The results demonstrate that supplementing traditional data with satellite-derived density significantly improves estimation performance, especially for links without local sensors. Real-world experiments also show the framework's potential for practical deployment on large-scale networks. Sensitivity analysis further evaluates the impact of data quality related to satellite imagery data.</description><author>Jiachao Liu, Pablo Guarda, Koichiro Niinuma, Sean Qian</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:57:23 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.22499v2</guid></item><item><title>RAGBoost: Efficient Retrieval-Augmented Generation with Accuracy-Preserving Context Reuse</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.03475v2</link><description>Retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) enhances large language models (LLMs) with retrieved context but often suffers from downgraded prefill performance as modern applications demand longer and more complex inputs. Existing caching techniques either preserve accuracy with low cache reuse or improve reuse at the cost of degraded reasoning quality. We present RAGBoost, an efficient RAG system that achieves high cache reuse without sacrificing accuracy through accuracy-preserving context reuse. RAGBoost detects overlapping retrieved items across concurrent sessions and multi-turn interactions, using efficient context indexing, ordering, and de-duplication to maximize reuse, while lightweight contextual hints maintain reasoning fidelity. It integrates seamlessly with existing LLM inference engines and improves their prefill performance by 1.5-3X over state-of-the-art methods, while preserving or even enhancing reasoning accuracy across diverse RAG and agentic AI workloads. Our code is released at: https://github.com/Edinburgh-AgenticAI/RAGBoost.</description><author>Yinsicheng Jiang, Yeqi Huang, Liang Cheng, Cheng Deng, Xuan Sun, Luo Mai</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:55:15 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.03475v2</guid></item><item><title>Benchmarking 3D Human Pose Estimation Models under Occlusions</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.10350v3</link><description>Human Pose Estimation (HPE) involves detecting and localizing keypoints on the human body from visual data. In 3D HPE, occlusions, where parts of the body are not visible in the image, pose a significant challenge for accurate pose reconstruction. This paper presents a benchmark on the robustness of 3D HPE models under realistic occlusion conditions, involving combinations of occluded keypoints commonly observed in real-world scenarios. We evaluate nine state-of-the-art 2D-to-3D HPE models, spanning convolutional, transformer-based, graph-based, and diffusion-based architectures, using the BlendMimic3D dataset, a synthetic dataset with ground-truth 2D/3D annotations and occlusion labels. All models were originally trained on Human3.6M and tested here without retraining to assess their generalization. We introduce a protocol that simulates occlusion by adding noise into 2D keypoints based on real detector behavior, and conduct both global and per-joint sensitivity analyses. Our findings reveal that all models exhibit notable performance degradation under occlusion, with diffusion-based models underperforming despite their stochastic nature. Additionally, a per-joint occlusion analysis identifies consistent vulnerability in distal joints (e.g., wrists, feet) across models. Overall, this work highlights critical limitations of current 3D HPE models in handling occlusions, and provides insights for improving real-world robustness.</description><author>Filipa Lino, Carlos Santiago, Manuel Marques</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:53:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.10350v3</guid></item><item><title>Drug Release Modeling using Physics-Informed Neural Networks</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09963v1</link><description>Accurate modeling of drug release is essential for designing and developing controlled-release systems. Classical models (Fick, Higuchi, Peppas) rely on simplifying assumptions that limit their accuracy in complex geometries and release mechanisms. Here, we propose a novel approach using Physics-Informed Neural Networks (PINNs) and Bayesian PINNs (BPINNs) for predicting release from planar, 1D-wrinkled, and 2D-crumpled films. This approach uniquely integrates Fick's diffusion law with limited experimental data to enable accurate long-term predictions from short-term measurements, and is systematically benchmarked against classical drug release models. We embedded Fick's second law into PINN as loss with 10,000 Latin-hypercube collocation points and utilized previously published experimental datasets to assess drug release performance through mean absolute error (MAE) and root mean square error (RMSE), considering noisy conditions and limited-data scenarios. Our approach reduced mean error by up to 40% relative to classical baselines across all film types. The PINN formulation achieved RMSE &lt;0.05 utilizing only the first 6% of the release time data (reducing 94% of release time required for the experiments) for the planar film. For wrinkled and crumpled films, the PINN reached RMSE &lt;0.05 in 33% of the release time data. BPINNs provide tighter and more reliable uncertainty quantification under noise. By combining physical laws with experimental data, the proposed framework yields highly accurate long-term release predictions from short-term measurements, offering a practical route for accelerated characterization and more efficient early-stage drug release system formulation.</description><author>Daanish Aleem Qureshi, Khemraj Shukla, Vikas Srivastava</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:51:50 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09963v1</guid></item><item><title>Chunking Strategies for Multimodal AI Systems</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.00185v2</link><description>Chunking has emerged as a critical technique that enhances generative models by grounding their responses in efficiently segmented knowledge [1]. While initially developed for unimodal (primarily textual) domains, recent advances in multimodal foundation models have extended chunking approaches to incorporate diverse data types, including images, audio, and video [2]. A critical component underpinning the success of these systems is the chunking strategy how large, continuous streams of multimodal data are segmented into semantically meaningful units suitable for processing [3]. Despite its importance, chunking remains an under-explored area, especially in the context of multimodal systems where modality-specific constraints, semantic preservation, and alignment across modalities introduce unique challenges.Our goal is to consolidating the landscape of multimodal chunking strategies, providing researchers and practitioners with a technical foundation and design space for developing more effective and efficient multimodal AI systems. This survey paves the way for innovations in robust chunking pipelines that scale with modality complexity, enhance processing accuracy, and improve generative coherence in real-world applications. This survey provides a comprehensive taxonomy and technical analysis of chunking strategies tailored for each modality: text, images, audio, video, and cross-modal data. We examine classical and modern approaches such as fixed-size token windowing, recursive text splitting, object-centric visual chunking, silence-based audio segmentation, and scene detection in videos. Each approach is analyzed in terms of its underlying methodology, supporting tools (e.g., LangChain, Detectron2, PySceneDetect), benefits, and challenges, particularly those related to granularity-context trade-offs and multimodal alignment. Furthermore, we explore emerging cross-modal chunking strategies that aim to preserve alignment and semantic consistency across disparate data types [4]. We also include comparative insights, highlight open problems such as asynchronous information density and noisy alignment signals, and identify opportunities for future research in adaptive, learning-based, and task-specific chunking.</description><author>Shashanka B R, Mohith Charan R, Seema Banu F</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:51:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.00185v2</guid></item><item><title>ViMultiChoice: Toward a Method That Gives Explanation for Multiple-Choice Reading Comprehension in Vietnamese</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09961v1</link><description>Multiple-choice Reading Comprehension (MCRC) models aim to select the correct answer from a set of candidate options for a given question. However, they typically lack the ability to explain the reasoning behind their choices. In this paper, we introduce a novel Vietnamese dataset designed to train and evaluate MCRC models with explanation generation capabilities. Furthermore, we propose ViMultiChoice, a new method specifically designed for modeling Vietnamese reading comprehension that jointly predicts the correct answer and generates a corresponding explanation. Experimental results demonstrate that ViMultiChoice outperforms existing MCRC baselines, achieving state-of-the-art (SotA) performance on both the ViMMRC 2.0 benchmark and the newly introduced dataset. Additionally, we show that jointly training option decision and explanation generation leads to significant improvements in multiple-choice accuracy.</description><author>Trung Tien Cao, Lam Minh Thai, Nghia Hieu Nguyen, Duc-Vu Nguyen, Ngan Luu-Thuy Nguyen</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:48:07 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09961v1</guid></item><item><title>Entropy-Aware Structural Alignment for Zero-Shot Handwritten Chinese Character Recognition</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.03913v2</link><description>Zero-shot Handwritten Chinese Character Recognition (HCCR) aims to recognize unseen characters by leveraging radical-based semantic compositions. However, existing approaches often treat characters as flat radical sequences, neglecting the hierarchical topology and the uneven information density of different components. To address these limitations, we propose an Entropy-Aware Structural Alignment Network that bridges the visual-semantic gap through information-theoretic modeling. First, we introduce an Information Entropy Prior to dynamically modulate positional embeddings via multiplicative interaction, acting as a saliency detector that prioritizes discriminative roots over ubiquitous components. Second, we construct a Dual-View Radical Tree to extract multi-granularity structural features, which are integrated via an adaptive Sigmoid-based gating network to encode both global layout and local spatial roles. Finally, a Top-K Semantic Feature Fusion mechanism is devised to augment the decoding process by utilizing the centroid of semantic neighbors, effectively rectifying visual ambiguities through feature-level consensus. Extensive experiments demonstrate that our method establishes new state-of-the-art performance, achieving an accuracy of 55.04\% on the ICDAR 2013 dataset ($m=1500$), significantly outperforming existing CLIP-based baselines in the challenging zero-shot setting. Furthermore, the framework exhibits exceptional data efficiency, demonstrating rapid adaptability with minimal support samples, achieving 92.41\% accuracy with only one support sample per class.</description><author>Qiuming Luo, Tao Zeng, Feng Li, Heming Liu, Rui Mao, Chang Kong</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:46:50 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.03913v2</guid></item><item><title>Residual Decoding: Mitigating Hallucinations in Large Vision-Language Models via History-Aware Residual Guidance</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.01047v2</link><description>Large Vision-Language Models (LVLMs) can reason effectively from image-text inputs and perform well in various multimodal tasks. Despite this success, they are affected by language priors and often produce hallucinations. Hallucinations denote generated content that is grammatically and syntactically coherent, yet bears no match or direct relevance to actual visual input. To address this problem, we propose Residual Decoding (ResDec). It is a novel training-free method that uses historical information to aid decoding. The method relies on the internal implicit reasoning mechanism and token logits evolution mechanism of LVLMs to correct biases. Extensive experiments demonstrate that ResDec effectively suppresses hallucinations induced by language priors, significantly improves visual grounding, and reduces object hallucinations. In addition to mitigating hallucinations, ResDec also performs exceptionally well on comprehensive LVLM benchmarks, highlighting its broad applicability.</description><author>Xinrong Chen, Xu Chu, Yingmin Qiu, Hengyuan Zhang, Jing Xiong, Shiyu Tang, Shuai Liu, Shaokang Yang, Cheng Yang, Hayden Kwok-Hay So, Ngai Wong</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:46:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.01047v2</guid></item><item><title>Statistical-Computational Trade-offs in Learning Multi-Index Models via Harmonic Analysis</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09959v1</link><description>We study the problem of learning multi-index models (MIMs), where the label depends on the input $\boldsymbol{x} \in \mathbb{R}^d$ only through an unknown $\mathsf{s}$-dimensional projection $\boldsymbol{W}_*^\mathsf{T} \boldsymbol{x} \in \mathbb{R}^\mathsf{s}$. Exploiting the equivariance of this problem under the orthogonal group $\mathcal{O}_d$, we obtain a sharp harmonic-analytic characterization of the learning complexity for MIMs with spherically symmetric inputs -- which refines and generalizes previous Gaussian-specific analyses. Specifically, we derive statistical and computational complexity lower bounds within the Statistical Query (SQ) and Low-Degree Polynomial (LDP) frameworks. These bounds decompose naturally across spherical harmonic subspaces. Guided by this decomposition, we construct a family of spectral algorithms based on harmonic tensor unfolding that sequentially recover the latent directions and (nearly) achieve these SQ and LDP lower bounds. Depending on the choice of harmonic degree sequence, these estimators can realize a broad range of trade-offs between sample and runtime complexity. From a technical standpoint, our results build on the semisimple decomposition of the $\mathcal{O}_d$-action on $L^2 (\mathbb{S}^{d-1})$ and the intertwining isomorphism between spherical harmonics and traceless symmetric tensors.</description><author>Hugo Latourelle-Vigeant, Theodor Misiakiewicz</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:46:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09959v1</guid></item><item><title>ContextBench: A Benchmark for Context Retrieval in Coding Agents</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05892v2</link><description>LLM-based coding agents have shown strong performance on automated issue resolution benchmarks, yet existing evaluations largely focus on final task success, providing limited insight into how agents retrieve and use code context during problem solving. We introduce ContextBench, a process-oriented evaluation of context retrieval in coding agents. ContextBench consists of 1,136 issue-resolution tasks from 66 repositories across eight programming languages, each augmented with human-annotated gold contexts. We further implement an automated evaluation framework that tracks agent trajectories and measures context recall, precision, and efficiency throughout issue resolution. Using ContextBench, we evaluate four frontier LLMs and five coding agents. Our results show that sophisticated agent scaffolding yields only marginal gains in context retrieval ("The Bitter Lesson" of coding agents), LLMs consistently favor recall over precision, and substantial gaps exist between explored and utilized context. ContextBench augments existing end-to-end benchmarks with intermediate gold-context metrics that unbox the issue-resolution process. These contexts offer valuable intermediate signals for guiding LLM reasoning in software tasks.</description><author>Han Li, Letian Zhu, Bohan Zhang, Rili Feng, Jiaming Wang, Yue Pan, Earl T. Barr, Sarro Federica, Zhaoyang Chu, He Ye</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:46:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05892v2</guid></item><item><title>Spark: Modular Spiking Neural Networks</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.02306v2</link><description>Nowadays, neural networks act as a synonym for artificial intelligence. Present neural network models, although remarkably powerful, are inefficient both in terms of data and energy. Several alternative forms of neural networks have been proposed to address some of these problems. Specifically, spiking neural networks are suitable for efficient hardware implementations. However, effective learning algorithms for spiking networks remain elusive, although it is suspected that effective plasticity mechanisms could alleviate the problem of data efficiency. Here, we present a new framework for spiking neural networks - Spark - built upon the idea of modular design, from simple components to entire models. The aim of this framework is to provide an efficient and streamlined pipeline for spiking neural networks. We showcase this framework by solving the sparse-reward cartpole problem with simple plasticity mechanisms. We hope that a framework compatible with traditional ML pipelines may accelerate research in the area, specifically for continuous and unbatched learning, akin to the one animals exhibit.</description><author>Mario Franco, Carlos Gershenson</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:45:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.02306v2</guid></item><item><title>ATTNPO: Attention-Guided Process Supervision for Efficient Reasoning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09953v1</link><description>Large reasoning models trained with reinforcement learning and verifiable rewards (RLVR) achieve strong performance on complex reasoning tasks, yet often overthink, generating redundant reasoning without performance gains. Existing trajectory-level length penalties often fail to effectively shorten reasoning length and degrade accuracy, as they uniformly treat all reasoning steps and lack fine-grained signals to distinguish redundancy from necessity. Meanwhile, process-supervised methods are typically resource-intensive and suffer from inaccurate credit assignment. To address these issues, we propose ATTNPO, a low-overhead process-supervised RL framework that leverages the model's intrinsic attention signals for step-level credit assignment. We first identify a set of special attention heads that naturally focus on essential steps while suppressing redundant ones. By leveraging the attention scores of these heads, We then employ two sub-strategies to mitigate overthinking by discouraging redundant steps while preserving accuracy by reducing penalties on essential steps. Experimental results show that ATTNPO substantially reduces reasoning length while significantly improving performance across 9 benchmarks.</description><author>Shuaiyi Nie, Siyu Ding, Wenyuan Zhang, Linhao Yu, Tianmeng Yang, Yao Chen, Tingwen Liu, Weichong Yin, Yu Sun, Hua Wu</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:40:22 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09953v1</guid></item><item><title>Inference-Aware Prompt Optimization for Aligning Black-Box Large Language Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.10030v3</link><description>Prompt optimization methods have demonstrated significant effectiveness in aligning black-box large language models (LLMs). In parallel, inference scaling strategies such as Best-of-N Sampling and Majority Voting have likewise been shown to improve alignment and performance by trading additional computation for better output. However, existing prompt optimization approaches are inference strategy agnostic; that is, they optimize prompts without accounting for the inference strategy. This constitutes a significant methodological gap, as our empirical and theoretical analysis reveals a strong interdependence between these two paradigms. Moreover, we find that user preferences regarding trade-offs among multiple objectives and inference budgets substantially influence the choice of prompt and inference configuration. To address this gap, we introduce a novel unified framework named IAPO (Inference-Aware Prompt Optimization) that jointly optimizes the prompt and inference scale, while being aware of the inference budget and different task objectives. We then develop a fixed-budget training algorithm for IAPO, called PSST (Prompt Scaling via Sequential Trimming), and establish finite-budget guarantees on the error probability. Finally, we evaluate the effectiveness of PSST on six tasks, including multi-objective text generation and reasoning, and demonstrate the critical role of incorporating inference-awareness in aligning black-box LLMs using prompt optimization.</description><author>Saaduddin Mahmud, Mason Nakamura, Kyle Hollins Wray, Shlomo Zilberstein</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:38:03 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.10030v3</guid></item><item><title>Structural Plasticity as Active Inference: A Biologically-Inspired Architecture for Homeostatic Control</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.02241v4</link><description>Traditional neural networks, while powerful, rely on biologically implausible learning mechanisms such as global backpropagation. This paper introduces the Structurally Adaptive Predictive Inference Network (SAPIN), a novel computational model inspired by the principles of active inference and the morphological plasticity observed in biological neural cultures. SAPIN operates on a 2D grid where processing units, or cells, learn by minimizing local prediction errors. The model features two primary, concurrent learning mechanisms: a local, Hebbian-like synaptic plasticity rule based on the temporal difference between a cell's actual activation and its learned expectation, and a structural plasticity mechanism where cells physically migrate across the grid to optimize their information-receptive fields. This dual approach allows the network to learn both how to process information (synaptic weights) and also where to position its computational resources (network topology). We validated the SAPIN model on the classic Cart Pole reinforcement learning benchmark. Our results demonstrate that the architecture can successfully solve the CartPole task, achieving robust performance. The network's intrinsic drive to minimize prediction error and maintain homeostasis was sufficient to discover a stable balancing policy. We also found that while continual learning led to instability, locking the network's parameters after achieving success resulted in a stable policy. When evaluated for 100 episodes post-locking (repeated over 100 successful agents), the locked networks maintained an average 82% success rate.</description><author>Brennen A. Hill</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:34:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.02241v4</guid></item><item><title>Bladder Vessel Segmentation using a Hybrid Attention-Convolution Framework</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09949v1</link><description>Urinary bladder cancer surveillance requires tracking tumor sites across repeated interventions, yet the deformable and hollow bladder lacks stable landmarks for orientation. While blood vessels visible during endoscopy offer a patient-specific "vascular fingerprint" for navigation, automated segmentation is challenged by imperfect endoscopic data, including sparse labels, artifacts like bubbles or variable lighting, continuous deformation, and mucosal folds that mimic vessels. State-of-the-art vessel segmentation methods often fail to address these domain-specific complexities. We introduce a Hybrid Attention-Convolution (HAC) architecture that combines Transformers to capture global vessel topology prior with a CNN that learns a residual refinement map to precisely recover thin-vessel details. To prioritize structural connectivity, the Transformer is trained on optimized ground truth data that exclude short and terminal branches. Furthermore, to address data scarcity, we employ a physics-aware pretraining, that is a self-supervised strategy using clinically grounded augmentations on unlabeled data. Evaluated on the BlaVeS dataset, consisting of endoscopic video frames, our approach achieves high accuracy (0.94) and superior precision (0.61) and clDice (0.66) compared to state-of-the-art medical segmentation models. Crucially, our method successfully suppresses false positives from mucosal folds that dynamically appear and vanish as the bladder fills and empties during surgery. Hence, HAC provides the reliable structural stability required for clinical navigation.</description><author>Franziska Krauß, Matthias Ege, Zoltan Lovasz, Albrecht Bartz-Schmidt, Igor Tsaur, Oliver Sawodny, Carina Veil</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:34:17 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09949v1</guid></item><item><title>OmniMER: Auxiliary-Enhanced LLM Adaptation for Indonesian Multimodal Emotion Recognition</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.19379v3</link><description>Indonesian, spoken by over 200 million people, remains underserved in multimodal emotion recognition research despite its dominant presence on Southeast Asian social media platforms. We introduce IndoMER, the first multimodal emotion recognition benchmark for Indonesian, comprising 1,944 video segments from 203 speakers with temporally aligned text, audio, and visual annotations across seven emotion categories. The dataset exhibits realistic challenges including cross-modal inconsistency and long-tailed class distributions shaped by Indonesian cultural communication norms. To address these challenges, we propose OmniMER, a multimodal adaptation framework built upon Qwen2.5-Omni that enhances emotion recognition through three auxiliary modality-specific perception tasks: emotion keyword extraction for text, facial expression analysis for video, and prosody analysis for audio. These auxiliary tasks help the model identify emotion-relevant cues in each modality before fusion, reducing reliance on spurious correlations in low-resource settings. Experiments on IndoMER show that OmniMER achieves 0.582 Macro-F1 on sentiment classification and 0.454 on emotion recognition, outperforming the base model by 7.6 and 22.1 absolute points respectively. Cross-lingual evaluation on the Chinese CH-SIMS dataset further demonstrates the generalizability of the proposed framework. The dataset and code are publicly available. https://github.com/yanxm01/INDOMER</description><author>Xueming Yan, Boyan Xu, Yaochu Jin, Lixian Xiao, Wenlong Ye, Runyang Cai, Zeqi Zheng, Jingfa Liu, Aimin Yang, Yongduan Song</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:29:47 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.19379v3</guid></item><item><title>Closing Reasoning Gaps in Clinical Agents with Differential Reasoning Learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09945v1</link><description>Clinical decision support requires not only correct answers but also clinically valid reasoning. We propose Differential Reasoning Learning (DRL), a framework that improves clinical agents by learning from reasoning discrepancies. From reference reasoning rationales (e.g., physician-authored clinical rationale, clinical guidelines, or outputs from more capable models) and the agent's free-form chain-of-thought (CoT), DRL extracts reasoning graphs as directed acyclic graphs (DAGs) and performs a clinically weighted graph edit distance (GED)-based discrepancy analysis. An LLM-as-a-judge aligns semantically equivalent nodes and diagnoses discrepancies between graphs. These graph-level discrepancy diagnostics are converted into natural-language instructions and stored in a Differential Reasoning Knowledge Base (DR-KB). At inference, we retrieve top-$k$ instructions via Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) to augment the agent prompt and patch likely logic gaps. Evaluation on open medical question answering (QA) benchmarks and a Return Visit Admissions (RVA) prediction task from internal clinical data demonstrates gains over baselines, improving both final-answer accuracy and reasoning fidelity. Ablation studies confirm gains from infusing reference reasoning rationales and the top-$k$ retrieval strategy. Clinicians' review of the output provides further assurance of the approach. Together, results suggest that DRL supports more reliable clinical decision-making in complex reasoning scenarios and offers a practical mechanism for deployment under limited token budgets.</description><author>Jinsong Liu, Yuhang Jiang, Ramayya Krishnan, Rema Padman, Yiye Zhang, Jiang Bian</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:29:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09945v1</guid></item><item><title>Instruct2Act: From Human Instruction to Actions Sequencing and Execution via Robot Action Network for Robotic Manipulation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09940v1</link><description>Robots often struggle to follow free-form human instructions in real-world settings due to computational and sensing limitations. We address this gap with a lightweight, fully on-device pipeline that converts natural-language commands into reliable manipulation. Our approach has two stages: (i) the instruction to actions module (Instruct2Act), a compact BiLSTM with a multi-head-attention autoencoder that parses an instruction into an ordered sequence of atomic actions (e.g., reach, grasp, move, place); and (ii) the robot action network (RAN), which uses the dynamic adaptive trajectory radial network (DATRN) together with a vision-based environment analyzer (YOLOv8) to generate precise control trajectories for each sub-action. The entire system runs on a modest system with no cloud services. On our custom proprietary dataset, Instruct2Act attains 91.5% sub-actions prediction accuracy while retaining a small footprint. Real-robot evaluations across four tasks (pick-place, pick-pour, wipe, and pick-give) yield an overall 90% success; sub-action inference completes in &lt; 3.8s, with end-to-end executions in 30-60s depending on task complexity. These results demonstrate that fine-grained instruction-to-action parsing, coupled with DATRN-based trajectory generation and vision-guided grounding, provides a practical path to deterministic, real-time manipulation in resource-constrained, single-camera settings.</description><author>Archit Sharma, Dharmendra Sharma, John Rebeiro, Peeyush Thakur, Narendra Dhar, Laxmidhar Behera</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:25:39 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09940v1</guid></item><item><title>Generative AI and Firm Productivity: Field Experiments in Online Retail</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.12049v3</link><description>We quantify the impact of Generative Artificial Intelligence (GenAI) on firm productivity through a series of large-scale randomized field experiments involving millions of users and products at a leading cross-border online retail platform. Over six months in 2023-2024, GenAI-based enhancements were integrated into seven consumer-facing business workflows. We find that GenAI adoption significantly increases sales, with treatment effects ranging from $0\%$ to $16.3\%$, depending on GenAI's marginal contribution relative to existing firm practices. Because inputs and prices were held constant across experimental arms, these gains map directly into total factor productivity improvements. Across the four GenAI applications with positive sales effects, the implied annual incremental value is approximately $\$ 5$ per consumer-an economically meaningful impact given the retailer's scale and the early stage of GenAI adoption. The primary mechanism operates through higher conversion rates, consistent with GenAI reducing frictions and improving consumer experience. Importantly, these effects are not associated with worse post-purchase outcomes, as product return rates and customer ratings do not deteriorate. Finally, we document substantial demand-side heterogeneity, with larger gains for less experienced consumers. Our findings provide novel, large-scale causal evidence on the productivity effects of GenAI in online retail, highlighting both its immediate value and broader potential.</description><author>Lu Fang, Zhe Yuan, Kaifu Zhang, Dante Donati, Miklos Sarvary</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:24:46 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.12049v3</guid></item><item><title>Multi-Objective $\textit{min-max}$ Online Convex Optimization</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.13560v3</link><description>In this paper, we broaden the horizon of online convex optimization (OCO), and consider multi-objective OCO, where there are $K$ distinct loss function sequences, and an algorithm has to choose its action at time $t$, before the $K$ loss functions at time $t$ are revealed. To capture the tradeoff between tracking the $K$ different sequences, we consider the {\it min-max} regret, where the benchmark (optimal offline algorithm) takes a static action across all time slots that minimizes the maximum of the total loss (summed across time slots) incurred by each of the $K$ sequences. An online algorithm is allowed to change its action across time slots, and its {\it min-max} regret is defined as the difference between its {\it min-max} cost and that of the benchmark. The {\it min-max} regret is a stringent performance measure and an algorithm with small regret needs to `track' all loss functions simultaneously. We first show that with adversarial input, {\it min-max} regret scales linearly with the time horizon $T$ for any online algorithm. Consequently, we consider a stochastic i.i.d. input model where all loss functions are i.i.d. generated from an unknown joint distribution and propose a simple algorithm that combines the well-known {\it Hedge} and online gradient descent (OGD) and show via a remarkably simple proof that its expected {\it min-max} regret is $O(\sqrt{T \log (T K)})$. Analogous results are also derived for Martingale difference and Markov input models.</description><author>Rahul Vaze, Sumiran Mishra</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:23:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.13560v3</guid></item><item><title>Predictive Modeling of Power Outages during Extreme Events: Integrating Weather and Socio-Economic Factors</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.22699v3</link><description>This paper presents a novel learning based framework for predicting power outages caused by extreme events. The proposed approach targets low-probability high-consequence outage scenarios and leverages a comprehensive set of features derived from publicly available data sources. We integrate EAGLE-I outage records from 2014 to 2024 with weather, socioeconomic, infrastructure, and seasonal event data. Incorporating social and demographic indicators reveals patterns of community vulnerability and improves understanding of outage risk during extreme conditions. Four machine learning models are evaluated, including Random Forest (RF), Graph Neural Network (GNN), Adaptive Boosting (AdaBoost), and Long Short-Term Memory (LSTM). Experimental validation is performed on a large-scale dataset covering counties in the lower peninsula of Michigan. Among all models tested, the LSTM network achieves higher accuracy.</description><author>Nina Fatehi, Antar Kumar Biswas, Masoud H. Nazari</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:22:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.22699v3</guid></item><item><title>Toward Efficient and Robust Behavior Models for Multi-Agent Driving Simulation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.05812v3</link><description>Scalable multi-agent driving simulation requires behavior models that are both realistic and computationally efficient. We address this by optimizing the behavior model that controls individual traffic participants. To improve efficiency, we adopt an instance-centric scene representation, where each traffic participant and map element is modeled in its own local coordinate frame. This design enables efficient, viewpoint-invariant scene encoding and allows static map tokens to be reused across simulation steps. To model interactions, we employ a query-centric symmetric context encoder with relative positional encodings between local frames. We use Adversarial Inverse Reinforcement Learning to learn the behavior model and propose an adaptive reward transformation that automatically balances robustness and realism during training. Experiments demonstrate that our approach scales efficiently with the number of tokens, significantly reducing training and inference times, while outperforming several agent-centric baselines in terms of positional accuracy and robustness.</description><author>Fabian Konstantinidis, Moritz Sackmann, Ulrich Hofmann, Christoph Stiller</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:20:31 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.05812v3</guid></item><item><title>Why Do AI Agents Systematically Fail at Cloud Root Cause Analysis?</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09937v1</link><description>Failures in large-scale cloud systems incur substantial financial losses, making automated Root Cause Analysis (RCA) essential for operational stability. Recent efforts leverage Large Language Model (LLM) agents to automate this task, yet existing systems exhibit low detection accuracy even with capable models, and current evaluation frameworks assess only final answer correctness without revealing why the agent's reasoning failed. This paper presents a process level failure analysis of LLM-based RCA agents. We execute the full OpenRCA benchmark across five LLM models, producing 1,675 agent runs, and classify observed failures into 12 pitfall types across intra-agent reasoning, inter-agent communication, and agent-environment interaction. Our analysis reveals that the most prevalent pitfalls, notably hallucinated data interpretation and incomplete exploration, persist across all models regardless of capability tier, indicating that these failures originate from the shared agent architecture rather than from individual model limitations. Controlled mitigation experiments further show that prompt engineering alone cannot resolve the dominant pitfalls, whereas enriching the inter-agent communication protocol reduces communication-related failures by up to 15 percentage points. The pitfall taxonomy and diagnostic methodology developed in this work provide a foundation for designing more reliable autonomous agents for cloud RCA.</description><author>Taeyoon Kim, Woohyeok Park, Hoyeong Yun, Kyungyong Lee</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:14:05 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09937v1</guid></item><item><title>The Catastrophic Failure of The k-Means Algorithm in High Dimensions, and How Hartigan's Algorithm Avoids It</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09936v1</link><description>Lloyd's k-means algorithm is one of the most widely used clustering methods. We prove that in high-dimensional, high-noise settings, the algorithm exhibits catastrophic failure: with high probability, essentially every partition of the data is a fixed point. Consequently, Lloyd's algorithm simply returns its initial partition - even when the underlying clusters are trivially recoverable by other methods. In contrast, we prove that Hartigan's k-means algorithm does not exhibit this pathology. Our results show the stark difference between these algorithms and offer a theoretical explanation for the empirical difficulties often observed with k-means in high dimensions.</description><author>Roy R. Lederman, David Silva-Sánchez, Ziling Chen, Gilles Mordant, Amnon Balanov, Tamir Bendory</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:10:59 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09936v1</guid></item></channel></rss>