<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Arxivfresh papers</title><link></link><description>Arxiv paper</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 12:00:04 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.0.0</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Dataset Distillation for Pre-Trained Self-Supervised Vision Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16674v1</link><description>The task of dataset distillation aims to find a small set of synthetic images such that training a model on them reproduces the performance of the same model trained on a much larger dataset of real samples. Existing distillation methods focus on synthesizing datasets that enable training randomly initialized models. In contrast, state-of-the-art vision approaches are increasingly building on large, pre-trained self-supervised models rather than training from scratch. In this paper, we investigate the problem of distilling datasets that enable us to optimally train linear probes on top of such large, pre-trained vision models. We introduce a method of dataset distillation for this task called Linear Gradient Matching that optimizes the synthetic images such that, when passed through a pre-trained feature extractor, they induce gradients in the linear classifier similar to those produced by the real data. Our method yields synthetic data that outperform all real-image baselines and, remarkably, generalize across pre-trained vision models, enabling us, for instance, to train a linear CLIP probe that performs competitively using a dataset distilled via a DINO backbone. Further, we show that our distilled datasets are exceptionally effective for fine-grained classification and provide a valuable tool for model interpretability, predicting, among other things, how similar two models' embedding spaces are under the platonic representation hypothesis or whether a model is sensitive to spurious correlations in adversarial datasets.</description><author>George Cazenavette, Antonio Torralba, Vincent Sitzmann</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:59:57 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16674v1</guid></item><item><title>NoPo-Avatar: Generalizable and Animatable Avatars from Sparse Inputs without Human Poses</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16673v1</link><description>We tackle the task of recovering an animatable 3D human avatar from a single or a sparse set of images. For this task, beyond a set of images, many prior state-of-the-art methods use accurate "ground-truth" camera poses and human poses as input to guide reconstruction at test-time. We show that pose-dependent reconstruction degrades results significantly if pose estimates are noisy. To overcome this, we introduce NoPo-Avatar, which reconstructs avatars solely from images, without any pose input. By removing the dependence of test-time reconstruction on human poses, NoPo-Avatar is not affected by noisy human pose estimates, making it more widely applicable. Experiments on challenging THuman2.0, XHuman, and HuGe100K data show that NoPo-Avatar outperforms existing baselines in practical settings (without ground-truth poses) and delivers comparable results in lab settings (with ground-truth poses).</description><author>Jing Wen, Alexander G. Schwing, Shenlong Wang</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:59:54 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16673v1</guid></item><item><title>EvoLMM: Self-Evolving Large Multimodal Models with Continuous Rewards</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16672v1</link><description>Recent advances in large multimodal models (LMMs) have enabled impressive reasoning and perception abilities, yet most existing training pipelines still depend on human-curated data or externally verified reward models, limiting their autonomy and scalability. In this work, we strive to improve LMM reasoning capabilities in a purely unsupervised fashion (without any annotated data or reward distillation). To this end, we propose a self-evolving framework, named EvoLMM, that instantiates two cooperative agents from a single backbone model: a Proposer, which generates diverse, image-grounded questions, and a Solver, which solves them through internal consistency, where learning proceeds through a continuous self-rewarding process. This dynamic feedback encourages both the generation of informative queries and the refinement of structured reasoning without relying on ground-truth or human judgments. When using the popular Qwen2.5-VL as the base model, our EvoLMM yields consistent gains upto $\sim$3\% on multimodal math-reasoning benchmarks, including ChartQA, MathVista, and MathVision, using only raw training images. We hope our simple yet effective approach will serve as a solid baseline easing future research in self-improving LMMs in a fully-unsupervised fashion. Our code and models are available at https://github.com/mbzuai-oryx/EvoLMM.</description><author>Omkat Thawakar, Shravan Venkatraman, Ritesh Thawkar, Abdelrahman Shaker, Hisham Cholakkal, Rao Muhammad Anwer, Salman Khan, Fahad Khan</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:59:54 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16672v1</guid></item><item><title>Thinking-while-Generating: Interleaving Textual Reasoning throughout Visual Generation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16671v1</link><description>Recent advances in visual generation have increasingly explored the integration of reasoning capabilities. They incorporate textual reasoning, i.e., think, either before (as pre-planning) or after (as post-refinement) the generation process, yet they lack on-the-fly multimodal interaction during the generation itself. In this preliminary study, we introduce Thinking-while-Generating (TwiG), the first interleaved framework that enables co-evolving textual reasoning throughout the visual generation process. As visual content is progressively generating, textual reasoning is interleaved to both guide upcoming local regions and reflect on previously synthesized ones. This dynamic interplay produces more context-aware and semantically rich visual outputs. To unveil the potential of this framework, we investigate three candidate strategies, zero-shot prompting, supervised fine-tuning (SFT) on our curated TwiG-50K dataset, and reinforcement learning (RL) via a customized TwiG-GRPO strategy, each offering unique insights into the dynamics of interleaved reasoning. We hope this work inspires further research into interleaving textual reasoning for enhanced visual generation. Code will be released at: https://github.com/ZiyuGuo99/Thinking-while-Generating.</description><author>Ziyu Guo, Renrui Zhang, Hongyu Li, Manyuan Zhang, Xinyan Chen, Sifan Wang, Yan Feng, Peng Pei, Pheng-Ann Heng</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:59:52 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16671v1</guid></item><item><title>Learning to Think Fast and Slow for Visual Language Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16670v1</link><description>When confronted with complex problems, we tend to think slowly; conversely, for simple questions, we think quickly. Such a two-system thinking mechanism allows us to efficiently allocate cognitive resources, enabling quick decision-making for straightforward issues while reserving deeper analytical thinking for more intricate challenges. However, existing reasoning-oriented visual language models (VLMs), whether trained with explicit chain-of-thought annotations or rule-based RL rewards, mainly pursue lengthy, detailed reasoning chains, which often lead to excessive computational costs. In this work, we propose a simple RL approach, which enables VLMs to automatically switch between fast and slow thinking modes depending on task difficulty. The approach consists of two stages: in the first stage, we label data as either requiring fast thinking or slow thinking based on the model output length, which is inspired by the observation that pre-trained VLMs typically produce answers of varying lengths for different types of questions; in the second stage, we train the model using GRPO along with the thinking mode labels to develop dual-mode thinking. Despite its simplicity, our model, named DualMindVLM, significantly outperforms the base model and achieves performance on par with state-of-the-art visual reasoning models, while maintaining exceptionally high token efficiency.</description><author>Chenyu Lin, Cheng Chi, Jinlin Wu, Sharon Li, Kaiyang Zhou</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:59:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16670v1</guid></item><item><title>Video-as-Answer: Predict and Generate Next Video Event with Joint-GRPO</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16669v1</link><description>While language models have become impactful in many real-world applications, video generation remains largely confined to entertainment. Motivated by video's inherent capacity to demonstrate physical-world information that is difficult to convey through language alone (e.g., imagine teaching someone to tie a tie using only text), we identify an underutilized opportunity to extend video as a new answer modality for Next-Event Prediction (NEP), formalized as Video-Next-Event Prediction (VNEP). While the established NEP task takes a video with a procedural or predictive question as input to predict the next event in text, VNEP requires dynamic video responses. This shift from telling to showing unlocks more intuitive and customized answers for procedural learning and creative exploration. However, this task remains challenging for existing models, as it demands an understanding of multimodal input, instruction-conditioned reasoning, and the generation of video with visual and semantic consistency. To address this, we introduce VANS, a model that leverages reinforcement learning to align a Vision-Language Model (VLM) with a Video Diffusion Model (VDM) for VNEP. The core of VANS is our proposed Joint-GRPO that orchestrates the VLM and VDM to function as a unit. Driven by a shared reward on their respective output, it optimizes the VLM to produce captions that are both accurate and friendly to visualize, while guiding the VDM to generate videos that are faithful to these captions and the input visual context. To enable this learning, we craft VANS-Data-100K, a dedicated dataset for the VNEP task. Experiments on procedural and predictive benchmarks demonstrate that VANS achieves state-of-the-art performance in both video event prediction and visualization. Codes are released in https://github.com/KlingTeam/VANS.</description><author>Junhao Cheng, Liang Hou, Xin Tao, Jing Liao</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:59:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16669v1</guid></item><item><title>V-ReasonBench: Toward Unified Reasoning Benchmark Suite for Video Generation Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16668v1</link><description>Recent progress in generative video models, such as Veo-3, has shown surprising zero-shot reasoning abilities, creating a growing need for systematic and reliable evaluation. We introduce V-ReasonBench, a benchmark designed to assess video reasoning across four key dimensions: structured problem-solving, spatial cognition, pattern-based inference, and physical dynamics. The benchmark is built from both synthetic and real-world image sequences and provides a diverse set of answer-verifiable tasks that are reproducible, scalable, and unambiguous. Evaluations of six state-of-the-art video models reveal clear dimension-wise differences, with strong variation in structured, spatial, pattern-based, and physical reasoning. We further compare video models with strong image models, analyze common hallucination behaviors, and study how video duration affects Chain-of-Frames reasoning. Overall, V-ReasonBench offers a unified and reproducible framework for measuring video reasoning and aims to support the development of models with more reliable, human-aligned reasoning skills.</description><author>Yang Luo, Xuanlei Zhao, Baijiong Lin, Lingting Zhu, Liyao Tang, Yuqi Liu, Ying-Cong Chen, Shengju Qian, Xin Wang, Yang You</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:59:42 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16668v1</guid></item><item><title>SceneDesigner: Controllable Multi-Object Image Generation with 9-DoF Pose Manipulation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16666v1</link><description>Controllable image generation has attracted increasing attention in recent years, enabling users to manipulate visual content such as identity and style. However, achieving simultaneous control over the 9D poses (location, size, and orientation) of multiple objects remains an open challenge. Despite recent progress, existing methods often suffer from limited controllability and degraded quality, falling short of comprehensive multi-object 9D pose control. To address these limitations, we propose SceneDesigner, a method for accurate and flexible multi-object 9-DoF pose manipulation. SceneDesigner incorporates a branched network to the pre-trained base model and leverages a new representation, CNOCS map, which encodes 9D pose information from the camera view. This representation exhibits strong geometric interpretation properties, leading to more efficient and stable training. To support training, we construct a new dataset, ObjectPose9D, which aggregates images from diverse sources along with 9D pose annotations. To further address data imbalance issues, particularly performance degradation on low-frequency poses, we introduce a two-stage training strategy with reinforcement learning, where the second stage fine-tunes the model using a reward-based objective on rebalanced data. At inference time, we propose Disentangled Object Sampling, a technique that mitigates insufficient object generation and concept confusion in complex multi-object scenes. Moreover, by integrating user-specific personalization weights, SceneDesigner enables customized pose control for reference subjects. Extensive qualitative and quantitative experiments demonstrate that SceneDesigner significantly outperforms existing approaches in both controllability and quality. Code is publicly available at https://github.com/FudanCVL/SceneDesigner.</description><author>Zhenyuan Qin, Xincheng Shuai, Henghui Ding</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:59:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16666v1</guid></item><item><title>Taming the Long-Tail: Efficient Reasoning RL Training with Adaptive Drafter</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16665v1</link><description>The emergence of Large Language Models (LLMs) with strong reasoning capabilities marks a significant milestone, unlocking new frontiers in complex problem-solving. However, training these reasoning models, typically using Reinforcement Learning (RL), encounters critical efficiency bottlenecks: response generation during RL training exhibits a persistent long-tail distribution, where a few very long responses dominate execution time, wasting resources and inflating costs. To address this, we propose TLT, a system that accelerates reasoning RL training losslessly by integrating adaptive speculative decoding. Applying speculative decoding in RL is challenging due to the dynamic workloads, evolving target model, and draft model training overhead. TLT overcomes these obstacles with two synergistic components: (1) Adaptive Drafter, a lightweight draft model trained continuously on idle GPUs during long-tail generation to maintain alignment with the target model at no extra cost; and (2) Adaptive Rollout Engine, which maintains a memory-efficient pool of pre-captured CUDAGraphs and adaptively select suitable SD strategies for each input batch. Evaluations demonstrate that TLT achieves over 1.7x end-to-end RL training speedup over state-of-the-art systems, preserves the model accuracy, and yields a high-quality draft model as a free byproduct suitable for efficient deployment. Code is released at https://github.com/mit-han-lab/fastrl.</description><author>Qinghao Hu, Shang Yang, Junxian Guo, Xiaozhe Yao, Yujun Lin, Yuxian Gu, Han Cai, Chuang Gan, Ana Klimovic, Song Han</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:59:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16665v1</guid></item><item><title>Nemotron Elastic: Towards Efficient Many-in-One Reasoning LLMs</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16664v1</link><description>Training a family of large language models targeting multiple scales and deployment objectives is prohibitively expensive, requiring separate training runs for each different size. Recent work on model compression through pruning and knowledge distillation has reduced this cost; however, this process still incurs hundreds of billions of tokens worth of training cost per compressed model. In this paper, we present Nemotron Elastic, a framework for building reasoning-oriented LLMs, including hybrid Mamba-Attention architectures, that embed multiple nested submodels within a single parent model, each optimized for different deployment configurations and budgets. Each of these submodels shares weights with the parent model and can be extracted zero-shot during deployment without additional training or fine-tuning. We enable this functionality through an end-to-end trained router, tightly coupled to a two-stage training curriculum designed specifically for reasoning models. We additionally introduce group-aware SSM elastification that preserves Mamba's structural constraints, heterogeneous MLP elastification, normalized MSE-based layer importance for improved depth selection, and knowledge distillation enabling simultaneous multi-budget optimization. We apply Nemotron Elastic to the Nemotron Nano V2 12B model, simultaneously producing a 9B and a 6B model using only 110B training tokens; this results in over 360x cost reduction compared to training model families from scratch, and around 7x compared to SoTA compression techniques. Each of the nested models performs on par or better than the SoTA in accuracy. Moreover, unlike other compression methods, the nested capability of our approach allows having a many-in-one reasoning model that has constant deployment memory against the number of models in the family.</description><author>Ali Taghibakhshi, Sharath Turuvekere Sreenivas, Saurav Muralidharan, Ruisi Cai, Marcin Chochowski, Ameya Sunil Mahabaleshwarkar, Yoshi Suhara, Oluwatobi Olabiyi, Daniel Korzekwa, Mostofa Patwary, Mohammad Shoeybi, Jan Kautz, Bryan Catanzaro, Ashwath Aithal, Nima Tajbakhsh, Pavlo Molchanov</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:59:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16664v1</guid></item><item><title>TriDiff-4D: Fast 4D Generation through Diffusion-based Triplane Re-posing</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16662v1</link><description>With the increasing demand for 3D animation, generating high-fidelity, controllable 4D avatars from textual descriptions remains a significant challenge. Despite notable efforts in 4D generative modeling, existing methods exhibit fundamental limitations that impede their broader applicability, including temporal and geometric inconsistencies, perceptual artifacts, motion irregularities, high computational costs, and limited control over dynamics. To address these challenges, we propose TriDiff-4D, a novel 4D generative pipeline that employs diffusion-based triplane re-posing to produce high-quality, temporally coherent 4D avatars. Our model adopts an auto-regressive strategy to generate 4D sequences of arbitrary length, synthesizing each 3D frame with a single diffusion process. By explicitly learning 3D structure and motion priors from large-scale 3D and motion datasets, TriDiff-4D enables skeleton-driven 4D generation that excels in temporal consistency, motion accuracy, computational efficiency, and visual fidelity. Specifically, TriDiff-4D first generates a canonical 3D avatar and a corresponding motion sequence from a text prompt, then uses a second diffusion model to animate the avatar according to the motion sequence, supporting arbitrarily long 4D generation. Experimental results demonstrate that TriDiff-4D significantly outperforms existing methods, reducing generation time from hours to seconds by eliminating the optimization process, while substantially improving the generation of complex motions with high-fidelity appearance and accurate 3D geometry.</description><author>Eddie Pokming Sheung, Qihao Liu, Wufei Ma, Prakhar Kaushik, Jianwen Xie, Alan Yuille</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:59:03 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16662v1</guid></item><item><title>Dexterity from Smart Lenses: Multi-Fingered Robot Manipulation with In-the-Wild Human Demonstrations</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16661v1</link><description>Learning multi-fingered robot policies from humans performing daily tasks in natural environments has long been a grand goal in the robotics community. Achieving this would mark significant progress toward generalizable robot manipulation in human environments, as it would reduce the reliance on labor-intensive robot data collection. Despite substantial efforts, progress toward this goal has been bottle-necked by the embodiment gap between humans and robots, as well as by difficulties in extracting relevant contextual and motion cues that enable learning of autonomous policies from in-the-wild human videos. We claim that with simple yet sufficiently powerful hardware for obtaining human data and our proposed framework AINA, we are now one significant step closer to achieving this dream. AINA enables learning multi-fingered policies from data collected by anyone, anywhere, and in any environment using Aria Gen 2 glasses. These glasses are lightweight and portable, feature a high-resolution RGB camera, provide accurate on-board 3D head and hand poses, and offer a wide stereo view that can be leveraged for depth estimation of the scene. This setup enables the learning of 3D point-based policies for multi-fingered hands that are robust to background changes and can be deployed directly without requiring any robot data (including online corrections, reinforcement learning, or simulation). We compare our framework against prior human-to-robot policy learning approaches, ablate our design choices, and demonstrate results across nine everyday manipulation tasks. Robot rollouts are best viewed on our website: https://aina-robot.github.io.</description><author>Irmak Guzey, Haozhi Qi, Julen Urain, Changhao Wang, Jessica Yin, Krishna Bodduluri, Mike Lambeta, Lerrel Pinto, Akshara Rai, Jitendra Malik, Tingfan Wu, Akash Sharma, Homanga Bharadhwaj</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:59:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16661v1</guid></item><item><title>Cognitive Foundations for Reasoning and Their Manifestation in LLMs</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16660v1</link><description>Large language models solve complex problems yet fail on simpler variants, suggesting they achieve correct outputs through mechanisms fundamentally different from human reasoning. We synthesize cognitive science research into a taxonomy of 28 cognitive elements spanning computational constraints, meta-cognitive controls, knowledge representations, and transformation operations, then analyze their behavioral manifestations in reasoning traces. We propose a fine-grained cognitive evaluation framework and conduct the first large-scale analysis of 170K traces from 17 models across text, vision, and audio modalities, alongside 54 human think-aloud traces, which we make publicly available. Our analysis reveals systematic structural differences: humans employ hierarchical nesting and meta-cognitive monitoring while models rely on shallow forward chaining, with divergence most pronounced on ill-structured problems. Meta-analysis of 1,598 LLM reasoning papers reveals the research community concentrates on easily quantifiable behaviors (sequential organization: 55%, decomposition: 60%) while neglecting meta-cognitive controls (self-awareness: 16%, evaluation: 8%) that correlate with success. Models possess behavioral repertoires associated with success but fail to deploy them spontaneously. Leveraging these patterns, we develop test-time reasoning guidance that automatically scaffold successful structures, improving performance by up to 60% on complex problems. By bridging cognitive science and LLM research, we establish a foundation for developing models that reason through principled cognitive mechanisms rather than brittle spurious reasoning shortcuts or memorization, opening new directions for both improving model capabilities and testing theories of human cognition at scale.</description><author>Priyanka Kargupta, Shuyue Stella Li, Haocheng Wang, Jinu Lee, Shan Chen, Orevaoghene Ahia, Dean Light, Thomas L. Griffiths, Max Kleiman-Weiner, Jiawei Han, Asli Celikyilmaz, Yulia Tsvetkov</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:59:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16660v1</guid></item><item><title>PartUV: Part-Based UV Unwrapping of 3D Meshes</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16659v1</link><description>UV unwrapping flattens 3D surfaces to 2D with minimal distortion, often requiring the complex surface to be decomposed into multiple charts. Although extensively studied, existing UV unwrapping methods frequently struggle with AI-generated meshes, which are typically noisy, bumpy, and poorly conditioned. These methods often produce highly fragmented charts and suboptimal boundaries, introducing artifacts and hindering downstream tasks. We introduce PartUV, a part-based UV unwrapping pipeline that generates significantly fewer, part-aligned charts while maintaining low distortion. Built on top of a recent learning-based part decomposition method PartField, PartUV combines high-level semantic part decomposition with novel geometric heuristics in a top-down recursive framework. It ensures each chart's distortion remains below a user-specified threshold while minimizing the total number of charts. The pipeline integrates and extends parameterization and packing algorithms, incorporates dedicated handling of non-manifold and degenerate meshes, and is extensively parallelized for efficiency. Evaluated across four diverse datasets, including man-made, CAD, AI-generated, and Common Shapes, PartUV outperforms existing tools and recent neural methods in chart count and seam length, achieves comparable distortion, exhibits high success rates on challenging meshes, and enables new applications like part-specific multi-tiles packing. Our project page is at https://www.zhaoningwang.com/PartUV.</description><author>Zhaoning Wang, Xinyue Wei, Ruoxi Shi, Xiaoshuai Zhang, Hao Su, Minghua Liu</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:58:39 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16659v1</guid></item><item><title>Enhancing Forex Forecasting Accuracy: The Impact of Hybrid Variable Sets in Cognitive Algorithmic Trading Systems</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16657v1</link><description>This paper presents the implementation of an advanced artificial intelligence-based algorithmic trading system specifically designed for the EUR-USD pair within the high-frequency environment of the Forex market. The methodological approach centers on integrating a holistic set of input features: key fundamental macroeconomic variables (for example, Gross Domestic Product and Unemployment Rate) collected from both the Euro Zone and the United States, alongside a comprehensive suite of technical variables (including indicators, oscillators, Fibonacci levels, and price divergences). The performance of the resulting algorithm is evaluated using standard machine learning metrics to quantify predictive accuracy and backtesting simulations across historical data to assess trading profitability and risk. The study concludes with a comparative analysis to determine which class of input features, fundamental or technical, provides greater and more reliable predictive capacity for generating profitable trading signals.</description><author>Juan C. King, Jose M. Amigo</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:58:22 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16657v1</guid></item><item><title>Distance-Preserving Representations for Genomic Spatial Reconstruction</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00911v3</link><description>The spatial context of single-cell gene expression data is crucial for many downstream analyses, yet often remains inaccessible due to practical and technical limitations, restricting the utility of such datasets. In this paper, we propose a generic representation learning and transfer learning framework dp-VAE, capable of reconstructing the spatial coordinates associated with the provided gene expression data. Central to our approach is a distance-preserving regularizer integrated into the loss function during training, ensuring the model effectively captures and utilizes spatial context signals from reference datasets. During the inference stage, the produced latent representation of the model can be used to reconstruct or impute the spatial context of the provided gene expression by solving a constrained optimization problem. We also explore the theoretical connections between distance-preserving loss, distortion, and the bi-Lipschitz condition within generative models. Finally, we demonstrate the effectiveness of dp-VAE in different tasks involving training robustness, out-of-sample evaluation, and transfer learning inference applications by testing it over 27 publicly available datasets. This underscores its applicability to a wide range of genomics studies that were previously hindered by the absence of spatial data.</description><author>Wenbin Zhou, Jin-Hong Du</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:57:06 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.00911v3</guid></item><item><title>Solving Spatial Supersensing Without Spatial Supersensing</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16655v1</link><description>Cambrian-S aims to take the first steps towards improving video world models with spatial supersensing by introducing (i) two benchmarks, VSI-Super-Recall (VSR) and VSI-Super-Counting (VSC), and (ii) bespoke predictive sensing inference strategies tailored to each benchmark. In this work, we conduct a critical analysis of Cambrian-S across both these fronts. First, we introduce a simple baseline, NoSense, which discards almost all temporal structure and uses only a bag-of-words SigLIP model, yet near-perfectly solves VSR, achieving 95% accuracy even on 4-hour videos. This shows benchmarks like VSR can be nearly solved without spatial cognition, world modeling or spatial supersensing. Second, we hypothesize that the tailored inference methods proposed by Cambrian-S likely exploit shortcut heuristics in the benchmark. We illustrate this with a simple sanity check on the VSC benchmark, called VSC-Repeat: We concatenate each video with itself 1-5 times, which does not change the number of unique objects. However, this simple perturbation entirely collapses the mean relative accuracy of Cambrian-S from 42% to 0%. A system that performs spatial supersensing and integrates information across experiences should recognize views of the same scene and keep object-count predictions unchanged; instead, Cambrian-S inference algorithm relies largely on a shortcut in the VSC benchmark that rooms are never revisited. Taken together, our findings suggest that (i) current VSI-Super benchmarks do not yet reliably measure spatial supersensing, and (ii) predictive-sensing inference recipes used by Cambrian-S improve performance by inadvertently exploiting shortcuts rather than from robust spatial supersensing. We include the response from the Cambrian-S authors (in Appendix A) to provide a balanced perspective alongside our claims. We release our code at: https://github.com/bethgelab/supersanity</description><author>Vishaal Udandarao, Shyamgopal Karthik, Surabhi S. Nath, Andreas Hochlehnert, Matthias Bethge, Ameya Prabhu</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:57:05 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16655v1</guid></item><item><title>Comparison of Text-Based and Image-Based Retrieval in Multimodal Retrieval Augmented Generation Large Language Model Systems</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16654v1</link><description>Recent advancements in Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) have enabled Large Language Models (LLMs) to access multimodal knowledge bases containing both text and visual information such as charts, diagrams, and tables in financial documents. However, existing multimodal RAG systems rely on LLM-based summarization to convert images into text during preprocessing, storing only text representations in vector databases, which causes loss of contextual information and visual details critical for downstream retrieval and question answering. To address this limitation, we present a comprehensive comparative analysis of two retrieval approaches for multimodal RAG systems, including text-based chunk retrieval (where images are summarized into text before embedding) and direct multimodal embedding retrieval (where images are stored natively in the vector space). We evaluate all three approaches across 6 LLM models and a two multi-modal embedding models on a newly created financial earnings call benchmark comprising 40 question-answer pairs, each paired with 2 documents (1 image and 1 text chunk). Experimental results demonstrate that direct multimodal embedding retrieval significantly outperforms LLM-summary-based approaches, achieving absolute improvements of 13% in mean average precision (mAP@5) and 11% in normalized discounted cumulative gain. These gains correspond to relative improvements of 32% in mAP@5 and 20% in nDCG@5, providing stronger evidence of their practical impact. We additionally find that direct multimodal retrieval produces more accurate and factually consistent answers as measured by LLM-as-a-judge pairwise comparisons. We demonstrate that LLM summarization introduces information loss during preprocessing, whereas direct multimodal embeddings preserve visual context for retrieval and inference.</description><author>Elias Lumer, Alex Cardenas, Matt Melich, Myles Mason, Sara Dieter, Vamse Kumar Subbiah, Pradeep Honaganahalli Basavaraju, Roberto Hernandez</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:56:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16654v1</guid></item><item><title>LightFusion: A Light-weighted, Double Fusion Framework for Unified Multimodal Understanding and Generation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.22946v4</link><description>Unified multimodal models have recently shown remarkable gains in both capability and versatility, yet most leading systems are still trained from scratch and require substantial computational resources. In this paper, we show that competitive performance can be obtained far more efficiently by strategically fusing publicly available models specialized for either generation or understanding. Our key design is to retain the original blocks while additionally interleaving multimodal self-attention blocks throughout the networks. This double fusion mechanism (1) effectively enables rich multi-modal fusion while largely preserving the original strengths of the base models, and (2) catalyzes synergistic fusion of high-level semantic representations from the understanding encoder with low-level spatial signals from the generation encoder. By training with only ~ 35B tokens, this approach achieves strong results across multiple benchmarks: 0.91 on GenEval for compositional text-to-image generation, 82.16 on DPG-Bench for complex text-to-image generation, 6.06 on GEditBench, and 3.77 on ImgEdit-Bench for image editing. By fully releasing the entire suite of code, model weights, and datasets, we hope to support future research on unified multimodal modeling.</description><author>Zeyu Wang, Zilong Chen, Chenhui Gou, Feng Li, Chaorui Deng, Deyao Zhu, Kunchang Li, Weihao Yu, Haoqin Tu, Haoqi Fan, Cihang Xie</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:56:11 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.22946v4</guid></item><item><title>Evolution Strategies at the Hyperscale</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16652v1</link><description>We introduce Evolution Guided General Optimization via Low-rank Learning (EGGROLL), an evolution strategies (ES) algorithm designed to scale backprop-free optimization to large population sizes for modern large neural network architectures with billions of parameters. ES is a set of powerful blackbox optimisation methods that can handle non-differentiable or noisy objectives with excellent scaling potential through parallelisation. Na{ï}ve ES becomes prohibitively expensive at scale due to the computational and memory costs associated with generating matrix perturbations $E\in\mathbb{R}^{m\times n}$ and the batched matrix multiplications needed to compute per-member forward passes. EGGROLL overcomes these bottlenecks by generating random matrices $A\in \mathbb{R}^{m\times r},\ B\in \mathbb{R}^{n\times r}$ with $r\ll \min(m,n)$ to form a low-rank matrix perturbation $A B^\top$ that are used in place of the full-rank perturbation $E$. As the overall update is an average across a population of $N$ workers, this still results in a high-rank update but with significant memory and computation savings, reducing the auxiliary storage from $mn$ to $r(m+n)$ per layer and the cost of a forward pass from $\mathcal{O}(mn)$ to $\mathcal{O}(r(m+n))$ when compared to full-rank ES. A theoretical analysis reveals our low-rank update converges to the full-rank update at a fast $\mathcal{O}\left(\frac{1}{r}\right)$ rate. Our experiments show that (1) EGGROLL does not compromise the performance of ES in tabula-rasa RL settings, despite being faster, (2) it is competitive with GRPO as a technique for improving LLM reasoning, and (3) EGGROLL enables stable pre-training of nonlinear recurrent language models that operate purely in integer datatypes.</description><author>Bidipta Sarkar, Mattie Fellows, Juan Agustin Duque, Alistair Letcher, Antonio León Villares, Anya Sims, Dylan Cope, Jarek Liesen, Lukas Seier, Theo Wolf, Uljad Berdica, Alexander David Goldie, Aaron Courville, Karin Sevegnani, Shimon Whiteson, Jakob Nicolaus Foerster</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:56:05 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16652v1</guid></item><item><title>Teacher-Guided One-Shot Pruning via Context-Aware Knowledge Distillation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16653v1</link><description>Unstructured pruning remains a powerful strategy for compressing deep neural networks, yet it often demands iterative train-prune-retrain cycles, resulting in significant computational overhead. To address this challenge, we introduce a novel teacher-guided pruning framework that tightly integrates Knowledge Distillation (KD) with importance score estimation. Unlike prior approaches that apply KD as a post-pruning recovery step, our method leverages gradient signals informed by the teacher during importance score calculation to identify and retain parameters most critical for both task performance and knowledge transfer. Our method facilitates a one-shot global pruning strategy that efficiently eliminates redundant weights while preserving essential representations. After pruning, we employ sparsity-aware retraining with and without KD to recover accuracy without reactivating pruned connections. Comprehensive experiments across multiple image classification benchmarks, including CIFAR-10, CIFAR-100, and TinyImageNet, demonstrate that our method consistently achieves high sparsity levels with minimal performance degradation. Notably, our approach outperforms state-of-the-art baselines such as EPG and EPSD at high sparsity levels, while offering a more computationally efficient alternative to iterative pruning schemes like COLT. The proposed framework offers a computation-efficient, performance-preserving solution well suited for deployment in resource-constrained environments.</description><author>Md. Samiul Alim, Sharjil Khan, Amrijit Biswas, Fuad Rahman, Shafin Rahman, Nabeel Mohammed</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:56:05 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16653v1</guid></item><item><title>Late-decoupled 3D Hierarchical Semantic Segmentation with Semantic Prototype Discrimination based Bi-branch Supervision</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16650v1</link><description>3D hierarchical semantic segmentation (3DHS) is crucial for embodied intelligence applications that demand a multi-grained and multi-hierarchy understanding of 3D scenes. Despite the progress, previous 3DHS methods have overlooked following two challenges: I) multi-label learning with a parameter-sharing model can lead to multi-hierarchy conflicts in cross-hierarchy optimization, and II) the class imbalance issue is inevitable across multiple hierarchies of 3D scenes, which makes the model performance become dominated by major classes. To address these issues, we propose a novel framework with a primary 3DHS branch and an auxiliary discrimination branch. Specifically, to alleviate the multi-hierarchy conflicts, we propose a late-decoupled 3DHS framework which employs multiple decoders with the coarse-to-fine hierarchical guidance and consistency. The late-decoupled architecture can mitigate the underfitting and overfitting conflicts among multiple hierarchies and can also constrain the class imbalance problem in each individual hierarchy. Moreover, we introduce a 3DHS-oriented semantic prototype based bi-branch supervision mechanism, which additionally learns class-wise discriminative point cloud features and performs mutual supervision between the auxiliary and 3DHS branches, to enhance the class-imbalance segmentation. Extensive experiments on multiple datasets and backbones demonstrate that our approach achieves state-of-the-art 3DHS performance, and its core components can also be used as a plug-and-play enhancement to improve previous methods.</description><author>Shuyu Cao, Chongshou Li, Jie Xu, Tianrui Li, Na Zhao</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:54:31 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16650v1</guid></item><item><title>LLMInit: A Free Lunch from Large Language Models for Selective Initialization of Recommendation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.01814v2</link><description>Collaborative filtering (CF) is widely adopted in industrial recommender systems (RecSys) for modeling user-item interactions across numerous applications, but often struggles with cold-start and data-sparse scenarios. Recent advancements in pre-trained large language models (LLMs) with rich semantic knowledge, offer promising solutions to these challenges. However, deploying LLMs at scale is hindered by their significant computational demands and latency. In this paper, we propose a novel and scalable LLM-RecSys framework, LLMInit, designed to integrate pretrained LLM embeddings into CF models through selective initialization strategies. Specifically, we identify the embedding collapse issue observed when CF models scale and match the large embedding sizes in LLMs and avoid the problem by introducing efficient sampling methods, including, random, uniform, and variance-based selections. Comprehensive experiments conducted on multiple real-world datasets demonstrate that LLMInit significantly improves recommendation performance while maintaining low computational costs, offering a practical and scalable solution for industrial applications. To facilitate industry adoption and promote future research, we provide open-source access to our implementation at https://github.com/DavidZWZ/LLMInit.</description><author>Weizhi Zhang, Liangwei Yang, Wooseong Yang, Henry Peng Zou, Yuqing Liu, Ke Xu, Sourav Medya, Philip S. Yu</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:51:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.01814v2</guid></item><item><title>TRIM: Scalable 3D Gaussian Diffusion Inference with Temporal and Spatial Trimming</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16642v1</link><description>Recent advances in 3D Gaussian diffusion models suffer from time-intensive denoising and post-denoising processing due to the massive number of Gaussian primitives, resulting in slow generation and limited scalability along sampling trajectories. To improve the efficiency of 3D diffusion models, we propose $\textbf{TRIM}$ ($\textbf{T}$rajectory $\textbf{R}$eduction and $\textbf{I}$nstance $\textbf{M}$ask denoising), a post-training approach that incorporates both temporal and spatial trimming strategies, to accelerate inference without compromising output quality while supporting the inference-time scaling for Gaussian diffusion models. Instead of scaling denoising trajectories in a costly end-to-end manner, we develop a lightweight selector model to evaluate latent Gaussian primitives derived from multiple sampled noises, enabling early trajectory reduction by selecting candidates with high-quality potential. Furthermore, we introduce instance mask denoising to prune learnable Gaussian primitives by filtering out redundant background regions, reducing inference computation at each denoising step. Extensive experiments and analysis demonstrate that TRIM significantly improves both the efficiency and quality of 3D generation. Source code is available at $\href{https://github.com/zeyuanyin/TRIM}{link}$.</description><author>Zeyuan Yin, Xiaoming Liu</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:49:09 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16642v1</guid></item><item><title>Codec2Vec: Self-Supervised Speech Representation Learning Using Neural Speech Codecs</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16639v1</link><description>Recent advancements in neural audio codecs have not only enabled superior audio compression but also enhanced speech synthesis techniques. Researchers are now exploring their potential as universal acoustic feature extractors for a broader range of speech processing tasks. Building on this trend, we introduce Codec2Vec, the first speech representation learning framework that relies exclusively on discrete audio codec units. This approach offers several advantages, including improved data storage and transmission efficiency, faster training, and enhanced data privacy. We explore masked prediction with various training target derivation strategies to thoroughly understand the effectiveness of this framework. Evaluated on the SUPERB benchmark, Codec2Vec achieves competitive performance compared to continuous-input models while reducing storage requirements by up to 16.5x and training time by 2.3x, showcasing its scalability and efficiency.</description><author>Wei-Cheng Tseng, David Harwath</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:46:15 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16639v1</guid></item><item><title>Sigma: Semantically Informative Pre-training for Skeleton-based Sign Language Understanding</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.21223v2</link><description>Pre-training has proven effective for learning transferable features in sign language understanding (SLU) tasks. Recently, skeleton-based methods have gained increasing attention because they can robustly handle variations in subjects and backgrounds without being affected by appearance or environmental factors. Current SLU methods continue to face three key limitations: 1) weak semantic grounding, as models often capture low-level motion patterns from skeletal data but struggle to relate them to linguistic meaning; 2) imbalance between local details and global context, with models either focusing too narrowly on fine-grained cues or overlooking them for broader context; and 3) inefficient cross-modal learning, as constructing semantically aligned representations across modalities remains difficult. To address these, we propose Sigma, a unified skeleton-based SLU framework featuring: 1) a sign-aware early fusion mechanism that facilitates deep interaction between visual and textual modalities, enriching visual features with linguistic context; 2) a hierarchical alignment learning strategy that jointly maximises agreements across different levels of paired features from different modalities, effectively capturing both fine-grained details and high-level semantic relationships; and 3) a unified pre-training framework that combines contrastive learning, text matching and language modelling to promote semantic consistency and generalisation. Sigma achieves new state-of-the-art results on isolated sign language recognition, continuous sign language recognition, and gloss-free sign language translation on multiple benchmarks spanning different sign and spoken languages, demonstrating the impact of semantically informative pre-training and the effectiveness of skeletal data as a stand-alone solution for SLU.</description><author>Muxin Pu, Mei Kuan Lim, Chun Yong Chong, Chen Change Loy</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:44:59 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.21223v2</guid></item><item><title>Faster Certified Symmetry Breaking Using Orders With Auxiliary Variables</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16637v1</link><description>Symmetry breaking is a crucial technique in modern combinatorial solving, but it is difficult to be sure it is implemented correctly. The most successful approach to deal with bugs is to make solvers certifying, so that they output not just a solution, but also a mathematical proof of correctness in a standard format, which can then be checked by a formally verified checker. This requires justifying symmetry reasoning within the proof, but developing efficient methods for this has remained a long-standing open challenge. A fully general approach was recently proposed by Bogaerts et al. (2023), but it relies on encoding lexicographic orders with big integers, which quickly becomes infeasible for large symmetries. In this work, we develop a method for instead encoding orders with auxiliary variables. We show that this leads to orders-of-magnitude speed-ups in both theory and practice by running experiments on proof logging and checking for SAT symmetry breaking using the state-of-the-art satsuma symmetry breaker and the VeriPB proof checking toolchain.</description><author>Markus Anders, Bart Bogaerts, Benjamin Bogø, Arthur Gontier, Wietze Koops, Ciaran McCreesh, Magnus O. Myreen, Jakob Nordström, Andy Oertel, Adrian Rebola-Pardo, Yong Kiam Tan</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:43:05 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16637v1</guid></item><item><title>Modular Jump Gaussian Processes</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.15557v3</link><description>Gaussian processes (GPs) furnish accurate nonlinear predictions with well-calibrated uncertainty. However, the typical GP setup has a built-in stationarity assumption, making it ill-suited for modeling data from processes with sudden changes, or "jumps" in the output variable. The "jump GP" (JGP) was developed for modeling data from such processes, combining local GPs and latent "level" variables under a joint inferential framework. But joint modeling can be fraught with difficulty. We aim to simplify by suggesting a more modular setup, eschewing joint inference but retaining the main JGP themes: (a) learning optimal neighborhood sizes that locally respect manifolds of discontinuity; and (b) a new cluster-based (latent) feature to capture regions of distinct output levels on both sides of the manifold. We show that each of (a) and (b) separately leads to dramatic improvements when modeling processes with jumps. In tandem (but without requiring joint inference) that benefit is compounded, as illustrated on real and synthetic benchmark examples from the recent literature.</description><author>Anna R. Flowers, Christopher T. Franck, Mickaël Binois, Chiwoo Park, Robert B. Gramacy</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:42:59 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.15557v3</guid></item><item><title>SurvAgent: Hierarchical CoT-Enhanced Case Banking and Dichotomy-Based Multi-Agent System for Multimodal Survival Prediction</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16635v1</link><description>Survival analysis is critical for cancer prognosis and treatment planning, yet existing methods lack the transparency essential for clinical adoption. While recent pathology agents have demonstrated explainability in diagnostic tasks, they face three limitations for survival prediction: inability to integrate multimodal data, ineffective region-of-interest exploration, and failure to leverage experiential learning from historical cases. We introduce SurvAgent, the first hierarchical chain-of-thought (CoT)-enhanced multi-agent system for multimodal survival prediction. SurvAgent consists of two stages: (1) WSI-Gene CoT-Enhanced Case Bank Construction employs hierarchical analysis through Low-Magnification Screening, Cross-Modal Similarity-Aware Patch Mining, and Confidence-Aware Patch Mining for pathology images, while Gene-Stratified analysis processes six functional gene categories. Both generate structured reports with CoT reasoning, storing complete analytical processes for experiential learning. (2) Dichotomy-Based Multi-Expert Agent Inference retrieves similar cases via RAG and integrates multimodal reports with expert predictions through progressive interval refinement. Extensive experiments on five TCGA cohorts demonstrate SurvAgent's superority over conventional methods, proprietary MLLMs, and medical agents, establishing a new paradigm for explainable AI-driven survival prediction in precision oncology.</description><author>Guolin Huang, Wenting Chen, Jiaqi Yang, Xinheng Lyu, Xiaoling Luo, Sen Yang, Xiaohan Xing, Linlin Shen</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:41:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16635v1</guid></item><item><title>Beyond Patches: Mining Interpretable Part-Prototypes for Explainable AI</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.12197v3</link><description>As AI systems grow more capable, it becomes increasingly important that their decisions remain understandable and aligned with human expectations. A key challenge is the limited interpretability of deep models. Post-hoc methods like GradCAM offer heatmaps but provide limited conceptual insight, while prototype-based approaches offer example-based explanations but often rely on rigid region selection and lack semantic consistency. To address these limitations, we propose PCMNet, a part-prototypical concept mining network that learns human-comprehensible prototypes from meaningful image regions without additional supervision. By clustering these prototypes into concept groups and extracting concept activation vectors, PCMNet provides structured, concept-level explanations and enhances robustness to occlusion and challenging conditions, which are both critical for building reliable and aligned AI systems. Experiments across multiple image classification benchmarks show that PCMNet outperforms state-of-the-art methods in interpretability, stability, and robustness. This work contributes to AI alignment by enhancing transparency, controllability, and trustworthiness in AI systems. Our code is available at: https://github.com/alehdaghi/PCMNet.</description><author>Mahdi Alehdaghi, Rajarshi Bhattacharya, Pourya Shamsolmoali, Rafael M. O. Cruz, Maguelonne Heritier, Eric Granger</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:37:09 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.12197v3</guid></item><item><title>Stabilizing Policy Gradient Methods via Reward Profiling</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16629v1</link><description>Policy gradient methods, which have been extensively studied in the last decade, offer an effective and efficient framework for reinforcement learning problems. However, their performances can often be unsatisfactory, suffering from unreliable reward improvements and slow convergence, due to high variance in gradient estimations. In this paper, we propose a universal reward profiling framework that can be seamlessly integrated with any policy gradient algorithm, where we selectively update the policy based on high-confidence performance estimations. We theoretically justify that our technique will not slow down the convergence of the baseline policy gradient methods, but with high probability, will result in stable and monotonic improvements of their performance. Empirically, on eight continuous-control benchmarks (Box2D and MuJoCo/PyBullet), our profiling yields up to 1.5x faster convergence to near-optimal returns, up to 1.75x reduction in return variance on some setups. Our profiling approach offers a general, theoretically grounded path to more reliable and efficient policy learning in complex environments.</description><author>Shihab Ahmed, El Houcine Bergou, Aritra Dutta, Yue Wang</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:35:51 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16629v1</guid></item><item><title>MedBayes-Lite: Bayesian Uncertainty Quantification for Safe Clinical Decision Support</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16625v1</link><description>We propose MedBayes-Lite, a lightweight Bayesian enhancement for transformer-based clinical language models designed to produce reliable, uncertainty-aware predictions. Although transformers show strong potential for clinical decision support, they remain prone to overconfidence, especially in ambiguous medical cases where calibrated uncertainty is critical. MedBayes-Lite embeds uncertainty quantification directly into existing transformer pipelines without any retraining or architectural rewiring, adding no new trainable layers and keeping parameter overhead under 3 percent. The framework integrates three components: (i) Bayesian Embedding Calibration using Monte Carlo dropout for epistemic uncertainty, (ii) Uncertainty-Weighted Attention that marginalizes over token reliability, and (iii) Confidence-Guided Decision Shaping inspired by clinical risk minimization. Across biomedical QA and clinical prediction benchmarks (MedQA, PubMedQA, MIMIC-III), MedBayes-Lite consistently improves calibration and trustworthiness, reducing overconfidence by 32 to 48 percent. In simulated clinical settings, it can prevent up to 41 percent of diagnostic errors by flagging uncertain predictions for human review. These results demonstrate its effectiveness in enabling reliable uncertainty propagation and improving interpretability in medical AI systems.</description><author>Elias Hossain, Md Mehedi Hasan Nipu, Maleeha Sheikh, Rajib Rana, Subash Neupane, Niloofar Yousefi</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:33:12 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16625v1</guid></item><item><title>SAM 3D: 3Dfy Anything in Images</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16624v1</link><description>We present SAM 3D, a generative model for visually grounded 3D object reconstruction, predicting geometry, texture, and layout from a single image. SAM 3D excels in natural images, where occlusion and scene clutter are common and visual recognition cues from context play a larger role. We achieve this with a human- and model-in-the-loop pipeline for annotating object shape, texture, and pose, providing visually grounded 3D reconstruction data at unprecedented scale. We learn from this data in a modern, multi-stage training framework that combines synthetic pretraining with real-world alignment, breaking the 3D "data barrier". We obtain significant gains over recent work, with at least a 5:1 win rate in human preference tests on real-world objects and scenes. We will release our code and model weights, an online demo, and a new challenging benchmark for in-the-wild 3D object reconstruction.</description><author>SAM 3D Team, Xingyu Chen, Fu-Jen Chu, Pierre Gleize, Kevin J Liang, Alexander Sax, Hao Tang, Weiyao Wang, Michelle Guo, Thibaut Hardin, Xiang Li, Aohan Lin, Jiawei Liu, Ziqi Ma, Anushka Sagar, Bowen Song, Xiaodong Wang, Jianing Yang, Bowen Zhang, Piotr Dollár, Georgia Gkioxari, Matt Feiszli, Jitendra Malik</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:31:46 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16624v1</guid></item><item><title>Leveraging Reinforcement Learning, Genetic Algorithms and Transformers for background determination in particle physics</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14894v2</link><description>Experimental studies of beauty hadron decays face significant challenges due to a wide range of backgrounds arising from the numerous possible decay channels with similar final states. For a particular signal decay, the process for ascertaining the most relevant background processes necessitates a detailed analysis of final state particles, potential misidentifications, and kinematic overlaps, which, due to computational limitations, is restricted to the simulation of only the most relevant backgrounds. Moreover, this process typically relies on the physicist's intuition and expertise, as no systematic method exists. This paper has two primary goals. First, from a particle physics perspective, we present a novel approach that utilises Reinforcement Learning (RL) to overcome the aforementioned challenges by systematically determining the critical backgrounds affecting beauty hadron decay measurements. While beauty hadron physics serves as the case study in this work, the proposed strategy is broadly adaptable to other types of particle physics measurements. Second, from a Machine Learning perspective, we introduce a novel algorithm which exploits the synergy between RL and Genetic Algorithms (GAs) for environments with highly sparse rewards and a large trajectory space. This strategy leverages GAs to efficiently explore the trajectory space and identify successful trajectories, which are used to guide the RL agent's training. Our method also incorporates a transformer architecture for the RL agent to handle token sequences representing decays.</description><author>Guillermo Hijano Mendizabal, Davide Lancierini, Alex Marshall, Andrea Mauri, Patrick Haworth Owen, Mitesh Patel, Konstantinos Petridis, Shah Rukh Qasim, Nicola Serra, William Sutcliffe, Hanae Tilquin</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:30:59 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14894v2</guid></item><item><title>From Polynomials to Databases: Arithmetic Structures in Galois Theory</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16622v1</link><description>We develop a computational framework for classifying Galois groups of irreducible degree-7 polynomials over~$\mathbb{Q}$, combining explicit resolvent methods with machine learning techniques. A database of over one million normalized projective septics is constructed, each annotated with algebraic invariants~$J_0, \dots, J_4$ derived from binary transvections. For each polynomial, we compute resolvent factorizations to determine its Galois group among the seven transitive subgroups of~$S_7$ identified by Foulkes. Using this dataset, we train a neurosymbolic classifier that integrates invariant-theoretic features with supervised learning, yielding improved accuracy in detecting rare solvable groups compared to coefficient-based models. The resulting database provides a reproducible resource for constructive Galois theory and supports empirical investigations into group distribution under height constraints. The methodology extends to higher-degree cases and illustrates the utility of hybrid symbolic-numeric techniques in computational algebra.</description><author>Jurgen Mezinaj</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:29:38 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16622v1</guid></item><item><title>SAM2S: Segment Anything in Surgical Videos via Semantic Long-term Tracking</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16618v1</link><description>Surgical video segmentation is crucial for computer-assisted surgery, enabling precise localization and tracking of instruments and tissues. Interactive Video Object Segmentation (iVOS) models such as Segment Anything Model 2 (SAM2) provide prompt-based flexibility beyond methods with predefined categories, but face challenges in surgical scenarios due to the domain gap and limited long-term tracking. To address these limitations, we construct SA-SV, the largest surgical iVOS benchmark with instance-level spatio-temporal annotations (masklets) spanning eight procedure types (61k frames, 1.6k masklets), enabling comprehensive development and evaluation for long-term tracking and zero-shot generalization. Building on SA-SV, we propose SAM2S, a foundation model enhancing \textbf{SAM2} for \textbf{S}urgical iVOS through: (1) DiveMem, a trainable diverse memory mechanism for robust long-term tracking; (2) temporal semantic learning for instrument understanding; and (3) ambiguity-resilient learning to mitigate annotation inconsistencies across multi-source datasets. Extensive experiments demonstrate that fine-tuning on SA-SV enables substantial performance gains, with SAM2 improving by 12.99 average $\mathcal{J}$\&amp;$\mathcal{F}$ over vanilla SAM2. SAM2S further advances performance to 80.42 average $\mathcal{J}$\&amp;$\mathcal{F}$, surpassing vanilla and fine-tuned SAM2 by 17.10 and 4.11 points respectively, while maintaining 68 FPS real-time inference and strong zero-shot generalization. Code and dataset will be released at https://jinlab-imvr.github.io/SAM2S.</description><author>Haofeng Liu, Ziyue Wang, Sudhanshu Mishra, Mingqi Gao, Guanyi Qin, Chang Han Low, Alex Y. W. Kong, Yueming Jin</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:18:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16618v1</guid></item><item><title>Rate-optimal community detection near the KS threshold via node-robust algorithms</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16613v1</link><description>We study community detection in the \emph{symmetric $k$-stochastic block model}, where $n$ nodes are evenly partitioned into $k$ clusters with intra- and inter-cluster connection probabilities $p$ and $q$, respectively. Our main result is a polynomial-time algorithm that achieves the minimax-optimal misclassification rate \begin{equation*} \exp \Bigl(-\bigl(1 \pm o(1)\bigr) \tfrac{C}{k}\Bigr), \quad \text{where } C = (\sqrt{pn} - \sqrt{qn})^2, \end{equation*} whenever $C \ge K\,k^2\,\log k$ for some universal constant $K$, matching the Kesten--Stigum (KS) threshold up to a $\log k$ factor. Notably, this rate holds even when an adversary corrupts an $η\le \exp\bigl(- (1 \pm o(1)) \tfrac{C}{k}\bigr)$ fraction of the nodes. To the best of our knowledge, the minimax rate was previously only attainable either via computationally inefficient procedures [ZZ15] or via polynomial-time algorithms that require strictly stronger assumptions such as $C \ge K k^3$ [GMZZ17]. In the node-robust setting, the best known algorithm requires the substantially stronger condition $C \ge K k^{102}$ [LM22]. Our results close this gap by providing the first polynomial-time algorithm that achieves the minimax rate near the KS threshold in both settings. Our work has two key technical contributions: (1) we robustify majority voting via the Sum-of-Squares framework, (2) we develop a novel graph bisection algorithm via robust majority voting, which allows us to significantly improve the misclassification rate to $1/\mathrm{poly}(k)$ for the initial estimation near the KS threshold.</description><author>Jingqiu Ding, Yiding Hua, Kasper Lindberg, David Steurer, Aleksandr Storozhenko</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:11:01 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16613v1</guid></item><item><title>Turning Up the Heat: Min-p Sampling for Creative and Coherent LLM Outputs</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.01082v8</link><description>Large Language Models (LLMs) generate text by sampling the next token from a probability distribution over the vocabulary at each decoding step. Popular sampling methods like top-p (nucleus sampling) often struggle to balance quality and diversity, especially at higher temperatures which lead to incoherent or repetitive outputs. We propose min-p sampling, a dynamic truncation method that adjusts the sampling threshold based on the model's confidence by using the top token's probability as a scaling factor. Our experiments on benchmarks including GPQA, GSM8K, and AlpacaEval Creative Writing show that min-p sampling improves both the quality and diversity of generated text across different model families (Mistral and Llama 3) and model sizes (1B to 123B parameters), especially at higher temperatures. Human evaluations further show a clear preference for min-p sampling, in both text quality and creativity. Min-p sampling has been adopted by popular open-source LLM frameworks, including Hugging Face Transformers, VLLM, and many others, highlighting its considerable impact on improving text generation quality.</description><author>Minh Nhat Nguyen, Andrew Baker, Clement Neo, Allen Roush, Andreas Kirsch, Ravid Shwartz-Ziv</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:07:18 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.01082v8</guid></item><item><title>Nonparametric estimation of conditional probability distributions using a generative approach based on conditional push-forward neural networks</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.14455v2</link><description>We introduce conditional push-forward neural networks (CPFN), a generative framework for conditional distribution estimation. Instead of directly modeling the conditional density $f_{Y|X}$, CPFN learns a stochastic map $\varphi=\varphi(x,u)$ such that $\varphi(x,U)$ and $Y|X=x$ follow approximately the same law, with $U$ a suitable random vector of pre-defined latent variables. This enables efficient conditional sampling and straightforward estimation of conditional statistics through Monte Carlo methods. The model is trained via an objective function derived from a Kullback-Leibler formulation, without requiring invertibility or adversarial training. We establish a near-asymptotic consistency result and demonstrate experimentally that CPFN can achieve performance competitive with, or even superior to, state-of-the-art methods, including kernel estimators, tree-based algorithms, and popular deep learning techniques, all while remaining lightweight and easy to train.</description><author>Nicola Rares Franco, Lorenzo Tedesco</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:06:01 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.14455v2</guid></item><item><title>Probing the Critical Point (CritPt) of AI Reasoning: a Frontier Physics Research Benchmark</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.26574v3</link><description>While large language models (LLMs) with reasoning capabilities are progressing rapidly on high-school math competitions and coding, can they reason effectively through complex, open-ended challenges found in frontier physics research? And crucially, what kinds of reasoning tasks do physicists want LLMs to assist with? To address these questions, we present the CritPt (Complex Research using Integrated Thinking - Physics Test, pronounced "critical point"), the first benchmark designed to test LLMs on unpublished, research-level reasoning tasks that broadly covers modern physics research areas, including condensed matter, quantum physics, atomic, molecular &amp; optical physics, astrophysics, high energy physics, mathematical physics, statistical physics, nuclear physics, nonlinear dynamics, fluid dynamics and biophysics. CritPt consists of 71 composite research challenges designed to simulate full-scale research projects at the entry level, which are also decomposed to 190 simpler checkpoint tasks for more fine-grained insights. All problems are newly created by 50+ active physics researchers based on their own research. Every problem is hand-curated to admit a guess-resistant and machine-verifiable answer and is evaluated by an automated grading pipeline heavily customized for advanced physics-specific output formats. We find that while current state-of-the-art LLMs show early promise on isolated checkpoints, they remain far from being able to reliably solve full research-scale challenges: the best average accuracy among base models is only 5.7%, achieved by GPT-5 (high), moderately rising to around 10% when equipped with coding tools. Through the realistic yet standardized evaluation offered by CritPt, we highlight a large disconnect between current model capabilities and realistic physics research demands, offering a foundation to guide the development of scientifically grounded AI tools.</description><author>Minhui Zhu, Minyang Tian, Xiaocheng Yang, Tianci Zhou, Lifan Yuan, Penghao Zhu, Eli Chertkov, Shengyan Liu, Yufeng Du, Ziming Ji, Indranil Das, Junyi Cao, Yufeng Du, Jiabin Yu, Peixue Wu, Jinchen He, Yifan Su, Yikun Jiang, Yujie Zhang, Chang Liu, Ze-Min Huang, Weizhen Jia, Yunkai Wang, Farshid Jafarpour, Yong Zhao, Xinan Chen, Jessie Shelton, Aaron W. Young, John Bartolotta, Wenchao Xu, Yue Sun, Anjun Chu, Victor Colussi, Chris Akers, Nathan Brooks, Wenbo Fu, Jinchao Zhao, Marvin Qi, Anqi Mu, Yubo Yang, Allen Zang, Yang Lyu, Peizhi Mai, Christopher Wilson, Xuefei Guo, Juntai Zhou, Daniel Inafuku, Chi Xue, Luyu Gao, Ze Yang, Yaïr Hein, Yonatan Kahn, Kevin Zhou, Di Luo, John Drew Wilson, Jarrod T. Reilly, Dmytro Bandak, Ofir Press, Liang Yang, Xueying Wang, Hao Tong, Nicolas Chia, Eliu Huert</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:01:52 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.26574v3</guid></item><item><title>Measuring and Controlling Solution Degeneracy across Task-Trained Recurrent Neural Networks</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.03972v3</link><description>Task-trained recurrent neural networks (RNNs) are widely used in neuroscience and machine learning to model dynamical computations. To gain mechanistic insight into how neural systems solve tasks, prior work often reverse-engineers individual trained networks. However, different RNNs trained on the same task and achieving similar performance can exhibit strikingly different internal solutions, a phenomenon known as solution degeneracy. Here, we develop a unified framework to systematically quantify and control solution degeneracy across three levels: behavior, neural dynamics, and weight space. We apply this framework to 3,400 RNNs trained on four neuroscience-relevant tasks: flip-flop memory, sine wave generation, delayed discrimination, and path integration, while systematically varying task complexity, learning regime, network size, and regularization. We find that higher task complexity and stronger feature learning reduce degeneracy in neural dynamics but increase it in weight space, with mixed effects on behavior. In contrast, larger networks and structural regularization reduce degeneracy at all three levels. These findings empirically validate the Contravariance Principle and provide practical guidance for researchers seeking to tune the variability of RNN solutions, either to uncover shared neural mechanisms or to model the individual variability observed in biological systems. This work provides a principled framework for quantifying and controlling solution degeneracy in task-trained RNNs, offering new tools for building more interpretable and biologically grounded models of neural computation.</description><author>Ann Huang, Satpreet H. Singh, Flavio Martinelli, Kanaka Rajan</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:58:39 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.03972v3</guid></item><item><title>Bridging VLMs and Embodied Intelligence with Deliberate Practice Policy Optimization</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16602v1</link><description>Developing a universal and versatile embodied intelligence system presents two primary challenges: the critical embodied data bottleneck, where real-world data is scarce and expensive, and the algorithmic inefficiency of existing methods, which are resource-prohibitive. To address these limitations, we introduce Deliberate Practice Policy Optimization (DPPO), a metacognitive ``Metaloop'' training framework that dynamically alternates between supervised fine-tuning (competence expansion) and reinforcement learning (skill refinement). This enables automatic weakness identification and targeted resource allocation, specifically designed to maximize learning efficiency from sparse, finite data. Theoretically, DPPO can be formalised as a unified preference-learning framework. Empirically, training a vision-language embodied model with DPPO, referred to as Pelican-VL 1.0, yields a 20.3% performance improvement over the base model and surpasses open-source models at the 100B-parameter scale by 10.6%. We are open-sourcing both the models and code, providing the first systematic framework that alleviates the data and resource bottleneck and enables the community to build versatile embodied agents efficiently.</description><author>Yi Zhang, Che Liu, Xiancong Ren, Hanchu Ni, Yingji Zhang, Shuai Zhang, Zeyuan Ding, Jiayu Hu, Haozhe Shan, Junbo Qi, Yan Bai, Dengjie Li, Jiachen Luo, Yidong Wang, Yong Dai, Zenglin Xu, Bin Shen, Qifan Wang, Jian Tang, Xiaozhu Ju</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:58:04 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16602v1</guid></item><item><title>Time dependent loss reweighting for flow matching and diffusion models is theoretically justified</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16599v1</link><description>This brief note clarifies that, in Generator Matching (which subsumes a large family of flow matching and diffusion models over continuous, manifold, and discrete spaces), both the Bregman divergence loss and the linear parameterization of the generator can depend on both the current state $X_t$ and the time $t$, and we show that the expectation over time in the loss can be taken with respect to a broad class of time distributions. We also show this for Edit Flows, which falls outside of Generator Matching. That the loss can depend on $t$ clarifies that time-dependent loss weighting schemes, often used in practice to stabilize training, are theoretically justified when the specific flow or diffusion scheme is a special case of Generator Matching (or Edit Flows). It also often simplifies the construction of $X_1$-predictor schemes, which are sometimes preferred for model-related reasons. We show examples that rely upon the dependence of linear parameterizations, and of the Bregman divergence loss, on $t$ and $X_t$.</description><author>Lukas Billera, Hedwig Nora Nordlinder, Ben Murrell</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:55:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16599v1</guid></item><item><title>You Only Forward Once: An Efficient Compositional Judging Paradigm</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16600v1</link><description>Multimodal large language models (MLLMs) show strong potential as judges. However, existing approaches face a fundamental trade-off: adapting MLLMs to output a single score misaligns with the generative nature of MLLMs and limits fine-grained requirement understanding, whereas autoregressively generating judging analyses is prohibitively slow in high-throughput settings. Observing that judgment reduces to verifying whether inputs satisfy a set of structured requirements, we propose YOFO, a template-conditioned method that judges all requirements in a single forward pass. Built on an autoregressive model, YOFO accepts a structured requirement template and, in one inference step, produces a binary yes/no decision for each requirement by reading the logits of the final token associated with that requirement. This design yields orders-of-magnitude speedups while preserving interpretability. Extensive experiments show that YOFO not only achieves state-of-the-art results on standard recommendation datasets, but also supports dependency-aware analysis-where subsequent judgments are conditioned on previous ones-and further benefits from post-hoc CoT.</description><author>Tianlong Zhang, Hongwei Xue, Shilin Yan, Di Wu, Chen Xu, Yunyun Yang</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:55:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16600v1</guid></item><item><title>Complex variational autoencoders admit Kähler structure</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.15172v2</link><description>It has been discovered that latent-Euclidean variational autoencoders (VAEs) admit, in various capacities, Riemannian structure. We adapt these arguments but for complex VAEs with a complex latent stage. We show that complex VAEs reveal to some level Kähler geometric structure. Our methods will be tailored for decoder geometry. We derive the Fisher information metric in the complex case under a latent complex Gaussian regularization with trivial relation matrix. It is well known from statistical information theory that the Fisher information coincides with the Hessian of the Kullback-Leibler (KL) divergence. Thus, the metric Kähler potential relation is exactly achieved under relative entropy. We propose a Kähler potential derivative of complex Gaussian mixtures that has rough equivalence to the Fisher information metric while still being faithful to the underlying Kähler geometry. Computation of the metric via this potential is efficient, and through our potential, valid as a plurisubharmonic (PSH) function, large scale computational burden of automatic differentiation is displaced to small scale. We show that we can regularize the latent space with decoder geometry, and that we can sample in accordance with a weighted complex volume element. We demonstrate these strategies, at the exchange of sample variation, yield consistently smoother representations and fewer semantic outliers.</description><author>Andrew Gracyk</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:51:33 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.15172v2</guid></item><item><title>Bridging the Gap in XAI-Why Reliable Metrics Matter for Explainability and Compliance</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.04695v2</link><description>Reliable explainability is not only a technical goal but also a cornerstone of private AI governance. As AI models enter high-stakes sectors, private actors such as auditors, insurers, certification bodies, and procurement agencies require standardized evaluation metrics to assess trustworthiness. However, current XAI evaluation metrics remain fragmented and prone to manipulation, which undermines accountability and compliance. We argue that standardized metrics can function as governance primitives, embedding auditability and accountability within AI systems for effective private oversight. Building upon prior work in XAI benchmarking, we identify key limitations in ensuring faithfulness, tamper resistance, and regulatory alignment. Furthermore, interpretability can directly support model alignment by providing a verifiable means of ensuring behavioral integrity in General Purpose AI (GPAI) systems. This connection between interpretability and alignment positions XAI metrics as both technical and regulatory instruments that help prevent alignment faking, a growing concern among oversight bodies. We propose a Governance by Metrics paradigm that treats explainability evaluation as a central mechanism of private AI governance. Our framework introduces a hierarchical model linking transparency, tamper resistance, scalability, and legal alignment, extending evaluation from model introspection toward systemic accountability. Through conceptual synthesis and alignment with governance standards, we outline a roadmap for integrating explainability metrics into continuous AI assurance pipelines that serve both private oversight and regulatory needs.</description><author>Pratinav Seth, Vinay Kumar Sankarapu</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:50:45 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.04695v2</guid></item><item><title>Variational Quantum Integrated Sensing and Communication</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16597v1</link><description>The integration of sensing and communication functionalities within a common system is one of the main innovation drivers for next-generation networks. In this paper, we introduce a quantum integrated sensing and communication (QISAC) protocol that leverages entanglement in quantum carriers of information to enable both superdense coding and quantum sensing. The proposed approach adaptively optimizes encoding and quantum measurement via variational circuit learning, while employing classical machine learning-based decoders and estimators to process the measurement outcomes. Numerical results for qudit systems demonstrate that the proposed QISAC protocol can achieve a flexible trade-off between classical communication rate and accuracy of parameter estimation.</description><author>Ivana Nikoloska, Osvaldo Simeone</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:50:34 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16597v1</guid></item><item><title>Toward Artificial Palpation: Representation Learning of Touch on Soft Bodies</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16596v1</link><description>Palpation, the use of touch in medical examination, is almost exclusively performed by humans. We investigate a proof of concept for an artificial palpation method based on self-supervised learning. Our key idea is that an encoder-decoder framework can learn a $\textit{representation}$ from a sequence of tactile measurements that contains all the relevant information about the palpated object. We conjecture that such a representation can be used for downstream tasks such as tactile imaging and change detection. With enough training data, it should capture intricate patterns in the tactile measurements that go beyond a simple map of forces -- the current state of the art. To validate our approach, we both develop a simulation environment and collect a real-world dataset of soft objects and corresponding ground truth images obtained by magnetic resonance imaging (MRI). We collect palpation sequences using a robot equipped with a tactile sensor, and train a model that predicts sensory readings at different positions on the object. We investigate the representation learned in this process, and demonstrate its use in imaging and change detection.</description><author>Zohar Rimon, Elisei Shafer, Tal Tepper, Efrat Shimron, Aviv Tamar</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:49:08 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16596v1</guid></item><item><title>TimeViper: A Hybrid Mamba-Transformer Vision-Language Model for Efficient Long Video Understanding</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16595v1</link><description>We introduce TimeViper, a hybrid vision-language model designed to tackle challenges of long video understanding. Processing long videos demands both an efficient model architecture and an effective mechanism for handling extended temporal contexts. To this end, TimeViper adopts a hybrid Mamba-Transformer backbone that combines the efficiency of state-space models with the expressivity of attention mechanisms. Through this hybrid design, we reveal the vision-to-text information aggregation phenomenon, where information progressively flows from vision tokens to text tokens across increasing LLM depth, resulting in severe vision token redundancy. Motivated by this observation, we propose TransV, a token information transfer module that transfers and compresses vision tokens into instruction tokens while maintaining multimodal understanding capabilities. This design enables TimeViper to process hour-long videos exceeding 10,000 frames. Extensive experiments across multiple benchmarks demonstrate that TimeViper competes with state-of-the-art models while extending frame numbers. We further analyze attention behaviors of both Mamba and Transformer layers, offering new insights into hybrid model interpretability. This work represents an initial step towards developing, interpreting, and compressing hybrid Mamba-Transformer architectures.</description><author>Boshen Xu, Zihan Xiao, Jiaze Li, Jianzhong Ju, Zhenbo Luo, Jian Luan, Qin Jin</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:48:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16595v1</guid></item><item><title>Green Resilience of Cyber-Physical Systems: Doctoral Dissertation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16593v1</link><description>Cyber-physical systems (CPS) combine computational and physical components. Online Collaborative AI System (OL-CAIS) is a type of CPS that learn online in collaboration with humans to achieve a common goal, which makes it vulnerable to disruptive events that degrade performance. Decision-makers must therefore restore performance while limiting energy impact, creating a trade-off between resilience and greenness. This research addresses how to balance these two properties in OL-CAIS. It aims to model resilience for automatic state detection, develop agent-based policies that optimize the greenness-resilience trade-off, and understand catastrophic forgetting to maintain performance consistency. We model OL-CAIS behavior through three operational states: steady, disruptive, and final. To support recovery during disruptions, we introduce the GResilience framework, which provides recovery strategies through multi-objective optimization (one-agent), game-theoretic decision-making (two-agent), and reinforcement learning (RL-agent). We also design a measurement framework to quantify resilience and greenness. Empirical evaluation uses real and simulated experiments with a collaborative robot learning object classification from human demonstrations. Results show that the resilience model captures performance transitions during disruptions, and that GResilience policies improve green recovery by shortening recovery time, stabilizing performance, and reducing human dependency. RL-agent policies achieve the strongest results, although with a marginal increase in CO2 emissions. We also observe catastrophic forgetting after repeated disruptions, while our policies help maintain steadiness. A comparison with containerized execution shows that containerization cuts CO2 emissions by half. Overall, this research provides models, metrics, and policies that ensure the green recovery of OL-CAIS.</description><author>Diaeddin Rimawi</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:46:41 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16593v1</guid></item><item><title>gfnx: Fast and Scalable Library for Generative Flow Networks in JAX</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16592v1</link><description>In this paper, we present gfnx, a fast and scalable package for training and evaluating Generative Flow Networks (GFlowNets) written in JAX. gfnx provides an extensive set of environments and metrics for benchmarking, accompanied with single-file implementations of core objectives for training GFlowNets. We include synthetic hypergrids, multiple sequence generation environments with various editing regimes and particular reward designs for molecular generation, phylogenetic tree construction, Bayesian structure learning, and sampling from the Ising model energy. Across different tasks, gfnx achieves significant wall-clock speedups compared to Pytorch-based benchmarks (such as torchgfn library) and author implementations. For example, gfnx achieves up to 55 times speedup on CPU-based sequence generation environments, and up to 80 times speedup with the GPU-based Bayesian network structure learning setup. Our package provides a diverse set of benchmarks and aims to standardize empirical evaluation and accelerate research and applications of GFlowNets. The library is available on GitHub (https://github.com/d-tiapkin/gfnx) and on pypi (https://pypi.org/project/gfnx/). Documentation is available on https://gfnx.readthedocs.io.</description><author>Daniil Tiapkin, Artem Agarkov, Nikita Morozov, Ian Maksimov, Askar Tsyganov, Timofei Gritsaev, Sergey Samsonov</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:44:45 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16592v1</guid></item><item><title>D-GARA: A Dynamic Benchmarking Framework for GUI Agent Robustness in Real-World Anomalies</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16590v1</link><description>Developing intelligent agents capable of operating a wide range of Graphical User Interfaces (GUIs) with human-level proficiency is a key milestone on the path toward Artificial General Intelligence. While most existing datasets and benchmarks for training and evaluating GUI agents are static and idealized, failing to reflect the complexity and unpredictability of real-world environments, particularly the presence of anomalies. To bridge this research gap, we propose D-GARA, a dynamic benchmarking framework, to evaluate Android GUI agent robustness in real-world anomalies. D-GARA introduces a diverse set of real-world anomalies that GUI agents commonly face in practice, including interruptions such as permission dialogs, battery warnings, and update prompts. Based on D-GARA framework, we construct and annotate a benchmark featuring commonly used Android applications with embedded anomalies to support broader community research. Comprehensive experiments and results demonstrate substantial performance degradation in state-of-the-art GUI agents when exposed to anomaly-rich environments, highlighting the need for robustness-aware learning. D-GARA is modular and extensible, supporting the seamless integration of new tasks, anomaly types, and interaction scenarios to meet specific evaluation goals.</description><author>Sen Chen, Tong Zhao, Yi Bin, Fei Ma, Wenqi Shao, Zheng Wang</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:43:46 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16590v1</guid></item><item><title>Formal Abductive Latent Explanations for Prototype-Based Networks</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16588v1</link><description>Case-based reasoning networks are machine-learning models that make predictions based on similarity between the input and prototypical parts of training samples, called prototypes. Such models are able to explain each decision by pointing to the prototypes that contributed the most to the final outcome. As the explanation is a core part of the prediction, they are often qualified as ``interpretable by design". While promising, we show that such explanations are sometimes misleading, which hampers their usefulness in safety-critical contexts. In particular, several instances may lead to different predictions and yet have the same explanation. Drawing inspiration from the field of formal eXplainable AI (FXAI), we propose Abductive Latent Explanations (ALEs), a formalism to express sufficient conditions on the intermediate (latent) representation of the instance that imply the prediction. Our approach combines the inherent interpretability of case-based reasoning models and the guarantees provided by formal XAI. We propose a solver-free and scalable algorithm for generating ALEs based on three distinct paradigms, compare them, and present the feasibility of our approach on diverse datasets for both standard and fine-grained image classification. The associated code can be found at https://github.com/julsoria/ale</description><author>Jules Soria, Zakaria Chihani, Julien Girard-Satabin, Alban Grastien, Romain Xu-Darme, Daniela Cancila</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:42:41 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16588v1</guid></item><item><title>Almost Sure Convergence Analysis of Differentially Private Stochastic Gradient Methods</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16587v1</link><description>Differentially private stochastic gradient descent (DP-SGD) has become the standard algorithm for training machine learning models with rigorous privacy guarantees. Despite its widespread use, the theoretical understanding of its long-run behavior remains limited: existing analyses typically establish convergence in expectation or with high probability, but do not address the almost sure convergence of single trajectories. In this work, we prove that DP-SGD converges almost surely under standard smoothness assumptions, both in nonconvex and strongly convex settings, provided the step sizes satisfy some standard decaying conditions. Our analysis extends to momentum variants such as the stochastic heavy ball (DP-SHB) and Nesterov's accelerated gradient (DP-NAG), where we show that careful energy constructions yield similar guarantees. These results provide stronger theoretical foundations for differentially private optimization and suggest that, despite privacy-induced distortions, the algorithm remains pathwise stable in both convex and nonconvex regimes.</description><author>Amartya Mukherjee, Jun Liu</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:42:40 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16587v1</guid></item><item><title>Interpretability as Alignment: Making Internal Understanding a Design Principle</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.08592v2</link><description>Frontier AI systems require governance mechanisms that can verify internal alignment, not just behavioral compliance. Private governance mechanisms audits, certification, insurance, and procurement are emerging to complement public regulation, but they require technical substrates that generate verifiable causal evidence about model behavior. This paper argues that mechanistic interpretability provides this substrate. We frame interpretability not as post-hoc explanation but as a design constraint embedding auditability, provenance, and bounded transparency within model architectures. Integrating causal abstraction theory and empirical benchmarks such as MIB and LoBOX, we outline how interpretability-first models can underpin private assurance pipelines and role-calibrated transparency frameworks. This reframing situates interpretability as infrastructure for private AI governance bridging the gap between technical reliability and institutional accountability.</description><author>Aadit Sengupta, Pratinav Seth, Vinay Kumar Sankarapu</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:40:35 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.08592v2</guid></item><item><title>Consciousness in Artificial Intelligence? A Framework for Classifying Objections and Constraints</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16582v1</link><description>We develop a taxonomical framework for classifying challenges to the possibility of consciousness in digital artificial intelligence systems. This framework allows us to identify the level of granularity at which a given challenge is intended (the levels we propose correspond to Marr's levels) and to disambiguate its degree of force: is it a challenge to computational functionalism that leaves the possibility of digital consciousness open (degree 1), a practical challenge to digital consciousness that suggests improbability without claiming impossibility (degree 2), or an argument claiming that digital consciousness is strictly impossible (degree 3)? We apply this framework to 14 prominent examples from the scientific and philosophical literature. Our aim is not to take a side in the debate, but to provide structure and a tool for disambiguating between challenges to computational functionalism and challenges to digital consciousness, as well as between different ways of parsing such challenges.</description><author>Andres Campero, Derek Shiller, Jaan Aru, Jonathan Simon</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:36:34 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16582v1</guid></item><item><title>On Geometry-Enhanced Parameter-Efficient Fine-Tuning for 3D Scene Segmentation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.22444v2</link><description>The emergence of large-scale pre-trained point cloud models has significantly advanced 3D scene understanding, but adapting these models to specific downstream tasks typically demands full fine-tuning, incurring high computational and storage costs. Parameter-efficient fine-tuning (PEFT) techniques, successful in natural language processing and 2D vision tasks, would underperform when naively applied to 3D point cloud models due to significant geometric and spatial distribution shifts. Existing PEFT methods commonly treat points as orderless tokens, neglecting important local spatial structures and global geometric contexts in 3D modeling. To bridge this gap, we introduce the Geometric Encoding Mixer (GEM), a novel geometry-aware PEFT module specifically designed for 3D point cloud transformers. GEM explicitly integrates fine-grained local positional encodings with a lightweight latent attention mechanism to capture comprehensive global context, thereby effectively addressing the spatial and geometric distribution mismatch. Extensive experiments demonstrate that GEM achieves performance comparable to or sometimes even exceeding full fine-tuning, while only updating 1.6% of the model's parameters, fewer than other PEFT methods. With significantly reduced training time and memory requirements, our approach thus sets a new benchmark for efficient, scalable, and geometry-aware fine-tuning of large-scale 3D point cloud models. Code is available at https://github.com/LiyaoTang/GEM.</description><author>Liyao Tang, Zhe Chen, Dacheng Tao</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:35:54 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.22444v2</guid></item><item><title>Synthesis of Safety Specifications for Probabilistic Systems</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16579v1</link><description>Ensuring that agents satisfy safety specifications can be crucial in safety-critical environments. While methods exist for controller synthesis with safe temporal specifications, most existing methods restrict safe temporal specifications to probabilistic-avoidance constraints. Formal methods typically offer more expressive ways to express safety in probabilistic systems, such as Probabilistic Computation Tree Logic (PCTL) formulas. Thus, in this paper, we develop a new approach that supports more general temporal properties expressed in PCTL. Our contribution is twofold. First, we develop a theoretical framework for the Synthesis of safe-PCTL specifications. We show how the reducing global specification satisfaction to local constraints, and define CPCTL, a fragment of safe-PCTL. We demonstrate how the expressiveness of CPCTL makes it a relevant fragment for the Synthesis Problem. Second, we leverage these results and propose a new Value Iteration-based algorithm to solve the synthesis problem for these more general temporal properties, and we prove the soundness and completeness of our method.</description><author>Gaspard Ohlmann, Edwin Hamel-De le Court, Francesco Belardinelli</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:34:56 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16579v1</guid></item><item><title>Integrating Symbolic Natural Language Understanding and Language Models for Word Sense Disambiguation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16577v1</link><description>Word sense disambiguation is a fundamental challenge in natural language understanding. Current methods are primarily aimed at coarse-grained representations (e.g. WordNet synsets or FrameNet frames) and require hand-annotated training data to construct. This makes it difficult to automatically disambiguate richer representations (e.g. built on OpenCyc) that are needed for sophisticated inference. We propose a method that uses statistical language models as oracles for disambiguation that does not require any hand-annotation of training data. Instead, the multiple candidate meanings generated by a symbolic NLU system are converted into distinguishable natural language alternatives, which are used to query an LLM to select appropriate interpretations given the linguistic context. The selected meanings are propagated back to the symbolic NLU system. We evaluate our method against human-annotated gold answers to demonstrate its effectiveness.</description><author>Kexin Zhao, Ken Forbus</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:32:15 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16577v1</guid></item><item><title>Self-Supervised Discriminative Feature Learning for Deep Multi-View Clustering</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2103.15069v3</link><description>Multi-view clustering is an important research topic due to its capability to utilize complementary information from multiple views. However, there are few methods to consider the negative impact caused by certain views with unclear clustering structures, resulting in poor multi-view clustering performance. To address this drawback, we propose self-supervised discriminative feature learning for deep multi-view clustering (SDMVC). Concretely, deep autoencoders are applied to learn embedded features for each view independently. To leverage the multi-view complementary information, we concatenate all views' embedded features to form the global features, which can overcome the negative impact of some views' unclear clustering structures. In a self-supervised manner, pseudo-labels are obtained to build a unified target distribution to perform multi-view discriminative feature learning. During this process, global discriminative information can be mined to supervise all views to learn more discriminative features, which in turn are used to update the target distribution. Besides, this unified target distribution can make SDMVC learn consistent cluster assignments, which accomplishes the clustering consistency of multiple views while preserving their features' diversity. Experiments on various types of multi-view datasets show that SDMVC outperforms 14 competitors including classic and state-of-the-art methods. The code is available at https://github.com/SubmissionsIn/SDMVC.</description><author>Jie Xu, Yazhou Ren, Huayi Tang, Zhimeng Yang, Lili Pan, Yang Yang, Xiaorong Pu, Philip S. Yu, Lifang He</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:31:35 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2103.15069v3</guid></item><item><title>ECPv2: Fast, Efficient, and Scalable Global Optimization of Lipschitz Functions</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16575v1</link><description>We propose ECPv2, a scalable and theoretically grounded algorithm for global optimization of Lipschitz-continuous functions with unknown Lipschitz constants. Building on the Every Call is Precious (ECP) framework, which ensures that each accepted function evaluation is potentially informative, ECPv2 addresses key limitations of ECP, including high computational cost and overly conservative early behavior. ECPv2 introduces three innovations: (i) an adaptive lower bound to avoid vacuous acceptance regions, (ii) a Worst-m memory mechanism that restricts comparisons to a fixed-size subset of past evaluations, and (iii) a fixed random projection to accelerate distance computations in high dimensions. We theoretically show that ECPv2 retains ECP's no-regret guarantees with optimal finite-time bounds and expands the acceptance region with high probability. We further empirically validate these findings through extensive experiments and ablation studies. Using principled hyperparameter settings, we evaluate ECPv2 across a wide range of high-dimensional, non-convex optimization problems. Across benchmarks, ECPv2 consistently matches or outperforms state-of-the-art optimizers, while significantly reducing wall-clock time.</description><author>Fares Fourati, Mohamed-Slim Alouini, Vaneet Aggarwal</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:30:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16575v1</guid></item><item><title>Erase to Retain: Low Rank Adaptation Guided Selective Unlearning in Medical Segmentation Networks</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16574v1</link><description>The ability to selectively remove knowledge from medical segmentation networks is increasingly important for privacy compliance, ethical deployment, and continual dataset revision. We introduce Erase to Retain, a controllable unlearning framework for medical image segmentation that achieves targeted forgetting without full retraining. Our method uses a teacher-student distillation paradigm with Low-Rank Adaptation (LoRA) constrained subspace updates, enabling the student network to erase lesion-specific or class-specific representations in low-rank decoder spaces while preserving global anatomical understanding. During the strong unlearning phase, LoRA modules are adversarially optimized to contradict the teacher's confident predictions on a designated forget subset, enforcing semantic removal. This is followed by a gentle restoration phase that recovers generalization on retained data through head-only supervised refinement. For ISIC segmentation, the student reduces forget-set IoU from 0.875 to 0.509 while maintaining competitive performance on the retain and validation splits (0.647 to 0.677 IoU). On the cross-domain CHASE dataset, Erase to Retain consistently lowers forget-set IoU while preserving utility on retain and validation sets. For ISIC classification, our method decreases accuracy on the forget subset from 87.0 percent to 64.1 percent while improving retain accuracy from 83.9 percent to 90.6 percent. These results demonstrate that LoRA-based subspace unlearning provides a practical pathway toward responsible, controllable, and reversible unlearning in medical image analysis, enabling models to forget sensitive samples or structures while preserving performance where it matters most.</description><author>Nirjhor Datta, Md. Golam Rabiul Alam</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:30:16 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16574v1</guid></item><item><title>An Exterior-Embedding Neural Operator Framework for Preserving Conservation Laws</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16573v1</link><description>Neural operators have demonstrated considerable effectiveness in accelerating the solution of time-dependent partial differential equations (PDEs) by directly learning governing physical laws from data. However, for PDEs governed by conservation laws(e.g., conservation of mass, energy, or matter), existing neural operators fail to satisfy conservation properties, which leads to degraded model performance and limited generalizability. Moreover, we observe that distinct PDE problems generally require different optimal neural network architectures. This finding underscores the inherent limitations of specialized models in generalizing across diverse problem domains. To address these limitations, we propose Exterior-Embedded Conservation Framework (ECF), a universal conserving framework that can be integrated with various data-driven neural operators to enforce conservation laws strictly in predictions. The framework consists of two key components: a conservation quantity encoder that extracts conserved quantities from input data, and a conservation quantity decoder that adjusts the neural operator's predictions using these quantities to ensure strict conservation compliance in the final output. Since our architecture enforces conservation laws, we theoretically prove that it enhances model performance. To validate the performance of our method, we conduct experiments on multiple conservation-law-constrained PDE scenarios, including adiabatic systems, shallow water equations, and the Allen-Cahn problem. These baselines demonstrate that our method effectively improves model accuracy while strictly enforcing conservation laws in the predictions.</description><author>Huanshuo Dong, Hong Wang, Hao Wu, Zhiwei Zhuang, Xuanze Yang, Ruiqi Shu, Yuan Gao, Xiaomeng Huang</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:29:19 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16573v1</guid></item><item><title>Boosting Predictive Performance on Tabular Data through Data Augmentation with Latent-Space Flow-Based Diffusion</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16571v1</link><description>Severe class imbalance is common in real-world tabular learning, where rare but important minority classes are essential for reliable prediction. Existing generative oversampling methods such as GANs, VAEs, and diffusion models can improve minority-class performance, but they often struggle with tabular heterogeneity, training stability, and privacy concerns. We propose a family of latent-space, tree-driven diffusion methods for minority oversampling that use conditional flow matching with gradient-boosted trees as the vector-field learner. The models operate in compact latent spaces to preserve tabular structure and reduce computation. We introduce three variants: PCAForest, which uses linear PCA embedding; EmbedForest, which uses a learned nonlinear embedding; and AttentionForest, which uses an attention-augmented embedding. Each method couples a GBT-based flow with a decoder back to the original feature space. Across 11 datasets from healthcare, finance, and manufacturing, AttentionForest achieves the best average minority recall while maintaining competitive precision, calibration, and distributional similarity. PCAForest and EmbedForest reach similar utility with much faster generation, offering favorable accuracy-efficiency trade-offs. Privacy evaluated with nearest-neighbor distance ratio and distance-to-closest-record is comparable to or better than the ForestDiffusion baseline. Ablation studies show that smaller embeddings tend to improve minority recall, while aggressive learning rates harm stability. Overall, latent-space, tree-driven diffusion provides an efficient and privacy-aware approach to high-fidelity tabular data augmentation under severe class imbalance.</description><author>Md. Tawfique Ihsan, Md. Rakibul Hasan Rafi, Ahmed Shoyeb Raihan, Imtiaz Ahmed, Abdullahil Azeem</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:28:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16571v1</guid></item><item><title>Failure of uniform laws of large numbers for subdifferentials and beyond</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16568v1</link><description>We provide counterexamples showing that uniform laws of large numbers do not hold for subdifferentials under natural assumptions. Our results apply to random Lipschitz functions and random convex functions with a finite number of smooth pieces. Consequently, they resolve the questions posed by Shapiro and Xu [J. Math. Anal. Appl., 325(2), 2007] in the negative and highlight the obstacles nonsmoothness poses to uniform results.</description><author>Lai Tian, Johannes O. Royset</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:24:15 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16568v1</guid></item><item><title>POMA-3D: The Point Map Way to 3D Scene Understanding</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16567v1</link><description>In this paper, we introduce POMA-3D, the first self-supervised 3D representation model learned from point maps. Point maps encode explicit 3D coordinates on a structured 2D grid, preserving global 3D geometry while remaining compatible with the input format of 2D foundation models. To transfer rich 2D priors into POMA-3D, a view-to-scene alignment strategy is designed. Moreover, as point maps are view-dependent with respect to a canonical space, we introduce POMA-JEPA, a joint embedding-predictive architecture that enforces geometrically consistent point map features across multiple views. Additionally, we introduce ScenePoint, a point map dataset constructed from 6.5K room-level RGB-D scenes and 1M 2D image scenes to facilitate large-scale POMA-3D pretraining. Experiments show that POMA-3D serves as a strong backbone for both specialist and generalist 3D understanding. It benefits diverse tasks, including 3D question answering, embodied navigation, scene retrieval, and embodied localization, all achieved using only geometric inputs (i.e., 3D coordinates). Overall, our POMA-3D explores a point map way to 3D scene understanding, addressing the scarcity of pretrained priors and limited data in 3D representation learning. Project Page: https://matchlab-imperial.github.io/poma3d/</description><author>Ye Mao, Weixun Luo, Ranran Huang, Junpeng Jing, Krystian Mikolajczyk</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:22:51 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16567v1</guid></item><item><title>NutriScreener: Retrieval-Augmented Multi-Pose Graph Attention Network for Malnourishment Screening</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16566v1</link><description>Child malnutrition remains a global crisis, yet existing screening methods are laborious and poorly scalable, hindering early intervention. In this work, we present NutriScreener, a retrieval-augmented, multi-pose graph attention network that combines CLIP-based visual embeddings, class-boosted knowledge retrieval, and context awareness to enable robust malnutrition detection and anthropometric prediction from children's images, simultaneously addressing generalizability and class imbalance. In a clinical study, doctors rated it 4.3/5 for accuracy and 4.6/5 for efficiency, confirming its deployment readiness in low-resource settings. Trained and tested on 2,141 children from AnthroVision and additionally evaluated on diverse cross-continent populations, including ARAN and an in-house collected CampusPose dataset, it achieves 0.79 recall, 0.82 AUC, and significantly lower anthropometric RMSEs, demonstrating reliable measurement in unconstrained pediatric settings. Cross-dataset results show up to 25% recall gain and up to 3.5 cm RMSE reduction using demographically matched knowledge bases. NutriScreener offers a scalable and accurate solution for early malnutrition detection in low-resource environments.</description><author>Misaal Khan, Mayank Vatsa, Kuldeep Singh, Richa Singh</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:20:42 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16566v1</guid></item><item><title>Context-Aware Multimodal Representation Learning for Spatio-Temporally Explicit Environmental Modelling</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.11706v3</link><description>Earth observation (EO) foundation models have emerged as an effective approach to derive latent representations of the Earth system from various remote sensing sensors. These models produce embeddings that can be used as analysis-ready datasets, enabling the modelling of ecosystem dynamics without extensive sensor-specific preprocessing. However, existing models typically operate at fixed spatial or temporal scales, limiting their use for ecological analyses that require both fine spatial detail and high temporal fidelity. To overcome these limitations, we propose a representation learning framework that integrates different EO modalities into a unified feature space at high spatio-temporal resolution. We introduce the framework using Sentinel-1 and Sentinel-2 data as representative modalities. Our approach produces a latent space at native 10 m resolution and the temporal frequency of cloud-free Sentinel-2 acquisitions. Each sensor is first modeled independently to capture its sensor-specific characteristics. Their representations are then combined into a shared model. This two-stage design enables modality-specific optimisation and easy extension to new sensors, retaining pretrained encoders while retraining only fusion layers. This enables the model to capture complementary remote sensing data and to preserve coherence across space and time. Qualitative analyses reveal that the learned embeddings exhibit high spatial and semantic consistency across heterogeneous landscapes. Quantitative evaluation in modelling Gross Primary Production reveals that they encode ecologically meaningful patterns and retain sufficient temporal fidelity to support fine-scale analyses. Overall, the proposed framework provides a flexible, analysis-ready representation learning approach for environmental applications requiring diverse spatial and temporal resolutions.</description><author>Julia Peters, Karin Mora, Miguel D. Mahecha, Chaonan Ji, David Montero, Clemens Mosig, Guido Kraemer</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:16:38 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.11706v3</guid></item><item><title>Interfacial and bulk switching MoS2 memristors for an all-2D reservoir computing framework</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16557v1</link><description>In this study, we design a reservoir computing (RC) network by exploiting short- and long-term memory dynamics in Au/Ti/MoS$_2$/Au memristive devices. The temporal dynamics is engineered by controlling the thickness of the Chemical Vapor Deposited (CVD) MoS$_2$ films. Devices with a monolayer (1L)-MoS$_2$ film exhibit volatile (short-term memory) switching dynamics. We also report non-volatile resistance switching with excellent uniformity and analog behavior in conductance tuning for the multilayer (ML) MoS$_2$ memristive devices. We correlate this performance with trap-assisted space-charge limited conduction (SCLC) mechanism, leading to a bulk-limited resistance switching behavior. Four-bit reservoir states are generated using volatile memristors. The readout layer is implemented with an array of nonvolatile synapses. This small RC network achieves 89.56\% precision in a spoken-digit recognition task and is also used to analyze a nonlinear time series equation.</description><author>Asmita S. Thool, Sourodeep Roy, Prahalad Kanti Barman, Kartick Biswas, Pavan Nukala, Abhishek Misra, Saptarshi Das, and Bhaswar Chakrabarti</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:11:06 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16557v1</guid></item><item><title>vMFCoOp: Towards Equilibrium on a Unified Hyperspherical Manifold for Prompting Biomedical VLMs</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.09540v3</link><description>Recent advances in context optimization (CoOp) guided by large language model (LLM)-distilled medical semantic priors offer a scalable alternative to manual prompt engineering and full fine-tuning for adapting biomedical CLIP-based vision-language models (VLMs). However, prompt learning in this context is challenged by semantic misalignment between LLMs and CLIP variants due to divergent training corpora and model architectures; it further lacks scalability across continuously evolving families of foundation models. More critically, pairwise multimodal alignment via conventional Euclidean-space optimization lacks the capacity to model unified representations or apply localized geometric constraints, which tends to amplify modality gaps in complex biomedical imaging and destabilize few-shot adaptation. In this work, we propose vMFCoOp, a framework that inversely estimates von Mises-Fisher (vMF) distributions on a shared Hyperspherical Manifold, aligning semantic biases between arbitrary LLMs and CLIP backbones via Unified Semantic Anchors to achieve robust biomedical prompting and superior few-shot classification. Grounded in three complementary constraints, vMFCoOp demonstrates consistent improvements across 14 medical datasets, 12 medical imaging modalities, and 13 anatomical regions, outperforming state-of-the-art methods in accuracy, generalization, and clinical applicability. This work aims to continuously expand to encompass more downstream applications, and the corresponding resources are intended to be shared through https://github.com/VinyehShaw/UniEqui.</description><author>Minye Shao, Sihan Guo, Xinrun Li, Xingyu Miao, Haoran Duan, Yang Long</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:09:57 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.09540v3</guid></item><item><title>Lite Any Stereo: Efficient Zero-Shot Stereo Matching</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16555v1</link><description>Recent advances in stereo matching have focused on accuracy, often at the cost of significantly increased model size. Traditionally, the community has regarded efficient models as incapable of zero-shot ability due to their limited capacity. In this paper, we introduce Lite Any Stereo, a stereo depth estimation framework that achieves strong zero-shot generalization while remaining highly efficient. To this end, we design a compact yet expressive backbone to ensure scalability, along with a carefully crafted hybrid cost aggregation module. We further propose a three-stage training strategy on million-scale data to effectively bridge the sim-to-real gap. Together, these components demonstrate that an ultra-light model can deliver strong generalization, ranking 1st across four widely used real-world benchmarks. Remarkably, our model attains accuracy comparable to or exceeding state-of-the-art non-prior-based accurate methods while requiring less than 1% computational cost, setting a new standard for efficient stereo matching.</description><author>Junpeng Jing, Weixun Luo, Ye Mao, Krystian Mikolajczyk</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:07:06 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16555v1</guid></item><item><title>Toward Valid Generative Clinical Trial Data with Survival Endpoints</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16551v1</link><description>Clinical trials face mounting challenges: fragmented patient populations, slow enrollment, and unsustainable costs, particularly for late phase trials in oncology and rare diseases. While external control arms built from real-world data have been explored, a promising alternative is the generation of synthetic control arms using generative AI. A central challenge is the generation of time-to-event outcomes, which constitute primary endpoints in oncology and rare disease trials, but are difficult to model under censoring and small sample sizes. Existing generative approaches, largely GAN-based, are data-hungry, unstable, and rely on strong assumptions such as independent censoring. We introduce a variational autoencoder (VAE) that jointly generates mixed-type covariates and survival outcomes within a unified latent variable framework, without assuming independent censoring. Across synthetic and real trial datasets, we evaluate our model in two realistic scenarios: (i) data sharing under privacy constraints, where synthetic controls substitute for original data, and (ii) control-arm augmentation, where synthetic patients mitigate imbalances between treated and control groups. Our method outperforms GAN baselines on fidelity, utility, and privacy metrics, while revealing systematic miscalibration of type I error and power. We propose a post-generation selection procedure that improves calibration, highlighting both progress and open challenges for generative survival modeling.</description><author>Perrine Chassat, Van Tuan Nguyen, Lucas Ducrot, Emilie Lanoy, Agathe Guilloux</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:03:38 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16551v1</guid></item><item><title>Broad stochastic configuration residual learning system for norm-convergent universal approximation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16550v1</link><description>Universal approximation serves as the foundation of neural network learning algorithms. However, some networks establish their universal approximation property by demonstrating that the iterative errors converge in probability measure rather than the more rigorous norm convergence, which makes the universal approximation property of randomized learning networks highly sensitive to random parameter selection, Broad residual learning system (BRLS), as a member of randomized learning models, also encounters this issue. We theoretically demonstrate the limitation of its universal approximation property, that is, the iterative errors do not satisfy norm convergence if the selection of random parameters is inappropriate and the convergence rate meets certain conditions. To address this issue, we propose the broad stochastic configuration residual learning system (BSCRLS) algorithm, which features a novel supervisory mechanism adaptively constraining the range settings of random parameters on the basis of BRLS framework, Furthermore, we prove the universal approximation theorem of BSCRLS based on the more stringent norm convergence. Three versions of incremental BSCRLS algorithms are presented to satisfy the application requirements of various network updates. Solar panels dust detection experiments are performed on publicly available dataset and compared with 13 deep and broad learning algorithms. Experimental results reveal the effectiveness and superiority of BSCRLS algorithms.</description><author>Han Su, Zhongyan Li, Wanquan Liu</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:02:27 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16550v1</guid></item><item><title>FairLRF: Achieving Fairness through Sparse Low Rank Factorization</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16549v1</link><description>As deep learning (DL) techniques become integral to various applications, ensuring model fairness while maintaining high performance has become increasingly critical, particularly in sensitive fields such as medical diagnosis. Although a variety of bias-mitigation methods have been proposed, many rely on computationally expensive debiasing strategies or suffer substantial drops in model accuracy, which limits their practicality in real-world, resource-constrained settings. To address this issue, we propose a fairness-oriented low rank factorization (LRF) framework that leverages singular value decomposition (SVD) to improve DL model fairness. Unlike traditional SVD, which is mainly used for model compression by decomposing and reducing weight matrices, our work shows that SVD can also serve as an effective tool for fairness enhancement. Specifically, we observed that elements in the unitary matrices obtained from SVD contribute unequally to model bias across groups defined by sensitive attributes. Motivated by this observation, we propose a method, named FairLRF, that selectively removes bias-inducing elements from unitary matrices to reduce group disparities, thus enhancing model fairness. Extensive experiments show that our method outperforms conventional LRF methods as well as state-of-the-art fairness-enhancing techniques. Additionally, an ablation study examines how major hyper-parameters may influence the performance of processed models. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first work utilizing SVD not primarily for compression but for fairness enhancement.</description><author>Yuanbo Guo, Jun Xia, Yiyu Shi</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:01:52 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16549v1</guid></item><item><title>Utilizing Large Language Models for Zero-Shot Medical Ontology Extension from Clinical Notes</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16548v1</link><description>Integrating novel medical concepts and relationships into existing ontologies can significantly enhance their coverage and utility for both biomedical research and clinical applications. Clinical notes, as unstructured documents rich with detailed patient observations, offer valuable context-specific insights and represent a promising yet underutilized source for ontology extension. Despite this potential, directly leveraging clinical notes for ontology extension remains largely unexplored. To address this gap, we propose CLOZE, a novel framework that uses large language models (LLMs) to automatically extract medical entities from clinical notes and integrate them into hierarchical medical ontologies. By capitalizing on the strong language understanding and extensive biomedical knowledge of pre-trained LLMs, CLOZE effectively identifies disease-related concepts and captures complex hierarchical relationships. The zero-shot framework requires no additional training or labeled data, making it a cost-efficient solution. Furthermore, CLOZE ensures patient privacy through automated removal of protected health information (PHI). Experimental results demonstrate that CLOZE provides an accurate, scalable, and privacy-preserving ontology extension framework, with strong potential to support a wide range of downstream applications in biomedical research and clinical informatics.</description><author>Guanchen Wu, Yuzhang Xie, Huanwei Wu, Zhe He, Hui Shao, Xiao Hu, Carl Yang</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:00:46 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16548v1</guid></item><item><title>A low-rank non-convex norm method for multiview graph clustering</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.11157v2</link><description>This study introduces a novel technique for multi-view clustering known as the "Consensus Graph-Based Multi-View Clustering Method Using Low-Rank Non-Convex Norm" (CGMVC-NC). Multi-view clustering is a challenging task in machine learning as it requires the integration of information from multiple data sources or views to cluster data points accurately. The suggested approach makes use of the structural characteristics of multi-view data tensors, introducing a non-convex tensor norm to identify correlations between these views. In contrast to conventional methods, this approach demonstrates superior clustering accuracy across several benchmark datasets. Despite the non-convex nature of the tensor norm used, the proposed method remains amenable to efficient optimization using existing algorithms. The approach provides a valuable tool for multi-view data analysis and has the potential to enhance our understanding of complex systems in various fields. Further research can explore the application of this method to other types of data and extend it to other machine-learning tasks.</description><author>Alaeddine Zahir, Khalide Jbilou, Ahmed Ratnani</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:00:12 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.11157v2</guid></item><item><title>Progressive Supernet Training for Efficient Visual Autoregressive Modeling</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16546v1</link><description>Visual Auto-Regressive (VAR) models significantly reduce inference steps through the "next-scale" prediction paradigm. However, progressive multi-scale generation incurs substantial memory overhead due to cumulative KV caching, limiting practical deployment. We observe a scale-depth asymmetric dependency in VAR: early scales exhibit extreme sensitivity to network depth, while later scales remain robust to depth reduction. Inspired by this, we propose VARiant: by equidistant sampling, we select multiple subnets ranging from 16 to 2 layers from the original 30-layer VAR-d30 network. Early scales are processed by the full network, while later scales utilize subnet. Subnet and the full network share weights, enabling flexible depth adjustment within a single model. However, weight sharing between subnet and the entire network can lead to optimization conflicts. To address this, we propose a progressive training strategy that breaks through the Pareto frontier of generation quality for both subnets and the full network under fixed-ratio training, achieving joint optimality. Experiments on ImageNet demonstrate that, compared to the pretrained VAR-d30 (FID 1.95), VARiant-d16 and VARiant-d8 achieve nearly equivalent quality (FID 2.05/2.12) while reducing memory consumption by 40-65%. VARiant-d2 achieves 3.5 times speedup and 80% memory reduction at moderate quality cost (FID 2.97). In terms of deployment, VARiant's single-model architecture supports zero-cost runtime depth switching and provides flexible deployment options from high quality to extreme efficiency, catering to diverse application scenarios.</description><author>Xiaoyue Chen, Yuling Shi, Kaiyuan Li, Huandong Wang, Yong Li, Xiaodong Gu, Xinlei Chen, Mingbao Lin</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:59:24 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16546v1</guid></item><item><title>WER is Unaware: Assessing How ASR Errors Distort Clinical Understanding in Patient Facing Dialogue</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16544v1</link><description>As Automatic Speech Recognition (ASR) is increasingly deployed in clinical dialogue, standard evaluations still rely heavily on Word Error Rate (WER). This paper challenges that standard, investigating whether WER or other common metrics correlate with the clinical impact of transcription errors. We establish a gold-standard benchmark by having expert clinicians compare ground-truth utterances to their ASR-generated counterparts, labeling the clinical impact of any discrepancies found in two distinct doctor-patient dialogue datasets. Our analysis reveals that WER and a comprehensive suite of existing metrics correlate poorly with the clinician-assigned risk labels (No, Minimal, or Significant Impact). To bridge this evaluation gap, we introduce an LLM-as-a-Judge, programmatically optimized using GEPA to replicate expert clinical assessment. The optimized judge (Gemini-2.5-Pro) achieves human-comparable performance, obtaining 90% accuracy and a strong Cohen's $κ$ of 0.816. This work provides a validated, automated framework for moving ASR evaluation beyond simple textual fidelity to a necessary, scalable assessment of safety in clinical dialogue.</description><author>Zachary Ellis, Jared Joselowitz, Yash Deo, Yajie He, Anna Kalygina, Aisling Higham, Mana Rahimzadeh, Yan Jia, Ibrahim Habli, Ernest Lim</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:59:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16544v1</guid></item><item><title>The Oracle and The Prism: A Decoupled and Efficient Framework for Generative Recommendation Explanation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16543v1</link><description>The integration of Large Language Models (LLMs) into explainable recommendation systems often leads to a performance-efficiency trade-off in end-to-end architectures, where joint optimization of ranking and explanation can result in suboptimal compromises. To resolve this, we propose Prism, a novel decoupled framework that rigorously separates the recommendation process into a dedicated ranking stage and an explanation generation stage. Inspired by knowledge distillation, Prism leverages a powerful teacher LLM (e.g., FLAN-T5-XXL) as an Oracle to produce high-fidelity explanatory knowledge. A compact, fine-tuned student model (e.g., BART-Base), the Prism, then specializes in synthesizing this knowledge into personalized explanations. This decomposition ensures that each component is optimized for its specific objective, eliminating inherent conflicts in coupled models. Extensive experiments on benchmark datasets demonstrate that our 140M-parameter Prism model significantly outperforms its 11B-parameter teacher in human evaluations of faithfulness and personalization, while achieving a 24 times speedup and a 10 times reduction in memory consumption during inference. These results validate that decoupling, coupled with targeted distillation, provides an efficient and effective pathway to high-quality explainable recommendation.</description><author>Jiaheng Zhang, Daqiang Zhang</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:59:16 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16543v1</guid></item><item><title>EOGS++: Earth Observation Gaussian Splatting with Internal Camera Refinement and Direct Panchromatic Rendering</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16542v1</link><description>Recently, 3D Gaussian Splatting has been introduced as a compelling alternative to NeRF for Earth observation, offering com- petitive reconstruction quality with significantly reduced training times. In this work, we extend the Earth Observation Gaussian Splatting (EOGS) framework to propose EOGS++, a novel method tailored for satellite imagery that directly operates on raw high-resolution panchromatic data without requiring external preprocessing. Furthermore, leveraging optical flow techniques we embed bundle adjustment directly within the training process, avoiding reliance on external optimization tools while improving camera pose estimation. We also introduce several improvements to the original implementation, including early stopping and TSDF post-processing, all contributing to sharper reconstructions and better geometric accuracy. Experiments on the IARPA 2016 and DFC2019 datasets demonstrate that EOGS++ achieves state-of-the-art performance in terms of reconstruction quality and effi- ciency, outperforming the original EOGS method and other NeRF-based methods while maintaining the computational advantages of Gaussian Splatting. Our model demonstrates an improvement from 1.33 to 1.19 mean MAE errors on buildings compared to the original EOGS models</description><author>Pierrick Bournez, Luca Savant Aira, Thibaud Ehret, Gabriele Facciolo</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:54:17 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16542v1</guid></item><item><title>Supervised Contrastive Learning for Few-Shot AI-Generated Image Detection and Attribution</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16541v1</link><description>The rapid advancement of generative artificial intelligence has enabled the creation of synthetic images that are increasingly indistinguishable from authentic content, posing significant challenges for digital media integrity. This problem is compounded by the accelerated release cycle of novel generative models, which renders traditional detection approaches (reliant on periodic retraining) computationally infeasible and operationally impractical. This work proposes a novel two-stage detection framework designed to address the generalization challenge inherent in synthetic image detection. The first stage employs a vision deep learning model trained via supervised contrastive learning to extract discriminative embeddings from input imagery. Critically, this model was trained on a strategically partitioned subset of available generators, with specific architectures withheld from training to rigorously ablate cross-generator generalization capabilities. The second stage utilizes a k-nearest neighbors (k-NN) classifier operating on the learned embedding space, trained in a few-shot learning paradigm incorporating limited samples from previously unseen test generators. With merely 150 images per class in the few-shot learning regime, which are easily obtainable from current generation models, the proposed framework achieves an average detection accuracy of 91.3\%, representing a 5.2 percentage point improvement over existing approaches . For the source attribution task, the proposed approach obtains improvements of of 14.70\% and 4.27\% in AUC and OSCR respectively on an open set classification context, marking a significant advancement toward robust, scalable forensic attribution systems capable of adapting to the evolving generative AI landscape without requiring exhaustive retraining protocols.</description><author>Jaime Álvarez Urueña, David Camacho, Javier Huertas Tato</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:53:24 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16541v1</guid></item><item><title>Beyond Tokens in Language Models: Interpreting Activations through Text Genre Chunks</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16540v1</link><description>Understanding Large Language Models (LLMs) is key to ensure their safe and beneficial deployment. This task is complicated by the difficulty of interpretability of LLM structures, and the inability to have all their outputs human-evaluated. In this paper, we present the first step towards a predictive framework, where the genre of a text used to prompt an LLM, is predicted based on its activations. Using Mistral-7B and two datasets, we show that genre can be extracted with F1-scores of up to 98% and 71% using scikit-learn classifiers. Across both datasets, results consistently outperform the control task, providing a proof of concept that text genres can be inferred from LLMs with shallow learning models.</description><author>Éloïse Benito-Rodriguez, Einar Urdshals, Jasmina Nasufi, Nicky Pochinkov</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:53:12 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16540v1</guid></item><item><title>Investigating Optical Flow Computation: From Local Methods to a Multiresolution Horn-Schunck Implementation with Bilinear Interpolation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16535v1</link><description>This paper presents an applied analysis of local and global methods, with a focus on the Horn-Schunck algorithm for optical flow computation. We explore the theoretical and practical aspects of local approaches, such as the Lucas-Kanade method, and global techniques such as Horn-Schunck. Additionally, we implement a multiresolution version of the Horn-Schunck algorithm, using bilinear interpolation and prolongation to improve accuracy and convergence. The study investigates the effectiveness of these combined strategies in estimating motion between frames, particularly under varying image conditions.</description><author>Haytham Ziani</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:49:05 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16535v1</guid></item><item><title>Enhancing Multi-Camera Gymnast Tracking Through Domain Knowledge Integration</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16532v1</link><description>We present a robust multi-camera gymnast tracking, which has been applied at international gymnastics championships for gymnastics judging. Despite considerable progress in multi-camera tracking algorithms, tracking gymnasts presents unique challenges: (i) due to space restrictions, only a limited number of cameras can be installed in the gymnastics stadium; and (ii) due to variations in lighting, background, uniforms, and occlusions, multi-camera gymnast detection may fail in certain views and only provide valid detections from two opposing views. These factors complicate the accurate determination of a gymnast's 3D trajectory using conventional multi-camera triangulation. To alleviate this issue, we incorporate gymnastics domain knowledge into our tracking solution. Given that a gymnast's 3D center typically lies within a predefined vertical plane during \revised{much of their} performance, we can apply a ray-plane intersection to generate coplanar 3D trajectory candidates for opposing-view detections. More specifically, we propose a novel cascaded data association (DA) paradigm that employs triangulation to generate 3D trajectory candidates when cross-view detections are sufficient, and resort to the ray-plane intersection when they are insufficient. Consequently, coplanar candidates are used to compensate for uncertain trajectories, thereby minimizing tracking failures. The robustness of our method is validated through extensive experimentation, demonstrating its superiority over existing methods in challenging scenarios. Furthermore, our gymnastics judging system, equipped with this tracking method, has been successfully applied to recent Gymnastics World Championships, earning significant recognition from the International Gymnastics Federation.</description><author>Fan Yang, Shigeyuki Odashima, Shoichi Masui, Ikuo Kusajima, Sosuke Yamao, Shan Jiang</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:47:45 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16532v1</guid></item><item><title>DiffuSyn Bench: Evaluating Vision-Language Models on Real-World Complexities with Diffusion-Generated Synthetic Benchmarks</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.04470v3</link><description>This study assesses the ability of Large Vision-Language Models (LVLMs) to differentiate between AI-generated and human-generated images. It introduces a new automated benchmark construction method for this evaluation. The experiment compared common LVLMs with human participants using a mixed dataset of AI and human-created images. Results showed that LVLMs could distinguish between the image types to some extent but exhibited a rightward bias, and perform significantly worse compared to humans. To build on these findings, we developed an automated benchmark construction process using AI. This process involved topic retrieval, narrative script generation, error embedding, and image generation, creating a diverse set of text-image pairs with intentional errors. We validated our method through constructing two caparable benchmarks. This study highlights the strengths and weaknesses of LVLMs in real-world understanding and advances benchmark construction techniques, providing a scalable and automatic approach for AI model evaluation.</description><author>Haokun Zhou, Yipeng Hong</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:45:08 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.04470v3</guid></item><item><title>TurkColBERT: A Benchmark of Dense and Late-Interaction Models for Turkish Information Retrieval</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16528v1</link><description>Neural information retrieval systems excel in high-resource languages but remain underexplored for morphologically rich, lower-resource languages such as Turkish. Dense bi-encoders currently dominate Turkish IR, yet late-interaction models -- which retain token-level representations for fine-grained matching -- have not been systematically evaluated. We introduce TurkColBERT, the first comprehensive benchmark comparing dense encoders and late-interaction models for Turkish retrieval. Our two-stage adaptation pipeline fine-tunes English and multilingual encoders on Turkish NLI/STS tasks, then converts them into ColBERT-style retrievers using PyLate trained on MS MARCO-TR. We evaluate 10 models across five Turkish BEIR datasets covering scientific, financial, and argumentative domains. Results show strong parameter efficiency: the 1.0M-parameter colbert-hash-nano-tr is 600$\times$ smaller than the 600M turkish-e5-large dense encoder while preserving over 71\% of its average mAP. Late-interaction models that are 3--5$\times$ smaller than dense encoders significantly outperform them; ColmmBERT-base-TR yields up to +13.8\% mAP on domain-specific tasks. For production-readiness, we compare indexing algorithms: MUVERA+Rerank is 3.33$\times$ faster than PLAID and offers +1.7\% relative mAP gain. This enables low-latency retrieval, with ColmmBERT-base-TR achieving 0.54 ms query times under MUVERA. We release all checkpoints, configs, and evaluation scripts. Limitations include reliance on moderately sized datasets ($\leq$50K documents) and translated benchmarks, which may not fully reflect real-world Turkish retrieval conditions; larger-scale MUVERA evaluations remain necessary.</description><author>Özay Ezerceli, Mahmoud El Hussieni, Selva Taş, Reyhan Bayraktar, Fatma Betül Terzioğlu, Yusuf Çelebi, Yağız Asker</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:42:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16528v1</guid></item><item><title>Contrastive vision-language learning with paraphrasing and negation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16527v1</link><description>Contrastive vision-language models continue to be the dominant approach for image and text retrieval. Contrastive Language-Image Pre-training (CLIP) trains two neural networks in contrastive manner to align their image and text embeddings in a shared latent space. Recent results evaluating CLIP on negated or paraphrased text have shown mixed performance because negation changes meaning radically with minimal lexical changes, while paraphrasing can create very different textual expressions with the same intended meaning. This poses a significant challenge for improving the evaluation results and alignment of vision-language models. To address this challenge, this paper evaluates the combination of paraphrasing and negation, proposes a new CLIP contrastive loss function accounting for both paraphrasing and negation, and applies LLM-generated training triples consisting of original, paraphrased and negated textual captions to CLIP-like training models. The approach, called SemCLIP, is shown to move paraphrased captions towards the original image embeddings while pushing negated captions further away in embedding space. Empirically, SemCLIP is shown to be capable of preserving CLIP's performance while increasing considerably the distances to negated captions. On the CC-Neg benchmark using an original over negation image-retrieval accuracy metric, SemCLIP improves accuracy from 68.1% to 78.1%. Although results are mixed when compared with CLIP on the Sugarcrepe++ benchmark, SemCLIP's performance is generally better than the models trained with negated captions. This robustness to negation extends to downstream zero-shot classification tasks where SemCLIP pre-trained on Sugarcrepe++ performs better than CLIP on all tested downstream tasks. These results indicate that SemCLIP can achieve significant robustness to semantic transformations.</description><author>Kwun Ho Ngan, Saman Sadeghi Afgeh, Joe Townsend, Artur d'Avila Garcez</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:41:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16527v1</guid></item><item><title>Securing Smart Contract Languages with a Unified Agentic Framework for Vulnerability Repair in Solidity and Move</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.18515v2</link><description>The rapid growth of the blockchain ecosystem and the increasing value locked in smart contracts necessitate robust security measures. While languages like Solidity and Move aim to improve smart contract security, vulnerabilities persist. This paper presents Smartify, a novel multi-agent framework leveraging Large Language Models (LLMs) to automatically detect and repair vulnerabilities in Solidity and Move smart contracts. Unlike traditional methods that rely solely on vast pre-training datasets, Smartify employs a team of specialized agents working on different specially fine-tuned LLMs to analyze code based on underlying programming concepts and language-specific security principles. We evaluated Smartify on a dataset for Solidity and a curated dataset for Move, demonstrating its effectiveness in fixing a wide range of vulnerabilities. Our results show that Smartify (Gemma2+codegemma) achieves state-of-the-art performance, surpassing existing LLMs and enhancing general-purpose models' capabilities, such as Llama 3.1. Notably, Smartify can incorporate language-specific knowledge, such as the nuances of Move, without requiring massive language-specific pre-training datasets. This work offers a detailed analysis of various LLMs' performance on smart contract repair, highlighting the strengths of our multi-agent approach and providing a blueprint for developing more secure and reliable decentralized applications in the growing blockchain landscape. We also provide a detailed recipe for extending this to other similar use cases.</description><author>Rabimba Karanjai, Lei Xu, Weidong Shi</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:39:11 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.18515v2</guid></item><item><title>A Decade of You Only Look Once (YOLO) for Object Detection: A Review</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.18586v3</link><description>This review marks the tenth anniversary of You Only Look Once (YOLO), one of the most influential frameworks in real-time object detection. Over the past decade, YOLO has evolved from a streamlined detector into a diverse family of architectures characterized by efficient design, modular scalability, and cross-domain adaptability. The paper presents a technical overview of the main versions (from YOLOv1 to YOLOv13), highlights key architectural trends, and surveys the principal application areas in which YOLO has been adopted. It also addresses evaluation practices, ethical considerations, and potential future directions for the framework's continued development. The analysis aims to provide a comprehensive and critical perspective on YOLO's trajectory and ongoing transformation.</description><author>Leo Thomas Ramos, Angel D. Sappa</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:38:26 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.18586v3</guid></item><item><title>BoxingVI: A Multi-Modal Benchmark for Boxing Action Recognition and Localization</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16524v1</link><description>Accurate analysis of combat sports using computer vision has gained traction in recent years, yet the development of robust datasets remains a major bottleneck due to the dynamic, unstructured nature of actions and variations in recording environments. In this work, we present a comprehensive, well-annotated video dataset tailored for punch detection and classification in boxing. The dataset comprises 6,915 high-quality punch clips categorized into six distinct punch types, extracted from 20 publicly available YouTube sparring sessions and involving 18 different athletes. Each clip is manually segmented and labeled to ensure precise temporal boundaries and class consistency, capturing a wide range of motion styles, camera angles, and athlete physiques. This dataset is specifically curated to support research in real-time vision-based action recognition, especially in low-resource and unconstrained environments. By providing a rich benchmark with diverse punch examples, this contribution aims to accelerate progress in movement analysis, automated coaching, and performance assessment within boxing and related domains.</description><author>Rahul Kumar, Vipul Baghel, Sudhanshu Singh, Bikash Kumar Badatya, Shivam Yadav, Babji Srinivasan, Ravi Hegde</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:37:07 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16524v1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Participation in Federated Learning: Benchmarks and a Knowledge Pool Plugin</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16523v1</link><description>Federated learning (FL) enables clients to collaboratively train a shared model in a distributed manner, setting it apart from traditional deep learning paradigms. However, most existing FL research assumes consistent client participation, overlooking the practical scenario of dynamic participation (DPFL), where clients may intermittently join or leave during training. Moreover, no existing benchmarking framework systematically supports the study of DPFL-specific challenges. In this work, we present the first open-source framework explicitly designed for benchmarking FL models under dynamic client participation. Our framework provides configurable data distributions, participation patterns, and evaluation metrics tailored to DPFL scenarios. Using this platform, we benchmark four major categories of widely adopted FL models and uncover substantial performance degradation under dynamic participation. To address these challenges, we further propose Knowledge-Pool Federated Learning (KPFL), a generic plugin that maintains a shared knowledge pool across both active and idle clients. KPFL leverages dual-age and data-bias weighting, combined with generative knowledge distillation, to mitigate instability and prevent knowledge loss. Extensive experiments demonstrate the significant impact of dynamic participation on FL performance and the effectiveness of KPFL in improving model robustness and generalization.</description><author>Ming-Lun Lee, Fu-Shiang Yang, Cheng-Kuan Lin, Yan-Ann Chen, Chih-Yu Lin, Yu-Chee Tseng</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:36:50 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16523v1</guid></item><item><title>YOWO: You Only Walk Once to Jointly Map An Indoor Scene and Register Ceiling-mounted Cameras</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16521v1</link><description>Using ceiling-mounted cameras (CMCs) for indoor visual capturing opens up a wide range of applications. However, registering CMCs to the target scene layout presents a challenging task. While manual registration with specialized tools is inefficient and costly, automatic registration with visual localization may yield poor results when visual ambiguity exists. To alleviate these issues, we propose a novel solution for jointly mapping an indoor scene and registering CMCs to the scene layout. Our approach involves equipping a mobile agent with a head-mounted RGB-D camera to traverse the entire scene once and synchronize CMCs to capture this mobile agent. The egocentric videos generate world-coordinate agent trajectories and the scene layout, while the videos of CMCs provide pseudo-scale agent trajectories and CMC relative poses. By correlating all the trajectories with their corresponding timestamps, the CMC relative poses can be aligned to the world-coordinate scene layout. Based on this initialization, a factor graph is customized to enable the joint optimization of ego-camera poses, scene layout, and CMC poses. We also develop a new dataset, setting the first benchmark for collaborative scene mapping and CMC registration (https://sites.google.com/view/yowo/home). Experimental results indicate that our method not only effectively accomplishes two tasks within a unified framework, but also jointly enhances their performance. We thus provide a reliable tool to facilitate downstream position-aware applications.</description><author>Fan Yang, Sosuke Yamao, Ikuo Kusajima, Atsunori Moteki, Shoichi Masui, Shan Jiang</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:36:16 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16521v1</guid></item><item><title>Saving Foundation Flow-Matching Priors for Inverse Problems</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16520v1</link><description>Foundation flow-matching (FM) models promise a universal prior for solving inverse problems (IPs), yet today they trail behind domain-specific or even untrained priors. How can we unlock their potential? We introduce FMPlug, a plug-in framework that redefines how foundation FMs are used in IPs. FMPlug combines an instance-guided, time-dependent warm-start strategy with a sharp Gaussianity regularization, adding problem-specific guidance while preserving the Gaussian structures. This leads to a significant performance boost across image restoration and scientific IPs. Our results point to a path for making foundation FM models practical, reusable priors for IP solving.</description><author>Yuxiang Wan, Ryan Devera, Wenjie Zhang, Ju Sun</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:35:57 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16520v1</guid></item><item><title>MiMo-Embodied: X-Embodied Foundation Model Technical Report</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16518v1</link><description>We open-source MiMo-Embodied, the first cross-embodied foundation model to successfully integrate and achieve state-of-the-art performance in both Autonomous Driving and Embodied AI. MiMo-Embodied sets new records across 17 embodied AI benchmarks in Task Planning, Affordance Prediction and Spatial Understanding, while also excelling in 12 autonomous driving benchmarks across Environmental Perception, Status Prediction, and Driving Planning. Across these tasks, MiMo-Embodied significantly outperforms existing open-source, closed-source, and specialized baselines. Our results indicate that through multi-stage learning, curated data construction, and CoT/RL fine-tuning, these two domains exhibit strong positive transfer and mutually reinforce one another. We provide a detailed analysis of our model design and training methodologies to facilitate further research. Code and models are available at https://github.com/XiaomiMiMo/MiMo-Embodied.</description><author>Xiaoshuai Hao, Lei Zhou, Zhijian Huang, Zhiwen Hou, Yingbo Tang, Lingfeng Zhang, Guang Li, Zheng Lu, Shuhuai Ren, Xianhui Meng, Yuchen Zhang, Jing Wu, Jinghui Lu, Chenxu Dang, Jiayi Guan, Jianhua Wu, Zhiyi Hou, Hanbing Li, Shumeng Xia, Mingliang Zhou, Yinan Zheng, Zihao Yue, Shuhao Gu, Hao Tian, Yuannan Shen, Jianwei Cui, Wen Zhang, Shaoqing Xu, Bing Wang, Haiyang Sun, Zeyu Zhu, Yuncheng Jiang, Zibin Guo, Chuhong Gong, Chaofan Zhang, Wenbo Ding, Kun Ma, Guang Chen, Rui Cai, Diyun Xiang, Heng Qu, Fuli Luo, Hangjun Ye, Long Chen</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:34:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16518v1</guid></item><item><title>Loss Functions Robust to the Presence of Label Errors</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16512v1</link><description>Methods for detecting label errors in training data require models that are robust to label errors (i.e., not fit to erroneously labelled data points). However, acquiring such models often involves training on corrupted data, which presents a challenge. Adjustments to the loss function present an opportunity for improvement. Motivated by Focal Loss (which emphasizes difficult-to-classify samples), two novel, yet simple, loss functions are proposed that de-weight or ignore these difficult samples (i.e., those likely to have label errors). Results on artificially corrupted data show promise, such that F1 scores for detecting errors are improved from the baselines of conventional categorical Cross Entropy and Focal Loss.</description><author>Nicholas Pellegrino, David Szczecina, Paul Fieguth</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:30:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16512v1</guid></item><item><title>STAMP: Spatial-Temporal Adapter with Multi-Head Pooling</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.10848v2</link><description>Time series foundation models (TSFMs) pretrained on data from multiple domains have shown strong performance on diverse modeling tasks. Various efforts have been made to develop foundation models specific to electroencephalography (EEG) data, which records brain electrical activity as time series. However, no comparative analysis of EEG-specific foundation models (EEGFMs) versus general TSFMs has been performed on EEG-specific tasks. We introduce a novel Spatial-Temporal Adapter with Multi-Head Pooling (STAMP), which leverages univariate embeddings produced by a general TSFM, implicitly models spatial-temporal characteristics of EEG data, and achieves performance comparable to state-of-the-art EEGFMs. A comprehensive analysis is performed on 8 benchmark datasets of clinical tasks using EEG for classification, along with ablation studies. Our proposed adapter is lightweight in trainable parameters and flexible in the inputs it can accommodate, supporting easy modeling of EEG data using TSFMs.</description><author>Brad Shook, Abby Turner, Jieshi Chen, Michał Wiliński, Mononito Goswami, Jonathan Elmer, Artur Dubrawski</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:28:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.10848v2</guid></item><item><title>Active Measurement: Efficient Estimation at Scale</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.01372v2</link><description>AI has the potential to transform scientific discovery by analyzing vast datasets with little human effort. However, current workflows often do not provide the accuracy or statistical guarantees that are needed. We introduce active measurement, a human-in-the-loop AI framework for scientific measurement. An AI model is used to predict measurements for individual units, which are then sampled for human labeling using importance sampling. With each new set of human labels, the AI model is improved and an unbiased Monte Carlo estimate of the total measurement is refined. Active measurement can provide precise estimates even with an imperfect AI model, and requires little human effort when the AI model is very accurate. We derive novel estimators, weighting schemes, and confidence intervals, and show that active measurement reduces estimation error compared to alternatives in several measurement tasks.</description><author>Max Hamilton, Jinlin Lai, Wenlong Zhao, Subhransu Maji, Daniel Sheldon</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:27:52 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.01372v2</guid></item><item><title>Automatically Detecting Online Deceptive Patterns</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.07441v4</link><description>Deceptive patterns in digital interfaces manipulate users into making unintended decisions, exploiting cognitive biases and psychological vulnerabilities. These patterns have become ubiquitous on various digital platforms. While efforts to mitigate deceptive patterns have emerged from legal and technical perspectives, a significant gap remains in creating usable and scalable solutions. We introduce our AutoBot framework to address this gap and help web stakeholders navigate and mitigate online deceptive patterns. AutoBot accurately identifies and localizes deceptive patterns from a screenshot of a website without relying on the underlying HTML code. AutoBot employs a two-stage pipeline that leverages the capabilities of specialized vision models to analyze website screenshots, identify interactive elements, and extract textual features. Next, using a large language model, AutoBot understands the context surrounding these elements to determine the presence of deceptive patterns. We also use AutoBot, to create a synthetic dataset to distill knowledge from 'teacher' LLMs to smaller language models. Through extensive evaluation, we demonstrate AutoBot's effectiveness in detecting deceptive patterns on the web, achieving an F1-score of 0.93 when detecting deceptive patterns, underscoring its potential as an essential tool for mitigating online deceptive patterns. We implement AutoBot, across three downstream applications targeting different web stakeholders: (1) a local browser extension providing users with real-time feedback, (2) a Lighthouse audit to inform developers of potential deceptive patterns on their sites, and (3) as a measurement tool designed for researchers and regulators.</description><author>Asmit Nayak, Shirley Zhang, Yash Wani, Rishabh Khandelwal, Kassem Fawaz</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:26:59 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.07441v4</guid></item><item><title>ODE-ViT: Plug &amp; Play Attention Layer from the Generalization of the ViT as an Ordinary Differential Equation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16501v1</link><description>In recent years, increasingly large models have achieved outstanding performance across CV tasks. However, these models demand substantial computational resources and storage, and their growing complexity limits our understanding of how they make decisions. Most of these architectures rely on the attention mechanism within Transformer-based designs. Building upon the connection between residual neural networks and ordinary differential equations (ODEs), we introduce ODE-ViT, a Vision Transformer reformulated as an ODE system that satisfies the conditions for well-posed and stable dynamics. Experiments on CIFAR-10 and CIFAR-100 demonstrate that ODE-ViT achieves stable, interpretable, and competitive performance with up to one order of magnitude fewer parameters, surpassing prior ODE-based Transformer approaches in classification tasks. We further propose a plug-and-play teacher-student framework in which a discrete ViT guides the continuous trajectory of ODE-ViT by treating the intermediate representations of the teacher as solutions of the ODE. This strategy improves performance by more than 10% compared to training a free ODE-ViT from scratch.</description><author>Carlos Boned Riera, David Romero Sanchez, Oriol Ramos Terrades</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:19:41 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16501v1</guid></item><item><title>Acquisition Time-Informed Breast Tumor Segmentation from Dynamic Contrast-Enhanced MRI</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16498v1</link><description>Dynamic contrast-enhanced magnetic resonance imaging (DCE-MRI) plays an important role in breast cancer screening, tumor assessment, and treatment planning and monitoring. The dynamic changes in contrast in different tissues help to highlight the tumor in post-contrast images. However, varying acquisition protocols and individual factors result in large variation in the appearance of tissues, even for images acquired in the same phase (e.g., first post-contrast phase), making automated tumor segmentation challenging. Here, we propose a tumor segmentation method that leverages knowledge of the image acquisition time to modulate model features according to the specific acquisition sequence. We incorporate the acquisition times using feature-wise linear modulation (FiLM) layers, a lightweight method for incorporating temporal information that also allows for capitalizing on the full, variables number of images acquired per imaging study. We trained baseline and different configurations for the time-modulated models with varying backbone architectures on a large public multisite breast DCE-MRI dataset. Evaluation on in-domain images and a public out-of-domain dataset showed that incorporating knowledge of phase acquisition time improved tumor segmentation performance and model generalization.</description><author>Rui Wang, Yuexi Du, John Lewin, R. Todd Constable, Nicha C. Dvornek</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:13:24 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.16498v1</guid></item></channel></rss>