<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Arxivfresh papers</title><link></link><description>Arxiv paper</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 12:00:32 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.0.0</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>HiStream: Efficient High-Resolution Video Generation via Redundancy-Eliminated Streaming</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21338v1</link><description>High-resolution video generation, while crucial for digital media and film, is computationally bottlenecked by the quadratic complexity of diffusion models, making practical inference infeasible. To address this, we introduce HiStream, an efficient autoregressive framework that systematically reduces redundancy across three axes: i) Spatial Compression: denoising at low resolution before refining at high resolution with cached features; ii) Temporal Compression: a chunk-by-chunk strategy with a fixed-size anchor cache, ensuring stable inference speed; and iii) Timestep Compression: applying fewer denoising steps to subsequent, cache-conditioned chunks. On 1080p benchmarks, our primary HiStream model (i+ii) achieves state-of-the-art visual quality while demonstrating up to 76.2x faster denoising compared to the Wan2.1 baseline and negligible quality loss. Our faster variant, HiStream+, applies all three optimizations (i+ii+iii), achieving a 107.5x acceleration over the baseline, offering a compelling trade-off between speed and quality, thereby making high-resolution video generation both practical and scalable.</description><author>Haonan Qiu, Shikun Liu, Zijian Zhou, Zhaochong An, Weiming Ren, Zhiheng Liu, Jonas Schult, Sen He, Shoufa Chen, Yuren Cong, Tao Xiang, Ziwei Liu, Juan-Manuel Perez-Rua</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 18:59:58 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21338v1</guid></item><item><title>Beyond Memorization: A Multi-Modal Ordinal Regression Benchmark to Expose Popularity Bias in Vision-Language Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21337v1</link><description>We expose a significant popularity bias in state-of-the-art vision-language models (VLMs), which achieve up to 34% higher accuracy on famous buildings compared to ordinary ones, indicating a reliance on memorization over generalizable understanding. To systematically investigate this, we introduce the largest open benchmark for this task: the YearGuessr dataset, a collection of 55,546 building images with multi-modal attributes from 157 countries, annotated with continuous ordinal labels of their construction year (1001-2024), GPS data, and page-view counts as a proxy for popularity. Using this dataset, we frame the construction year prediction task as ordinal regression and introduce popularity-aware interval accuracy metrics to quantify this bias. Our resulting benchmark of 30+ models, including our YearCLIP model, confirms that VLMs excel on popular, memorized items but struggle significantly with unrecognized subjects, exposing a critical flaw in their reasoning capabilities. Project page: https://sytwu.github.io/BeyondMemo/</description><author>Li-Zhong Szu-Tu, Ting-Lin Wu, Chia-Jui Chang, He Syu, Yu-Lun Liu</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 18:59:54 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21337v1</guid></item><item><title>Optimizing Decoding Paths in Masked Diffusion Models by Quantifying Uncertainty</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21336v1</link><description>Masked Diffusion Models (MDMs) offer flexible, non-autoregressive generation, but this freedom introduces a challenge: final output quality is highly sensitive to the decoding order. We are the first to formalize this issue, attributing the variability in output quality to the cumulative predictive uncertainty along a generative path. To quantify this uncertainty, we introduce Denoising Entropy, a computable metric that serves as an internal signal for evaluating generative process. Leveraging this metric, we propose two algorithms designed to optimize the decoding path: a post-hoc selection method and a real-time guidance strategy. Experiments demonstrate that our entropy-guided methods significantly improve generation quality, consistently boosting accuracy on challenging reasoning, planning, and code benchmarks. Our work establishes Denoising Entropy as a principled tool for understanding and controlling generation, effectively turning the uncertainty in MDMs from a liability into a key advantage for discovering high-quality solutions.</description><author>Ziyu Chen, Xinbei Jiang, Peng Sun, Tao Lin</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 18:59:51 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21336v1</guid></item><item><title>Autonomous Uncertainty Quantification for Computational Point-of-care Sensors</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21335v1</link><description>Computational point-of-care (POC) sensors enable rapid, low-cost, and accessible diagnostics in emergency, remote and resource-limited areas that lack access to centralized medical facilities. These systems can utilize neural network-based algorithms to accurately infer a diagnosis from the signals generated by rapid diagnostic tests or sensors. However, neural network-based diagnostic models are subject to hallucinations and can produce erroneous predictions, posing a risk of misdiagnosis and inaccurate clinical decisions. To address this challenge, here we present an autonomous uncertainty quantification technique developed for POC diagnostics. As our testbed, we used a paper-based, computational vertical flow assay (xVFA) platform developed for rapid POC diagnosis of Lyme disease, the most prevalent tick-borne disease globally. The xVFA platform integrates a disposable paper-based assay, a handheld optical reader and a neural network-based inference algorithm, providing rapid and cost-effective Lyme disease diagnostics in under 20 min using only 20 uL of patient serum. By incorporating a Monte Carlo dropout (MCDO)-based uncertainty quantification approach into the diagnostics pipeline, we identified and excluded erroneous predictions with high uncertainty, significantly improving the sensitivity and reliability of the xVFA in an autonomous manner, without access to the ground truth diagnostic information of patients. Blinded testing using new patient samples demonstrated an increase in diagnostic sensitivity from 88.2% to 95.7%, indicating the effectiveness of MCDO-based uncertainty quantification in enhancing the robustness of neural network-driven computational POC sensing systems.</description><author>Artem Goncharov, Rajesh Ghosh, Hyou-Arm Joung, Dino Di Carlo, Aydogan Ozcan</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 18:59:47 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21335v1</guid></item><item><title>Streaming Video Instruction Tuning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21334v1</link><description>We present Streamo, a real-time streaming video LLM that serves as a general-purpose interactive assistant. Unlike existing online video models that focus narrowly on question answering or captioning, Streamo performs a broad spectrum of streaming video tasks, including real-time narration, action understanding, event captioning, temporal event grounding, and time-sensitive question answering. To develop such versatility, we construct Streamo-Instruct-465K, a large-scale instruction-following dataset tailored for streaming video understanding. The dataset covers diverse temporal contexts and multi-task supervision, enabling unified training across heterogeneous streaming tasks. After training end-to-end on the instruction-following dataset through a streamlined pipeline, Streamo exhibits strong temporal reasoning, responsive interaction, and broad generalization across a variety of streaming benchmarks. Extensive experiments show that Streamo bridges the gap between offline video perception models and real-time multimodal assistants, making a step toward unified, intelligent video understanding in continuous video streams.</description><author>Jiaer Xia, Peixian Chen, Mengdan Zhang, Xing Sun, Kaiyang Zhou</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 18:59:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21334v1</guid></item><item><title>Fast SAM2 with Text-Driven Token Pruning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21333v1</link><description>Segment Anything Model 2 (SAM2), a vision foundation model has significantly advanced in prompt-driven video object segmentation, yet their practical deployment remains limited by the high computational and memory cost of processing dense visual tokens across time. The SAM2 pipelines typically propagate all visual tokens produced by the image encoder through downstream temporal reasoning modules, regardless of their relevance to the target object, resulting in reduced scalability due to quadratic memory attention overhead. In this work, we introduce a text-guided token pruning framework that improves inference efficiency by selectively reducing token density prior to temporal propagation, without modifying the underlying segmentation architecture. Operating after visual encoding and before memory based propagation, our method ranks tokens using a lightweight routing mechanism that integrates local visual context, semantic relevance derived from object-centric textual descriptions (either user-provided or automatically generated), and uncertainty cues that help preserve ambiguous or boundary critical regions. By retaining only the most informative tokens for downstream processing, the proposed approach reduces redundant computation while maintaining segmentation fidelity. Extensive experiments across multiple challenging video segmentation benchmarks demonstrate that post-encoder token pruning provides a practical and effective pathway to efficient, prompt-aware video segmentation, achieving up to 42.50 percent faster inference and 37.41 percent lower GPU memory usage compared to the unpruned baseline SAM2, while preserving competitive J and F performance. These results highlight the potential of early token selection to improve the scalability of transformer-based video segmentation systems for real-time and resource-constrained applications.</description><author>Avilasha Mandal, Chaoning Zhang, Fachrina Dewi Puspitasari, Xudong Wang, Jiaquan Zhang, Caiyan Qin, Guoqing Wang, Yang Yang, Heng Tao Shen</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 18:59:05 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21333v1</guid></item><item><title>C2LLM Technical Report: A New Frontier in Code Retrieval via Adaptive Cross-Attention Pooling</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21332v1</link><description>We present C2LLM - Contrastive Code Large Language Models, a family of code embedding models in both 0.5B and 7B sizes. Building upon Qwen-2.5-Coder backbones, C2LLM adopts a Pooling by Multihead Attention (PMA) module for generating sequence embedding from token embeddings, effectively 1) utilizing the LLM's causal representations acquired during pretraining, while also 2) being able to aggregate information from all tokens in the sequence, breaking the information bottleneck in EOS-based sequence embeddings, and 3) supporting flexible adaptation of embedding dimension, serving as an alternative to MRL. Trained on three million publicly available data, C2LLM models set new records on MTEB-Code among models of similar sizes, with C2LLM-7B ranking 1st on the overall leaderboard.</description><author>Jin Qin, Zihan Liao, Ziyin Zhang, Hang Yu, Peng Di, Rui Wang</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 18:59:01 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21332v1</guid></item><item><title>TICON: A Slide-Level Tile Contextualizer for Histopathology Representation Learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21331v1</link><description>The interpretation of small tiles in large whole slide images (WSI) often needs a larger image context. We introduce TICON, a transformer-based tile representation contextualizer that produces rich, contextualized embeddings for ''any'' application in computational pathology. Standard tile encoder-based pipelines, which extract embeddings of tiles stripped from their context, fail to model the rich slide-level information essential for both local and global tasks. Furthermore, different tile-encoders excel at different downstream tasks. Therefore, a unified model is needed to contextualize embeddings derived from ''any'' tile-level foundation model. TICON addresses this need with a single, shared encoder, pretrained using a masked modeling objective to simultaneously unify and contextualize representations from diverse tile-level pathology foundation models. Our experiments demonstrate that TICON-contextualized embeddings significantly improve performance across many different tasks, establishing new state-of-the-art results on tile-level benchmarks (i.e., HEST-Bench, THUNDER, CATCH) and slide-level benchmarks (i.e., Patho-Bench). Finally, we pretrain an aggregator on TICON to form a slide-level foundation model, using only 11K WSIs, outperforming SoTA slide-level foundation models pretrained with up to 350K WSIs.</description><author>Varun Belagali, Saarthak Kapse, Pierre Marza, Srijan Das, Zilinghan Li, Sofiène Boutaj, Pushpak Pati, Srikar Yellapragada, Tarak Nath Nandi, Ravi K Madduri, Joel Saltz, Prateek Prasanna, Stergios Christodoulidis Maria Vakalopoulou, Dimitris Samaras</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 18:58:16 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21331v1</guid></item><item><title>Your Reasoning Benchmark May Not Test Reasoning: Revealing Perception Bottleneck in Abstract Reasoning Benchmarks</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21329v1</link><description>Reasoning benchmarks such as the Abstraction and Reasoning Corpus (ARC) and ARC-AGI are widely used to assess progress in artificial intelligence and are often interpreted as probes of core, so-called ``fluid'' reasoning abilities. Despite their apparent simplicity for humans, these tasks remain challenging for frontier vision-language models (VLMs), a gap commonly attributed to deficiencies in machine reasoning. We challenge this interpretation and hypothesize that the gap arises primarily from limitations in visual perception rather than from shortcomings in inductive reasoning. To verify this hypothesis, we introduce a two-stage experimental pipeline that explicitly separates perception and reasoning. In the perception stage, each image is independently converted into a natural-language description, while in the reasoning stage a model induces and applies rules using these descriptions. This design prevents leakage of cross-image inductive signals and isolates reasoning from perception bottlenecks. Across three ARC-style datasets, Mini-ARC, ACRE, and Bongard-LOGO, we show that the perception capability is the dominant factor underlying the observed performance gap by comparing the two-stage pipeline with against standard end-to-end one-stage evaluation. Manual inspection of reasoning traces in the VLM outputs further reveals that approximately 80 percent of model failures stem from perception errors. Together, these results demonstrate that ARC-style benchmarks conflate perceptual and reasoning challenges and that observed performance gaps may overstate deficiencies in machine reasoning. Our findings underscore the need for evaluation protocols that disentangle perception from reasoning when assessing progress in machine intelligence.</description><author>Xinhe Wang, Jin Huang, Xingjian Zhang, Tianhao Wang, Jiaqi W. Ma</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 18:58:04 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21329v1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring all the noises of LLM Evals</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21326v1</link><description>Separating signal from noise is central to experimental science. Applying well-established statistical method effectively to LLM evals requires consideration of their unique noise characteristics. We clearly define and measure three types of noise: prediction noise from generating different answers on a given question, data noise from sampling questions, and their combined total noise following the law of total variance. To emphasize relative comparisons and gain statistical power, we propose the all-pairs paired method, which applies the paired analysis to all pairs of LLMs and measures all the noise components based on millions of question-level predictions across many evals and settings. These measurements revealed clear patterns. First, each eval exhibits a characteristic and highly predictable total noise level across all model pairs. Second, paired prediction noise typically exceeds paired data noise, which means reducing prediction noise by averaging can significantly increase statistical power. These findings enable practitioners to assess significance without custom testing and to detect much smaller effects in controlled experiments.</description><author>Sida Wang</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 18:54:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21326v1</guid></item><item><title>Parallel Token Prediction for Language Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21323v1</link><description>We propose Parallel Token Prediction (PTP), a universal framework for parallel sequence generation in language models. PTP jointly predicts multiple dependent tokens in a single transformer call by incorporating the sampling procedure into the model. This reduces the latency bottleneck of autoregressive decoding, and avoids the restrictive independence assumptions common in existing multi-token prediction methods. We prove that PTP can represent arbitrary autoregressive sequence distributions. PTP is trained either by distilling an existing model or through inverse autoregressive training without a teacher. Experimentally, we achieve state-of-the-art speculative decoding performance on Vicuna-7B by accepting over four tokens per step on Spec-Bench. The universality of our framework indicates that parallel generation of long sequences is feasible without loss of modeling power.</description><author>Felix Draxler, Justus Will, Farrin Marouf Sofian, Theofanis Karaletsos, Sameer Singh, Stephan Mandt</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 18:46:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21323v1</guid></item><item><title>Toward Human-Centered AI-Assisted Terminology Work</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.18859v2</link><description>The rapid diffusion of generative artificial intelligence is transforming terminology work. While this technology promises gains in efficiency, its unstructured adoption risks weakening professional autonomy, amplifying bias, and eroding linguistic and conceptual diversity. This paper argues that a human-centered approach to artificial intelligence has become a necessity for terminology work. Building on research in artificial intelligence and translation studies, it proposes a human-centered framework that conceptualizes artificial intelligence as a means of amplifying the terminologist's capabilities, rather than replacing them. The framework is organized around three interrelated dimensions: the augmented terminologist, ethical AI, and human-centered design. Together, these dimensions emphasize the compatibility of high automation with strong human control, the central role of terminologists in bias mitigation, and the importance of designing AI tools and workflows around the needs, values, and well-being of the terminologist. The paper concludes by stressing that current choices in AI adoption will shape not only terminological practice, but also the preservation of accuracy, adequacy, and diversity in terminology and specialized knowledge.</description><author>Antonio San Martin</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 18:41:46 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.18859v2</guid></item><item><title>Complex variational autoencoders admit Kähler structure</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.15172v3</link><description>It has been discovered that latent-Euclidean variational autoencoders (VAEs) admit, in various capacities, Riemannian structure. We adapt these arguments but for complex VAEs with a complex latent stage. We show that complex VAEs reveal to some level Kähler geometric structure. Our methods will be tailored for decoder geometry. We derive the Fisher information metric in the complex case under a latent complex Gaussian with trivial relation matrix. It is well known from statistical information theory that the Fisher information coincides with the Hessian of the Kullback-Leibler (KL) divergence. Thus, the metric Kähler potential relation is exactly achieved under relative entropy. We propose a Kähler potential derivative of complex Gaussian mixtures that acts as a rough proxy to the Fisher information metric while still being faithful to the underlying Kähler geometry. Computation of the metric via this potential is efficient, and through our potential, valid as a plurisubharmonic (PSH) function, large scale computational burden of automatic differentiation is displaced to small scale. Our methods leverage the law of total covariance to bridge behavior between our potential and the Fisher metric. We show that we can regularize the latent space with decoder geometry, and that we can sample in accordance with a weighted complex volume element. We demonstrate these strategies, at the exchange of sample variation, yield consistently smoother representations and fewer semantic outliers.</description><author>Andrew Gracyk</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 18:38:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.15172v3</guid></item><item><title>Variationally correct operator learning: Reduced basis neural operator with a posteriori error estimation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21319v1</link><description>Minimizing PDE-residual losses is a common strategy to promote physical consistency in neural operators. However, standard formulations often lack variational correctness, meaning that small residuals do not guarantee small solution errors due to the use of non-compliant norms or ad hoc penalty terms for boundary conditions. This work develops a variationally correct operator learning framework by constructing first-order system least-squares (FOSLS) objectives whose values are provably equivalent to the solution error in PDE-induced norms. We demonstrate this framework on stationary diffusion and linear elasticity, incorporating mixed Dirichlet-Neumann boundary conditions via variational lifts to preserve norm equivalence without inconsistent penalties. To ensure the function space conformity required by the FOSLS loss, we propose a Reduced Basis Neural Operator (RBNO). The RBNO predicts coefficients for a pre-computed, conforming reduced basis, thereby ensuring variational stability by design while enabling efficient training. We provide a rigorous convergence analysis that bounds the total error by the sum of finite element discretization bias, reduced basis truncation error, neural network approximation error, and statistical estimation errors arising from finite sampling and optimization. Numerical benchmarks validate these theoretical bounds and demonstrate that the proposed approach achieves superior accuracy in PDE-compliant norms compared to standard baselines, while the residual loss serves as a reliable, computable a posteriori error estimator.</description><author>Yuan Qiu, Wolfgang Dahmen, Peng Chen</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 18:37:59 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21319v1</guid></item><item><title>View-aware Cross-modal Distillation for Multi-view Action Recognition</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.12870v2</link><description>The widespread use of multi-sensor systems has increased research in multi-view action recognition. While existing approaches in multi-view setups with fully overlapping sensors benefit from consistent view coverage, partially overlapping settings where actions are visible in only a subset of views remain underexplored. This challenge becomes more severe in real-world scenarios, as many systems provide only limited input modalities and rely on sequence-level annotations instead of dense frame-level labels. In this study, we propose View-aware Cross-modal Knowledge Distillation (ViCoKD), a framework that distills knowledge from a fully supervised multi-modal teacher to a modality- and annotation-limited student. ViCoKD employs a cross-modal adapter with cross-modal attention, allowing the student to exploit multi-modal correlations while operating with incomplete modalities. Moreover, we propose a View-aware Consistency module to address view misalignment, where the same action may appear differently or only partially across viewpoints. It enforces prediction alignment when the action is co-visible across views, guided by human-detection masks and confidence-weighted Jensen-Shannon divergence between their predicted class distributions. Experiments on the real-world MultiSensor-Home dataset show that ViCoKD consistently outperforms competitive distillation methods across multiple backbones and environments, delivering significant gains and surpassing the teacher model under limited conditions.</description><author>Trung Thanh Nguyen, Yasutomo Kawanishi, Vijay John, Takahiro Komamizu, Ichiro Ide</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 18:29:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.12870v2</guid></item><item><title>Scaling Laws for Economic Productivity: Experimental Evidence in LLM-Assisted Consulting, Data Analyst, and Management Tasks</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21316v1</link><description>This paper derives `Scaling Laws for Economic Impacts' -- empirical relationships between the training compute of Large Language Models (LLMs) and professional productivity. In a preregistered experiment, over 500 consultants, data analysts, and managers completed professional tasks using one of 13 LLMs. We find that each year of AI model progress reduced task time by 8%, with 56% of gains driven by increased compute and 44% by algorithmic progress. However, productivity gains were significantly larger for non-agentic analytical tasks compared to agentic workflows requiring tool use. These findings suggest continued model scaling could boost U.S. productivity by approximately 20% over the next decade.</description><author>Ali Merali</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 18:24:29 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21316v1</guid></item><item><title>Does the Data Processing Inequality Reflect Practice? On the Utility of Low-Level Tasks</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21315v1</link><description>The data processing inequality is an information-theoretic principle stating that the information content of a signal cannot be increased by processing the observations. In particular, it suggests that there is no benefit in enhancing the signal or encoding it before addressing a classification problem. This assertion can be proven to be true for the case of the optimal Bayes classifier. However, in practice, it is common to perform "low-level" tasks before "high-level" downstream tasks despite the overwhelming capabilities of modern deep neural networks. In this paper, we aim to understand when and why low-level processing can be beneficial for classification. We present a comprehensive theoretical study of a binary classification setup, where we consider a classifier that is tightly connected to the optimal Bayes classifier and converges to it as the number of training samples increases. We prove that for any finite number of training samples, there exists a pre-classification processing that improves the classification accuracy. We also explore the effect of class separation, training set size, and class balance on the relative gain from this procedure. We support our theory with an empirical investigation of the theoretical setup. Finally, we conduct an empirical study where we investigate the effect of denoising and encoding on the performance of practical deep classifiers on benchmark datasets. Specifically, we vary the size and class distribution of the training set, and the noise level, and demonstrate trends that are consistent with our theoretical results.</description><author>Roy Turgeman, Tom Tirer</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 18:21:01 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21315v1</guid></item><item><title>Learning to Solve PDEs on Neural Shape Representations</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21311v1</link><description>Solving partial differential equations (PDEs) on shapes underpins many shape analysis and engineering tasks; yet, prevailing PDE solvers operate on polygonal/triangle meshes while modern 3D assets increasingly live as neural representations. This mismatch leaves no suitable method to solve surface PDEs directly within the neural domain, forcing explicit mesh extraction or per-instance residual training, preventing end-to-end workflows. We present a novel, mesh-free formulation that learns a local update operator conditioned on neural (local) shape attributes, enabling surface PDEs to be solved directly where the (neural) data lives. The operator integrates naturally with prevalent neural surface representations, is trained once on a single representative shape, and generalizes across shape and topology variations, enabling accurate, fast inference without explicit meshing or per-instance optimization while preserving differentiability. Across analytic benchmarks (heat equation and Poisson solve on sphere) and real neural assets across different representations, our method slightly outperforms CPM while remaining reasonably close to FEM, and, to our knowledge, delivers the first end-to-end pipeline that solves surface PDEs on both neural and classical surface representations. Code will be released on acceptance.</description><author>Lilian Welschinger, Yilin Liu, Zican Wang, Niloy Mitra</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 18:14:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21311v1</guid></item><item><title>Predicting Metabolic Dysfunction-Associated Steatotic Liver Disease using Machine Learning Methods</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.22293v2</link><description>Background: Metabolic Dysfunction-Associated Steatotic Liver Disease (MASLD) affects ~33% of U.S. adults and is the most common chronic liver disease. Although often asymptomatic, progression can lead to cirrhosis. Early detection is important, as lifestyle interventions can prevent disease progression. We developed a fair, rigorous, and reproducible MASLD prediction model and compared it to prior methods using a large electronic health record database. Methods: We evaluated LASSO logistic regression, random forest, XGBoost, and a neural network for MASLD prediction using clinical feature subsets, including the top 10 SHAP-ranked features. To reduce disparities in true positive rates across racial and ethnic subgroups, we applied an equal opportunity postprocessing method. Results: This study included 59,492 patients in the training data, 24,198 in the validating data, and 25,188 in the testing data. The LASSO logistic regression model with the top 10 features was selected for its interpretability and comparable performance. Before fairness adjustment, the model achieved AUROC of 0.84, accuracy of 78%, sensitivity of 72%, specificity of 79%, and F1-score of 0.617. After equal opportunity postprocessing, accuracy modestly increased to 81% and specificity to 94%, while sensitivity decreased to 41% and F1-score to 0.515, reflecting the fairness trade-off. Conclusions: We developed the MASER prediction model (MASLD Static EHR Risk Prediction), a LASSO logistic regression model which achieved competitive performance for MASLD prediction (AUROC 0.836, accuracy 77.6%), comparable to previously reported ensemble and tree-based models. Overall, this approach demonstrates that interpretable models can achieve a balance of predictive performance and fairness in diverse patient populations.</description><author>Mary E. An, Paul Griffin, Jonathan G. Stine, Ramakrishna Balakrishnan, Soundar Kumara</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 18:06:18 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.22293v2</guid></item><item><title>When F1 Fails: Granularity-Aware Evaluation for Dialogue Topic Segmentation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.17083v2</link><description>Dialogue topic segmentation supports summarization, retrieval, memory management, and conversational continuity. Despite decades of work, evaluation practice remains dominated by strict boundary matching and F1-based metrics. Modern large language model (LLM) based conversational systems increasingly rely on segmentation to manage conversation history beyond fixed context windows. In such systems, unstructured context accumulation degrades efficiency and coherence. This paper introduces an evaluation framework that reports boundary density and segment alignment diagnostics (purity and coverage) alongside window-tolerant F1 (W-F1). By separating boundary scoring from boundary selection, we evaluate segmentation quality across density regimes rather than at a single operating point. Cross-dataset evaluation shows that reported performance differences often reflect annotation granularity mismatch rather than boundary placement quality alone. We evaluate structurally distinct segmentation strategies across eight dialogue datasets spanning task-oriented, open-domain, meeting-style, and synthetic interactions. Boundary-based metrics are strongly coupled to boundary density: threshold sweeps produce larger W-F1 changes than switching between methods. These findings support viewing topic segmentation as a granularity selection problem rather than prediction of a single correct boundary set. This motivates separating boundary scoring from boundary selection for analyzing and tuning segmentation under varying annotation granularities.</description><author>Michael H. Coen</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 18:05:57 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.17083v2</guid></item><item><title>Intrinsic Benefits of Categorical Distributional Loss: Uncertainty-aware Regularized Exploration in Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2110.03155v8</link><description>The remarkable empirical performance of distributional reinforcement learning (RL) has garnered increasing attention to understanding its theoretical advantages over classical RL. By decomposing the categorical distributional loss commonly employed in distributional RL, we find that the potential superiority of distributional RL can be attributed to a derived distribution-matching entropy regularization. This less-studied entropy regularization aims to capture additional knowledge of return distribution beyond only its expectation, contributing to an augmented reward signal in policy optimization. In contrast to the vanilla entropy regularization in MaxEnt RL, which explicitly encourages exploration by promoting diverse actions, the novel entropy regularization derived from categorical distributional loss implicitly updates policies to align the learned policy with (estimated) environmental uncertainty. Finally, extensive experiments verify the significance of this uncertainty-aware regularization from distributional RL on the empirical benefits over classical RL. Our study offers an innovative exploration perspective to explain the intrinsic benefits of distributional learning in RL.</description><author>Ke Sun, Yingnan Zhao, Enze Shi, Yafei Wang, Xiaodong Yan, Bei Jiang, Linglong Kong</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 17:53:45 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2110.03155v8</guid></item><item><title>AndroidLens: Long-latency Evaluation with Nested Sub-targets for Android GUI Agents</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21302v1</link><description>Graphical user interface (GUI) agents can substantially improve productivity by automating frequently executed long-latency tasks on mobile devices. However, existing evaluation benchmarks are still constrained to limited applications, simple tasks, and coarse-grained metrics. To address this, we introduce AndroidLens, a challenging evaluation framework for mobile GUI agents, comprising 571 long-latency tasks in both Chinese and English environments, each requiring an average of more than 26 steps to complete. The framework features: (1) tasks derived from real-world user scenarios across 38 domains, covering complex types such as multi-constraint, multi-goal, and domain-specific tasks; (2) static evaluation that preserves real-world anomalies and allows multiple valid paths to reduce bias; and (3) dynamic evaluation that employs a milestone-based scheme for fine-grained progress measurement via Average Task Progress (ATP). Our evaluation indicates that even the best models reach only a 12.7% task success rate and 50.47% ATP. We also underscore key challenges in real-world environments, including environmental anomalies, adaptive exploration, and long-term memory retention.</description><author>Yue Cao, Yingyao Wang, Pi Bu, Jingxuan Xing, Wei Jiang, Zekun Zhu, Junpeng Ma, Sashuai Zhou, Tong Lu, Jun Song, Yu Cheng, Yuning Jiang, Bo Zheng</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 17:40:42 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21302v1</guid></item><item><title>Transcriptome-Conditioned Personalized De Novo Drug Generation for AML Using Metaheuristic Assembly and Target-Driven Filtering</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21301v1</link><description>Acute Myeloid Leukemia (AML) remains a clinical challenge due to its extreme molecular heterogeneity and high relapse rates. While precision medicine has introduced mutation-specific therapies, many patients still lack effective, personalized options. This paper presents a novel, end-to-end computational framework that bridges the gap between patient-specific transcriptomics and de novo drug discovery. By analyzing bulk RNA sequencing data from the TCGA-LAML cohort, the study utilized Weighted Gene Co-expression Network Analysis (WGCNA) to prioritize 20 high-value biomarkers, including metabolic transporters like HK3 and immune-modulatory receptors such as SIGLEC9. The physical structures of these targets were modeled using AlphaFold3, and druggable hotspots were quantitatively mapped via the DOGSiteScorer engine. Then developed a novel, reaction-first evolutionary metaheuristic algorithm as well as multi-objective optimization programming that assembles novel ligands from fragment libraries, guided by spatial alignment to these identified hotspots. The generative model produced structurally unique chemical entities with a strong bias toward drug-like space, as evidenced by QED scores peaking between 0.5 and 0.7. Validation through ADMET profiling and SwissDock molecular docking identified high-confidence candidates, such as Ligand L1, which achieved a binding free energy of -6.571 kcal/mol against the A08A96 biomarker. These results demonstrate that integrating systems biology with metaheuristic molecular assembly can produce pharmacologically viable, patient tailored leads, offering a scalable blueprint for precision oncology in AML and beyond</description><author>Abdullah G. Elafifi, Basma Mamdouh, Mariam Hanafy, Muhammed Alaa Eldin, Yosef Khaled, Nesma Mohamed El-Gelany, Tarek H. M. Abou-El-Enien</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 17:39:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21301v1</guid></item><item><title>Alternating Gradient Flows: A Theory of Feature Learning in Two-layer Neural Networks</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.06489v4</link><description>What features neural networks learn, and how, remains an open question. In this paper, we introduce Alternating Gradient Flows (AGF), an algorithmic framework that describes the dynamics of feature learning in two-layer networks trained from small initialization. Prior works have shown that gradient flow in this regime exhibits a staircase-like loss curve, alternating between plateaus where neurons slowly align to useful directions and sharp drops where neurons rapidly grow in norm. AGF approximates this behavior as an alternating two-step process: maximizing a utility function over dormant neurons and minimizing a cost function over active ones. AGF begins with all neurons dormant. At each iteration, a dormant neuron activates, triggering the acquisition of a feature and a drop in the loss. AGF quantifies the order, timing, and magnitude of these drops, matching experiments across several commonly studied architectures. We show that AGF unifies and extends existing saddle-to-saddle analyses in fully connected linear networks and attention-only linear transformers, where the learned features are singular modes and principal components, respectively. In diagonal linear networks, we prove AGF converges to gradient flow in the limit of vanishing initialization. Applying AGF to quadratic networks trained to perform modular addition, we give the first complete characterization of the training dynamics, revealing that networks learn Fourier features in decreasing order of coefficient magnitude. Altogether, AGF offers a promising step towards understanding feature learning in neural networks.</description><author>Daniel Kunin, Giovanni Luca Marchetti, Feng Chen, Dhruva Karkada, James B. Simon, Michael R. DeWeese, Surya Ganguli, Nina Miolane</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 17:26:35 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.06489v4</guid></item><item><title>Post-detection inference for sequential changepoint localization</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.06096v4</link><description>This paper addresses a fundamental but largely unexplored challenge in sequential changepoint analysis: conducting inference following a detected change. We develop a very general framework to construct confidence sets for the unknown changepoint using only the data observed up to a data-dependent stopping time at which an arbitrary sequential detection algorithm declares a change. Our framework is nonparametric, making no assumption on the composite post-change class, the observation space, or the sequential detection procedure used, and is non-asymptotically valid. We also extend it to handle composite pre-change classes under a suitable assumption, and also derive confidence sets for the change magnitude in parametric settings. We provide theoretical guarantees on the width of our confidence intervals. Extensive simulations demonstrate that the produced sets have reasonable size, and slightly conservative coverage. In summary, we present the first general method for sequential changepoint localization, which is theoretically sound and broadly applicable in practice.</description><author>Aytijhya Saha, Aaditya Ramdas</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 17:17:29 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.06096v4</guid></item><item><title>DiTSinger: Scaling Singing Voice Synthesis with Diffusion Transformer and Implicit Alignment</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.09016v2</link><description>Recent progress in diffusion-based Singing Voice Synthesis (SVS) demonstrates strong expressiveness but remains limited by data scarcity and model scalability. We introduce a two-stage pipeline: a compact seed set of human-sung recordings is constructed by pairing fixed melodies with diverse LLM-generated lyrics, and melody-specific models are trained to synthesize over 500 hours of high-quality Chinese singing data. Building on this corpus, we propose DiTSinger, a Diffusion Transformer with RoPE and qk-norm, systematically scaled in depth, width, and resolution for enhanced fidelity. Furthermore, we design an implicit alignment mechanism that obviates phoneme-level duration labels by constraining phoneme-to-acoustic attention within character-level spans, thereby improving robustness under noisy or uncertain alignments. Extensive experiments validate that our approach enables scalable, alignment-free, and high-fidelity SVS.</description><author>Zongcai Du, Guilin Deng, Xiaofeng Guo, Xin Gao, Linke Li, Kaichang Cheng, Fubo Han, Siyu Yang, Peng Liu, Pan Zhong, Qiang Fu</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 17:16:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.09016v2</guid></item><item><title>Rethinking Popularity Bias in Collaborative Filtering via Analytical Vector Decomposition</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.10688v5</link><description>Popularity bias fundamentally undermines the personalization capabilities of collaborative filtering (CF) models, causing them to disproportionately recommend popular items while neglecting users' genuine preferences for niche content. While existing approaches treat this as an external confounding factor, we reveal that popularity bias is an intrinsic geometric artifact of Bayesian Pairwise Ranking (BPR) optimization in CF models. Through rigorous mathematical analysis, we prove that BPR systematically organizes item embeddings along a dominant "popularity direction" where embedding magnitudes directly correlate with interaction frequency. This geometric distortion forces user embeddings to simultaneously handle two conflicting tasks-expressing genuine preference and calibrating against global popularity-trapping them in suboptimal configurations that favor popular items regardless of individual tastes. We propose Directional Decomposition and Correction (DDC), a universally applicable framework that surgically corrects this embedding geometry through asymmetric directional updates. DDC guides positive interactions along personalized preference directions while steering negative interactions away from the global popularity direction, disentangling preference from popularity at the geometric source. Extensive experiments across multiple BPR-based architectures demonstrate that DDC significantly outperforms state-of-the-art debiasing methods, reducing training loss to less than 5% of heavily-tuned baselines while achieving superior recommendation quality and fairness. Code is available in https://github.com/LingFeng-Liu-AI/DDC.</description><author>Lingfeng Liu, Yixin Song, Dazhong Shen, Bing Yin, Hao Li, Yanyong Zhang, Chao Wang</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 17:12:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.10688v5</guid></item><item><title>Model Merging via Multi-Teacher Knowledge Distillation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21288v1</link><description>Model merging has emerged as a lightweight alternative to joint multi-task learning (MTL), yet the generalization properties of merged models remain largely unexplored. Establishing such theoretical guarantees is non-trivial, as the merging process typically forbids access to the original training data and involves combining fine-tuned models trained on fundamentally heterogeneous data distributions. Without a principled understanding of these dynamics, current methods often rely on heuristics to approximate the optimal combination of parameters. This dependence is most critical in coefficient scaling, the weighting factors that modulate the magnitude of each fine-tuned model's contribution to the shared parameter. However, without a principled objective to guide their selection, these methods lead to brittle performance and are highly sensitive to scaling initialization. We address this gap by (i) establishing a novel flatness-aware PAC-Bayes generalization bound specifically for the model merging setting. This analysis introduces a "cross-task heterogeneity" term that formally captures the mismatch between diverse fine-tuned model priors and the target multi-task distributions. Guided by this theoretical insight, (ii) we frame model merging as multi-teacher knowledge distillation on scarce, unlabeled data. We formally demonstrate that minimizing the student-teacher Kullback-Leibler divergence directly tightens the upper bound on the merged model's excess risk. Guided by the flatness-aware bound derived, (iii) we operationalize this objective via SAMerging, a method that employs Sharpness-Aware Minimization (SAM) to find flat minima. Empirically, SAMerging establishes a new state of the art across vision and NLP benchmarks, achieving remarkable performance. The code is available at https://github.com/arshandalili/SAMerging.</description><author>Seyed Arshan Dalili, Mehrdad Mahdavi</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 17:10:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21288v1</guid></item><item><title>Post-Processing Mask-Based Table Segmentation for Structural Coordinate Extraction</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21287v1</link><description>Structured data extraction from tables plays a crucial role in document image analysis for scanned documents and digital archives. Although many methods have been proposed to detect table structures and extract cell contents, accurately identifying table segment boundaries (rows and columns) remains challenging, particularly in low-resolution or noisy images. In many real-world scenarios, table data are incomplete or degraded, limiting the adaptability of transformer-based methods to noisy inputs. Mask-based edge detection techniques have shown greater robustness under such conditions, as their sensitivity can be adjusted through threshold tuning; however, existing approaches typically apply masks directly to images, leading to noise sensitivity, resolution loss, or high computational cost. This paper proposes a novel multi-scale signal-processing method for detecting table edges from table masks. Row and column transitions are modeled as one-dimensional signals and processed using Gaussian convolution with progressively increasing variances, followed by statistical thresholding to suppress noise while preserving stable structural edges. Detected signal peaks are mapped back to image coordinates to obtain accurate segment boundaries. Experimental results show that applying the proposed approach to column edge detection improves Cell-Aware Segmentation Accuracy (CASA) a layout-aware metric evaluating both textual correctness and correct cell placement from 67% to 76% on the PubLayNet-1M benchmark when using TableNet with PyTesseract OCR. The method is robust to resolution variations through zero-padding and scaling strategies and produces optimized structured tabular outputs suitable for downstream analysis.</description><author>Suren Bandara</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 17:10:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21287v1</guid></item><item><title>Surgical Scene Segmentation using a Spike-Driven Video Transformer with Real-Time Potential</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21284v1</link><description>Modern surgical systems increasingly rely on intelligent scene understanding to provide timely situational awareness for enhanced intra-operative safety. Within this pipeline, surgical scene segmentation plays a central role in accurately perceiving operative events. Although recent deep learning models, particularly large-scale foundation models, achieve remarkable segmentation accuracy, their substantial computational demands and power consumption hinder real-time deployment in resource-constrained surgical environments. To address this limitation, we explore the emerging SNN as a promising paradigm for highly efficient surgical intelligence. However, their performance is still constrained by the scarcity of labeled surgical data and the inherently sparse nature of surgical video representations. To this end, we propose \textit{SpikeSurgSeg}, the first spike-driven video Transformer framework tailored for surgical scene segmentation with real-time potential on non-GPU platforms. To address the limited availability of surgical annotations, we introduce a surgical-scene masked autoencoding pretraining strategy for SNNs that enables robust spatiotemporal representation learning via layer-wise tube masking. Building on this pretrained backbone, we further adopt a lightweight spike-driven segmentation head that produces temporally consistent predictions while preserving the low-latency characteristics of SNNs. Extensive experiments on EndoVis18 and our in-house SurgBleed dataset demonstrate that SpikeSurgSeg achieves mIoU comparable to SOTA ANN-based models while reducing inference latency by at least $8\times$. Notably, it delivers over $20\times$ acceleration relative to most foundation-model baselines, underscoring its potential for time-critical surgical scene segmentation.</description><author>Shihao Zou, Jingjing Li, Wei Ji, Jincai Huang, Kai Wang, Guo Dan, Weixin Si, Yi Pan</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 17:05:09 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21284v1</guid></item><item><title>SMART SLM: Structured Memory and Reasoning Transformer, A Small Language Model for Accurate Document Assistance</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21280v1</link><description>The user of Engineering Manuals (EM) finds it difficult to read EM s because they are long, have a dense format which includes written documents, step by step procedures, and standard parameter lists for engineering equipment. Off the shelf transformers, especially compact ones, treat this material as a flat stream of tokens. This approach leads to confident but incorrect numeric answers and forces the models to memorize separate facts inefficiently. SMART (Structured Memory and Reasoning Transformer) offers a different and practical solution to the above problem. SMART structures its processing by using a hierarchical approach, and is based upon three main job categories (1) A syntax-aware Fact Extractor (Grammarian) Tree LSTM which extracts facts as subject relation object relations from EM sentences (2) A compact indexed memory MANN (Memory Augmented Neural Network) that indexes these Rational Subject Relation Objects as 384 dimensional vectors that are associated with the source of the information, and (3) A 6 layer Transformer that learns to fuse the previously retrieved facts into its generated response. The entire SMART model utilizes 45.51M parameters, which is 64% less than GPT-2 (124M) and 69% less than BERT (133M), and it achieves a 21.3% higher accuracy than GPT-2, indicating that SMART fits the data better with the least amount of processing requirements. SMART employs dual modes of inference an indexed fast path for known documents (sub-second answer times) and an indexed dynamic path assisted by RAGs for new uploads (FAISS Top 20 results with memory severed at 64 slots). In real world deployment, this framework leads to more well supported results with reduced hallucinations than comparable small transformer models.</description><author>Divij Dudeja, Mayukha Pal</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 16:59:04 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21280v1</guid></item><item><title>Agnostic Process Tomography</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.11957v2</link><description>Characterizing a quantum system by learning its state or evolution is a fundamental problem in quantum physics and learning theory with a myriad of applications. Recently, as a new approach to this problem, the task of agnostic state tomography was defined, in which one aims to approximate an arbitrary quantum state by a simpler one in a given class. Generalizing this notion to quantum processes, we initiate the study of agnostic process tomography: given query access to an unknown quantum channel $Φ$ and a known concept class $\mathcal{C}$ of channels, output a quantum channel that approximates $Φ$ as well as any channel in the concept class $\mathcal{C}$, up to some error. In this work, we propose several natural applications for this new task in quantum machine learning, quantum metrology, classical simulation, and error mitigation. In addition, we give efficient agnostic process tomography algorithms for a wide variety of concept classes, including Pauli strings, Pauli channels, quantum junta channels, low-degree channels, and a class of channels produced by $\mathsf{QAC}^0$ circuits. The main technical tool we use is Pauli spectrum analysis of operators and superoperators. We also prove that, using ancilla qubits, any agnostic state tomography algorithm can be extended to one solving agnostic process tomography for a compatible concept class of unitaries, immediately giving us efficient agnostic learning algorithms for Clifford circuits, Clifford circuits with few T gates, and circuits consisting of a tensor product of single-qubit gates. Together, our results provide insight into the conditions and new algorithms necessary to extend the learnability of a concept class from the standard tomographic setting to the agnostic one.</description><author>Chirag Wadhwa, Laura Lewis, Elham Kashefi, Mina Doosti</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 16:49:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.11957v2</guid></item><item><title>GriDiT: Factorized Grid-Based Diffusion for Efficient Long Image Sequence Generation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21276v1</link><description>Modern deep learning methods typically treat image sequences as large tensors of sequentially stacked frames. However, is this straightforward representation ideal given the current state-of-the-art (SoTA)? In this work, we address this question in the context of generative models and aim to devise a more effective way of modeling image sequence data. Observing the inefficiencies and bottlenecks of current SoTA image sequence generation methods, we showcase that rather than working with large tensors, we can improve the generation process by factorizing it into first generating the coarse sequence at low resolution and then refining the individual frames at high resolution. We train a generative model solely on grid images comprising subsampled frames. Yet, we learn to generate image sequences, using the strong self-attention mechanism of the Diffusion Transformer (DiT) to capture correlations between frames. In effect, our formulation extends a 2D image generator to operate as a low-resolution 3D image-sequence generator without introducing any architectural modifications. Subsequently, we super-resolve each frame individually to add the sequence-independent high-resolution details. This approach offers several advantages and can overcome key limitations of the SoTA in this domain. Compared to existing image sequence generation models, our method achieves superior synthesis quality and improved coherence across sequences. It also delivers high-fidelity generation of arbitrary-length sequences and increased efficiency in inference time and training data usage. Furthermore, our straightforward formulation enables our method to generalize effectively across diverse data domains, which typically require additional priors and supervision to model in a generative context. Our method consistently outperforms SoTA in quality and inference speed (at least twice-as-fast) across datasets.</description><author>Snehal Singh Tomar, Alexandros Graikos, Arjun Krishna, Dimitris Samaras, Klaus Mueller</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 16:46:04 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21276v1</guid></item><item><title>Learning to Refocus with Video Diffusion Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.19823v2</link><description>Focus is a cornerstone of photography, yet autofocus systems often fail to capture the intended subject, and users frequently wish to adjust focus after capture. We introduce a novel method for realistic post-capture refocusing using video diffusion models. From a single defocused image, our approach generates a perceptually accurate focal stack, represented as a video sequence, enabling interactive refocusing and unlocking a range of downstream applications. We release a large-scale focal stack dataset acquired under diverse real-world smartphone conditions to support this work and future research. Our method consistently outperforms existing approaches in both perceptual quality and robustness across challenging scenarios, paving the way for more advanced focus-editing capabilities in everyday photography. Code and data are available at https://learn2refocus.github.io</description><author>SaiKiran Tedla, Zhoutong Zhang, Xuaner Zhang, Shumian Xin</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 16:32:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.19823v2</guid></item><item><title>ACD: Direct Conditional Control for Video Diffusion Models via Attention Supervision</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21268v1</link><description>Controllability is a fundamental requirement in video synthesis, where accurate alignment with conditioning signals is essential. Existing classifier-free guidance methods typically achieve conditioning indirectly by modeling the joint distribution of data and conditions, which often results in limited controllability over the specified conditions. Classifier-based guidance enforces conditions through an external classifier, but the model may exploit this mechanism to raise the classifier score without genuinely satisfying the intended condition, resulting in adversarial artifacts and limited effective controllability. In this paper, we propose Attention-Conditional Diffusion (ACD), a novel framework for direct conditional control in video diffusion models via attention supervision. By aligning the model's attention maps with external control signals, ACD achieves better controllability. To support this, we introduce a sparse 3D-aware object layout as an efficient conditioning signal, along with a dedicated Layout ControlNet and an automated annotation pipeline for scalable layout integration. Extensive experiments on benchmark video generation datasets demonstrate that ACD delivers superior alignment with conditioning inputs while preserving temporal coherence and visual fidelity, establishing an effective paradigm for conditional video synthesis.</description><author>Weiqi Li, Zehao Zhang, Liang Lin, Guangrun Wang</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 16:24:18 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21268v1</guid></item><item><title>AnyAD: Unified Any-Modality Anomaly Detection in Incomplete Multi-Sequence MRI</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21264v1</link><description>Reliable anomaly detection in brain MRI remains challenging due to the scarcity of annotated abnormal cases and the frequent absence of key imaging modalities in real clinical workflows. Existing single-class or multi-class anomaly detection (AD) models typically rely on fixed modality configurations, require repetitive training, or fail to generalize to unseen modality combinations, limiting their clinical scalability. In this work, we present a unified Any-Modality AD framework that performs robust anomaly detection and localization under arbitrary MRI modality availability. The framework integrates a dual-pathway DINOv2 encoder with a feature distribution alignment mechanism that statistically aligns incomplete-modality features with full-modality representations, enabling stable inference even with severe modality dropout. To further enhance semantic consistency, we introduce an Intrinsic Normal Prototypes (INPs) extractor and an INP-guided decoder that reconstruct only normal anatomical patterns while naturally amplifying abnormal deviations. Through randomized modality masking and indirect feature completion during training, the model learns to adapt to all modality configurations without re-training. Extensive experiments on BraTS2018, MU-Glioma-Post, and Pretreat-MetsToBrain-Masks demonstrate that our approach consistently surpasses state-of-the-art industrial and medical AD baselines across 7 modality combinations, achieving superior generalization. This study establishes a scalable paradigm for multimodal medical AD under real-world, imperfect modality conditions. Our source code is available at https://github.com/wuchangw/AnyAD.</description><author>Changwei Wu, Yifei Chen, Yuxin Du, Mingxuan Liu, Jinying Zong, Beining Wu, Jie Dong, Feiwei Qin, Yunkang Cao, Qiyuan Tian</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 16:16:09 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21264v1</guid></item><item><title>ReaSeq: Unleashing World Knowledge via Reasoning for Sequential Modeling</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21257v1</link><description>Industrial recommender systems face two fundamental limitations under the log-driven paradigm: (1) knowledge poverty in ID-based item representations that causes brittle interest modeling under data sparsity, and (2) systemic blindness to beyond-log user interests that constrains model performance within platform boundaries. These limitations stem from an over-reliance on shallow interaction statistics and close-looped feedback while neglecting the rich world knowledge about product semantics and cross-domain behavioral patterns that Large Language Models have learned from vast corpora. To address these challenges, we introduce ReaSeq, a reasoning-enhanced framework that leverages world knowledge in Large Language Models to address both limitations through explicit and implicit reasoning. Specifically, ReaSeq employs explicit Chain-of-Thought reasoning via multi-agent collaboration to distill structured product knowledge into semantically enriched item representations, and latent reasoning via Diffusion Large Language Models to infer plausible beyond-log behaviors. Deployed on Taobao's ranking system serving hundreds of millions of users, ReaSeq achieves substantial gains: &gt;6.0% in IPV and CTR, &gt;2.9% in Orders, and &gt;2.5% in GMV, validating the effectiveness of world-knowledge-enhanced reasoning over purely log-driven approaches.</description><author>Chuan Wang, Gaoming Yang, Han Wu, Jiakai Tang, Jiahao Yu, Jian Wu, Jianwu Hu, Junjun Zheng, Shuwen Xiao, Yeqiu Yang, Yuning Jiang, Ahjol Nurlanbek, Binbin Cao, Bo Zheng, Fangmei Zhu, Gaoming Zhou, Huimin Yi, Huiping Chu, Jin Huang, Jinzhe Shan, Kenan Cui, Longbin Li, Silu Zhou, Wen Chen, Xia Ming, Xiang Gao, Xin Yao, Xingyu Wen, Yan Zhang, Yiwen Hu, Yulin Wang, Ziheng Bao, Zongyuan Wu</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 16:06:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21257v1</guid></item><item><title>DreaMontage: Arbitrary Frame-Guided One-Shot Video Generation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21252v1</link><description>The "one-shot" technique represents a distinct and sophisticated aesthetic in filmmaking. However, its practical realization is often hindered by prohibitive costs and complex real-world constraints. Although emerging video generation models offer a virtual alternative, existing approaches typically rely on naive clip concatenation, which frequently fails to maintain visual smoothness and temporal coherence. In this paper, we introduce DreaMontage, a comprehensive framework designed for arbitrary frame-guided generation, capable of synthesizing seamless, expressive, and long-duration one-shot videos from diverse user-provided inputs. To achieve this, we address the challenge through three primary dimensions. (i) We integrate a lightweight intermediate-conditioning mechanism into the DiT architecture. By employing an Adaptive Tuning strategy that effectively leverages base training data, we unlock robust arbitrary-frame control capabilities. (ii) To enhance visual fidelity and cinematic expressiveness, we curate a high-quality dataset and implement a Visual Expression SFT stage. In addressing critical issues such as subject motion rationality and transition smoothness, we apply a Tailored DPO scheme, which significantly improves the success rate and usability of the generated content. (iii) To facilitate the production of extended sequences, we design a Segment-wise Auto-Regressive (SAR) inference strategy that operates in a memory-efficient manner. Extensive experiments demonstrate that our approach achieves visually striking and seamlessly coherent one-shot effects while maintaining computational efficiency, empowering users to transform fragmented visual materials into vivid, cohesive one-shot cinematic experiences.</description><author>Jiawei Liu, Junqiao Li, Jiangfan Deng, Gen Li, Siyu Zhou, Zetao Fang, Shanshan Lao, Zengde Deng, Jianing Zhu, Tingting Ma, Jiayi Li, Yunqiu Wang, Qian He, Xinglong Wu</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 16:00:15 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21252v1</guid></item><item><title>Step-DeepResearch Technical Report</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20491v2</link><description>As LLMs shift toward autonomous agents, Deep Research has emerged as a pivotal metric. However, existing academic benchmarks like BrowseComp often fail to meet real-world demands for open-ended research, which requires robust skills in intent recognition, long-horizon decision-making, and cross-source verification. To address this, we introduce Step-DeepResearch, a cost-effective, end-to-end agent. We propose a Data Synthesis Strategy Based on Atomic Capabilities to reinforce planning and report writing, combined with a progressive training path from agentic mid-training to SFT and RL. Enhanced by a Checklist-style Judger, this approach significantly improves robustness. Furthermore, to bridge the evaluation gap in the Chinese domain, we establish ADR-Bench for realistic deep research scenarios. Experimental results show that Step-DeepResearch (32B) scores 61.4% on Scale AI Research Rubrics. On ADR-Bench, it significantly outperforms comparable models and rivals SOTA closed-source models like OpenAI and Gemini DeepResearch. These findings prove that refined training enables medium-sized models to achieve expert-level capabilities at industry-leading cost-efficiency.</description><author>Chen Hu, Haikuo Du, Heng Wang, Lin Lin, Mingrui Chen, Peng Liu, Ruihang Miao, Tianchi Yue, Wang You, Wei Ji, Wei Yuan, Wenjin Deng, Xiaojian Yuan, Xiaoyun Zhang, Xiangyu Liu, Xikai Liu, Yanming Xu, Yicheng Cao, Yifei Zhang, Yongyao Wang, Yubo Shu, Yurong Zhang, Yuxiang Zhang, Zheng Gong, Zhichao Chang, Binyan Li, Dan Ma, Furong Jia, Hongyuan Wang, Jiayu Liu, Jing Bai, Junlan Liu, Manjiao Liu, Na Wang, Qiuping Wu, Qinxin Du, Shiwei Li, Wen Sun, Yifeng Gong, Yonglin Chen, Yuling Zhao, Yuxuan Lin, Ziqi Ren, Zixuan Wang, Aihu Zhang, Brian Li, Buyun Ma, Kang An, Li Xie, Mingliang Li, Pan Li, Shidong Yang, Xi Chen, Xiaojia Liu, Yuchu Luo, Yuan Song, YuanHao Ding, Yuanwei Liang, Zexi Li, Zhaoning Zhang, Zixin Zhang, Binxing Jiao, Daxin Jiang, Jiansheng Chen, Jing Li, Xiangyu Zhang, Yibo Zhu</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:52:31 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20491v2</guid></item><item><title>Learning Factors in AI-Augmented Education: A Comparative Study of Middle and High School Students</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21246v1</link><description>The increasing integration of AI tools in education has led prior research to explore their impact on learning processes. Nevertheless, most existing studies focus on higher education and conventional instructional contexts, leaving open questions about how key learning factors are related in AI-mediated learning environments and how these relationships may vary across different age groups. Addressing these gaps, our work investigates whether four critical learning factors, experience, clarity, comfort, and motivation, maintain coherent interrelationships in AI-augmented educational settings, and how the structure of these relationships differs between middle and high school students. The study was conducted in authentic classroom contexts where students interacted with AI tools as part of programming learning activities to collect data on the four learning factors and students' perceptions. Using a multimethod quantitative analysis, which combined correlation analysis and text mining, we revealed markedly different dimensional structures between the two age groups. Middle school students exhibit strong positive correlations across all dimensions, indicating holistic evaluation patterns whereby positive perceptions in one dimension generalise to others. In contrast, high school students show weak or near-zero correlations between key dimensions, suggesting a more differentiated evaluation process in which dimensions are assessed independently. These findings reveal that perception dimensions actively mediate AI-augmented learning and that the developmental stage moderates their interdependencies. This work establishes a foundation for the development of AI integration strategies that respond to learners' developmental levels and account for age-specific dimensional structures in student-AI interactions.</description><author>Gaia Ebli, Bianca Raimondi, Maurizio Gabbrielli</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:43:58 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21246v1</guid></item><item><title>Interpretable Plant Leaf Disease Detection Using Attention-Enhanced CNN</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.17864v2</link><description>Plant diseases pose a significant threat to global food security, necessitating accurate and interpretable disease detection methods. This study introduces an interpretable attention-guided Convolutional Neural Network (CNN), CBAM-VGG16, for plant leaf disease detection. By integrating Convolution Block Attention Module (CBAM) at each convolutional stage, the model enhances feature extraction and disease localization. Trained on five diverse plant disease datasets, our approach outperforms recent techniques, achieving high accuracy (up to 98.87%) and demonstrating robust generalization. Here, we show the effectiveness of our method through comprehensive evaluation and interpretability analysis using CBAM attention maps, Grad-CAM, Grad-CAM++, and Layer-wise Relevance Propagation (LRP). This study advances the application of explainable AI in agricultural diagnostics, offering a transparent and reliable system for smart farming. The code of our proposed work is available at https://github.com/BS0111/PlantAttentionCBAM.</description><author>Balram Singh, Ram Prakash Sharma, Somnath Dey</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:38:23 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.17864v2</guid></item><item><title>LookPlanGraph: Embodied Instruction Following Method with VLM Graph Augmentation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21243v1</link><description>Methods that use Large Language Models (LLM) as planners for embodied instruction following tasks have become widespread. To successfully complete tasks, the LLM must be grounded in the environment in which the robot operates. One solution is to use a scene graph that contains all the necessary information. Modern methods rely on prebuilt scene graphs and assume that all task-relevant information is available at the start of planning. However, these approaches do not account for changes in the environment that may occur between the graph construction and the task execution. We propose LookPlanGraph - a method that leverages a scene graph composed of static assets and object priors. During plan execution, LookPlanGraph continuously updates the graph with relevant objects, either by verifying existing priors or discovering new entities. This is achieved by processing the agents egocentric camera view using a Vision Language Model. We conducted experiments with changed object positions VirtualHome and OmniGibson simulated environments, demonstrating that LookPlanGraph outperforms methods based on predefined static scene graphs. To demonstrate the practical applicability of our approach, we also conducted experiments in a real-world setting. Additionally, we introduce the GraSIF (Graph Scenes for Instruction Following) dataset with automated validation framework, comprising 514 tasks drawn from SayPlan Office, BEHAVIOR-1K, and VirtualHome RobotHow. Project page available at https://lookplangraph.github.io .</description><author>Anatoly O. Onishchenko, Alexey K. Kovalev, Aleksandr I. Panov</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:36:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21243v1</guid></item><item><title>Improving the Convergence Rate of Ray Search Optimization for Query-Efficient Hard-Label Attacks</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21241v1</link><description>In hard-label black-box adversarial attacks, where only the top-1 predicted label is accessible, the prohibitive query complexity poses a major obstacle to practical deployment. In this paper, we focus on optimizing a representative class of attacks that search for the optimal ray direction yielding the minimum $\ell_2$-norm perturbation required to move a benign image into the adversarial region. Inspired by Nesterov's Accelerated Gradient (NAG), we propose a momentum-based algorithm, ARS-OPT, which proactively estimates the gradient with respect to a future ray direction inferred from accumulated momentum. We provide a theoretical analysis of its convergence behavior, showing that ARS-OPT enables more accurate directional updates and achieves faster, more stable optimization. To further accelerate convergence, we incorporate surrogate-model priors into ARS-OPT's gradient estimation, resulting in PARS-OPT with enhanced performance. The superiority of our approach is supported by theoretical guarantees under standard assumptions. Extensive experiments on ImageNet and CIFAR-10 demonstrate that our method surpasses 13 state-of-the-art approaches in query efficiency.</description><author>Xinjie Xu, Shuyu Cheng, Dongwei Xu, Qi Xuan, Chen Ma</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:35:03 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21241v1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Model Selection for Conformalized Robust Optimization</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.04716v2</link><description>In decision-making under uncertainty, Contextual Robust Optimization (CRO) provides reliability by minimizing the worst-case decision loss over a prediction set. While recent advances use conformal prediction to construct prediction sets for machine learning models, the downstream decisions critically depend on model selection. This paper introduces novel model selection frameworks for CRO that unify robustness control with decision risk minimization. We first propose Conformalized Robust Optimization with Model Selection (CROMS), a framework that selects the model to approximately minimize the averaged decision risk in CRO solutions. Given the target robustness level 1-α, we present a computationally efficient algorithm called E-CROMS, which achieves asymptotic robustness control and decision optimality. To correct the control bias in finite samples, we further develop two algorithms: F-CROMS, which ensures a 1-αrobustness but requires searching the label space; and J-CROMS, which offers lower computational cost while achieving a 1-2αrobustness. Furthermore, we extend the CROMS framework to the individualized setting, where model selection is performed by minimizing the conditional decision risk given the covariates of the test data. This framework advances conformal prediction methodology by enabling covariate-aware model selection. Numerical results demonstrate significant improvements in decision efficiency across diverse synthetic and real-world applications, outperforming baseline approaches.</description><author>Yajie Bao, Yang Hu, Haojie Ren, Peng Zhao, Changliang Zou</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:30:39 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.04716v2</guid></item><item><title>Assessing the Software Security Comprehension of Large Language Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21238v1</link><description>Large language models (LLMs) are increasingly used in software development, but their level of software security expertise remains unclear. This work systematically evaluates the security comprehension of five leading LLMs: GPT-4o-Mini, GPT-5-Mini, Gemini-2.5-Flash, Llama-3.1, and Qwen-2.5, using Blooms Taxonomy as a framework. We assess six cognitive dimensions: remembering, understanding, applying, analyzing, evaluating, and creating. Our methodology integrates diverse datasets, including curated multiple-choice questions, vulnerable code snippets (SALLM), course assessments from an Introduction to Software Security course, real-world case studies (XBOW), and project-based creation tasks from a Secure Software Engineering course. Results show that while LLMs perform well on lower-level cognitive tasks such as recalling facts and identifying known vulnerabilities, their performance degrades significantly on higher-order tasks that require reasoning, architectural evaluation, and secure system creation. Beyond reporting aggregate accuracy, we introduce a software security knowledge boundary that identifies the highest cognitive level at which a model consistently maintains reliable performance. In addition, we identify 51 recurring misconception patterns exhibited by LLMs across Blooms levels.</description><author>Mohammed Latif Siddiq, Natalie Sekerak, Antonio Karam, Maria Leal, Arvin Islam-Gomes, Joanna C. S. Santos</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:29:54 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21238v1</guid></item><item><title>GeoTransolver: Learning Physics on Irregular Domains Using Multi-scale Geometry Aware Physics Attention Transformer</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20399v2</link><description>We present GeoTransolver, a Multiscale Geometry-Aware Physics Attention Transformer for CAE that replaces standard attention with GALE, coupling physics-aware self-attention on learned state slices with cross-attention to a shared geometry/global/boundary-condition context computed from multi-scale ball queries (inspired by DoMINO) and reused in every block. Implemented and released in NVIDIA PhysicsNeMo, GeoTransolver persistently projects geometry, global and boundary condition parameters into physical state spaces to anchor latent computations to domain structure and operating regimes. We benchmark GeoTransolver on DrivAerML, Luminary SHIFT-SUV, and Luminary SHIFT-Wing, comparing against Domino, Transolver (as released in PhysicsNeMo), and literature-reported AB-UPT, and evaluate drag/lift R2 and Relative L1 errors for field variables. GeoTransolver delivers better accuracy, improved robustness to geometry/regime shifts, and favorable data efficiency; we include ablations on DrivAerML and qualitative results such as contour plots and design trends for the best GeoTransolver models. By unifying multiscale geometry-aware context with physics-based attention in a scalable transformer, GeoTransolver advances operator learning for high-fidelity surrogate modeling across complex, irregular domains and non-linear physical regimes.</description><author>Corey Adams, Rishikesh Ranade, Ram Cherukuri, Sanjay Choudhry</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:28:58 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20399v2</guid></item><item><title>SegMo: Segment-aligned Text to 3D Human Motion Generation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21237v1</link><description>Generating 3D human motions from textual descriptions is an important research problem with broad applications in video games, virtual reality, and augmented reality. Recent methods align the textual description with human motion at the sequence level, neglecting the internal semantic structure of modalities. However, both motion descriptions and motion sequences can be naturally decomposed into smaller and semantically coherent segments, which can serve as atomic alignment units to achieve finer-grained correspondence. Motivated by this, we propose SegMo, a novel Segment-aligned text-conditioned human Motion generation framework to achieve fine-grained text-motion alignment. Our framework consists of three modules: (1) Text Segment Extraction, which decomposes complex textual descriptions into temporally ordered phrases, each representing a simple atomic action; (2) Motion Segment Extraction, which partitions complete motion sequences into corresponding motion segments; and (3) Fine-grained Text-Motion Alignment, which aligns text and motion segments with contrastive learning. Extensive experiments demonstrate that SegMo improves the strong baseline on two widely used datasets, achieving an improved TOP 1 score of 0.553 on the HumanML3D test set. Moreover, thanks to the learned shared embedding space for text and motion segments, SegMo can also be applied to retrieval-style tasks such as motion grounding and motion-to-text retrieval.</description><author>Bowen Dang, Lin Wu, Xiaohang Yang, Zheng Yuan, Zhixiang Chen</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:26:11 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21237v1</guid></item><item><title>Casting a SPELL: Sentence Pairing Exploration for LLM Limitation-breaking</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21236v1</link><description>Large language models (LLMs) have revolutionized software development through AI-assisted coding tools, enabling developers with limited programming expertise to create sophisticated applications. However, this accessibility extends to malicious actors who may exploit these powerful tools to generate harmful software. Existing jailbreaking research primarily focuses on general attack scenarios against LLMs, with limited exploration of malicious code generation as a jailbreak target. To address this gap, we propose SPELL, a comprehensive testing framework specifically designed to evaluate the weakness of security alignment in malicious code generation. Our framework employs a time-division selection strategy that systematically constructs jailbreaking prompts by intelligently combining sentences from a prior knowledge dataset, balancing exploration of novel attack patterns with exploitation of successful techniques. Extensive evaluation across three advanced code models (GPT-4.1, Claude-3.5, and Qwen2.5-Coder) demonstrates SPELL's effectiveness, achieving attack success rates of 83.75%, 19.38%, and 68.12% respectively across eight malicious code categories. The generated prompts successfully produce malicious code in real-world AI development tools such as Cursor, with outputs confirmed as malicious by state-of-the-art detection systems at rates exceeding 73%. These findings reveal significant security gaps in current LLM implementations and provide valuable insights for improving AI safety alignment in code generation applications.</description><author>Yifan Huang, Xiaojun Jia, Wenbo Guo, Yuqiang Sun, Yihao Huang, Chong Wang, Yang Liu</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:25:31 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21236v1</guid></item><item><title>Knowledge Augmentation via Synthetic Data: A Framework for Real-World ECG Image Classification</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.21968v2</link><description>In real-world clinical practice, electrocardiograms (ECGs) are often captured and shared as photographs. However, publicly available ECG data, and thus most related research, relies on digital signals. This has led to a disconnect in which computer assisted interpretation of ECG cannot easily be applied to ECG images. The emergence of high-fidelity synthetic data generators has introduced practical alternatives by producing realistic, photo-like, ECG images derived from the digital signal that could help narrow this divide. To address this, we propose a novel knowledge augmentation framework that uses synthetic data generated from multiple sources to provide generalisable and accurate interpretation of ECG photographs. Our framework features two key contributions. First, we introduce a robust pre-processing pipeline designed to remove background artifacts and reduces visual differences between images. Second, we implement a two-stage training strategy: a Morphology Learning Stage, where the model captures broad morphological features from visually different, scan-like synthetic data, followed by a Task-Specific Adaptation Stage, where the model is fine-tuned on the photo-like target data. We tested the model on the British Heart Foundation Challenge dataset, to classify five common ECG findings: myocardial infarction (MI), atrial fibrillation, hypertrophy, conduction disturbance, and ST/T changes. Our approach, built upon the ConvNeXt backbone, outperforms a single-source training baseline and achieved \textbf{1st} place in the challenge with an macro-AUROC of \textbf{0.9677}. These results suggest that incorporating morphology learning from heterogeneous sources offers a more robust and generalizable paradigm than conventional single-source training.</description><author>Xiaoyu Wang, Ramesh Nadarajah, Zhiqiang Zhang, David Wong</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:24:31 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.21968v2</guid></item><item><title>Rethinking Memory in LLM based Agents: Representations, Operations, and Emerging Topics</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00675v3</link><description>Memory is fundamental to large language model (LLM)-based agents, but existing surveys emphasize application-level use (e.g., personalized dialogue), while overlooking the atomic operations governing memory dynamics. This work categorizes memory into parametric (implicit in model weights) and contextual (explicit external data, structured/unstructured) forms, and defines six core operations: Consolidation, Updating, Indexing, Forgetting, Retrieval, and Condensation. Mapping these dimensions reveals four key research topics: long-term, long-context, parametric modification, and multi-source memory. The taxonomy provides a structured view of memory-related research, benchmarks, and tools, clarifying functional interactions in LLM-based agents and guiding future advancements. The datasets, papers, and tools are publicly available at https://github.com/Elvin-Yiming-Du/Survey_Memory_in_AI.</description><author>Yiming Du, Wenyu Huang, Danna Zheng, Zhaowei Wang, Sebastien Montella, Mirella Lapata, Kam-Fai Wong, Jeff Z. Pan</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:24:04 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.00675v3</guid></item><item><title>MiST: Understanding the Role of Mid-Stage Scientific Training in Developing Chemical Reasoning Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21231v1</link><description>Large Language Models can develop reasoning capabilities through online fine-tuning with rule-based rewards. However, recent studies reveal a critical constraint: reinforcement learning succeeds only when the base model already assigns non-negligible probability to correct answers -- a property we term 'latent solvability'. This work investigates the emergence of chemical reasoning capabilities and what these prerequisites mean for chemistry. We identify two necessary conditions for RL-based chemical reasoning: 1) Symbolic competence, and 2) Latent chemical knowledge. We propose mid-stage scientific training (MiST): a set of mid-stage training techniques to satisfy these, including data-mixing with SMILES/CIF-aware pre-processing, continued pre-training on 2.9B tokens, and supervised fine-tuning on 1B tokens. These steps raise the latent-solvability score on 3B and 7B models by up to 1.8x, and enable RL to lift top-1 accuracy from 10.9 to 63.9% on organic reaction naming, and from 40.6 to 67.4% on inorganic material generation. Similar results are observed for other challenging chemical tasks, while producing interpretable reasoning traces. Our results define clear prerequisites for chemical reasoning training and highlight the broader role of mid-stage training in unlocking reasoning capabilities.</description><author>Andres M Bran, Tong Xie, Shai Pranesh, Jeffrey Meng, Xuan Vu Nguyen, Jeremy Goumaz, David Ming Segura, Ruizhi Xu, Dongzhan Zhou, Wenjie Zhang, Bram Hoex, Philippe Schwaller</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:15:18 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21231v1</guid></item><item><title>PhononBench:A Large-Scale Phonon-Based Benchmark for Dynamical Stability in Crystal Generation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21227v1</link><description>In this work, we introduce PhononBench, the first large-scale benchmark for dynamical stability in AI-generated crystals. Leveraging the recently developed MatterSim interatomic potential, which achieves DFT-level accuracy in phonon predictions across more than 10,000 materials, PhononBench enables efficient large-scale phonon calculations and dynamical-stability analysis for 108,843 crystal structures generated by six leading crystal generation models. PhononBench reveals a widespread limitation of current generative models in ensuring dynamical stability: the average dynamical-stability rate across all generated structures is only 25.83%, with the top-performing model, MatterGen, reaching just 41.0%. Further case studies show that in property-targeted generation-illustrated here by band-gap conditioning with MatterGen--the dynamical-stability rate remains as low as 23.5% even at the optimal band-gap condition of 0.5 eV. In space-group-controlled generation, higher-symmetry crystals exhibit better stability (e.g., cubic systems achieve rates up to 49.2%), yet the average stability across all controlled generations is still only 34.4%. An important additional outcome of this study is the identification of 28,119 crystal structures that are phonon-stable across the entire Brillouin zone, providing a substantial pool of reliable candidates for future materials exploration. By establishing the first large-scale dynamical-stability benchmark, this work systematically highlights the current limitations of crystal generation models and offers essential evaluation criteria and guidance for their future development toward the design and discovery of physically viable materials. All model-generated crystal structures, phonon calculation results, and the high-throughput evaluation workflows developed in PhononBench will be openly released at https://github.com/xqh19970407/PhononBench</description><author>Xiao-Qi Han, Ze-Feng Gao, Peng-Jie Guo, Zhong-Yi Lu</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:07:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21227v1</guid></item><item><title>Leveraging Lightweight Entity Extraction for Scalable Event-Based Image Retrieval</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21221v1</link><description>Retrieving images from natural language descriptions is a core task at the intersection of computer vision and natural language processing, with wide-ranging applications in search engines, media archiving, and digital content management. However, real-world image-text retrieval remains challenging due to vague or context-dependent queries, linguistic variability, and the need for scalable solutions. In this work, we propose a lightweight two-stage retrieval pipeline that leverages event-centric entity extraction to incorporate temporal and contextual signals from real-world captions. The first stage performs efficient candidate filtering using BM25 based on salient entities, while the second stage applies BEiT-3 models to capture deep multimodal semantics and rerank the results. Evaluated on the OpenEvents v1 benchmark, our method achieves a mean average precision of 0.559, substantially outperforming prior baselines. These results highlight the effectiveness of combining event-guided filtering with long-text vision-language modeling for accurate and efficient retrieval in complex, real-world scenarios. Our code is available at https://github.com/PhamPhuHoa-23/Event-Based-Image-Retrieval</description><author>Dao Sy Duy Minh, Huynh Trung Kiet, Nguyen Lam Phu Quy, Phu-Hoa Pham, Tran Chi Nguyen</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:02:33 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21221v1</guid></item><item><title>RoboSafe: Safeguarding Embodied Agents via Executable Safety Logic</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21220v1</link><description>Embodied agents powered by vision-language models (VLMs) are increasingly capable of executing complex real-world tasks, yet they remain vulnerable to hazardous instructions that may trigger unsafe behaviors. Runtime safety guardrails, which intercept hazardous actions during task execution, offer a promising solution due to their flexibility. However, existing defenses often rely on static rule filters or prompt-level control, which struggle to address implicit risks arising in dynamic, temporally dependent, and context-rich environments. To address this, we propose RoboSafe, a hybrid reasoning runtime safeguard for embodied agents through executable predicate-based safety logic. RoboSafe integrates two complementary reasoning processes on a Hybrid Long-Short Safety Memory. We first propose a Backward Reflective Reasoning module that continuously revisits recent trajectories in short-term memory to infer temporal safety predicates and proactively triggers replanning when violations are detected. We then propose a Forward Predictive Reasoning module that anticipates upcoming risks by generating context-aware safety predicates from the long-term safety memory and the agent's multimodal observations. Together, these components form an adaptive, verifiable safety logic that is both interpretable and executable as code. Extensive experiments across multiple agents demonstrate that RoboSafe substantially reduces hazardous actions (-36.8% risk occurrence) compared with leading baselines, while maintaining near-original task performance. Real-world evaluations on physical robotic arms further confirm its practicality. Code will be released upon acceptance.</description><author>Le Wang, Zonghao Ying, Xiao Yang, Quanchen Zou, Zhenfei Yin, Tianlin Li, Jian Yang, Yaodong Yang, Aishan Liu, Xianglong Liu</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:01:26 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21220v1</guid></item><item><title>Latent Implicit Visual Reasoning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21218v1</link><description>While Large Multimodal Models (LMMs) have made significant progress, they remain largely text-centric, relying on language as their core reasoning modality. As a result, they are limited in their ability to handle reasoning tasks that are predominantly visual. Recent approaches have sought to address this by supervising intermediate visual steps with helper images, depth maps, or image crops. However, these strategies impose restrictive priors on what "useful" visual abstractions look like, add heavy annotation costs, and struggle to generalize across tasks. To address this critical limitation, we propose a task-agnostic mechanism that trains LMMs to discover and use visual reasoning tokens without explicit supervision. These tokens attend globally and re-encode the image in a task-adaptive way, enabling the model to extract relevant visual information without hand-crafted supervision. Our approach outperforms direct fine-tuning and achieves state-of-the-art results on a diverse range of vision-centric tasks -- including those where intermediate abstractions are hard to specify -- while also generalizing to multi-task instruction tuning.</description><author>Kelvin Li, Chuyi Shang, Leonid Karlinsky, Rogerio Feris, Trevor Darrell, Roei Herzig</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:59:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21218v1</guid></item><item><title>Seeing Structural Failure Before it Happens: An Image-Based Physics-Informed Neural Network (PINN) for Spaghetti Bridge Load Prediction</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.23117v4</link><description>Physics Informed Neural Networks (PINNs) are gaining attention for their ability to embed physical laws into deep learning models, which is particularly useful in structural engineering tasks with limited data. This paper aims to explore the use of PINNs to predict the weight of small scale spaghetti bridges, a task relevant to understanding load limits and potential failure modes in simplified structural models. Our proposed framework incorporates physics-based constraints to the prediction model for improved performance. In addition to standard PINNs, we introduce a novel architecture named Physics Informed Kolmogorov Arnold Network (PIKAN), which blends universal function approximation theory with physical insights. The structural parameters provided as input to the model are collected either manually or through computer vision methods. Our dataset includes 15 real bridges, augmented to 100 samples, and our best model achieves an $R^2$ score of 0.9603 and a mean absolute error (MAE) of 10.50 units. From applied perspective, we also provide a web based interface for parameter entry and prediction. These results show that PINNs can offer reliable estimates of structural weight, even with limited data, and may help inform early stage failure analysis in lightweight bridge designs. The complete data and code are available at https://github.com/OmerJauhar/PINNS-For-Spaghetti-Bridges.</description><author>Omer Jauhar Khan, Sudais Khan, Hafeez Anwar, Shahzeb Khan, Shams Ul Arifeen, Farman Ullah</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:58:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.23117v4</guid></item><item><title>A study of EHVI vs fixed scalarization for molecule design</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.13704v3</link><description>Multi-objective Bayesian optimization (MOBO) provides a principled framework for navigating trade-offs in molecular design. However, its empirical advantages over scalarized alternatives remain underexplored. We benchmark a simple Pareto-based MOBO strategy - Expected Hypervolume Improvement (EHVI) - against a simple fixed-weight scalarized baseline using Expected Improvement (EI), under a tightly controlled setup with identical Gaussian Process surrogates and molecular representations. Across three molecular optimization tasks, EHVI consistently outperforms scalarized EI in terms of Pareto front coverage, convergence speed, and chemical diversity. While scalarization encompasses flexible variants - including random or adaptive schemes - our results show that even strong deterministic instantiations can underperform in low-data regimes. These findings offer concrete evidence for the practical advantages of Pareto-aware acquisition in de novo molecular optimization, especially when evaluation budgets are limited and trade-offs are nontrivial.</description><author>Anabel Yong, Austin Tripp, Layla Hosseini-Gerami, Brooks Paige</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:56:07 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.13704v3</guid></item><item><title>ChainReaction: Causal Chain-Guided Reasoning for Modular and Explainable Causal-Why Video Question Answering</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.21010v2</link><description>Existing Causal-Why Video Question Answering (VideoQA) models often struggle with higher-order reasoning, relying on opaque, monolithic pipelines that entangle video understanding, causal inference, and answer generation. These black-box approaches offer limited interpretability and tend to depend on shallow heuristics. We propose a novel, modular paradigm that explicitly decouples causal reasoning from answer generation, introducing natural language causal chains as interpretable intermediate representations. Inspired by human cognitive models, these structured cause-effect sequences bridge low-level video content with high-level causal reasoning, enabling transparent and logically coherent inference. Our two-stage architecture comprises a Causal Chain Extractor (CCE) that generates causal chains from video-question pairs, and a Causal Chain-Driven Answerer (CCDA) that derives answers grounded in these chains. To address the lack of annotated reasoning traces, we introduce a scalable method for generating accurate causal chains from existing datasets. We construct human verified causal chains for 46K samples. We also propose CauCo, a new evaluation metric for causality-oriented captioning. Experiments on three large-scale benchmarks demonstrate that our approach not only outperforms state-of-the-art models, but also yields substantial gains in explainability, user trust, and generalization -- positioning the CCE as a reusable causal reasoning engine across diverse domains. Project page: https://paritoshparmar.github.io/chainreaction/</description><author>Paritosh Parmar, Eric Peh, Basura Fernando</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:52:45 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.21010v2</guid></item><item><title>Causal-driven attribution (CDA): Estimating channel influence without user-level data</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21211v1</link><description>Attribution modelling lies at the heart of marketing effectiveness, yet most existing approaches depend on user-level path data, which are increasingly inaccessible due to privacy regulations and platform restrictions. This paper introduces a Causal-Driven Attribution (CDA) framework that infers channel influence using only aggregated impression-level data, avoiding any reliance on user identifiers or click-path tracking. CDA integrates temporal causal discovery (using PCMCI) with causal effect estimation via a Structural Causal Model to recover directional channel relationships and quantify their contributions to conversions. Using large-scale synthetic data designed to replicate real marketing dynamics, we show that CDA achieves an average relative RMSE of 9.50% when given the true causal graph, and 24.23% when using the predicted graph, demonstrating strong accuracy under correct structure and meaningful signal recovery even under structural uncertainty. CDA captures cross-channel interdependencies while providing interpretable, privacy-preserving attribution insights, offering a scalable and future-proof alternative to traditional path-based models.</description><author>Georgios Filippou, Boi Mai Quach, Diana Lenghel, Arthur White, Ashish Kumar Jha</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:51:12 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21211v1</guid></item><item><title>Human Motion Estimation with Everyday Wearables</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21209v1</link><description>While on-body device-based human motion estimation is crucial for applications such as XR interaction, existing methods often suffer from poor wearability, expensive hardware, and cumbersome calibration, which hinder their adoption in daily life. To address these challenges, we present EveryWear, a lightweight and practical human motion capture approach based entirely on everyday wearables: a smartphone, smartwatch, earbuds, and smart glasses equipped with one forward-facing and two downward-facing cameras, requiring no explicit calibration before use. We introduce Ego-Elec, a 9-hour real-world dataset covering 56 daily activities across 17 diverse indoor and outdoor environments, with ground-truth 3D annotations provided by the motion capture (MoCap), to facilitate robust research and benchmarking in this direction. Our approach employs a multimodal teacher-student framework that integrates visual cues from egocentric cameras with inertial signals from consumer devices. By training directly on real-world data rather than synthetic data, our model effectively eliminates the sim-to-real gap that constrains prior work. Experiments demonstrate that our method outperforms baseline models, validating its effectiveness for practical full-body motion estimation.</description><author>Siqi Zhu, Yixuan Li, Junfu Li, Qi Wu, Zan Wang, Haozhe Ma, Wei Liang</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:44:51 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21209v1</guid></item><item><title>Improving Action Smoothness for a Cascaded Online Learning Flight Control System</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.04346v5</link><description>This paper aims to improve the action smoothness of a cascaded online learning flight control system. Although the cascaded structure is widely used in flight control design, its stability can be compromised by oscillatory control actions, which poses challenges for practical engineering applications. To address this issue, we introduce an online temporal smoothness technique and a low-pass filter to reduce the amplitude and frequency of the control actions. Fast Fourier Transform (FFT) is used to analyze policy performance in the frequency domain. Simulation results demonstrate the improvements achieved by the two proposed techniques.</description><author>Yifei Li, Erik-jan van Kampen</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:44:39 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.04346v5</guid></item><item><title>Analytic and Variational Stability of Deep Learning Systems</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21208v1</link><description>We propose a unified analytic and variational framework for studying stability in deep learning systems viewed as coupled representation-parameter dynamics. The central object is the Learning Stability Profile, which tracks the infinitesimal response of representations, parameters, and update mechanisms to perturbations along the learning trajectory. We prove a Fundamental Analytic Stability Theorem showing that uniform boundedness of these stability signatures is equivalent, up to norm equivalence, to the existence of a Lyapunov-type energy that dissipates along the learning flow. In smooth regimes, the framework yields explicit stability exponents linking spectral norms, activation regularity, step sizes, and learning rates to contractivity of the learning dynamics. Classical spectral stability results for feedforward networks, a discrete CFL-type condition for residual architectures, and parametric and temporal stability laws for stochastic gradient methods arise as direct consequences. The theory extends to non-smooth learning systems, including ReLU networks, proximal and projected updates, and stochastic subgradient flows, by replacing classical derivatives with Clarke generalized derivatives and smooth energies with variational Lyapunov functionals. The resulting framework provides a unified dynamical description of stability across architectures and optimization methods, clarifying how architectural and algorithmic choices jointly govern robustness and sensitivity to perturbations. It also provides a foundation for further extensions to continuous-time limits and geometric formulations of learning dynamics.</description><author>Ronald Katende</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:43:59 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21208v1</guid></item><item><title>Hearing to Translate: The Effectiveness of Speech Modality Integration into LLMs</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.16378v2</link><description>As Large Language Models (LLMs) expand beyond text, integrating speech as a native modality has given rise to SpeechLLMs, which aim to translate spoken language directly, thereby bypassing traditional transcription-based pipelines. Whether this integration improves speech-to-text translation quality over established cascaded architectures, however, remains an open question. We present Hearing to Translate, the first comprehensive test suite rigorously benchmarking 5 state-of-the-art SpeechLLMs against 16 strong direct and cascade systems that couple leading speech foundation models (SFM), with multilingual LLMs. Our analysis spans 16 benchmarks, 13 language pairs, and 9 challenging conditions, including disfluent, noisy, and long-form speech. Across this extensive evaluation, we find that cascaded systems remain the most reliable overall, while current SpeechLLMs only match cascades in selected settings and SFMs lag behind both, highlighting that integrating an LLM, either within the model or in a pipeline, is essential for high-quality speech translation.</description><author>Sara Papi, Javier Garcia Gilabert, Zachary Hopton, Vilém Zouhar, Carlos Escolano, Gerard I. Gállego, Jorge Iranzo-Sánchez, Ahrii Kim, Dominik Macháček, Patricia Schmidtova, Maike Züfle</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:39:27 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.16378v2</guid></item><item><title>SpidR-Adapt: A Universal Speech Representation Model for Few-Shot Adaptation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21204v1</link><description>Human infants, with only a few hundred hours of speech exposure, acquire basic units of new languages, highlighting a striking efficiency gap compared to the data-hungry self-supervised speech models. To address this gap, this paper introduces SpidR-Adapt for rapid adaptation to new languages using minimal unlabeled data. We cast such low-resource speech representation learning as a meta-learning problem and construct a multi-task adaptive pre-training (MAdaPT) protocol which formulates the adaptation process as a bi-level optimization framework. To enable scalable meta-training under this framework, we propose a novel heuristic solution, first-order bi-level optimization (FOBLO), avoiding heavy computation costs. Finally, we stabilize meta-training by using a robust initialization through interleaved supervision which alternates self-supervised and supervised objectives. Empirically, SpidR-Adapt achieves rapid gains in phonemic discriminability (ABX) and spoken language modeling (sWUGGY, sBLIMP, tSC), improving over in-domain language models after training on less than 1h of target-language audio, over $100\times$ more data-efficient than standard training. These findings highlight a practical, architecture-agnostic path toward biologically inspired, data-efficient representations. We open-source the training code and model checkpoints at https://github.com/facebookresearch/spidr-adapt.</description><author>Mahi Luthra, Jiayi Shen, Maxime Poli, Angelo Ortiz, Yosuke Higuchi, Youssef Benchekroun, Martin Gleize, Charles-Eric Saint-James, Dongyan Lin, Phillip Rust, Angel Villar, Surya Parimi, Vanessa Stark, Rashel Moritz, Juan Pino, Yann LeCun, Emmanuel Dupoux</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:33:16 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21204v1</guid></item><item><title>Schrödinger's Navigator: Imagining an Ensemble of Futures for Zero-Shot Object Navigation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21201v1</link><description>Zero-shot object navigation (ZSON) requires a robot to locate a target object in a previously unseen environment without relying on pre-built maps or task-specific training. However, existing ZSON methods often struggle in realistic and cluttered environments, particularly when the scene contains heavy occlusions, unknown risks, or dynamically moving target objects. To address these challenges, we propose \textbf{Schrödinger's Navigator}, a navigation framework inspired by Schrödinger's thought experiment on uncertainty. The framework treats unobserved space as a set of plausible future worlds and reasons over them before acting. Conditioned on egocentric visual inputs and three candidate trajectories, a trajectory-conditioned 3D world model imagines future observations along each path. This enables the agent to see beyond occlusions and anticipate risks in unseen regions without requiring extra detours or dense global mapping. The imagined 3D observations are fused into the navigation map and used to update a value map. These updates guide the policy toward trajectories that avoid occlusions, reduce exposure to uncertain space, and better track moving targets. Experiments on a Go2 quadruped robot across three challenging scenarios, including severe static occlusions, unknown risks, and dynamically moving targets, show that Schrödinger's Navigator consistently outperforms strong ZSON baselines in self-localization, object localization, and overall Success Rate in occlusion-heavy environments. These results demonstrate the effectiveness of trajectory-conditioned 3D imagination in enabling robust zero-shot object navigation.</description><author>Yu He, Da Huang, Zhenyang Liu, Zixiao Gu, Qiang Sun, Guangnan Ye, Yanwei Fu</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:28:17 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21201v1</guid></item><item><title>VisRes Bench: On Evaluating the Visual Reasoning Capabilities of VLMs</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21194v1</link><description>Vision-Language Models (VLMs) have achieved remarkable progress across tasks such as visual question answering and image captioning. Yet, the extent to which these models perform visual reasoning as opposed to relying on linguistic priors remains unclear. To address this, we introduce VisRes Bench, a benchmark designed to study visual reasoning in naturalistic settings without contextual language supervision. Analyzing model behavior across three levels of complexity, we uncover clear limitations in perceptual and relational visual reasoning capacities. VisRes isolates distinct reasoning abilities across its levels. Level 1 probes perceptual completion and global image matching under perturbations such as blur, texture changes, occlusion, and rotation; Level 2 tests rule-based inference over a single attribute (e.g., color, count, orientation); and Level 3 targets compositional reasoning that requires integrating multiple visual attributes. Across more than 19,000 controlled task images, we find that state-of-the-art VLMs perform near random under subtle perceptual perturbations, revealing limited abstraction beyond pattern recognition. We conclude by discussing how VisRes provides a unified framework for advancing abstract visual reasoning in multimodal research.</description><author>Brigitta Malagurski Törtei, Yasser Dahou, Ngoc Dung Huynh, Wamiq Reyaz Para, Phúc H. Lê Khac, Ankit Singh, Sofian Chaybouti, Sanath Narayan</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:18:38 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21194v1</guid></item><item><title>UltraShape 1.0: High-Fidelity 3D Shape Generation via Scalable Geometric Refinement</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21185v1</link><description>In this report, we introduce UltraShape 1.0, a scalable 3D diffusion framework for high-fidelity 3D geometry generation. The proposed approach adopts a two-stage generation pipeline: a coarse global structure is first synthesized and then refined to produce detailed, high-quality geometry. To support reliable 3D generation, we develop a comprehensive data processing pipeline that includes a novel watertight processing method and high-quality data filtering. This pipeline improves the geometric quality of publicly available 3D datasets by removing low-quality samples, filling holes, and thickening thin structures, while preserving fine-grained geometric details. To enable fine-grained geometry refinement, we decouple spatial localization from geometric detail synthesis in the diffusion process. We achieve this by performing voxel-based refinement at fixed spatial locations, where voxel queries derived from coarse geometry provide explicit positional anchors encoded via RoPE, allowing the diffusion model to focus on synthesizing local geometric details within a reduced, structured solution space. Our model is trained exclusively on publicly available 3D datasets, achieving strong geometric quality despite limited training resources. Extensive evaluations demonstrate that UltraShape 1.0 performs competitively with existing open-source methods in both data processing quality and geometry generation. All code and trained models will be released to support future research.</description><author>Tanghui Jia, Dongyu Yan, Dehao Hao, Yang Li, Kaiyi Zhang, Xianyi He, Lanjiong Li, Jinnan Chen, Lutao Jiang, Qishen Yin, Long Quan, Ying-Cong Chen, Li Yuan</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:08:38 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21185v1</guid></item><item><title>Towards Arbitrary Motion Completing via Hierarchical Continuous Representation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21183v1</link><description>Physical motions are inherently continuous, and higher camera frame rates typically contribute to improved smoothness and temporal coherence. For the first time, we explore continuous representations of human motion sequences, featuring the ability to interpolate, inbetween, and even extrapolate any input motion sequences at arbitrary frame rates. To achieve this, we propose a novel parametric activation-induced hierarchical implicit representation framework, referred to as NAME, based on Implicit Neural Representations (INRs). Our method introduces a hierarchical temporal encoding mechanism that extracts features from motion sequences at multiple temporal scales, enabling effective capture of intricate temporal patterns. Additionally, we integrate a custom parametric activation function, powered by Fourier transformations, into the MLP-based decoder to enhance the expressiveness of the continuous representation. This parametric formulation significantly augments the model's ability to represent complex motion behaviors with high accuracy. Extensive evaluations across several benchmark datasets demonstrate the effectiveness and robustness of our proposed approach.</description><author>Chenghao Xu, Guangtao Lyu, Qi Liu, Jiexi Yan, Muli Yang, Cheng Deng</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:07:04 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21183v1</guid></item><item><title>FERA: A Pose-Based Semantic Pipeline for Automated Foil Fencing Refereeing</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.18527v4</link><description>Many multimedia tasks map raw video into structured semantic representations for downstream decision-making. Sports officiating is a representative case, where fast, subtle interactions must be judged via symbolic rules. We present FERA (FEncing Referee Assistant), a pose-based framework that turns broadcast foil fencing video into action tokens and rule-grounded explanations. From monocular footage, FERA extracts 2D poses, converts them into a 101-dimensional kinematic representation, and applies an encoder-only transformer (FERA-MDT) to recognize per-fencer footwork, blade actions, and blade-line position. To obtain a consistent single-fencer representation for both athletes, FERA processes each clip and a horizontally flipped copy, yielding time-aligned left/right predictions without requiring a multi-person pose pipeline. A dynamic temporal windowing scheme enables inference on untrimmed pose tracks. These structured predictions serve as tokens for a language model (FERA-LM) that applies simplified right-of-way rules to generate textual decisions. On 1,734 clips (2,386 annotated actions), FERA-MDT achieves a macro-F1 of 0.549 under 5-fold cross-validation, outperforming BiLSTM and TCN baselines. Combined with FERA-LM, the full pipeline recovers referee priority with 77.7% accuracy on 969 exchanges. FERA provides a case-study benchmark for pose-based semantic grounding in a two-person sport and illustrates a general pipeline for connecting video understanding with rule-based reasoning.</description><author>Ziwen Chen, Zhong Wang</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:04:28 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.18527v4</guid></item><item><title>Equivariant Multiscale Learned Invertible Reconstruction for Cone Beam CT: From Simulated to Real Data</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21180v1</link><description>Cone Beam CT (CBCT) is an important imaging modality nowadays, however lower image quality of CBCT compared to more conventional Computed Tomography (CT) remains a limiting factor in CBCT applications. Deep learning reconstruction methods are a promising alternative to classical analytical and iterative reconstruction methods, but applying such methods to CBCT is often difficult due to the lack of ground truth data, memory limitations and the need for fast inference at clinically-relevant resolutions. In this work we propose LIRE++, an end-to-end rotationally-equivariant multiscale learned invertible primal-dual scheme for fast and memory-efficient CBCT reconstruction. Memory optimizations and multiscale reconstruction allow for fast training and inference, while rotational equivariance improves parameter efficiency. LIRE++ was trained on simulated projection data from a fast quasi-Monte Carlo CBCT projection simulator that we developed as well. Evaluated on synthetic data, LIRE++ gave an average improvement of 1 dB in Peak Signal-to-Noise Ratio over alternative deep learning baselines. On real clinical data, LIRE++ improved the average Mean Absolute Error between the reconstruction and the corresponding planning CT by 10 Hounsfield Units with respect to current proprietary state-of-the-art hybrid deep-learning/iterative method.</description><author>Nikita Moriakov, Efstratios Gavves, Jonathan H. Mason, Carmen Seller-Oria, Jonas Teuwen, Jan-Jakob Sonke</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:59:43 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21180v1</guid></item><item><title>TrackNetV5: Residual-Driven Spatio-Temporal Refinement and Motion Direction Decoupling for Fast Object Tracking</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.02789v3</link><description>The TrackNet series has established a strong baseline for fast-moving small object tracking in sports. However, existing iterations face significant limitations: V1-V3 struggle with occlusions due to a reliance on purely visual cues, while TrackNetV4, despite introducing motion inputs, suffers from directional ambiguity as its absolute difference method discards motion polarity. To overcome these bottlenecks, we propose TrackNetV5, a robust architecture integrating two novel mechanisms. First, to recover lost directional priors, we introduce the Motion Direction Decoupling (MDD) module. Unlike V4, MDD decomposes temporal dynamics into signed polarity fields, explicitly encoding both movement occurrence and trajectory direction. Second, we propose the Residual-Driven Spatio-Temporal Refinement (R-STR) head. Operating on a coarse-to-fine paradigm, this Transformer-based module leverages factorized spatio-temporal contexts to estimate a corrective residual, effectively recovering occluded targets. Extensive experiments on the TrackNetV2 dataset demonstrate that TrackNetV5 achieves a new state-of-the-art F1-score of 0.9859 and an accuracy of 0.9733, significantly outperforming previous versions. Notably, this performance leap is achieved with a marginal 3.7% increase in FLOPs compared to V4, maintaining real-time inference capabilities while delivering superior tracking precision.</description><author>Haonan Tang, Yanjun Chen, Lezhi Jiang, Qianfei Li, Xinyu Guo</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:57:31 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.02789v3</guid></item><item><title>A Turn Toward Better Alignment: Few-Shot Generative Adaptation with Equivariant Feature Rotation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21174v1</link><description>Few-shot image generation aims to effectively adapt a source generative model to a target domain using very few training images. Most existing approaches introduce consistency constraints-typically through instance-level or distribution-level loss functions-to directly align the distribution patterns of source and target domains within their respective latent spaces. However, these strategies often fall short: overly strict constraints can amplify the negative effects of the domain gap, leading to distorted or uninformative content, while overly relaxed constraints may fail to leverage the source domain effectively. This limitation primarily stems from the inherent discrepancy in the underlying distribution structures of the source and target domains. The scarcity of target samples further compounds this issue by hindering accurate estimation of the target domain's distribution. To overcome these limitations, we propose Equivariant Feature Rotation (EFR), a novel adaptation strategy that aligns source and target domains at two complementary levels within a self-rotated proxy feature space. Specifically, we perform adaptive rotations within a parameterized Lie Group to transform both source and target features into an equivariant proxy space, where alignment is conducted. These learnable rotation matrices serve to bridge the domain gap by preserving intra-domain structural information without distortion, while the alignment optimization facilitates effective knowledge transfer from the source to the target domain. Comprehensive experiments on a variety of commonly used datasets demonstrate that our method significantly enhances the generative performance within the targeted domain.</description><author>Chenghao Xu, Qi Liu, Jiexi Yan, Muli Yang, Cheng Deng</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:48:22 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21174v1</guid></item><item><title>Parameter Efficient Continual Learning with Dynamic Low-Rank Adaptation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.11998v3</link><description>Catastrophic forgetting has remained a critical challenge for deep neural networks in Continual Learning (CL) as it undermines consolidated knowledge when learning new tasks. Parameter efficient fine tuning CL techniques are gaining traction for their effectiveness in addressing catastrophic forgetting with a lightweight training schedule while avoiding degradation of consolidated knowledge in pre-trained models. However, low rank adapters (LoRA) in these approaches are highly sensitive to rank selection which can lead to sub-optimal resource allocation and performance. To this end, we introduce PEARL, a rehearsal-free CL framework that entails dynamic rank allocation for LoRA components during CL training. Specifically, PEARL leverages reference task weights and adaptively determines the rank of task-specific LoRA components based on the current tasks' proximity to reference task weights in parameter space. To demonstrate the versatility of PEARL, we evaluate it across three vision architectures (ResNet, Separable Convolutional Network and Vision Transformer) and a multitude of CL scenarios, and show that PEARL outperforms all considered baselines by a large margin.</description><author>Prashant Shivaram Bhat, Shakib Yazdani, Elahe Arani, Bahram Zonooz</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:44:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.11998v3</guid></item><item><title>SSL4RL: Revisiting Self-supervised Learning as Intrinsic Reward for Visual-Language Reasoning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.16416v3</link><description>Vision-language models (VLMs) have shown remarkable abilities by integrating large language models with visual inputs. However, they often fail to utilize visual evidence adequately, either depending on linguistic priors in vision-centric tasks or resorting to textual shortcuts during reasoning. Although reinforcement learning (RL) can align models with desired behaviors, its application to VLMs has been hindered by the lack of scalable and reliable reward mechanisms. To overcome this challenge, we propose SSL4RL, a novel framework that leverages self-supervised learning (SSL) tasks as a source of verifiable rewards for RL-based fine-tuning. Our approach reformulates SSL objectives-such as predicting image rotation or reconstructing masked patches-into dense, automatic reward signals, eliminating the need for human preference data or unreliable AI evaluators. Experiments show that SSL4RL substantially improves performance on both vision-centric and vision-language reasoning benchmarks. Furthermore, through systematic ablations, we identify key factors-such as task difficulty, model scale, and semantic alignment with the target domain-that influence the effectiveness of SSL4RL tasks, offering new design principles for future work. We also demonstrate the framework's generality by applying it to graph learning, where it yields significant gains. SSL4RL establishes a versatile and effective paradigm for aligning multimodal models using verifiable, self-supervised objectives.</description><author>Xiaojun Guo, Runyu Zhou, Yifei Wang, Qi Zhang, Chenheng Zhang, Stefanie Jegelka, Xiaohan Wang, Jiajun Chai, Guojun Yin, Wei Lin, Yisen Wang</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:40:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.16416v3</guid></item><item><title>A Unified Framework for EEG Seizure Detection Using Universum-Integrated Generalized Eigenvalues Proximal Support Vector Machine</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21170v1</link><description>The paper presents novel Universum-enhanced classifiers: the Universum Generalized Eigenvalue Proximal Support Vector Machine (U-GEPSVM) and the Improved U-GEPSVM (IU-GEPSVM) for EEG signal classification. Using the computational efficiency of generalized eigenvalue decomposition and the generalization benefits of Universum learning, the proposed models address critical challenges in EEG analysis: non-stationarity, low signal-to-noise ratio, and limited labeled data. U-GEPSVM extends the GEPSVM framework by incorporating Universum constraints through a ratio-based objective function, while IU-GEPSVM enhances stability through a weighted difference-based formulation that provides independent control over class separation and Universum alignment. The models are evaluated on the Bonn University EEG dataset across two binary classification tasks: (O vs S)-healthy (eyes closed) vs seizure, and (Z vs S)-healthy (eyes open) vs seizure. IU-GEPSVM achieves peak accuracies of 85% (O vs S) and 80% (Z vs S), with mean accuracies of 81.29% and 77.57% respectively, outperforming baseline methods.</description><author>Yogesh Kumar, Vrushank Ahire, M. A. Ganaie</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:39:11 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21170v1</guid></item><item><title>Data-regularized Reinforcement Learning for Diffusion Models at Scale</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.04332v3</link><description>Aligning generative diffusion models with human preferences via reinforcement learning (RL) is critical yet challenging. Most existing algorithms are often vulnerable to reward hacking, such as quality degradation, over-stylization, or reduced diversity. Our analysis demonstrates that this can be attributed to the inherent limitations of their regularization, which provides unreliable penalties. We introduce Data-regularized Diffusion Reinforcement Learning (DDRL), a novel framework that uses the forward KL divergence to anchor the policy to an off-policy data distribution. Theoretically, DDRL enables robust, unbiased integration of RL with standard diffusion training. Empirically, this translates into a simple yet effective algorithm that combines reward maximization with diffusion loss minimization. With over a million GPU hours of experiments and ten thousand double-blind human evaluations, we demonstrate on high-resolution video generation tasks that DDRL significantly improves rewards while alleviating the reward hacking seen in baselines, achieving the highest human preference and establishing a robust and scalable paradigm for diffusion post-training.</description><author>Haotian Ye, Kaiwen Zheng, Jiashu Xu, Puheng Li, Huayu Chen, Jiaqi Han, Sheng Liu, Qinsheng Zhang, Hanzi Mao, Zekun Hao, Prithvijit Chattopadhyay, Dinghao Yang, Liang Feng, Maosheng Liao, Junjie Bai, Ming-Yu Liu, James Zou, Stefano Ermon</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:37:40 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.04332v3</guid></item><item><title>A Community-Enhanced Graph Representation Model for Link Prediction</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21166v1</link><description>Although Graph Neural Networks (GNNs) have become the dominant approach for graph representation learning, their performance on link prediction tasks does not always surpass that of traditional heuristic methods such as Common Neighbors and Jaccard Coefficient. This is mainly because existing GNNs tend to focus on learning local node representations, making it difficult to effectively capture structural relationships between node pairs. Furthermore, excessive reliance on local neighborhood information can lead to over-smoothing. Prior studies have shown that introducing global structural encoding can partially alleviate this issue. To address these limitations, we propose a Community-Enhanced Link Prediction (CELP) framework that incorporates community structure to jointly model local and global graph topology. Specifically, CELP enhances the graph via community-aware, confidence-guided edge completion and pruning, while integrating multi-scale structural features to achieve more accurate link prediction. Experimental results across multiple benchmark datasets demonstrate that CELP achieves superior performance, validating the crucial role of community structure in improving link prediction accuracy.</description><author>Lei Wang, Darong Lai</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:31:34 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21166v1</guid></item><item><title>Bootstrapping LLMs via Preference-Based Policy Optimization</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.12867v2</link><description>Bootstrapping large language models (LLMs) through preference-based policy optimization offers a promising direction for aligning model behavior with human preferences without relying on extensive manual annotations. In this work, we propose a novel preference-based policy optimization (PbPO) framework that formulates the learning process as a min-max game between the main policy and a reward model (RM). The RM is constrained within a confidence set derived from preference data to ensure reliable exploitation. Our iterative online algorithm actively collects preference data through guided exploration of the evolving policy, enabling continual self-improvement of both the policy and the RM. We provide theoretical guarantees for our method, establishing high-probability regret bounds for both settings with sequence-level RM and token-level RM, demonstrating its effectiveness in bootstrapping LLMs. Extensive experiments on five benchmarks show that our approach consistently outperforms existing state-of-the-art preference optimization techniques.</description><author>Chen Jia</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:31:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.12867v2</guid></item><item><title>VCB Bench: An Evaluation Benchmark for Audio-Grounded Large Language Model Conversational Agents</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.11098v2</link><description>Recent advances in large audio language models (LALMs) have greatly enhanced multimodal conversational systems. However, existing benchmarks remain limited -- they are mainly English-centric, rely on synthetic speech, and lack comprehensive, discriminative evaluation across multiple dimensions. To address these gaps, we present Voice Chat Bot Bench (VCB Bench) -- a high-quality Chinese benchmark built entirely on real human speech. VCB Bench evaluates LALMs from three complementary perspectives: instruction following (including speech-level control beyond text commands), knowledge understanding (general knowledge, reasoning, and daily dialogue), and robustness (stability under perturbations in content, environment, and speaker traits). Experiments on representative LALMs reveal notable performance gaps and highlight future directions for improvement. VCB Bench provides a reproducible and fine-grained evaluation framework, offering standardized methodology and practical insights for advancing Chinese voice conversational models.</description><author>Jiliang Hu, Wenfu Wang, Zuchao Li, Chenxing Li, Yiyang Zhao, Hanzhao Li, Liqiang Zhang, Meng Yu, Dong Yu</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:27:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.11098v2</guid></item><item><title>BALLAST: Bandit-Assisted Learning for Latency-Aware Stable Timeouts in Raft</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21165v1</link><description>Randomized election timeouts are a simple and effective liveness heuristic for Raft, but they become brittle under long-tail latency, jitter, and partition recovery, where repeated split votes can inflate unavailability. This paper presents BALLAST, a lightweight online adaptation mechanism that replaces static timeout heuristics with contextual bandits. BALLAST selects from a discrete set of timeout "arms" using efficient linear contextual bandits (LinUCB variants), and augments learning with safe exploration to cap risk during unstable periods. We evaluate BALLAST on a reproducible discrete-event simulation with long-tail delay, loss, correlated bursts, node heterogeneity, and partition/recovery turbulence. Across challenging WAN regimes, BALLAST substantially reduces recovery time and unwritable time compared to standard randomized timeouts and common heuristics, while remaining competitive on stable LAN/WAN settings.</description><author>Qizhi Wang</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:25:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21165v1</guid></item><item><title>CAKE: Cascading and Adaptive KV Cache Eviction with Layer Preferences</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.12491v2</link><description>Large language models (LLMs) excel at processing long sequences, boosting demand for key-value (KV) caching. While recent efforts to evict KV cache have alleviated the inference burden, they often fail to allocate resources rationally across layers with different attention patterns. In this paper, we introduce Cascading and Adaptive KV cache Eviction (CAKE), a novel approach that frames KV cache eviction as a "cake-slicing problem." CAKE assesses layer-specific preferences by considering attention dynamics in both spatial and temporal dimensions, allocates rational cache size for layers accordingly, and manages memory constraints in a cascading manner. This approach enables a global view of cache allocation, adaptively distributing resources across diverse attention mechanisms while maintaining memory budgets. CAKE also employs a new eviction indicator that considers the shifting importance of tokens over time, addressing limitations in existing methods that overlook temporal dynamics. Comprehensive experiments on LongBench and NeedleBench show that CAKE maintains model performance with only 3.2% of the KV cache and consistently outperforms current baselines across various models and memory constraints, particularly in low-memory settings. Additionally, CAKE achieves over 10x speedup in decoding latency compared to full cache when processing contexts of 128K tokens with FlashAttention-2. Our code is available at https://github.com/antgroup/cakekv.</description><author>Ziran Qin, Yuchen Cao, Mingbao Lin, Wen Hu, Shixuan Fan, Ke Cheng, Weiyao Lin, Jianguo Li</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:21:40 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.12491v2</guid></item><item><title>A European Multi-Center Breast Cancer MRI Dataset</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.00474v2</link><description>Early detection of breast cancer is critical for improving patient outcomes. While mammography remains the primary screening modality, magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) is increasingly recommended as a supplemental tool for women with dense breast tissue and those at elevated risk. However, the acquisition and interpretation of multiparametric breast MRI are time-consuming and require specialized expertise, limiting scalability in clinical practice. Artificial intelligence (AI) methods have shown promise in supporting breast MRI interpretation, but their development is hindered by the limited availability of large, diverse, and publicly accessible datasets. To address this gap, we present a publicly available, multi-center breast MRI dataset collected across six clinical institutions in five European countries. The dataset comprises 741 examinations from women undergoing screening or diagnostic breast MRI and includes malignant, benign, and non-lesion cases. Data were acquired using heterogeneous scanners, field strengths, and acquisition protocols, reflecting real-world clinical variability. In addition, we report baseline benchmark experiments using a transformer-based model to illustrate potential use cases of the dataset and to provide reference performance for future methodological comparisons.</description><author>Gustav Müller-Franzes, Lorena Escudero Sánchez, Nicholas Payne, Alexandra Athanasiou, Michael Kalogeropoulos, Aitor Lopez, Alfredo Miguel Soro Busto, Julia Camps Herrero, Nika Rasoolzadeh, Tianyu Zhang, Ritse Mann, Debora Jutz, Maike Bode, Christiane Kuhl, Yuan Gao, Wouter Veldhuis, Oliver Lester Saldanha, JieFu Zhu, Jakob Nikolas Kather, Daniel Truhn, Fiona J. Gilbert</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:19:04 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.00474v2</guid></item><item><title>Unbiased Region-Language Alignment for Open-Vocabulary Dense Prediction</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.06244v4</link><description>Pre-trained vision-language models (VLMs), such as CLIP, have demonstrated impressive zero-shot recognition capability, but still underperform in dense prediction tasks. Self-distillation recently is emerging as a promising approach for fine-tuning VLMs to better adapt to local regions without requiring extensive annotations. However, previous state-of-the-art approaches often suffer from significant `foreground bias', where models tend to wrongly identify background regions as foreground objects. To alleviate this issue, we propose DenseVLM, a framework designed to learn unbiased region-language alignment from powerful pre-trained VLM representations. To alleviate this issue, we propose DenseVLM, a framework designed to learn unbiased region-language alignment from powerful pre-trained VLM representations. DenseVLM leverages the pre-trained VLM to retrieve categories for unlabeled regions and then decouples the interference between foreground and background features. We show that DenseVLM can directly replace the original VLM in open-vocabulary object detection and image segmentation methods, leading to notable performance improvements. Furthermore, it exhibits promising zero-shot scalability when training on more extensive and diverse datasets. Our code is available at https://github.com/HVision-NKU/DenseVLM.</description><author>Yunheng Li, Yuxuan Li, Quansheng Zeng, Wenhai Wang, Qibin Hou, Ming-Ming Cheng</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:11:11 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.06244v4</guid></item><item><title>Coherence in the brain unfolds across separable temporal regimes</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20481v2</link><description>Coherence in language requires the brain to satisfy two competing temporal demands: gradual accumulation of meaning across extended context and rapid reconfiguration of representations at event boundaries. Despite their centrality to language and thought, how these processes are implemented in the human brain during naturalistic listening remains unclear. Here, we tested whether these two processes can be captured by annotation-free drift and shift signals and whether their neural expression dissociates across large-scale cortical systems. These signals were derived from a large language model (LLM) and formalized contextual drift and event shifts directly from the narrative input. To enable high-precision voxelwise encoding models with stable parameter estimates, we densely sampled one healthy adult across more than 7 hours of listening to thirteen crime stories while collecting ultra high-field (7T) BOLD data. We then modeled the feature-informed hemodynamic response using a regularized encoding framework validated on independent stories. Drift predictions were prevalent in default-mode network hubs, whereas shift predictions were evident bilaterally in the primary auditory cortex and language association cortex. Furthermore, activity in default-mode and parietal networks was best explained by a signal capturing how meaning accumulates and gradually fades over the course of the narrative. Together, these findings show that coherence during language comprehension is implemented through dissociable neural regimes of slow contextual integration and rapid event-driven reconfiguration, offering a mechanistic entry point for understanding disturbances of language coherence in psychiatric disorders.</description><author>Davide Stauba, Finn Rabe, Akhil Misra, Yves Pauli, Roya Hüppi, Ni Yang, Nils Lang, Lars Michels, Victoria Edkins, Sascha Frühholz, Iris Sommer, Wolfram Hinzen, Philipp Homan</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:51:11 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20481v2</guid></item><item><title>ElfCore: A 28nm Neural Processor Enabling Dynamic Structured Sparse Training and Online Self-Supervised Learning with Activity-Dependent Weight Update</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21153v1</link><description>In this paper, we present ElfCore, a 28nm digital spiking neural network processor tailored for event-driven sensory signal processing. ElfCore is the first to efficiently integrate: (1) a local online self-supervised learning engine that enables multi-layer temporal learning without labeled inputs; (2) a dynamic structured sparse training engine that supports high-accuracy sparse-to-sparse learning; and (3) an activity-dependent sparse weight update mechanism that selectively updates weights based solely on input activity and network dynamics. Demonstrated on tasks including gesture recognition, speech, and biomedical signal processing, ElfCore outperforms state-of-the-art solutions with up to 16X lower power consumption, 3.8X reduced on-chip memory requirements, and 5.9X greater network capacity efficiency.</description><author>Zhe Su, Giacomo Indiveri</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:45:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21153v1</guid></item><item><title>MODE: Multi-Objective Adaptive Coreset Selection</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21152v1</link><description>We present Mode(Multi-Objective adaptive Data Efficiency), a framework that dynamically combines coreset selection strategies based on their evolving contribution to model performance. Unlike static methods, \mode adapts selection criteria to training phases: emphasizing class balance early, diversity during representation learning, and uncertainty at convergence. We show that MODE achieves (1-1/e)-approximation with O(n \log n) complexity and demonstrates competitive accuracy while providing interpretable insights into data utility evolution. Experiments show \mode reduces memory requirements</description><author>Tanmoy Mukherjee, Pierre Marquis, Zied Bouraoui</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:43:40 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21152v1</guid></item><item><title>ORCA: Object Recognition and Comprehension for Archiving Marine Species</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21150v1</link><description>Marine visual understanding is essential for monitoring and protecting marine ecosystems, enabling automatic and scalable biological surveys. However, progress is hindered by limited training data and the lack of a systematic task formulation that aligns domain-specific marine challenges with well-defined computer vision tasks, thereby limiting effective model application. To address this gap, we present ORCA, a multi-modal benchmark for marine research comprising 14,647 images from 478 species, with 42,217 bounding box annotations and 22,321 expert-verified instance captions. The dataset provides fine-grained visual and textual annotations that capture morphology-oriented attributes across diverse marine species. To catalyze methodological advances, we evaluate 18 state-of-the-art models on three tasks: object detection (closed-set and open-vocabulary), instance captioning, and visual grounding. Results highlight key challenges, including species diversity, morphological overlap, and specialized domain demands, underscoring the difficulty of marine understanding. ORCA thus establishes a comprehensive benchmark to advance research in marine domain. Project Page: http://orca.hkustvgd.com/.</description><author>Yuk-Kwan Wong, Haixin Liang, Zeyu Ma, Yiwei Chen, Ziqiang Zheng, Rinaldi Gotama, Pascal Sebastian, Lauren D. Sparks, Sai-Kit Yeung</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:36:57 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21150v1</guid></item><item><title>Intersectional Fairness in Vision-Language Models for Medical Image Disease Classification</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.15249v2</link><description>Medical artificial intelligence (AI) systems, particularly multimodal vision-language models (VLM), often exhibit intersectional biases where models are systematically less confident in diagnosing marginalised patient subgroups. Such bias can lead to higher rates of inaccurate and missed diagnoses due to demographically skewed data and divergent distributions of diagnostic certainty. Current fairness interventions frequently fail to address these gaps or compromise overall diagnostic performance to achieve statistical parity among the subgroups. In this study, we developed Cross-Modal Alignment Consistency (CMAC-MMD), a training framework that standardises diagnostic certainty across intersectional patient subgroups. Unlike traditional debiasing methods, this approach equalises the model's decision confidence without requiring sensitive demographic data during clinical inference. We evaluated this approach using 10,015 skin lesion images (HAM10000) with external validation on 12,000 images (BCN20000), and 10,000 fundus images for glaucoma detection (Harvard-FairVLMed), stratifying performance by intersectional age, gender, and race attributes. In the dermatology cohort, the proposed method reduced the overall intersectional missed diagnosis gap (difference in True Positive Rate, $Δ$TPR) from 0.50 to 0.26 while improving the overall Area Under the Curve (AUC) from 0.94 to 0.97 compared to standard training. Similarly, for glaucoma screening, the method reduced $Δ$TPR from 0.41 to 0.31, achieving a better AUC of 0.72 (vs. 0.71 baseline). This establishes a scalable framework for developing high-stakes clinical decision support systems that are both accurate and can perform equitably across diverse patient subgroups, ensuring reliable performance without increasing privacy risks.</description><author>Yupeng Zhang, Adam G. Dunn, Usman Naseem, Jinman Kim</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:33:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.15249v2</guid></item><item><title>TGC-Net: A Structure-Aware and Semantically-Aligned Framework for Text-Guided Medical Image Segmentation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21135v1</link><description>Text-guided medical segmentation enhances segmentation accuracy by utilizing clinical reports as auxiliary information. However, existing methods typically rely on unaligned image and text encoders, which necessitate complex interaction modules for multimodal fusion. While CLIP provides a pre-aligned multimodal feature space, its direct application to medical imaging is limited by three main issues: insufficient preservation of fine-grained anatomical structures, inadequate modeling of complex clinical descriptions, and domain-specific semantic misalignment. To tackle these challenges, we propose TGC-Net, a CLIP-based framework focusing on parameter-efficient, task-specific adaptations. Specifically, it incorporates a Semantic-Structural Synergy Encoder (SSE) that augments CLIP's ViT with a CNN branch for multi-scale structural refinement, a Domain-Augmented Text Encoder (DATE) that injects large-language-model-derived medical knowledge, and a Vision-Language Calibration Module (VLCM) that refines cross-modal correspondence in a unified feature space. Experiments on five datasets across chest X-ray and thoracic CT modalities demonstrate that TGC-Net achieves state-of-the-art performance with substantially fewer trainable parameters, including notable Dice gains on challenging benchmarks.</description><author>Gaoren Lin, Huangxuan Zhao, Yuan Xiong, Lefei Zhang, Bo Du, Wentao Zhu</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:06:26 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21135v1</guid></item><item><title>AutoBaxBuilder: Bootstrapping Code Security Benchmarking</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21132v1</link><description>As LLMs see wide adoption in software engineering, the reliable assessment of the correctness and security of LLM-generated code is crucial. Notably, prior work has demonstrated that security is often overlooked, exposing that LLMs are prone to generating code with security vulnerabilities. These insights were enabled by specialized benchmarks, crafted through significant manual effort by security experts. However, relying on manually-crafted benchmarks is insufficient in the long term, because benchmarks (i) naturally end up contaminating training data, (ii) must extend to new tasks to provide a more complete picture, and (iii) must increase in difficulty to challenge more capable LLMs. In this work, we address these challenges and present AutoBaxBuilder, a framework that generates tasks and tests for code security benchmarking from scratch. We introduce a robust pipeline with fine-grained plausibility checks, leveraging the code understanding capabilities of LLMs to construct functionality tests and end-to-end security-probing exploits. To confirm the quality of the generated benchmark, we conduct both a qualitative analysis and perform quantitative experiments, comparing it against tasks constructed by human experts. We use AutoBaxBuilder to construct entirely new tasks and release them to the public as AutoBaxBench, together with a thorough evaluation of the security capabilities of LLMs on these tasks. We find that a new task can be generated in under 2 hours, costing less than USD 10.</description><author>Tobias von Arx, Niels Mündler, Mark Vero, Maximilian Baader, Martin Vechev</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:02:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21132v1</guid></item><item><title>Active inference and artificial reasoning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21129v1</link><description>This technical note considers the sampling of outcomes that provide the greatest amount of information about the structure of underlying world models. This generalisation furnishes a principled approach to structure learning under a plausible set of generative models or hypotheses. In active inference, policies - i.e., combinations of actions - are selected based on their expected free energy, which comprises expected information gain and value. Information gain corresponds to the KL divergence between predictive posteriors with, and without, the consequences of action. Posteriors over models can be evaluated quickly and efficiently using Bayesian Model Reduction, based upon accumulated posterior beliefs about model parameters. The ensuing information gain can then be used to select actions that disambiguate among alternative models, in the spirit of optimal experimental design. We illustrate this kind of active selection or reasoning using partially observed discrete models; namely, a 'three-ball' paradigm used previously to describe artificial insight and 'aha moments' via (synthetic) introspection or sleep. We focus on the sample efficiency afforded by seeking outcomes that resolve the greatest uncertainty about the world model, under which outcomes are generated.</description><author>Karl Friston, Lancelot Da Costa, Alexander Tschantz, Conor Heins, Christopher Buckley, Tim Verbelen, Thomas Parr</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 11:59:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21129v1</guid></item><item><title>A Real-World Evaluation of LLM Medication Safety Reviews in NHS Primary Care</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21127v1</link><description>Large language models (LLMs) often match or exceed clinician-level performance on medical benchmarks, yet very few are evaluated on real clinical data or examined beyond headline metrics. We present, to our knowledge, the first evaluation of an LLM-based medication safety review system on real NHS primary care data, with detailed characterisation of key failure behaviours across varying levels of clinical complexity. In a retrospective study using a population-scale EHR spanning 2,125,549 adults in NHS Cheshire and Merseyside, we strategically sampled patients to capture a broad range of clinical complexity and medication safety risk, yielding 277 patients after data-quality exclusions. An expert clinician reviewed these patients and graded system-identified issues and proposed interventions. Our primary LLM system showed strong performance in recognising when a clinical issue is present (sensitivity 100\% [95\% CI 98.2--100], specificity 83.1\% [95\% CI 72.7--90.1]), yet correctly identified all issues and interventions in only 46.9\% [95\% CI 41.1--52.8] of patients. Failure analysis reveals that, in this setting, the dominant failure mechanism is contextual reasoning rather than missing medication knowledge, with five primary patterns: overconfidence in uncertainty, applying standard guidelines without adjusting for patient context, misunderstanding how healthcare is delivered in practice, factual errors, and process blindness. These patterns persisted across patient complexity and demographic strata, and across a range of state-of-the-art models and configurations. We provide 45 detailed vignettes that comprehensively cover all identified failure cases. This work highlights shortcomings that must be addressed before LLM-based clinical AI can be safely deployed. It also begs larger-scale, prospective evaluations and deeper study of LLM behaviours in clinical contexts.</description><author>Oliver Normand, Esther Borsi, Mitch Fruin, Lauren E Walker, Jamie Heagerty, Chris C. Holmes, Anthony J Avery, Iain E Buchan, Harry Coppock</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 11:58:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21127v1</guid></item><item><title>MarineEval: Assessing the Marine Intelligence of Vision-Language Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21126v1</link><description>We have witnessed promising progress led by large language models (LLMs) and further vision language models (VLMs) in handling various queries as a general-purpose assistant. VLMs, as a bridge to connect the visual world and language corpus, receive both visual content and various text-only user instructions to generate corresponding responses. Though great success has been achieved by VLMs in various fields, in this work, we ask whether the existing VLMs can act as domain experts, accurately answering marine questions, which require significant domain expertise and address special domain challenges/requirements. To comprehensively evaluate the effectiveness and explore the boundary of existing VLMs, we construct the first large-scale marine VLM dataset and benchmark called MarineEval, with 2,000 image-based question-answering pairs. During our dataset construction, we ensure the diversity and coverage of the constructed data: 7 task dimensions and 20 capacity dimensions. The domain requirements are specially integrated into the data construction and further verified by the corresponding marine domain experts. We comprehensively benchmark 17 existing VLMs on our MarineEval and also investigate the limitations of existing models in answering marine research questions. The experimental results reveal that existing VLMs cannot effectively answer the domain-specific questions, and there is still a large room for further performance improvements. We hope our new benchmark and observations will facilitate future research. Project Page: http://marineeval.hkustvgd.com/</description><author>YuK-Kwan Wong, Tuan-An To, Jipeng Zhang, Ziqiang Zheng, Sai-Kit Yeung</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 11:57:50 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21126v1</guid></item><item><title>AD-R1: Closed-Loop Reinforcement Learning for End-to-End Autonomous Driving with Impartial World Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.20325v2</link><description>End-to-end models for autonomous driving hold the promise of learning complex behaviors directly from sensor data, but face critical challenges in safety and handling long-tail events. Reinforcement Learning (RL) offers a promising path to overcome these limitations, yet its success in autonomous driving has been elusive. We identify a fundamental flaw hindering this progress: a deep seated optimistic bias in the world models used for RL. To address this, we introduce a framework for post-training policy refinement built around an Impartial World Model. Our primary contribution is to teach this model to be honest about danger. We achieve this with a novel data synthesis pipeline, Counterfactual Synthesis, which systematically generates a rich curriculum of plausible collisions and off-road events. This transforms the model from a passive scene completer into a veridical forecaster that remains faithful to the causal link between actions and outcomes. We then integrate this Impartial World Model into our closed-loop RL framework, where it serves as an internal critic. During refinement, the agent queries the critic to ``dream" of the outcomes for candidate actions. We demonstrate through extensive experiments, including on a new Risk Foreseeing Benchmark, that our model significantly outperforms baselines in predicting failures. Consequently, when used as a critic, it enables a substantial reduction in safety violations in challenging simulations, proving that teaching a model to dream of danger is a critical step towards building truly safe and intelligent autonomous agents.</description><author>Tianyi Yan, Tao Tang, Xingtai Gui, Yongkang Li, Jiasen Zhesng, Weiyao Huang, Lingdong Kong, Wencheng Han, Xia Zhou, Xueyang Zhang, Yifei Zhan, Kun Zhan, Cheng-zhong Xu, Jianbing Shen</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 11:56:26 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.20325v2</guid></item><item><title>Automated Modeling Method for Pathloss Model Discovery</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.23383v3</link><description>Modeling propagation is the cornerstone for designing and optimizing next-generation wireless systems, with a particular emphasis on 5G and beyond era. Traditional modeling methods have long relied on statistic-based techniques to characterize propagation behavior across different environments. With the expansion of wireless communication systems, there is a growing demand for methods that guarantee the accuracy and interpretability of modeling. Artificial intelligence (AI)-based techniques, in particular, are increasingly being adopted to overcome this challenge, although the interpretability is not assured with most of these methods. Inspired by recent advancements in AI, this paper proposes a novel approach that accelerates the discovery of path loss models while maintaining interpretability. The proposed method automates the formulation, evaluation, and refinement of the model, facilitating the discovery of the model. We examine two techniques: one based on Deep Symbolic Regression, offering full interpretability, and the second based on Kolmogorov-Arnold Networks, providing two levels of interpretability. Both approaches are evaluated on two synthetic and two real-world datasets. Our results show that Kolmogorov-Arnold Networks achieve the coefficient of determination value R^2 close to 1 with minimal prediction error, while Deep Symbolic Regression generates compact models with moderate accuracy. Moreover, on the selected examples, we demonstrate that automated methods outperform traditional methods, achieving up to 75% reduction in prediction errors, offering accurate and explainable solutions with potential to increase the efficiency of discovering next-generation path loss models.</description><author>Ahmad Anaqreh, Shih-Kai Chou, Mihael Mohorčič, Thomas Lagkas, Carolina Fortuna</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 11:43:45 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.23383v3</guid></item><item><title>SemanticGen: Video Generation in Semantic Space</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20619v2</link><description>State-of-the-art video generative models typically learn the distribution of video latents in the VAE space and map them to pixels using a VAE decoder. While this approach can generate high-quality videos, it suffers from slow convergence and is computationally expensive when generating long videos. In this paper, we introduce SemanticGen, a novel solution to address these limitations by generating videos in the semantic space. Our main insight is that, due to the inherent redundancy in videos, the generation process should begin in a compact, high-level semantic space for global planning, followed by the addition of high-frequency details, rather than directly modeling a vast set of low-level video tokens using bi-directional attention. SemanticGen adopts a two-stage generation process. In the first stage, a diffusion model generates compact semantic video features, which define the global layout of the video. In the second stage, another diffusion model generates VAE latents conditioned on these semantic features to produce the final output. We observe that generation in the semantic space leads to faster convergence compared to the VAE latent space. Our method is also effective and computationally efficient when extended to long video generation. Extensive experiments demonstrate that SemanticGen produces high-quality videos and outperforms state-of-the-art approaches and strong baselines.</description><author>Jianhong Bai, Xiaoshi Wu, Xintao Wang, Xiao Fu, Yuanxing Zhang, Qinghe Wang, Xiaoyu Shi, Menghan Xia, Zuozhu Liu, Haoji Hu, Pengfei Wan, Kun Gai</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 11:39:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.20619v2</guid></item><item><title>ClarifyMT-Bench: Benchmarking and Improving Multi-Turn Clarification for Conversational Large Language Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21120v1</link><description>Large language models (LLMs) are increasingly deployed as conversational assistants in open-domain, multi-turn settings, where users often provide incomplete or ambiguous information. However, existing LLM-focused clarification benchmarks primarily assume single-turn interactions or cooperative users, limiting their ability to evaluate clarification behavior in realistic settings. We introduce \textbf{ClarifyMT-Bench}, a benchmark for multi-turn clarification grounded in a five-dimensional ambiguity taxonomy and a set of six behaviorally diverse simulated user personas. Through a hybrid LLM-human pipeline, we construct 6,120 multi-turn dialogues capturing diverse ambiguity sources and interaction patterns. Evaluating ten representative LLMs uncovers a consistent under-clarification bias: LLMs tend to answer prematurely, and performance degrades as dialogue depth increases. To mitigate this, we propose \textbf{ClarifyAgent}, an agentic approach that decomposes clarification into perception, forecasting, tracking, and planning, substantially improving robustness across ambiguity conditions. ClarifyMT-Bench establishes a reproducible foundation for studying when LLMs should ask, when they should answer, and how to navigate ambiguity in real-world human-LLM interactions.</description><author>Sichun Luo, Yi Huang, Mukai Li, Shichang Meng, Fengyuan Liu, Zefa Hu, Junlan Feng, Qi Liu</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 11:39:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21120v1</guid></item><item><title>STLDM: Spatio-Temporal Latent Diffusion Model for Precipitation Nowcasting</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21118v1</link><description>Precipitation nowcasting is a critical spatio-temporal prediction task for society to prevent severe damage owing to extreme weather events. Despite the advances in this field, the complex and stochastic nature of this task still poses challenges to existing approaches. Specifically, deterministic models tend to produce blurry predictions while generative models often struggle with poor accuracy. In this paper, we present a simple yet effective model architecture termed STLDM, a diffusion-based model that learns the latent representation from end to end alongside both the Variational Autoencoder and the conditioning network. STLDM decomposes this task into two stages: a deterministic forecasting stage handled by the conditioning network, and an enhancement stage performed by the latent diffusion model. Experimental results on multiple radar datasets demonstrate that STLDM achieves superior performance compared to the state of the art, while also improving inference efficiency. The code is available in https://github.com/sqfoo/stldm_official.</description><author>Shi Quan Foo, Chi-Ho Wong, Zhihan Gao, Dit-Yan Yeung, Ka-Hing Wong, Wai-Kin Wong</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 11:34:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.21118v1</guid></item><item><title>Sequence to Sequence Reward Modeling: Improving RLHF by Language Feedback</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.00162v2</link><description>Aligning the behavior of Large language models (LLMs) with human intentions and values remains a critical challenge. Reinforcement learning from human feedback (RLHF) aligns LLMs by training a reward model (RM) on human preferences and fine-tuning the LLMs to maximize RM feedback. Despite its effectiveness and popularity, RLHF is prone to biased local optimization. It means RM fails to provide feedback that accurately aligns with human preference, causing LLMs to explore unexpected generalizations, and failing to achieve alignment objectives. To mitigate this issue, we propose a novel \textit{sequence-to-sequence (seq2seq) reward modeling} method. Its key insight is that learning from language feedback rather than scalar feedback improves RLHF without additional annotations. We replaced the reward modeling target from binary maximum likelihood estimation (MLE) with sequence MLE. This method enables richer and fine-grained language feedback without additional annotations, models, or training stages. Our experiments demonstrated its effectiveness, specifically, reducing the refusal-to-response paradigm in single-turn safety dialogues and the long-response bias in text summarization tasks. We provide further analysis that seq2seq RM improves RLHF performance across 2B and 7B LLMs on 3 NLP tasks, achieving an average win rate of 76.9\%. We further show that seq2seq RM can still improve the performance of RLHF under out-of-distribution prompts.</description><author>Jiayi Zhou, Jiaming Ji, Juntao Dai, Dong Li, Yaodong Yang</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 11:32:24 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.00162v2</guid></item><item><title>Beyond Consensus: Mitigating the Agreeableness Bias in LLM Judge Evaluations</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.11822v2</link><description>New Large Language Models (LLMs) become available every few weeks, and modern application developers confronted with the unenviable task of having to decide if they should switch to a new model. While human evaluation remains the gold standard, it is costly and unscalable. The state-of-the-art approach is to use LLMs as evaluators ( LLM-as-a-judge), but this suffers from a critical flaw: LLMs exhibit a strong positive bias. We provide empirical evidence showing that while LLMs can identify valid outputs with high accuracy (i.e., True Positive Rate 96%), they are remarkably poor at identifying invalid ones (i.e., True Negative Rate &lt;25%). This systematic bias, coupled with class imbalance, often leads to inflated reliability scores. While ensemble-based methods like majority voting can help, we show that they are not good enough. We introduce an optimal minority-veto strategy that is resilient to missing data and mitigates this bias to a large extent. For scenarios requiring even higher precision, we propose a novel regression-based framework that directly models the validator bias using a small set of human-annotated ground truth data. On a challenging code feedback task over 366 high-school Python programs, our regression approach reduces the maximum absolute error to just 1.2%, achieving a 2x improvement over the best-performing ensemble of 14 state-of-the-art LLMs.</description><author>Suryaansh Jain, Umair Z. Ahmed, Shubham Sahai, Ben Leong</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 11:22:59 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.11822v2</guid></item></channel></rss>