<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Arxivfresh papers</title><link></link><description>Arxiv paper</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:00:53 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.0.0</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Native 3D Editing with Full Attention</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17501v1</link><description>Instruction-guided 3D editing is a rapidly emerging field with the potential to broaden access to 3D content creation. However, existing methods face critical limitations: optimization-based approaches are prohibitively slow, while feed-forward approaches relying on multi-view 2D editing often suffer from inconsistent geometry and degraded visual quality. To address these issues, we propose a novel native 3D editing framework that directly manipulates 3D representations in a single, efficient feed-forward pass. Specifically, we create a large-scale, multi-modal dataset for instruction-guided 3D editing, covering diverse addition, deletion, and modification tasks. This dataset is meticulously curated to ensure that edited objects faithfully adhere to the instructional changes while preserving the consistency of unedited regions with the source object. Building upon this dataset, we explore two distinct conditioning strategies for our model: a conventional cross-attention mechanism and a novel 3D token concatenation approach. Our results demonstrate that token concatenation is more parameter-efficient and achieves superior performance. Extensive evaluations show that our method outperforms existing 2D-lifting approaches, setting a new benchmark in generation quality, 3D consistency, and instruction fidelity.</description><author>Weiwei Cai, Shuangkang Fang, Weicai Ye, Xin Dong, Yunhan Yang, Xuanyang Zhang, Wei Cheng, Yanpei Cao, Gang Yu, Tao Chen</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:59:26 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17501v1</guid></item><item><title>The Loss of Control Playbook: Degrees, Dynamics, and Preparedness</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.15846v2</link><description>This research report addresses the absence of an actionable definition for Loss of Control (LoC) in AI systems by developing a novel taxonomy and preparedness framework. Despite increasing policy and research attention, existing LoC definitions vary significantly in scope and timeline, hindering effective LoC assessment and mitigation. To address this issue, we draw from an extensive literature review and propose a graded LoC taxonomy, based on the metrics of severity and persistence, that distinguishes between Deviation, Bounded LoC, and Strict LoC. We model pathways toward a societal state of vulnerability in which sufficiently advanced AI systems have acquired or could acquire the means to cause Bounded or Strict LoC once a catalyst, either misalignment or pure malfunction, materializes. We argue that this state becomes increasingly likely over time, absent strategic intervention, and propose a strategy to avoid reaching a state of vulnerability. Rather than focusing solely on intervening on AI capabilities and propensities potentially relevant for LoC or on preventing potential catalysts, we introduce a complementary framework that emphasizes three extrinsic factors: Deployment context, Affordances, and Permissions (the DAP framework). Compared to work on intrinsic factors and catalysts, this framework has the unfair advantage of being actionable today. Finally, we put forward a plan to maintain preparedness and prevent the occurrence of LoC outcomes should a state of societal vulnerability be reached, focusing on governance measures (threat modeling, deployment policies, emergency response) and technical controls (pre-deployment testing, control measures, monitoring) that could maintain a condition of perennial suspension.</description><author>Charlotte Stix, Annika Hallensleben, Alejandro Ortega, Matteo Pistillo</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:53:03 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.15846v2</guid></item><item><title>EvDiff: High Quality Video with an Event Camera</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17492v1</link><description>As neuromorphic sensors, event cameras asynchronously record changes in brightness as streams of sparse events with the advantages of high temporal resolution and high dynamic range. Reconstructing intensity images from events is a highly ill-posed task due to the inherent ambiguity of absolute brightness. Early methods generally follow an end-to-end regression paradigm, directly mapping events to intensity frames in a deterministic manner. While effective to some extent, these approaches often yield perceptually inferior results and struggle to scale up in model capacity and training data. In this work, we propose EvDiff, an event-based diffusion model that follows a surrogate training framework to produce high-quality videos. To reduce the heavy computational cost of high-frame-rate video generation, we design an event-based diffusion model that performs only a single forward diffusion step, equipped with a temporally consistent EvEncoder. Furthermore, our novel Surrogate Training Framework eliminates the dependence on paired event-image datasets, allowing the model to leverage large-scale image datasets for higher capacity. The proposed EvDiff is capable of generating high-quality colorful videos solely from monochromatic event streams. Experiments on real-world datasets demonstrate that our method strikes a sweet spot between fidelity and realism, outperforming existing approaches on both pixel-level and perceptual metrics.</description><author>Weilun Li, Lei Sun, Ruixi Gao, Qi Jiang, Yuqin Ma, Kaiwei Wang, Ming-Hsuan Yang, Luc Van Gool, Danda Pani Paudel</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:49:18 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17492v1</guid></item><item><title>Video-R4: Reinforcing Text-Rich Video Reasoning with Visual Rumination</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17490v1</link><description>Understanding text-rich videos requires reading small, transient textual cues that often demand repeated inspection. Yet most video QA models rely on single-pass perception over fixed frames, leading to hallucinations and failures on fine-grained evidence. Inspired by how humans pause, zoom, and re-read critical regions, we introduce Video-R4 (Reinforcing Text-Rich Video Reasoning with Visual Rumination), a video reasoning LMM that performs visual rumination: iteratively selecting frames, zooming into informative regions, re-encoding retrieved pixels, and updating its reasoning state. We construct two datasets with executable rumination trajectories: Video-R4-CoT-17k for supervised practice and Video-R4-RL-30k for reinforcement learning. We propose a multi-stage rumination learning framework that progressively finetunes a 7B LMM to learn atomic and mixing visual operations via SFT and GRPO-based RL. Video-R4-7B achieves state-of-the-art results on M4-ViteVQA and further generalizes to multi-page document QA, slides QA, and generic video QA, demonstrating that iterative rumination is an effective paradigm for pixel-grounded multimodal reasoning.</description><author>Yolo Yunlong Tang, Daiki Shimada, Hang Hua, Chao Huang, Jing Bi, Rogerio Feris, Chenliang Xu</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:47:09 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17490v1</guid></item><item><title>Harnessing Data from Clustered LQR Systems: Personalized and Collaborative Policy Optimization</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17489v1</link><description>It is known that reinforcement learning (RL) is data-hungry. To improve sample-efficiency of RL, it has been proposed that the learning algorithm utilize data from 'approximately similar' processes. However, since the process models are unknown, identifying which other processes are similar poses a challenge. In this work, we study this problem in the context of the benchmark Linear Quadratic Regulator (LQR) setting. Specifically, we consider a setting with multiple agents, each corresponding to a copy of a linear process to be controlled. The agents' local processes can be partitioned into clusters based on similarities in dynamics and tasks. Combining ideas from sequential elimination and zeroth-order policy optimization, we propose a new algorithm that performs simultaneous clustering and learning to output a personalized policy (controller) for each cluster. Under a suitable notion of cluster separation that captures differences in closed-loop performance across systems, we prove that our approach guarantees correct clustering with high probability. Furthermore, we show that the sub-optimality gap of the policy learned for each cluster scales inversely with the size of the cluster, with no additional bias, unlike in prior works on collaborative learning-based control. Our work is the first to reveal how clustering can be used in data-driven control to learn personalized policies that enjoy statistical gains from collaboration but do not suffer sub-optimality due to inclusion of data from dissimilar processes. From a distributed implementation perspective, our method is attractive as it incurs only a mild logarithmic communication overhead.</description><author>Vinay Kanakeri, Shivam Bajaj, Ashwin Verma, Vijay Gupta, Aritra Mitra</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:45:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17489v1</guid></item><item><title>Downscaling Intelligence: Exploring Perception and Reasoning Bottlenecks in Small Multimodal Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17487v1</link><description>Scaling up multimodal models has enabled remarkable advances in visual understanding and reasoning, but practical demands call for smaller, efficient systems. In this work, we conduct a principled analysis of downscaling intelligence in multimodal models, examining how reduced large language model (LLM) capacity affects multimodal capabilities. Our initial findings reveal an interesting trend: LLM downscaling disproportionately affects visual capabilities, rather than abilities inherited from the LLM. We then examine whether this drop mainly reflects the expected decline in visual reasoning or a more fundamental loss of perceptual abilities. Isolating the effect of LLM downscaling on perception, we find performance still drops sharply, often matching or exceeding the impact on reasoning. To address this bottleneck, we introduce visual extraction tuning, which explicitly trains the model to extract instruction-relevant visual details consistently across tasks. With these extracted visual details, we then apply step-by-step reasoning to generate answers. Together, these components form our Extract+Think approach, setting a new standard for efficiency and performance in this space.</description><author>Mark Endo, Serena Yeung-Levy</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:43:01 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17487v1</guid></item><item><title>Generalizable Radio-Frequency Radiance Fields for Spatial Spectrum Synthesis</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.05708v2</link><description>We present GRaF, Generalizable Radio-Frequency (RF) Radiance Fields, a framework that models RF signal propagation to synthesize spatial spectra at arbitrary transmitter or receiver locations, where each spectrum measures signal power across all surrounding directions at the receiver. Unlike state-of-the-art methods that adapt vanilla Neural Radiance Fields (NeRF) to the RF domain with scene-specific training, GRaF generalizes across scenes to synthesize spectra. To enable this, we prove an interpolation theory in the RF domain: the spatial spectrum from a transmitter can be approximated using spectra from geographically proximate transmitters. Building on this theory, GRaF comprises two components: (i) a geometry-aware Transformer encoder that captures spatial correlations from neighboring transmitters to learn a scene-independent latent RF radiance field, and (ii) a neural ray tracing algorithm that estimates spectrum reception at the receiver. Experimental results demonstrate that GRaF outperforms existing methods on single-scene benchmarks and achieves state-of-the-art performance on unseen scene layouts.</description><author>Kang Yang, Yuning Chen, Wan Du</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:40:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.05708v2</guid></item><item><title>An Artificial Intelligence Framework for Measuring Human Spine Aging Using MRI</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17485v1</link><description>The human spine is a complex structure composed of 33 vertebrae. It holds the body and is important for leading a healthy life. The spine is vulnerable to age-related degenerations that can be identified through magnetic resonance imaging (MRI). In this paper we propose a novel computer-vison-based deep learning method to estimate spine age using images from over 18,000 MRI series. Data are restricted to subjects with only age-related spine degeneration. Eligibility criteria are created by identifying common age-based clusters of degenerative spine conditions using uniform manifold approximation and projection (UMAP) and hierarchical density-based spatial clustering of applications with noise (HDBSCAN). Model selection is determined using a detailed ablation study on data size, loss, and the effect of different spine regions. We evaluate the clinical utility of our model by calculating the difference between actual spine age and model-predicted age, the spine age gap (SAG), and examining the association between these differences and spine degenerative conditions and lifestyle factors. We find that SAG is associated with conditions including disc bulges, disc osteophytes, spinal stenosis, and fractures, as well as lifestyle factors like smoking and physically demanding work, and thus may be a useful biomarker for measuring overall spine health.</description><author>Roozbeh Bazargani, Saqib Abdullah Basar, Daniel Daly-Grafstein, Rodrigo Solis Pompa, Soojin Lee, Saurabh Garg, Yuntong Ma, John A. Carrino, Siavash Khallaghi, Sam Hashemi</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:40:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17485v1</guid></item><item><title>Radar2Shape: 3D Shape Reconstruction from High-Frequency Radar using Multiresolution Signed Distance Functions</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17484v1</link><description>Determining the shape of 3D objects from high-frequency radar signals is analytically complex but critical for commercial and aerospace applications. Previous deep learning methods have been applied to radar modeling; however, they often fail to represent arbitrary shapes or have difficulty with real-world radar signals which are collected over limited viewing angles. Existing methods in optical 3D reconstruction can generate arbitrary shapes from limited camera views, but struggle when they naively treat the radar signal as a camera view. In this work, we present Radar2Shape, a denoising diffusion model that handles a partially observable radar signal for 3D reconstruction by correlating its frequencies with multiresolution shape features. Our method consists of a two-stage approach: first, Radar2Shape learns a regularized latent space with hierarchical resolutions of shape features, and second, it diffuses into this latent space by conditioning on the frequencies of the radar signal in an analogous coarse-to-fine manner. We demonstrate that Radar2Shape can successfully reconstruct arbitrary 3D shapes even from partially-observed radar signals, and we show robust generalization to two different simulation methods and real-world data. Additionally, we release two synthetic benchmark datasets to encourage future research in the high-frequency radar domain so that models like Radar2Shape can safely be adapted into real-world radar systems.</description><author>Neel Sortur, Justin Goodwin, Purvik Patel, Luis Enrique Martinez, Tzofi Klinghoffer, Rajmonda S. Caceres, Robin Walters</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:40:03 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17484v1</guid></item><item><title>Counterfactual World Models via Digital Twin-conditioned Video Diffusion</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17481v1</link><description>World models learn to predict the temporal evolution of visual observations given a control signal, potentially enabling agents to reason about environments through forward simulation. Because of the focus on forward simulation, current world models generate predictions based on factual observations. For many emerging applications, such as comprehensive evaluations of physical AI behavior under varying conditions, the ability of world models to answer counterfactual queries, such as "what would happen if this object was removed?", is of increasing importance. We formalize counterfactual world models that additionally take interventions as explicit inputs, predicting temporal sequences under hypothetical modifications to observed scene properties. Traditional world models operate directly on entangled pixel-space representations where object properties and relationships cannot be selectively modified. This modeling choice prevents targeted interventions on specific scene properties. We introduce CWMDT, a framework to overcome those limitations, turning standard video diffusion models into effective counterfactual world models. First, CWMDT constructs digital twins of observed scenes to explicitly encode objects and their relationships, represented as structured text. Second, CWMDT applies large language models to reason over these representations and predict how a counterfactual intervention propagates through time to alter the observed scene. Third, CWMDT conditions a video diffusion model with the modified representation to generate counterfactual visual sequences. Evaluations on two benchmarks show that the CWMDT approach achieves state-of-the-art performance, suggesting that alternative representations of videos, such as the digital twins considered here, offer powerful control signals for video forward simulation-based world models.</description><author>Yiqing Shen, Aiza Maksutova, Chenjia Li, Mathias Unberath</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:37:23 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17481v1</guid></item><item><title>ID-Crafter: VLM-Grounded Online RL for Compositional Multi-Subject Video Generation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.00511v3</link><description>Significant progress has been achieved in high-fidelity video synthesis, yet current paradigms often fall short in effectively integrating identity information from multiple subjects. This leads to semantic conflicts and suboptimal performance in preserving identities and interactions, limiting controllability and applicability. To tackle this issue, we introduce ID-Crafter, a framework for multi-subject video generation that achieves superior identity preservation and semantic coherence. ID-Crafter integrates three key components: (i) a hierarchical identity-preserving attention mechanism that progressively aggregates features at intra-subject, inter-subject, and cross-modal levels; (ii) a semantic understanding module powered by a pretrained Vision-Language Model (VLM) to provide fine-grained guidance and capture complex inter-subject relationships; and (iii) an online reinforcement learning phase to further refine the model for critical concepts. Furthermore, we construct a new dataset to facilitate robust training and evaluation. Extensive experiments demonstrate that ID-Crafter establishes new state-of-the-art performance on multi-subject video generation benchmarks, excelling in identity preservation, temporal consistency, and overall video quality.</description><author>Panwang Pan, Jingjing Zhao, Yuchen Lin, Chenguo Lin, Chenxin Li, Hengyu Liu, Tingting Shen, Yadong MU</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:35:34 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.00511v3</guid></item><item><title>SoK: Security Evaluation of Wi-Fi CSI Biometrics: Attacks, Metrics, and Open Challenges</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.11381v2</link><description>Wi-Fi Channel State Information (CSI) has been repeatedly proposed as a biometric modality, often with reports of high accuracy and operational feasibility. However, the field lacks a consolidated understanding of its security properties, adversarial resilience, and methodological consistency. This Systematization of Knowledge (SoK) examines CSI-based biometric authentication through a security lens, analyzing how existing works diverge in sensing infrastructure, signal representations, feature pipelines, learning models, and evaluation methodologies. Our synthesis reveals systemic inconsistencies: reliance on aggregate accuracy metrics, limited reporting of FAR/FRR/EER, absence of per-user risk analysis, and scarce consideration of threat models or adversarial feasibility. To this end, we construct a unified evaluation framework to expose these issues empirically and demonstrate how security-relevant metrics such as per-class EER, Frequency Count of Scores (FCS), and the Gini Coefficient uncover risk concentration that remains hidden under traditional reporting practices. The resulting analysis highlights concrete attack surfaces--including replay, geometric mimicry, and environmental perturbation--and shows how methodological choices materially influence vulnerability profiles. Based on these findings, we articulate the security boundaries of current CSI biometrics and provide guidelines for rigorous evaluation, reproducible experimentation, and future research directions. This SoK offers the security community a structured, evidence-driven reassessment of Wi-Fi CSI biometrics and their suitability as an authentication primitive.</description><author>Gioliano de Oliveira Braga, Pedro Henrique dos Santos Rocha, Rafael Pimenta de Mattos Paixão, Giovani Hoff da Costa, Gustavo Cavalcanti Morais, Lourenço Alves Pereira Júnior</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:34:04 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.11381v2</guid></item><item><title>YOLO Meets Mixture-of-Experts: Adaptive Expert Routing for Robust Object Detection</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.13344v3</link><description>This paper presents a novel Mixture-of-Experts framework for object detection, incorporating adaptive routing among multiple YOLOv9-T experts to enable dynamic feature specialization and achieve higher mean Average Precision (mAP) and Average Recall (AR) compared to a single YOLOv9-T model.</description><author>Ori Meiraz, Sharon Shalev, Avishai Weizman</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:33:16 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.13344v3</guid></item><item><title>MF-GCN: A Multi-Frequency Graph Convolutional Network for Tri-Modal Depression Detection Using Eye-Tracking, Facial, and Acoustic Features</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.15675v2</link><description>Depression is a prevalent global mental health disorder, characterised by persistent low mood and anhedonia. However, it remains underdiagnosed because current diagnostic methods depend heavily on subjective clinical assessments. To enable objective detection, we introduce a gold standard dataset of 103 clinically assessed participants collected through a tripartite data approach which uniquely integrated eye tracking data with audio and video to give a comprehensive representation of depressive symptoms. Eye tracking data quantifies the attentional bias towards negative stimuli that is frequently observed in depressed groups. Audio and video data capture the affective flattening and psychomotor retardation characteristic of depression. Statistical validation confirmed their significant discriminative power in distinguishing depressed from non depressed groups. We address a critical limitation of existing graph-based models that focus on low-frequency information and propose a Multi-Frequency Graph Convolutional Network (MF-GCN). This framework consists of a novel Multi-Frequency Filter Bank Module (MFFBM), which can leverage both low and high frequency signals. Extensive evaluation against traditional machine learning algorithms and deep learning frameworks demonstrates that MF-GCN consistently outperforms baselines. In binary classification, the model achieved a sensitivity of 0.96 and F2 score of 0.94. For the 3 class classification task, the proposed method achieved a sensitivity of 0.79 and specificity of 0.87 and siginificantly suprassed other models. To validate generalizability, the model was also evaluated on the Chinese Multimodal Depression Corpus (CMDC) dataset and achieved a sensitivity of 0.95 and F2 score of 0.96. These results confirm that our trimodal, multi frequency framework effectively captures cross modal interaction for accurate depression detection.</description><author>Sejuti Rahman, Swakshar Deb, MD. Sameer Iqbal Chowdhury, MD. Jubair Ahmed Sourov, Mohammad Shamsuddin</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:28:30 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.15675v2</guid></item><item><title>Enhancing Quranic Learning: A Multimodal Deep Learning Approach for Arabic Phoneme Recognition</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17477v1</link><description>Recent advances in multimodal deep learning have greatly enhanced the capability of systems for speech analysis and pronunciation assessment. Accurate pronunciation detection remains a key challenge in Arabic, particularly in the context of Quranic recitation, where subtle phonetic differences can alter meaning. Addressing this challenge, the present study proposes a transformer-based multimodal framework for Arabic phoneme mispronunciation detection that combines acoustic and textual representations to achieve higher precision and robustness. The framework integrates UniSpeech-derived acoustic embeddings with BERT-based textual embeddings extracted from Whisper transcriptions, creating a unified representation that captures both phonetic detail and linguistic context. To determine the most effective integration strategy, early, intermediate, and late fusion methods were implemented and evaluated on two datasets containing 29 Arabic phonemes, including eight hafiz sounds, articulated by 11 native speakers. Additional speech samples collected from publicly available YouTube recordings were incorporated to enhance data diversity and generalization. Model performance was assessed using standard evaluation metrics: accuracy, precision, recall, and F1-score, allowing a detailed comparison of the fusion strategies. Experimental findings show that the UniSpeech-BERT multimodal configuration provides strong results and that fusion-based transformer architectures are effective for phoneme-level mispronunciation detection. The study contributes to the development of intelligent, speaker-independent, and multimodal Computer-Aided Language Learning (CALL) systems, offering a practical step toward technology-supported Quranic pronunciation training and broader speech-based educational applications.</description><author>Ayhan Kucukmanisa, Derya Gelmez, Sukru Selim Calik, Zeynep Hilal Kilimci</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:25:46 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17477v1</guid></item><item><title>Fine-Grained Reward Optimization for Machine Translation using Error Severity Mappings</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.05986v3</link><description>Reinforcement learning (RL) has been proven to be an effective and robust method for training neural machine translation systems, especially when paired with powerful reward models that accurately assess translation quality. However, most research has focused on RL methods that use sentence-level feedback, leading to inefficient learning signals due to the reward sparsity problem -- the model receives a single score for the entire sentence. To address this, we propose a novel approach that leverages fine-grained, token-level quality assessments along with error severity levels using RL methods. Specifically, we use xCOMET, a state-of-the-art quality estimation system, as our token-level reward model. We conduct experiments on small and large translation datasets with standard encoder-decoder and large language models-based machine translation systems, comparing the impact of sentence-level versus fine-grained reward signals on translation quality. Our results show that training with token-level rewards improves translation quality across language pairs over baselines according to both automatic and human evaluation. Furthermore, token-level reward optimization improves training stability, evidenced by a steady increase in mean rewards over training epochs.</description><author>Miguel Moura Ramos, Tomás Almeida, Daniel Vareta, Filipe Azevedo, Sweta Agrawal, Patrick Fernandes, André F. T. Martins</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:25:29 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.05986v3</guid></item><item><title>Addressing A Posteriori Performance Degradation in Neural Network Subgrid Stress Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17475v1</link><description>Neural network subgrid stress models often have a priori performance that is far better than the a posteriori performance, leading to neural network models that look very promising a priori completely failing in a posteriori Large Eddy Simulations (LES). This performance gap can be decreased by combining two different methods, training data augmentation and reducing input complexity to the neural network. Augmenting the training data with two different filters before training the neural networks has no performance degradation a priori as compared to a neural network trained with one filter. A posteriori, neural networks trained with two different filters are far more robust across two different LES codes with different numerical schemes. In addition, by ablating away the higher order terms input into the neural network, the a priori versus a posteriori performance changes become less apparent. When combined, neural networks that use both training data augmentation and a less complex set of inputs have a posteriori performance far more reflective of their a priori evaluation.</description><author>Andy Wu, Sanjiva K. Lele</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:24:52 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17475v1</guid></item><item><title>Physically Interpretable World Models via Weakly Supervised Representation Learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.12870v5</link><description>Learning predictive models from high-dimensional sensory observations is fundamental for cyber-physical systems, yet the latent representations learned by standard world models lack physical interpretability. This limits their reliability, generalizability, and applicability to safety-critical tasks. We introduce Physically Interpretable World Models (PIWM), a framework that aligns latent representations with real-world physical quantities and constrains their evolution through partially known physical dynamics. Physical interpretability in PIWM is defined by two complementary properties: (i) the learned latent state corresponds to meaningful physical variables, and (ii) its temporal evolution follows physically consistent dynamics. To achieve this without requiring ground-truth physical annotations, PIWM employs weak distribution-based supervision that captures state uncertainty naturally arising from real-world sensing pipelines. The architecture integrates a VQ-based visual encoder, a transformer-based physical encoder, and a learnable dynamics model grounded in known physical equations. Across three case studies (Cart Pole, Lunar Lander, and Donkey Car), PIWM achieves accurate long-horizon prediction, recovers true system parameters, and significantly improves physical grounding over purely data-driven models. These results demonstrate the feasibility and advantages of learning physically interpretable world models directly from images under weak supervision.</description><author>Zhenjiang Mao, Mrinall Eashaan Umasudhan, Ivan Ruchkin</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:24:08 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.12870v5</guid></item><item><title>Masked-and-Reordered Self-Supervision for Reinforcement Learning from Verifiable Rewards</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17473v1</link><description>Test-time scaling has been shown to substantially improve large language models' (LLMs) mathematical reasoning. However, for a large portion of mathematical corpora, especially theorem proving, RLVR's scalability is limited: intermediate reasoning is crucial, while final answers are difficult to directly and reliably verify. Meanwhile, token-level SFT often degenerates into rote memorization rather than inducing longer chains of thought. Inspired by BERT's self-supervised tasks, we propose MR-RLVR (Masked-and-Reordered RLVR), which constructs process-level self-supervised rewards via "masked-then-fill" and "step reordering" to extract learnable signals from intermediate reasoning. Our training pipeline comprises two stages: we first perform self-supervised training on sampled mathematical calculation and proof data; we then conduct RLVR fine-tuning on mathematical calculation datasets where only outcomes are verifiable. We implement MR-RLVR on Qwen2.5-3B and DeepSeek-R1-Distill-Qwen-1.5B, and evaluate on AIME24, AIME25, AMC23, and MATH500. Under a fixed sampling and decoding budget, MR-RLVR achieves average relative gains over the original RLVR of +9.86% Pass@1, +5.27% Pass@5, and +4.00% Pass@8. These results indicate that incorporating process-aware self-supervised signals can effectively enhance RLVR's scalability and performance in only outcome-verifiable settings.</description><author>Zhen Wang, Zhifeng Gao, Guolin Ke</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:23:04 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17473v1</guid></item><item><title>Can AI Perceive Physical Danger and Intervene?</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.21651v2</link><description>When AI interacts with the physical world -- as a robot or an assistive agent -- new safety challenges emerge beyond those of purely ``digital AI". In such interactions, the potential for physical harm is direct and immediate. How well do state-of-the-art foundation models understand common-sense facts about physical safety, e.g. that a box may be too heavy to lift, or that a hot cup of coffee should not be handed to a child? In this paper, our contributions are three-fold: first, we develop a highly scalable approach to continuous physical safety benchmarking of Embodied AI systems, grounded in real-world injury narratives and operational safety constraints. To probe multi-modal safety understanding, we turn these narratives and constraints into photorealistic images and videos capturing transitions from safe to unsafe states, using advanced generative models. Secondly, we comprehensively analyze the ability of major foundation models to perceive risks, reason about safety, and trigger interventions; this yields multi-faceted insights into their deployment readiness for safety-critical agentic applications. Finally, we develop a post-training paradigm to teach models to explicitly reason about embodiment-specific safety constraints provided through system instructions. The resulting models generate thinking traces that make safety reasoning interpretable and transparent, achieving state of the art performance in constraint satisfaction evaluations. The benchmark is released at https://asimov-benchmark.github.io/v2</description><author>Abhishek Jindal, Dmitry Kalashnikov, R. Alex Hofer, Oscar Chang, Divya Garikapati, Anirudha Majumdar, Pierre Sermanet, Vikas Sindhwani</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:22:41 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.21651v2</guid></item><item><title>Topology Aware Neural Interpolation of Scalar Fields</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.17995v2</link><description>This paper presents a neural scheme for the topology-aware interpolation of time-varying scalar fields. Given a time-varying sequence of persistence diagrams, along with a sparse temporal sampling of the corresponding scalar fields, denoted as keyframes, our interpolation approach aims at "inverting" the non-keyframe diagrams to produce plausible estimations of the corresponding, missing data. For this, we rely on a neural architecture which learns the relation from a time value to the corresponding scalar field, based on the keyframe examples, and reliably extends this relation to the non-keyframe time steps. We show how augmenting this architecture with specific topological losses exploiting the input diagrams both improves the geometrical and topological reconstruction of the non-keyframe time steps. At query time, given an input time value for which an interpolation is desired, our approach instantaneously produces an output, via a single propagation of the time input through the network. Experiments interpolating 2D and 3D time-varying datasets show our approach superiority, both in terms of data and topological fitting, with regard to reference interpolation schemes. Our implementation is available at this GitHub link : https://github.com/MohamedKISSI/Topology-Aware-Neural-Interpolation-of-Scalar-Fields.git.</description><author>Mohamed Kissi, Keanu Sisouk, Joshua A. Levine, Julien Tierny</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:16:26 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.17995v2</guid></item><item><title>Brain-Like Processing Pathways Form in Models With Heterogeneous Experts</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.02813v3</link><description>The brain is made up of a vast set of heterogeneous regions that dynamically organize into pathways as a function of task demands. Examples of such pathways can be found in the interactions between cortical and subcortical networks during learning, or in sub-networks specializing for task characteristics such as difficulty or modality. Despite the large role these pathways play in cognition, the mechanisms through which brain regions organize into pathways remain unclear. In this work, we use an extension of the Heterogeneous Mixture-of-Experts architecture to show that heterogeneous regions do not form processing pathways by themselves, implying that the brain likely implements specific constraints which result in the reliable formation of pathways. We identify three biologically relevant inductive biases that encourage pathway formation: a routing cost imposed on the use of more complex regions, a scaling factor that reduces this cost when task performance is low, and randomized expert dropout. When comparing our resulting \textit{Mixture-of-Pathways} model with the brain, we observe that the artificial pathways in our model match how the brain uses cortical and subcortical systems to learn and solve tasks of varying difficulty. In summary, we introduce a novel framework for investigating how the brain forms task-specific pathways through inductive biases, and the effects these biases have on the behavior of Mixture-of-Experts models.</description><author>Jack Cook, Danyal Akarca, Rui Ponte Costa, Jascha Achterberg</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:16:23 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.02813v3</guid></item><item><title>PersonaAgent with GraphRAG: Community-Aware Knowledge Graphs for Personalized LLM</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17467v1</link><description>We propose a novel framework for persona-based language model system, motivated by the need for personalized AI agents that adapt to individual user preferences. In our approach, the agent embodies the user's "persona" (e.g. user profile or taste) and is powered by a large language model (LLM). To enable the agent to leverage rich contextual information, we introduce a Knowledge-Graph-enhanced Retrieval-Augmented Generation (Graph RAG) mechanism that constructs an LLM-derived graph index of relevant documents and summarizes communities of related information. Our framework generates personalized prompts by combining: (1) a summary of the user's historical behaviors and preferences extracted from the knowledge graph, and (2) relevant global interaction patterns identified through graph-based community detection. This dynamic prompt engineering approach allows the agent to maintain consistent persona-aligned behaviors while benefiting from collective knowledge. On the LaMP benchmark, our method improves news categorization F1 by 11.1%, movie tagging F1 by 56.1%, and reduces product rating MAE by 10.4% over prior methods. Our code is available at https://anonymous.4open.science/r/PersonaAgentwGraphRAG-DE6F</description><author>Siqi Liang, Yudi Zhang, Yue Guo</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:15:47 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17467v1</guid></item><item><title>The Coding Limits of Robust Watermarking for Generative Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.10577v2</link><description>We ask a basic question about cryptographic watermarking for generative models: to what extent can a watermark remain reliable when an adversary is allowed to corrupt the encoded signal? To study this question, we introduce a minimal coding abstraction that we call a zero-bit tamper-detection code. This is a secret-key procedure that samples a pseudorandom codeword and, given a candidate word, decides whether it should be treated as unmarked content or as the result of tampering with a valid codeword. It captures the two core requirements of robust watermarking: soundness and tamper detection. Within this abstraction we prove a sharp unconditional limit on robustness to independent symbol corruption. For an alphabet of size $q$, there is a critical corruption rate of $1 - 1/q$ such that no scheme with soundness, even relaxed to allow a fixed constant false positive probability on random content, can reliably detect tampering once an adversary can change more than this fraction of symbols. In particular, in the binary case no cryptographic watermark can remain robust if more than half of the encoded bits are modified. We also show that this threshold is tight by giving simple information-theoretic constructions that achieve soundness and tamper detection for all strictly smaller corruption rates. We then test experimentally whether this limit appears in practice by looking at the recent watermarking for images of Gunn, Zhao, and Song (ICLR 2025). We show that a simple crop and resize operation reliably flipped about half of the latent signs and consistently prevented belief-propagation decoding from recovering the codeword, erasing the watermark while leaving the image visually intact.</description><author>Danilo Francati, Yevin Nikhel Goonatilake, Shubham Pawar, Daniele Venturi, Giuseppe Ateniese</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:14:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.10577v2</guid></item><item><title>Do LLMs produce texts with "human-like" lexical diversity?</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.00086v2</link><description>The degree to which large language models (LLMs) produce writing that is truly human-like remains unclear despite the extensive empirical attention that this question has received. The present study addresses this question from the perspective of lexical diversity. Specifically, the study investigates patterns of lexical diversity in LLM-generated texts from four ChatGPT models (ChatGPT-3.5, ChatGPT-4, ChatGPT-o4 mini, and ChatGPT-4.5) in comparison with texts written by L1 and L2 English participants (n = 240) across four education levels. Six dimensions of lexical diversity were measured in each text: volume, abundance, variety-repetition, evenness, disparity, and dispersion. Results from one-way MANOVAs, one-way ANOVAs, and Support Vector Machines revealed that the ChatGPT-generated texts differed significantly from human-written texts for each variable, with ChatGPT-o4 mini and ChatGPT-4.5 differing the most. Within these two groups, ChatGPT-4.5 demonstrated higher levels of lexical diversity than older models despite producing fewer tokens. The human writers' lexical diversity did not differ across subgroups (i.e., education, language status). Altogether, the results indicate that ChatGPT models do not produce human-like texts in relation to lexical diversity, and the newer models produce less human-like text than older models. We discuss the implications of these results for language pedagogy and related applications.</description><author>Kelly Kendro, Jeffrey Maloney, Scott Jarvis</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:13:28 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.00086v2</guid></item><item><title>Forecasting Future Anatomies: Longitudinal Brain Mri-to-Mri Prediction</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.02558v2</link><description>Predicting future brain state from a baseline magnetic resonance image (MRI) is a central challenge in neuroimaging and has important implications for studying neurodegenerative diseases such as Alzheimer's disease (AD). Most existing approaches predict future cognitive scores or clinical outcomes, such as conversion from mild cognitive impairment to dementia. Instead, here we investigate longitudinal MRI image-to-image prediction that forecasts a participant's entire brain MRI several years into the future, intrinsically modeling complex, spatially distributed neurodegenerative patterns. We implement and evaluate five deep learning architectures (UNet, U2-Net, UNETR, Time-Embedding UNet, and ODE-UNet) on two longitudinal cohorts (ADNI and AIBL). Predicted follow-up MRIs are directly compared with the actual follow-up scans using metrics that capture global similarity and local differences. The best performing models achieve high-fidelity predictions, and all models generalize well to an independent external dataset, demonstrating robust cross-cohort performance. Our results indicate that deep learning can reliably predict participant-specific brain MRI at the voxel level, offering new opportunities for individualized prognosis.</description><author>Ali Farki, Elaheh Moradi, Deepika Koundal, Jussi Tohka</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:11:50 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.02558v2</guid></item><item><title>Automated Interpretable 2D Video Extraction from 3D Echocardiography</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.15946v2</link><description>Although the heart has complex three-dimensional (3D) anatomy, conventional medical imaging with cardiac ultrasound relies on a series of 2D videos showing individual cardiac structures. 3D echocardiography is a developing modality that now offers adequate image quality for clinical use, with potential to streamline acquisition and improve assessment of off-axis features. We propose an automated method to select standard 2D views from 3D cardiac ultrasound volumes, allowing physicians to interpret the data in their usual format while benefiting from the speed and usability of 3D scanning. Applying a deep learning view classifier and downstream heuristics based on anatomical landmarks together with heuristics provided by cardiologists, we reconstruct standard echocardiography views. This approach was validated by three cardiologists in blinded evaluation (96\% accuracy in 1,600 videos from 2 hospitals). The downstream 2D videos were also validated in their ability to detect cardiac abnormalities using AI echocardiography models (EchoPrime and PanEcho) as well as ability to generate clinical-grade measurements of cardiac anatomy (EchoNet-Measurement). We demonstrated that the extracted 2D videos preserve spatial calibration and diagnostic features, allowing clinicians to obtain accurate real-world interpretations from 3D volumes. We release the code and a dataset of 29 3D echocardiography videos https://github.com/echonet/3d-echo .</description><author>Milos Vukadinovic, Hirotaka Ieki, Yuki Sahashi, David Ouyang, Bryan He</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:09:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.15946v2</guid></item><item><title>SRA-CP: Spontaneous Risk-Aware Selective Cooperative Perception</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17461v1</link><description>Cooperative perception (CP) offers significant potential to overcome the limitations of single-vehicle sensing by enabling information sharing among connected vehicles (CVs). However, existing generic CP approaches need to transmit large volumes of perception data that are irrelevant to the driving safety, exceeding available communication bandwidth. Moreover, most CP frameworks rely on pre-defined communication partners, making them unsuitable for dynamic traffic environments. This paper proposes a Spontaneous Risk-Aware Selective Cooperative Perception (SRA-CP) framework to address these challenges. SRA-CP introduces a decentralized protocol where connected agents continuously broadcast lightweight perception coverage summaries and initiate targeted cooperation only when risk-relevant blind zones are detected. A perceptual risk identification module enables each CV to locally assess the impact of occlusions on its driving task and determine whether cooperation is necessary. When CP is triggered, the ego vehicle selects appropriate peers based on shared perception coverage and engages in selective information exchange through a fusion module that prioritizes safety-critical content and adapts to bandwidth constraints. We evaluate SRA-CP on a public dataset against several representative baselines. Results show that SRA-CP achieves less than 1% average precision (AP) loss for safety-critical objects compared to generic CP, while using only 20% of the communication bandwidth. Moreover, it improves the perception performance by 15% over existing selective CP methods that do not incorporate risk awareness.</description><author>Jiaxi Liu, Chengyuan Ma, Hang Zhou, Weizhe Tang, Shixiao Liang, Haoyang Ding, Xiaopeng Li, Bin Ran</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:03:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17461v1</guid></item><item><title>AI use in American newspapers is widespread, uneven, and rarely disclosed</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.18774v3</link><description>AI is rapidly transforming journalism, but the extent of its use in published newspaper articles remains unclear. We address this gap by auditing a large-scale dataset of 186K articles from online editions of 1.5K American newspapers published in the summer of 2025. Using Pangram, a state-of-the-art AI detector, we discover that approximately 9% of newly-published articles are either partially or fully AI-generated. This AI use is unevenly distributed, appearing more frequently in smaller, local outlets, in specific topics such as weather and technology, and within certain ownership groups. We also analyze 45K opinion pieces from Washington Post, New York Times, and Wall Street Journal, finding that they are 6.4 times more likely to contain AI-generated content than news articles from the same publications, with many AI-flagged op-eds authored by prominent public figures. Despite this prevalence, we find that AI use is rarely disclosed: a manual audit of 100 AI-flagged articles found only five disclosures of AI use. Overall, our audit highlights the immediate need for greater transparency and updated editorial standards regarding the use of AI in journalism to maintain public trust.</description><author>Jenna Russell, Marzena Karpinska, Destiny Akinode, Katherine Thai, Bradley Emi, Max Spero, Mohit Iyyer</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:01:12 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.18774v3</guid></item><item><title>GPR-OdomNet: Difference and Similarity-Driven Odometry Estimation Network for Ground Penetrating Radar-Based Localization</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17457v1</link><description>When performing robot/vehicle localization using ground penetrating radar (GPR) to handle adverse weather and environmental conditions, existing techniques often struggle to accurately estimate distances when processing B-scan images with minor distinctions. This study introduces a new neural network-based odometry method that leverages the similarity and difference features of GPR B-scan images for precise estimation of the Euclidean distances traveled between the B-scan images. The new custom neural network extracts multi-scale features from B-scan images taken at consecutive moments and then determines the Euclidean distance traveled by analyzing the similarities and differences between these features. To evaluate our method, an ablation study and comparison experiments have been conducted using the publicly available CMU-GPR dataset. The experimental results show that our method consistently outperforms state-of-the-art counterparts in all tests. Specifically, our method achieves a root mean square error (RMSE), and achieves an overall weighted RMSE of 0.449 m across all data sets, which is a 10.2\% reduction in RMSE when compared to the best state-of-the-art method.</description><author>Huaichao Wang, Xuanxin Fan, Ji Liu, Haifeng Li, Dezhen Song</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:59:17 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17457v1</guid></item><item><title>Improving Multimodal Distillation for 3D Semantic Segmentation under Domain Shift</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17455v1</link><description>Semantic segmentation networks trained under full supervision for one type of lidar fail to generalize to unseen lidars without intervention. To reduce the performance gap under domain shifts, a recent trend is to leverage vision foundation models (VFMs) providing robust features across domains. In this work, we conduct an exhaustive study to identify recipes for exploiting VFMs in unsupervised domain adaptation for semantic segmentation of lidar point clouds. Building upon unsupervised image-to-lidar knowledge distillation, our study reveals that: (1) the architecture of the lidar backbone is key to maximize the generalization performance on a target domain; (2) it is possible to pretrain a single backbone once and for all, and use it to address many domain shifts; (3) best results are obtained by keeping the pretrained backbone frozen and training an MLP head for semantic segmentation. The resulting pipeline achieves state-of-the-art results in four widely-recognized and challenging settings. The code will be available at: https://github.com/valeoai/muddos.</description><author>Björn Michele, Alexandre Boulch, Gilles Puy, Tuan-Hung Vu, Renaud Marlet, Nicolas Courty</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:57:43 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17455v1</guid></item><item><title>Illustrator's Depth: Monocular Layer Index Prediction for Image Decomposition</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17454v1</link><description>We introduce Illustrator's Depth, a novel definition of depth that addresses a key challenge in digital content creation: decomposing flat images into editable, ordered layers. Inspired by an artist's compositional process, illustrator's depth infers a layer index to each pixel, forming an interpretable image decomposition through a discrete, globally consistent ordering of elements optimized for editability. We also propose and train a neural network using a curated dataset of layered vector graphics to predict layering directly from raster inputs. Our layer index inference unlocks a range of powerful downstream applications. In particular, it significantly outperforms state-of-the-art baselines for image vectorization while also enabling high-fidelity text-to-vector-graphics generation, automatic 3D relief generation from 2D images, and intuitive depth-aware editing. By reframing depth from a physical quantity to a creative abstraction, illustrator's depth prediction offers a new foundation for editable image decomposition.</description><author>Nissim Maruani, Peiying Zhang, Siddhartha Chaudhuri, Matthew Fisher, Nanxuan Zhao, Vladimir G. Kim, Pierre Alliez, Mathieu Desbrun, Wang Yifan</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:56:43 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17454v1</guid></item><item><title>Planning with Sketch-Guided Verification for Physics-Aware Video Generation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17450v1</link><description>Recent video generation approaches increasingly rely on planning intermediate control signals such as object trajectories to improve temporal coherence and motion fidelity. However, these methods mostly employ single-shot plans that are typically limited to simple motions, or iterative refinement which requires multiple calls to the video generator, incuring high computational cost. To overcome these limitations, we propose SketchVerify, a training-free, sketch-verification-based planning framework that improves motion planning quality with more dynamically coherent trajectories (i.e., physically plausible and instruction-consistent motions) prior to full video generation by introducing a test-time sampling and verification loop. Given a prompt and a reference image, our method predicts multiple candidate motion plans and ranks them using a vision-language verifier that jointly evaluates semantic alignment with the instruction and physical plausibility. To efficiently score candidate motion plans, we render each trajectory as a lightweight video sketch by compositing objects over a static background, which bypasses the need for expensive, repeated diffusion-based synthesis while achieving comparable performance. We iteratively refine the motion plan until a satisfactory one is identified, which is then passed to the trajectory-conditioned generator for final synthesis. Experiments on WorldModelBench and PhyWorldBench demonstrate that our method significantly improves motion quality, physical realism, and long-term consistency compared to competitive baselines while being substantially more efficient. Our ablation study further shows that scaling up the number of trajectory candidates consistently enhances overall performance.</description><author>Yidong Huang, Zun Wang, Han Lin, Dong-Ki Kim, Shayegan Omidshafiei, Jaehong Yoon, Yue Zhang, Mohit Bansal</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:48:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17450v1</guid></item><item><title>MMT-ARD: Multimodal Multi-Teacher Adversarial Distillation for Robust Vision-Language Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17448v1</link><description>Vision-Language Models (VLMs) are increasingly deployed in safety-critical applications, making their adversarial robustness a crucial concern. While adversarial knowledge distillation has shown promise in transferring robustness from teacher to student models, traditional single-teacher approaches suffer from limited knowledge diversity, slow convergence, and difficulty in balancing robustness and accuracy. To address these challenges, we propose MMT-ARD: a Multimodal Multi-Teacher Adversarial Robust Distillation framework. Our key innovation is a dual-teacher knowledge fusion architecture that collaboratively optimizes clean feature preservation and robust feature enhancement. To better handle challenging adversarial examples, we introduce a dynamic weight allocation strategy based on teacher confidence, enabling adaptive focus on harder samples. Moreover, to mitigate bias among teachers, we design an adaptive sigmoid-based weighting function that balances the strength of knowledge transfer across modalities. Extensive experiments on ImageNet and zero-shot benchmarks demonstrate that MMT-ARD improves robust accuracy by +4.32% and zero-shot accuracy by +3.5% on the ViT-B-32 model, while achieving a 2.3x increase in training efficiency over traditional single-teacher methods. These results highlight the effectiveness and scalability of MMT-ARD in enhancing the adversarial robustness of multimodal large models. Our codes are available at https://github.com/itsnotacie/MMT-ARD.</description><author>Yuqi Li, Junhao Dong, Chuanguang Yang, Shiping Wen, Piotr Koniusz, Tingwen Huang, Yingli Tian, Yew-Soon Ong</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:46:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17448v1</guid></item><item><title>Unmasking Airborne Threats: Guided-Transformers for Portable Aerosol Mass Spectrometry</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17446v1</link><description>Matrix Assisted Laser Desorption/Ionization Mass Spectrometry (MALDI-MS) is a cornerstone in biomolecular analysis, offering precise identification of pathogens through unique mass spectral signatures. Yet, its reliance on labor-intensive sample preparation and multi-shot spectral averaging restricts its use to laboratory settings, rendering it impractical for real-time environmental monitoring. These limitations are especially pronounced in emerging aerosol MALDI-MS systems, where autonomous sampling generates noisy spectra for unknown aerosol analytes, requiring single-shot detection for effective analysis. Addressing these challenges, we propose the Mass Spectral Dictionary-Guided Transformer (MS-DGFormer): a data-driven framework that redefines spectral analysis by directly processing raw, minimally prepared mass spectral data. MS-DGFormer leverages a transformer architecture, designed to capture the long-range dependencies inherent in these time-series spectra. To enhance feature extraction, we introduce a novel dictionary encoder that integrates denoised spectral information derived from Singular Value Decomposition (SVD), enabling the model to discern critical biomolecular patterns from single-shot spectra with robust performance. This innovation provides a system to achieve superior pathogen identification from aerosol samples, facilitating autonomous, real-time analysis in field conditions. By eliminating the need for extensive preprocessing, our method unlocks the potential for portable, deployable MALDI-MS platforms, revolutionizing environmental pathogen detection and rapid response to biological threats.</description><author>Kyle M. Regan, Michael McLoughlin, Wayne A. Bryden, Gonzalo R. Arce</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:45:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17446v1</guid></item><item><title>GRAPHIC--Guidelines for Reviewing Algorithmic Practices in Human-centred Design and Interaction for Creativity</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17443v1</link><description>Artificial Intelligence (AI) has been increasingly applied to creative domains, leading to the development of systems that collaborate with humans in design processes. In Graphic Design, integrating computational systems into co-creative workflows presents specific challenges, as it requires balancing scientific rigour with the subjective and visual nature of design practice. Following the PRISMA methodology, we identified 872 articles, resulting in a final corpus of 71 publications describing 68 unique systems. Based on this review, we introduce GRAPHIC (Guidelines for Reviewing Algorithmic Practices in Human-centred Design and Interaction for Creativity), a framework for analysing AI-based systems applied to Graphic Design. Its goal is to understand how current systems support human-AI collaboration in the Graphic Design discipline. The framework comprises main dimensions, which our analysis revealed to be essential across diverse system types: (1) Collaborative Panorama, (2) Processes and Modalities, and (3) Graphic Design Principles. Its application revealed research gaps, including the need to balance initiative and control between agents, improve communication through explainable interaction models, and promote systems that support transformational creativity grounded in core design principles.</description><author>Joana Rovira Martins, Pedro Martins, Ana Boavida</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:42:09 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17443v1</guid></item><item><title>CATCODER: Repository-Level Code Generation with Relevant Code and Type Context</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.03283v2</link><description>Large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated remarkable capabilities in code generation tasks. However, repository-level code generation presents unique challenges, particularly due to the need to utilize information spread across multiple files within a repository. Specifically, successful generation depends on a solid grasp of both general, context-agnostic knowledge and specific, context-dependent knowledge. While LLMs are widely used for the context-agnostic aspect, existing retrieval-based approaches sometimes fall short as they are limited in obtaining a broader and deeper repository context. In this paper, we present CatCoder, a novel code generation framework designed for statically typed programming languages. CatCoder enhances repository-level code generation by integrating relevant code and type context. Specifically, it leverages static analyzers to extract type dependencies and merges this information with retrieved code to create comprehensive prompts for LLMs. To evaluate the effectiveness of CatCoder, we adapt and construct benchmarks that include 199 Java tasks and 90 Rust tasks. The results show that CatCoder outperforms the RepoCoder baseline by up to 14.44% and 17.35%, in terms of compile@k and pass@k scores. In addition, the generalizability of CatCoder is assessed using various LLMs, including both code-specialized models and general-purpose models. Our findings indicate consistent performance improvements across all models, which underlines the practicality of CatCoder. Furthermore, we evaluate the time consumption of CatCoder in a large open source repository, and the results demonstrate the scalability of CatCoder.</description><author>Zhiyuan Pan, Xing Hu, Xin Xia, Xiaohu Yang</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:41:45 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.03283v2</guid></item><item><title>REMSA: An LLM Agent for Foundation Model Selection in Remote Sensing</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17442v1</link><description>Foundation Models (FMs) are increasingly used in remote sensing (RS) for tasks such as environmental monitoring, disaster assessment, and land-use mapping. These models include unimodal vision encoders trained on a single data modality and multimodal architectures trained on combinations of SAR, multispectral, hyperspectral, and image-text data. They support diverse RS tasks including semantic segmentation, image classification, change detection, and visual question answering. However, selecting an appropriate remote sensing foundation model (RSFM) remains difficult due to scattered documentation, heterogeneous formats, and varied deployment constraints. We introduce the RSFM Database (RS-FMD), a structured resource covering over 150 RSFMs spanning multiple data modalities, resolutions, and learning paradigms. Built on RS-FMD, we present REMSA, the first LLM-based agent for automated RSFM selection from natural language queries. REMSA interprets user requirements, resolves missing constraints, ranks candidate models using in-context learning, and provides transparent justifications. We also propose a benchmark of 75 expert-verified RS query scenarios, producing 900 configurations under an expert-centered evaluation protocol. REMSA outperforms several baselines, including naive agents, dense retrieval, and unstructured RAG-based LLMs. It operates entirely on publicly available metadata and does not access private or sensitive data.</description><author>Binger Chen, Tacettin Emre Bök, Behnood Rasti, Volker Markl, Begüm Demir</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:41:26 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17442v1</guid></item><item><title>InTAct: Interval-based Task Activation Consolidation for Continual Learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17439v1</link><description>Continual learning aims to enable neural networks to acquire new knowledge without forgetting previously learned information. While recent prompt-based methods perform strongly in class-incremental settings, they remain vulnerable under domain shifts, where the input distribution changes but the label space remains fixed. This exposes a persistent problem known as representation drift. Shared representations evolve in ways that overwrite previously useful features and cause forgetting even when prompts isolate task-specific parameters. To address this issue, we introduce InTAct, a method that preserves functional behavior in shared layers without freezing parameters or storing past data. InTAct captures the characteristic activation ranges associated with previously learned tasks and constrains updates to ensure the network remains consistent within these regions, while still allowing for flexible adaptation elsewhere. In doing so, InTAct stabilizes the functional role of important neurons rather than directly restricting parameter values. The approach is architecture-agnostic and integrates seamlessly into existing prompt-based continual learning frameworks. By regulating representation changes where past knowledge is encoded, InTAct achieves a principled balance between stability and plasticity. Across diverse domain-incremental benchmarks, including DomainNet and ImageNet-R, InTAct consistently reduces representation drift and improves performance, increasing Average Accuracy by up to 8 percentage points over state-of-the-art baselines.</description><author>Patryk Krukowski, Jan Miksa, Piotr Helm, Jacek Tabor, Paweł Wawrzyński, Przemysław Spurek</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:36:12 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17439v1</guid></item><item><title>A Framework for Adaptive Stabilisation of Nonlinear Stochastic Systems</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17436v1</link><description>We consider the adaptive control problem for discrete-time, nonlinear stochastic systems with linearly parameterised uncertainty. Assuming access to a parameterised family of controllers that can stabilise the system in a bounded set within an informative region of the state space when the parameter is well-chosen, we propose a certainty equivalence learning-based adaptive control strategy, and subsequently derive stability bounds on the closed-loop system that hold for some probabilities. We then show that if the entire state space is informative, and the family of controllers is globally stabilising with appropriately chosen parameters, high probability stability guarantees can be derived.</description><author>Seth Siriya, Jingge Zhu, Dragan Nešić, Ye Pu</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:33:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17436v1</guid></item><item><title>Multi-Agent Pointer Transformer: Seq-to-Seq Reinforcement Learning for Multi-Vehicle Dynamic Pickup-Delivery Problems</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17435v1</link><description>This paper addresses the cooperative Multi-Vehicle Dynamic Pickup and Delivery Problem with Stochastic Requests (MVDPDPSR) and proposes an end-to-end centralized decision-making framework based on sequence-to-sequence, named Multi-Agent Pointer Transformer (MAPT). MVDPDPSR is an extension of the vehicle routing problem and a spatio-temporal system optimization problem, widely applied in scenarios such as on-demand delivery. Classical operations research methods face bottlenecks in computational complexity and time efficiency when handling large-scale dynamic problems. Although existing reinforcement learning methods have achieved some progress, they still encounter several challenges: 1) Independent decoding across multiple vehicles fails to model joint action distributions; 2) The feature extraction network struggles to capture inter-entity relationships; 3) The joint action space is exponentially large. To address these issues, we designed the MAPT framework, which employs a Transformer Encoder to extract entity representations, combines a Transformer Decoder with a Pointer Network to generate joint action sequences in an AutoRegressive manner, and introduces a Relation-Aware Attention module to capture inter-entity relationships. Additionally, we guide the model's decision-making using informative priors to facilitate effective exploration. Experiments on 8 datasets demonstrate that MAPT significantly outperforms existing baseline methods in terms of performance and exhibits substantial computational time advantages compared to classical operations research methods.</description><author>Zengyu Zou, Jingyuan Wang, Yixuan Huang, Junjie Wu</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:32:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17435v1</guid></item><item><title>SMILE: A Composite Lexical-Semantic Metric for Question-Answering Evaluation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17432v1</link><description>Traditional evaluation metrics for textual and visual question answering, like ROUGE, METEOR, and Exact Match (EM), focus heavily on n-gram based lexical similarity, often missing the deeper semantic understanding needed for accurate assessment. While measures like BERTScore and MoverScore leverage contextual embeddings to address this limitation, they lack flexibility in balancing sentence-level and keyword-level semantics and ignore lexical similarity, which remains important. Large Language Model (LLM) based evaluators, though powerful, come with drawbacks like high costs, bias, inconsistency, and hallucinations. To address these issues, we introduce SMILE: Semantic Metric Integrating Lexical Exactness, a novel approach that combines sentence-level semantic understanding with keyword-level semantic understanding and easy keyword matching. This composite method balances lexical precision and semantic relevance, offering a comprehensive evaluation. Extensive benchmarks across text, image, and video QA tasks show SMILE is highly correlated with human judgments and computationally lightweight, bridging the gap between lexical and semantic evaluation.</description><author>Shrikant Kendre, Austin Xu, Honglu Zhou, Michael Ryoo, Shafiq Joty, Juan Carlos Niebles</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:30:18 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17432v1</guid></item><item><title>TrackGS: Optimizing COLMAP-Free 3D Gaussian Splatting with Global Track Constraints</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.19800v3</link><description>We present TrackGS, a novel method to integrate global feature tracks with 3D Gaussian Splatting (3DGS) for COLMAP-free novel view synthesis. While 3DGS delivers impressive rendering quality, its reliance on accurate precomputed camera parameters remains a significant limitation. Existing COLMAP-free approaches depend on local constraints that fail in complex scenarios. Our key innovation lies in leveraging feature tracks to establish global geometric constraints, enabling simultaneous optimization of camera parameters and 3D Gaussians. Specifically, we: (1) introduce track-constrained Gaussians that serve as geometric anchors, (2) propose novel 2D and 3D track losses to enforce multi-view consistency, and (3) derive differentiable formulations for camera intrinsics optimization. Extensive experiments on challenging real-world and synthetic datasets demonstrate state-of-the-art performance, with much lower pose error than previous methods while maintaining superior rendering quality. Our approach eliminates the need for COLMAP preprocessing, making 3DGS more accessible for practical applications.</description><author>Dongbo Shi, Shen Cao, Lubin Fan, Bojian Wu, Jinhui Guo, Ligang Liu, Renjie Chen</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:27:18 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.19800v3</guid></item><item><title>Towards fully differentiable neural ocean model with Veros</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17427v1</link><description>We present a differentiable extension of the VEROS ocean model, enabling automatic differentiation through its dynamical core. We describe the key modifications required to make the model fully compatible with JAX autodifferentiation framework and evaluate the numerical consistency of the resulting implementation. Two illustrative applications are then demonstrated: (i) the correction of an initial ocean state through gradient-based optimization, and (ii) the calibration of unknown physical parameters directly from model observations. These examples highlight how differentiable programming can facilitate end-to-end learning and parameter tuning in ocean modeling. Our implementation is available online.</description><author>Etienne Meunier, Said Ouala, Hugo Frezat, Julien Le Sommer, Ronan Fablet</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:24:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17427v1</guid></item><item><title>Concise Reasoning via Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.05185v3</link><description>A major drawback of reasoning models is their excessive token usage, inflating computational cost, resource demand, and latency. We show this verbosity stems not from deeper reasoning but from reinforcement learning loss minimization when models produce incorrect answers. With unsolvable problems dominating training, this effect compounds into a systematic tendency toward longer outputs. Through theoretical analysis of PPO and GRPO, we prove that incorrect answers inherently drive policies toward verbosity \textit{even when} $γ=1$, reframing response lengthening as an optimization artifact. We further uncover a consistent correlation between conciseness and correctness across reasoning and non-reasoning models. Building on these insights, we propose a two-phase RL procedure where a brief secondary stage, trained on a small set of solvable problems, significantly reduces response length while preserving or improving accuracy. Finally, we show that while GRPO shares properties with PPO, it exhibits collapse modes, limiting its reliability for concise reasoning. Our claims are supported by extensive experiments.</description><author>Mehdi Fatemi, Banafsheh Rafiee, Mingjie Tang, Kartik Talamadupula</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:22:52 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.05185v3</guid></item><item><title>Live-SWE-agent: Can Software Engineering Agents Self-Evolve on the Fly?</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.13646v2</link><description>Large Language Models (LLMs) are reshaping almost all industries, including software engineering. In recent years, a number of LLM agents have been proposed to solve real-world software problems. Such software agents are typically equipped with a suite of coding tools and can autonomously decide the next actions to form complete trajectories to solve end-to-end software tasks. While promising, they typically require dedicated design and may still be suboptimal, since it can be extremely challenging and costly to exhaust the entire agent scaffold design space. Recognizing that software agents are inherently software themselves that can be further refined/modified, researchers have proposed a number of self-improving software agents recently, including the Darwin-Gödel Machine (DGM). Meanwhile, such self-improving agents require costly offline training on specific benchmarks and may not generalize well across different LLMs or benchmarks. In this paper, we propose Live-SWE-agent, the first live software agent that can autonomously and continuously evolve itself on-the-fly during runtime when solving real-world software problems. More specifically, Live-SWE-agent starts with the most basic agent scaffold with only access to bash tools (e.g., mini-SWE-agent), and autonomously evolves its own scaffold implementation while solving real-world software problems. Our evaluation on the widely studied SWE-bench Verified benchmark shows that LIVE-SWE-AGENT can achieve an impressive solve rate of 77.4% without test-time scaling, outperforming all existing software agents, including the best proprietary solution. Moreover, Live-SWE-agent outperforms state-of-the-art manually crafted software agents on the recent SWE-Bench Pro benchmark, achieving the best-known solve rate of 45.8%.</description><author>Chunqiu Steven Xia, Zhe Wang, Yan Yang, Yuxiang Wei, Lingming Zhang</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:22:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.13646v2</guid></item><item><title>Self-Supervised Learning by Curvature Alignment</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17426v1</link><description>Self-supervised learning (SSL) has recently advanced through non-contrastive methods that couple an invariance term with variance, covariance, or redundancy-reduction penalties. While such objectives shape first- and second-order statistics of the representation, they largely ignore the local geometry of the underlying data manifold. In this paper, we introduce CurvSSL, a curvature-regularized self-supervised learning framework, and its RKHS extension, kernel CurvSSL. Our approach retains a standard two-view encoder-projector architecture with a Barlow Twins-style redundancy-reduction loss on projected features, but augments it with a curvature-based regularizer. Each embedding is treated as a vertex whose $k$ nearest neighbors define a discrete curvature score via cosine interactions on the unit hypersphere; in the kernel variant, curvature is computed from a normalized local Gram matrix in an RKHS. These scores are aligned and decorrelated across augmentations by a Barlow-style loss on a curvature-derived matrix, encouraging both view invariance and consistency of local manifold bending. Experiments on MNIST and CIFAR-10 datasets with a ResNet-18 backbone show that curvature-regularized SSL yields competitive or improved linear evaluation performance compared to Barlow Twins and VICReg. Our results indicate that explicitly shaping local geometry is a simple and effective complement to purely statistical SSL regularizers.</description><author>Benyamin Ghojogh, M. Hadi Sepanj, Paul Fieguth</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:22:31 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17426v1</guid></item><item><title>Preventing Shortcut Learning in Medical Image Analysis through Intermediate Layer Knowledge Distillation from Specialist Teachers</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17421v1</link><description>Deep learning models are prone to learning shortcut solutions to problems using spuriously correlated yet irrelevant features of their training data. In high-risk applications such as medical image analysis, this phenomenon may prevent models from using clinically meaningful features when making predictions, potentially leading to poor robustness and harm to patients. We demonstrate that different types of shortcuts (those that are diffuse and spread throughout the image, as well as those that are localized to specific areas) manifest distinctly across network layers and can, therefore, be more effectively targeted through mitigation strategies that target the intermediate layers. We propose a novel knowledge distillation framework that leverages a teacher network fine-tuned on a small subset of task-relevant data to mitigate shortcut learning in a student network trained on a large dataset corrupted with a bias feature. Through extensive experiments on CheXpert, ISIC 2017, and SimBA datasets using various architectures (ResNet-18, AlexNet, DenseNet-121, and 3D CNNs), we demonstrate consistent improvements over traditional Empirical Risk Minimization, augmentation-based bias-mitigation, and group-based bias-mitigation approaches. In many cases, we achieve comparable performance with a baseline model trained on bias-free data, even on out-of-distribution test data. Our results demonstrate the practical applicability of our approach to real-world medical imaging scenarios where bias annotations are limited and shortcut features are difficult to identify a priori.</description><author>Christopher Boland, Sotirios Tsaftaris, Sonia Dahdouh</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:18:35 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17421v1</guid></item><item><title>DS-Span: Single-Phase Discriminative Subgraph Mining for Efficient Graph Embeddings</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17419v1</link><description>Graph representation learning seeks to transform complex, high-dimensional graph structures into compact vector spaces that preserve both topology and semantics. Among the various strategies, subgraph-based methods provide an interpretable bridge between symbolic pattern discovery and continuous embedding learning. Yet, existing frequent or discriminative subgraph mining approaches often suffer from redundant multi-phase pipelines, high computational cost, and weak coupling between mined structures and their discriminative relevance. We propose DS-Span, a single-phase discriminative subgraph mining framework that unifies pattern growth, pruning, and supervision-driven scoring within one traversal of the search space. DS-Span introduces a coverage-capped eligibility mechanism that dynamically limits exploration once a graph is sufficiently represented, and an information-gain-guided selection that promotes subgraphs with strong class-separating ability while minimizing redundancy. The resulting subgraph set serves as an efficient, interpretable basis for downstream graph embedding and classification. Extensive experiments across benchmarks demonstrate that DS-Span generates more compact and discriminative subgraph features than prior multi-stage methods, achieving higher or comparable accuracy with significantly reduced runtime. These results highlight the potential of unified, single-phase discriminative mining as a foundation for scalable and interpretable graph representation learning.</description><author>Yeamin Kaiser, Muhammed Tasnim Bin Anwar, Bholanath Das, Chowdhury Farhan Ahmed, Md. Tanvir Alam</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:17:51 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17419v1</guid></item><item><title>CREST: Improving Interpretability and Effectiveness of Troubleshooting at Ericsson through Criterion-Specific Trouble Report Retrieval</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17417v1</link><description>The rapid evolution of the telecommunication industry necessitates efficient troubleshooting processes to maintain network reliability, software maintainability, and service quality. Trouble Reports (TRs), which document issues in Ericsson's production system, play a critical role in facilitating the timely resolution of software faults. However, the complexity and volume of TR data, along with the presence of diverse criteria that reflect different aspects of each fault, present challenges for retrieval systems. Building on prior work at Ericsson, which utilized a two-stage workflow, comprising Initial Retrieval (IR) and Re-Ranking (RR) stages, this study investigates different TR observation criteria and their impact on the performance of retrieval models. We propose \textbf{CREST} (\textbf{C}riteria-specific \textbf{R}etrieval via \textbf{E}nsemble of \textbf{S}pecialized \textbf{T}R models), a criterion-driven retrieval approach that leverages specialized models for different TR fields to improve both effectiveness and interpretability, thereby enabling quicker fault resolution and supporting software maintenance. CREST utilizes specialized models trained on specific TR criteria and aggregates their outputs to capture diverse and complementary signals. This approach leads to enhanced retrieval accuracy, better calibration of predicted scores, and improved interpretability by providing relevance scores for each criterion, helping users understand why specific TRs were retrieved. Using a subset of Ericsson's internal TRs, this research demonstrates that criterion-specific models significantly outperform a single model approach across key evaluation metrics. This highlights the importance of all targeted criteria used in this study for optimizing the performance of retrieval systems.</description><author>Soroush Javdan, Pragash Krishnamoorthy, Olga Baysal</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:16:24 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17417v1</guid></item><item><title>SPEAR-1: Scaling Beyond Robot Demonstrations via 3D Understanding</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17411v1</link><description>Robotic Foundation Models (RFMs) hold great promise as generalist, end-to-end systems for robot control. Yet their ability to generalize across new environments, tasks, and embodiments remains limited. We argue that a major bottleneck lies in their foundations: most RFMs are built by fine-tuning internet-pretrained Vision-Language Models (VLMs). However, these VLMs are trained on 2D image-language tasks and lack the 3D spatial reasoning inherently required for embodied control in the 3D world. Bridging this gap directly with large-scale robotic data is costly and difficult to scale. Instead, we propose to enrich easy-to-collect non-robotic image data with 3D annotations and enhance a pretrained VLM with 3D understanding capabilities. Following this strategy, we train SPEAR-VLM, a 3D-aware VLM that infers object coordinates in 3D space from a single 2D image. Building on SPEAR-VLM, we introduce our main contribution, $~\textbf{SPEAR-1}$: a robotic foundation model that integrates grounded 3D perception with language-instructed embodied control. Trained on $\sim$45M frames from 24 Open X-Embodiment datasets, SPEAR-1 outperforms or matches state-of-the-art models such as $π_0$-FAST and $π_{0.5}$, while it uses 20$\times$ fewer robot demonstrations. This carefully-engineered training strategy unlocks new VLM capabilities and as a consequence boosts the reliability of embodied control beyond what is achievable with only robotic data. We make our model weights and 3D-annotated datasets publicly available.</description><author>Nikolay Nikolov, Giuliano Albanese, Sombit Dey, Aleksandar Yanev, Luc Van Gool, Jan-Nico Zaech, Danda Pani Paudel</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:09:43 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17411v1</guid></item><item><title>That's not natural: The Impact of Off-Policy Training Data on Probe Performance</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17408v1</link><description>Probing has emerged as a promising method for monitoring Large Language Models (LLMs), enabling inference-time detection of concerning behaviours such as deception and sycophancy. However, natural examples of many behaviours are rare, forcing researchers to rely on synthetic or off-policy LLM responses for training probes. We systematically evaluate how the use of synthetic and off-policy data influences probe generalisation across eight distinct LLM behaviours. Testing linear and attention probes across multiple LLMs, we find that the response generation strategy can significantly affect probe performance, though the magnitude of this effect varies by behaviour. We find that successful generalisation from off-policy data, to test sets where the model is incentivised to produce the target behaviour, is predictive of successful on-policy generalisation. Leveraging this result, we predict that Deception and Sandbagging probes may fail to generalise from off-policy to on-policy data when used in real monitoring scenarios. Notably, shifts in the training data domain still cause even larger performance degradation, with different-domain test scores being consistently lower than the same-domain ones. These results indicate that, in the absence of on-policy data, using same-domain off-policy data yields more reliable probes than using on-policy data from a different domain, emphasizing the need for methods that can better handle distribution shifts in LLM monitoring.</description><author>Nathalie Kirch, Samuel Dower, Adrians Skapars, Ekdeep Singh Lubana, Dmitrii Krasheninnikov</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:08:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17408v1</guid></item><item><title>Seeing the Forest and the Trees: Query-Aware Tokenizer for Long-Video Multimodal Language Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.11910v2</link><description>Despite the recent advances in the video understanding ability of multimodal large language models (MLLMs), long video understanding remains a challenge. One of the main issues is that the number of vision tokens grows linearly with video length, which causes an explosion in attention cost, memory, and latency. To solve this challenge, we present Query-aware Token Selector (\textbf{QTSplus}), a lightweight yet powerful visual token selection module that serves as an information gate between the vision encoder and LLMs. Given a text query and video tokens, QTSplus dynamically selects the most important visual evidence for the input text query by (i) scoring visual tokens via cross-attention, (ii) \emph{predicting} an instance-specific retention budget based on the complexity of the query, and (iii) \emph{selecting} Top-$n$ tokens with a differentiable straight-through estimator during training and a hard gate at inference. Furthermore, a small re-encoder preserves temporal order using absolute time information, enabling second-level localization while maintaining global coverage. Integrated into Qwen2.5-VL, QTSplus compresses the vision stream by up to \textbf{89\%} and reduces end-to-end latency by \textbf{28\%} on long videos. The evaluation on eight long video understanding benchmarks shows near-parity accuracy overall when compared with the original Qwen models and outperforms the original model by \textbf{+20.5} and \textbf{+5.6} points respectively on TempCompass direction and order accuracies. These results show that QTSplus is an effective, general mechanism for scaling MLLMs to real-world long-video scenarios while preserving task-relevant evidence.</description><author>Siyou Li, Huanan Wu, Juexi Shao, Yinghao Ma, Yujian Gan, Yihao Luo, Yuwei Wang, Dong Nie, Lu Wang, Wengqing Wu, Le Zhang, Massimo Poesio, Juntao Yu</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:08:33 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.11910v2</guid></item><item><title>Beyond Multiple Choice: A Hybrid Framework for Unifying Robust Evaluation and Verifiable Reasoning Training</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17405v1</link><description>Multiple-choice question answering (MCQA) has been a popular format for evaluating and reinforcement fine-tuning (RFT) of modern multimodal language models. Its constrained output format allows for simplified, deterministic automatic verification. However, we find that the options may leak exploitable signals, which makes the accuracy metrics unreliable for indicating real capabilities and encourages explicit or implicit answer guessing behaviors during RFT. We propose ReVeL (Rewrite and Verify by LLM), a framework that rewrites multiple-choice questions into open-form questions while keeping answers verifiable whenever possible. The framework categorizes questions according to different answer types, apply different rewriting and verification schemes, respectively. When applied for RFT, we converted 20k MCQA examples and use GRPO to finetune Qwen2.5-VL models. Models trained on ReVeL-OpenQA match MCQA accuracy on multiple-choice benchmarks and improve OpenQA accuracy by about six percentage points, indicating better data efficiency and more robust reward signals than MCQA-based training. When used for evaluation, ReVeL also reveals up to 20 percentage points of score inflation in MCQA benchmarks (relative to OpenQA), improves judging accuracy, and reduces both cost and latency. We will release code and data publicly.</description><author>Yesheng Liu, Hao Li, Haiyu Xu, Baoqi Pei, Jiahao Wang, Mingxuan Zhao, Jingshu Zheng, Zheqi He, JG Yao, Bowen Qin, Xi Yang, Jiajun Zhang</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:06:37 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17405v1</guid></item><item><title>Minimax Statistical Estimation under Wasserstein Contamination</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2308.01853v3</link><description>Contaminations are a key concern in modern statistical learning, as small but systematic perturbations of all datapoints can substantially alter estimation results. Here, we study Wasserstein-$r$ contaminations ($r\ge 1$) in an $\ell_q$ norm ($q\in [1,\infty]$), in which each observation may undergo an adversarial perturbation with bounded cost, complementing the classical Huber model, corresponding to total variation norm, where only a fraction of observations is arbitrarily corrupted. We study both independent and joint (coordinated) contaminations and develop a minimax theory under $\ell_q^r$ losses. Our analysis encompasses several fundamental problems: location estimation, linear regression, and pointwise nonparametric density estimation. For joint contaminations in location estimation and for prediction in linear regression, we obtain the exact minimax risk, identify least favorable contaminations, and show that the sample mean and least squares predictor are respectively minimax optimal. For location estimation under independent contaminations, we give sharp upper and lower bounds, including exact minimaxity in the Euclidean Wasserstein contamination case, when $q=r=2$. For pointwise density estimation in any dimension, we derive the optimal rate, showing that it is achieved by kernel density estimation with a bandwidth that is possibly larger than the classical one. Our proofs leverage powerful tools from optimal transport developed over the last 20 years, including the dynamic Benamou-Brenier formulation. Taken together, our results suggest that in contrast to the Huber contamination model, for norm-based Wasserstein contaminations, classical estimators may be nearly optimally robust.</description><author>Patrick Chao, Edgar Dobriban</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:03:29 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2308.01853v3</guid></item><item><title>PUCP-Metrix: A Comprehensive Open-Source Repository of Linguistic Metrics for Spanish</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17402v1</link><description>Linguistic features remain essential for interpretability and tasks involving style, structure, and readability, but existing Spanish tools offer limited coverage. We present PUCP-Metrix, an open-source repository of 182 linguistic metrics spanning lexical diversity, syntactic and semantic complexity, cohesion, psycholinguistics, and readability. PUCP-Metrix enables fine-grained, interpretable text analysis. We evaluate its usefulness on Automated Readability Assessment and Machine-Generated Text Detection, showing competitive performance compared to an existing repository and strong neural baselines. PUCP-Metrix offers a comprehensive, extensible resource for Spanish, supporting diverse NLP applications.</description><author>Javier Alonso Villegas Luis, Marco Antonio Sobrevilla Cabezudo</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:03:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17402v1</guid></item><item><title>Sparse Mixture-of-Experts for Multi-Channel Imaging: Are All Channel Interactions Required?</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17400v1</link><description>Vision Transformers ($\text{ViTs}$) have become the backbone of vision foundation models, yet their optimization for multi-channel domains - such as cell painting or satellite imagery - remains underexplored. A key challenge in these domains is capturing interactions between channels, as each channel carries different information. While existing works have shown efficacy by treating each channel independently during tokenization, this approach naturally introduces a major computational bottleneck in the attention block - channel-wise comparisons leads to a quadratic growth in attention, resulting in excessive $\text{FLOPs}$ and high training cost. In this work, we shift focus from efficacy to the overlooked efficiency challenge in cross-channel attention and ask: "Is it necessary to model all channel interactions?". Inspired by the philosophy of Sparse Mixture-of-Experts ($\text{MoE}$), we propose MoE-ViT, a Mixture-of-Experts architecture for multi-channel images in $\text{ViTs}$, which treats each channel as an expert and employs a lightweight router to select only the most relevant experts per patch for attention. Proof-of-concept experiments on real-world datasets - JUMP-CP and So2Sat - demonstrate that $\text{MoE-ViT}$ achieves substantial efficiency gains without sacrificing, and in some cases enhancing, performance, making it a practical and attractive backbone for multi-channel imaging.</description><author>Sukwon Yun, Heming Yao, Burkhard Hoeckendorf, David Richmond, Aviv Regev, Russell Littman</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:00:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17400v1</guid></item><item><title>Stable Coresets via Posterior Sampling: Aligning Induced and Full Loss Landscapes</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17399v1</link><description>As deep learning models continue to scale, the growing computational demands have amplified the need for effective coreset selection techniques. Coreset selection aims to accelerate training by identifying small, representative subsets of data that approximate the performance of the full dataset. Among various approaches, gradient based methods stand out due to their strong theoretical underpinnings and practical benefits, particularly under limited data budgets. However, these methods face challenges such as naive stochastic gradient descent (SGD) acting as a surprisingly strong baseline and the breakdown of representativeness due to loss curvature mismatches over time. In this work, we propose a novel framework that addresses these limitations. First, we establish a connection between posterior sampling and loss landscapes, enabling robust coreset selection even in high data corruption scenarios. Second, we introduce a smoothed loss function based on posterior sampling onto the model weights, enhancing stability and generalization while maintaining computational efficiency. We also present a novel convergence analysis for our sampling-based coreset selection method. Finally, through extensive experiments, we demonstrate how our approach achieves faster training and enhanced generalization across diverse datasets than the current state of the art.</description><author>Wei-Kai Chang, Rajiv Khanna</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17399v1</guid></item><item><title>SHIELD: Secure Hypernetworks for Incremental Expansion Learning Defense</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.08255v3</link><description>Continual learning under adversarial conditions remains an open problem, as existing methods often compromise either robustness, scalability, or both. We propose a novel framework that integrates Interval Bound Propagation (IBP) with a hypernetwork-based architecture to enable certifiably robust continual learning across sequential tasks. Our method, SHIELD, generates task-specific model parameters via a shared hypernetwork conditioned solely on compact task embeddings, eliminating the need for replay buffers or full model copies and enabling efficient over time. To further enhance robustness, we introduce Interval MixUp, a novel training strategy that blends virtual examples represented as $\ell_{\infty}$ balls centered around MixUp points. Leveraging interval arithmetic, this technique guarantees certified robustness while mitigating the wrapping effect, resulting in smoother decision boundaries. We evaluate SHIELD under strong white-box adversarial attacks, including PGD and AutoAttack, across multiple benchmarks. It consistently outperforms existing robust continual learning methods, achieving state-of-the-art average accuracy while maintaining both scalability and certification. These results represent a significant step toward practical and theoretically grounded continual learning in adversarial settings.</description><author>Patryk Krukowski, Łukasz Gorczyca, Piotr Helm, Kamil Książek, Przemysław Spurek</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:58:45 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.08255v3</guid></item><item><title>Value of Information-Enhanced Exploration in Bootstrapped DQN</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.02969v2</link><description>Efficient exploration in deep reinforcement learning remains a fundamental challenge, especially in environments characterized by high-dimensional states and sparse rewards. Traditional exploration strategies that rely on random local policy noise, such as $ε$-greedy and Boltzmann exploration methods, often struggle to efficiently balance exploration and exploitation. In this paper, we integrate the notion of (expected) value of information (EVOI) within the well-known Bootstrapped DQN algorithmic framework, to enhance the algorithm's deep exploration ability. Specifically, we develop two novel algorithms that incorporate the expected gain from learning the value of information into Bootstrapped DQN. Our methods use value of information estimates to measure the discrepancies of opinions among distinct network heads, and drive exploration towards areas with the most potential. We evaluate our algorithms with respect to performance and their ability to exploit inherent uncertainty arising from random network initialization. Our experiments in complex, sparse-reward Atari games demonstrate increased performance, all the while making better use of uncertainty, and, importantly, without introducing extra hyperparameters.</description><author>Stergios Plataniotis, Charilaos Akasiadis, Georgios Chalkiadakis</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:56:52 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.02969v2</guid></item><item><title>MCMoE: Completing Missing Modalities with Mixture of Experts for Incomplete Multimodal Action Quality Assessment</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17397v1</link><description>Multimodal Action Quality Assessment (AQA) has recently emerged as a promising paradigm. By leveraging complementary information across shared contextual cues, it enhances the discriminative evaluation of subtle intra-class variations in highly similar action sequences. However, partial modalities are frequently unavailable at the inference stage in reality. The absence of any modality often renders existing multimodal models inoperable. Furthermore, it triggers catastrophic performance degradation due to interruptions in cross-modal interactions. To address this issue, we propose a novel Missing Completion Framework with Mixture of Experts (MCMoE) that unifies unimodal and joint representation learning in single-stage training. Specifically, we propose an adaptive gated modality generator that dynamically fuses available information to reconstruct missing modalities. We then design modality experts to learn unimodal knowledge and dynamically mix the knowledge of all experts to extract cross-modal joint representations. With a mixture of experts, missing modalities are further refined and complemented. Finally, in the training phase, we mine the complete multimodal features and unimodal expert knowledge to guide modality generation and generation-based joint representation extraction. Extensive experiments demonstrate that our MCMoE achieves state-of-the-art results in both complete and incomplete multimodal learning on three public AQA benchmarks. Code is available at https://github.com/XuHuangbiao/MCMoE.</description><author>Huangbiao Xu, Huanqi Wu, Xiao Ke, Junyi Wu, Rui Xu, Jinglin Xu</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:56:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17397v1</guid></item><item><title>Designing and Generating Diverse, Equitable Face Image Datasets for Face Verification Tasks</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17393v1</link><description>Face verification is a significant component of identity authentication in various applications including online banking and secure access to personal devices. The majority of the existing face image datasets often suffer from notable biases related to race, gender, and other demographic characteristics, limiting the effectiveness and fairness of face verification systems. In response to these challenges, we propose a comprehensive methodology that integrates advanced generative models to create varied and diverse high-quality synthetic face images. This methodology emphasizes the representation of a diverse range of facial traits, ensuring adherence to characteristics permissible in identity card photographs. Furthermore, we introduce the Diverse and Inclusive Faces for Verification (DIF-V) dataset, comprising 27,780 images of 926 unique identities, designed as a benchmark for future research in face verification. Our analysis reveals that existing verification models exhibit biases toward certain genders and races, and notably, applying identity style modifications negatively impacts model performance. By tackling the inherent inequities in existing datasets, this work not only enriches the discussion on diversity and ethics in artificial intelligence but also lays the foundation for developing more inclusive and reliable face verification technologies</description><author>Georgia Baltsou, Ioannis Sarridis, Christos Koutlis, Symeon Papadopoulos</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:53:08 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17393v1</guid></item><item><title>MorphSeek: Fine-grained Latent Representation-Level Policy Optimization for Deformable Image Registration</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17392v1</link><description>Deformable image registration (DIR) remains a fundamental yet challenging problem in medical image analysis, largely due to the prohibitively high-dimensional deformation space of dense displacement fields and the scarcity of voxel-level supervision. Existing reinforcement learning frameworks often project this space into coarse, low-dimensional representations, limiting their ability to capture spatially variant deformations. We propose MorphSeek, a fine-grained representation-level policy optimization paradigm that reformulates DIR as a spatially continuous optimization process in the latent feature space. MorphSeek introduces a stochastic Gaussian policy head atop the encoder to model a distribution over latent features, facilitating efficient exploration and coarse-to-fine refinement. The framework integrates unsupervised warm-up with weakly supervised fine-tuning through Group Relative Policy Optimization, where multi-trajectory sampling stabilizes training and improves label efficiency. Across three 3D registration benchmarks (OASIS brain MRI, LiTS liver CT, and Abdomen MR-CT), MorphSeek achieves consistent Dice improvements over competitive baselines while maintaining high label efficiency with minimal parameter cost and low step-level latency overhead. Beyond optimizer specifics, MorphSeek advances a representation-level policy learning paradigm that achieves spatially coherent and data-efficient deformation optimization, offering a principled, backbone-agnostic, and optimizer-agnostic solution for scalable visual alignment in high-dimensional settings.</description><author>Runxun Zhang, Yizhou Liu, Li Dongrui, Bo XU, Jingwei Wei</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:52:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17392v1</guid></item><item><title>Selective Rotary Position Embedding</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17388v1</link><description>Position information is essential for language modeling. In softmax transformers, Rotary Position Embeddings (\textit{RoPE}) encode positions through \textit{fixed-angle} rotations, while in linear transformers, order is handled via input-dependent (selective) gating that decays past key-value associations. Selectivity has generally been shown to improve language-related tasks. Inspired by this, we introduce \textit{Selective RoPE}, an \textit{input-dependent} rotary embedding mechanism, that generalizes \textit{RoPE}, and enables rotation in \textit{arbitrary angles} for both linear and softmax transformers. We show that softmax attention already performs a hidden form of these rotations on query-key pairs, uncovering an implicit positional structure. We further show that in state-space models and gated linear transformers, the real part manages forgetting while the imaginary part encodes positions through rotations. We validate our method by equipping gated transformers with \textit{Selective RoPE}, demonstrating that its input-dependent rotations improve performance in language modeling and on difficult sequence tasks like copying, state tracking, and retrieval.</description><author>Sajad Movahedi, Timur Carstensen, Arshia Afzal, Frank Hutter, Antonio Orvieto, Volkan Cevher</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:50:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17388v1</guid></item><item><title>IndustryNav: Exploring Spatial Reasoning of Embodied Agents in Dynamic Industrial Navigation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17384v1</link><description>While Visual Large Language Models (VLLMs) show great promise as embodied agents, they continue to face substantial challenges in spatial reasoning. Existing embodied benchmarks largely focus on passive, static household environments and evaluate only isolated capabilities, failing to capture holistic performance in dynamic, real-world complexity. To fill this gap, we present IndustryNav, the first dynamic industrial navigation benchmark for active spatial reasoning. IndustryNav leverages 12 manually created, high-fidelity Unity warehouse scenarios featuring dynamic objects and human movement. Our evaluation employs a PointGoal navigation pipeline that effectively combines egocentric vision with global odometry to assess holistic local-global planning. Crucially, we introduce the "collision rate" and "warning rate" metrics to measure safety-oriented behaviors and distance estimation. A comprehensive study of nine state-of-the-art VLLMs (including models such as GPT-5-mini, Claude-4.5, and Gemini-2.5) reveals that closed-source models maintain a consistent advantage; however, all agents exhibit notable deficiencies in robust path planning, collision avoidance and active exploration. This highlights a critical need for embodied research to move beyond passive perception and toward tasks that demand stable planning, active exploration, and safe behavior in dynamic, real-world environment.</description><author>Yifan Li, Lichi Li, Anh Dao, Xinyu Zhou, Yicheng Qiao, Zheda Mai, Daeun Lee, Zichen Chen, Zhen Tan, Mohit Bansal, Yu Kong</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:48:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17384v1</guid></item><item><title>Non-Parametric Probabilistic Robustness: A Conservative Metric with Optimized Perturbation Distributions</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17380v1</link><description>Deep learning (DL) models, despite their remarkable success, remain vulnerable to small input perturbations that can cause erroneous outputs, motivating the recent proposal of probabilistic robustness (PR) as a complementary alternative to adversarial robustness (AR). However, existing PR formulations assume a fixed and known perturbation distribution, an unrealistic expectation in practice. To address this limitation, we propose non-parametric probabilistic robustness (NPPR), a more practical PR metric that does not rely on any predefined perturbation distribution. Following the non-parametric paradigm in statistical modeling, NPPR learns an optimized perturbation distribution directly from data, enabling conservative PR evaluation under distributional uncertainty. We further develop an NPPR estimator based on a Gaussian Mixture Model (GMM) with Multilayer Perceptron (MLP) heads and bicubic up-sampling, covering various input-dependent and input-independent perturbation scenarios. Theoretical analyses establish the relationships among AR, PR, and NPPR. Extensive experiments on CIFAR-10, CIFAR-100, and Tiny ImageNet across ResNet18/50, WideResNet50 and VGG16 validate NPPR as a more practical robustness metric, showing up to 40\% more conservative (lower) PR estimates compared to assuming those common perturbation distributions used in state-of-the-arts.</description><author>Zheng Wang, Yi Zhang, Siddartha Khastgir, Carsten Maple, Xingyu Zhao</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:44:01 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17380v1</guid></item><item><title>A Unified Stability Analysis of SAM vs SGD: Role of Data Coherence and Emergence of Simplicity Bias</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17378v1</link><description>Understanding the dynamics of optimization in deep learning is increasingly important as models scale. While stochastic gradient descent (SGD) and its variants reliably find solutions that generalize well, the mechanisms driving this generalization remain unclear. Notably, these algorithms often prefer flatter or simpler minima, particularly in overparameterized settings. Prior work has linked flatness to generalization, and methods like Sharpness-Aware Minimization (SAM) explicitly encourage flatness, but a unified theory connecting data structure, optimization dynamics, and the nature of learned solutions is still lacking. In this work, we develop a linear stability framework that analyzes the behavior of SGD, random perturbations, and SAM, particularly in two layer ReLU networks. Central to our analysis is a coherence measure that quantifies how gradient curvature aligns across data points, revealing why certain minima are stable and favored during training.</description><author>Wei-Kai Chang, Rajiv Khanna</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:41:14 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17378v1</guid></item><item><title>Evaluating AI-Driven Automated Map Digitization in QGIS</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.18777v3</link><description>Map digitization is an important process that converts maps into digital formats that can be used for further analysis. This process typically requires a deep human involvement because of the need for interpretation and decision-making when translating complex features. With the advancement of artificial intelligence, there is an alternative to conducting map digitization with the help of machine learning techniques. Deepness, or Deep Neural Remote Sensing, is an advanced AI-driven tool designed and integrated as a plugin in QGIS application. This research focuses on assessing the effectiveness of Deepness in automated digitization. This study analyses AI-generated digitization results from Google Earth imagery and compares them with digitized outputs from OpenStreetMap (OSM) to evaluate performance.</description><author>Diana Febrita</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:41:05 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.18777v3</guid></item><item><title>Quantum Masked Autoencoders for Vision Learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17372v1</link><description>Classical autoencoders are widely used to learn features of input data. To improve the feature learning, classical masked autoencoders extend classical autoencoders to learn the features of the original input sample in the presence of masked-out data. While quantum autoencoders exist, there is no design and implementation of quantum masked autoencoders that can leverage the benefits of quantum computing and quantum autoencoders. In this paper, we propose quantum masked autoencoders (QMAEs) that can effectively learn missing features of a data sample within quantum states instead of classical embeddings. We showcase that our QMAE architecture can learn the masked features of an image and can reconstruct the masked input image with improved visual fidelity in MNIST images. Experimental evaluation highlights that QMAE can significantly outperform (12.86% on average) in classification accuracy compared to state-of-the-art quantum autoencoders in the presence of masks.</description><author>Emma Andrews, Prabhat Mishra</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:37:18 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17372v1</guid></item><item><title>R2PS: Worst-Case Robust Real-Time Pursuit Strategies under Partial Observability</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17367v1</link><description>Computing worst-case robust strategies in pursuit-evasion games (PEGs) is time-consuming, especially when real-world factors like partial observability are considered. While important for general security purposes, real-time applicable pursuit strategies for graph-based PEGs are currently missing when the pursuers only have imperfect information about the evader's position. Although state-of-the-art reinforcement learning (RL) methods like Equilibrium Policy Generalization (EPG) and Grasper provide guidelines for learning graph neural network (GNN) policies robust to different game dynamics, they are restricted to the scenario of perfect information and do not take into account the possible case where the evader can predict the pursuers' actions. This paper introduces the first approach to worst-case robust real-time pursuit strategies (R2PS) under partial observability. We first prove that a traditional dynamic programming (DP) algorithm for solving Markov PEGs maintains optimality under the asynchronous moves by the evader. Then, we propose a belief preservation mechanism about the evader's possible positions, extending the DP pursuit strategies to a partially observable setting. Finally, we embed the belief preservation into the state-of-the-art EPG framework to finish our R2PS learning scheme, which leads to a real-time pursuer policy through cross-graph reinforcement learning against the asynchronous-move DP evasion strategies. After reinforcement learning, our policy achieves robust zero-shot generalization to unseen real-world graph structures and consistently outperforms the policy directly trained on the test graphs by the existing game RL approach.</description><author>Runyu Lu, Ruochuan Shi, Yuanheng Zhu, Dongbin Zhao</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:34:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17367v1</guid></item><item><title>METIS: Multi-Source Egocentric Training for Integrated Dexterous Vision-Language-Action Model</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17366v1</link><description>Building a generalist robot that can perceive, reason, and act across diverse tasks remains an open challenge, especially for dexterous manipulation. A major bottleneck lies in the scarcity of large-scale, action-annotated data for dexterous skills, as teleoperation is difficult and costly. Human data, with its vast scale and diverse manipulation behaviors, provides rich priors for learning robotic actions. While prior works have explored leveraging human demonstrations, they are often constrained by limited scenarios and a large visual gap between human and robots. To eliminate these limitations, we propose METIS, a vision-language-action (VLA) model for dexterous manipulation pretrained on multi-source egocentric datasets. We first construct EgoAtlas, which integrates large-scale human and robotic data from multiple sources, all unified under a consistent action space. We further extract motion-aware dynamics, a compact and discretized motion representation, which provides efficient and expressive supervision for VLA training. Built upon them, METIS integrates reasoning and acting into a unified framework, enabling effective deployment to downstream dexterous manipulation tasks. Our method demonstrates exceptional dexterous manipulation capabilities, achieving highest average success rate in six real-world tasks. Experimental results also highlight the superior generalization and robustness to out-of-distribution scenarios. These findings emphasize METIS as a promising step toward a generalist model for dexterous manipulation.</description><author>Yankai Fu, Ning Chen, Junkai Zhao, Shaozhe Shan, Guocai Yao, Pengwei Wang, Zhongyuan Wang, Shanghang Zhang</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:32:36 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17366v1</guid></item><item><title>SVRecon: Sparse Voxel Rasterization for Surface Reconstruction</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17364v1</link><description>We extend the recently proposed sparse voxel rasterization paradigm to the task of high-fidelity surface reconstruction by integrating Signed Distance Function (SDF), named SVRecon. Unlike 3D Gaussians, sparse voxels are spatially disentangled from their neighbors and have sharp boundaries, which makes them prone to local minima during optimization. Although SDF values provide a naturally smooth and continuous geometric field, preserving this smoothness across independently parameterized sparse voxels is nontrivial. To address this challenge, we promote coherent and smooth voxel-wise structure through (1) robust geometric initialization using a visual geometry model and (2) a spatial smoothness loss that enforces coherent relationships across parent-child and sibling voxel groups. Extensive experiments across various benchmarks show that our method achieves strong reconstruction accuracy while having consistently speedy convergence. The code will be made public.</description><author>Seunghun Oh, Jaesung Choe, Dongjae Lee, Daeun Lee, Seunghoon Jeong, Yu-Chiang Frank Wang, Jaesik Park</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:32:01 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17364v1</guid></item><item><title>Crafting Imperceptible On-Manifold Adversarial Attacks for Tabular Data</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.10998v3</link><description>Adversarial attacks on tabular data present unique challenges due to the heterogeneous nature of mixed categorical and numerical features. Unlike images where pixel perturbations maintain visual similarity, tabular data lacks intuitive similarity metrics, making it difficult to define imperceptible modifications. Additionally, traditional gradient-based methods prioritise $\ell_p$-norm constraints, often producing adversarial examples that deviate from the original data distributions. To address this, we propose a latent-space perturbation framework using a mixed-input Variational Autoencoder (VAE) to generate statistically consistent adversarial examples. The proposed VAE integrates categorical embeddings and numerical features into a unified latent manifold, enabling perturbations that preserve statistical consistency. We introduce In-Distribution Success Rate (IDSR) to jointly evaluate attack effectiveness and distributional alignment. Evaluation across six publicly available datasets and three model architectures demonstrates that our method achieves substantially lower outlier rates and more consistent performance compared to traditional input-space attacks and other VAE-based methods adapted from image domain approaches, achieving substantially lower outlier rates and higher IDSR across six datasets and three model architectures. Our comprehensive analyses of hyperparameter sensitivity, sparsity control, and generative architecture demonstrate that the effectiveness of VAE-based attacks depends strongly on reconstruction quality and the availability of sufficient training data. When these conditions are met, the proposed framework achieves superior practical utility and stability compared with input-space methods. This work underscores the importance of maintaining on-manifold perturbations for generating realistic and robust adversarial examples in tabular domains.</description><author>Zhipeng He, Alexander Stevens, Chun Ouyang, Johannes De Smedt, Alistair Barros, Catarina Moreira</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:31:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.10998v3</guid></item><item><title>ATAC: Augmentation-Based Test-Time Adversarial Correction for CLIP</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17362v1</link><description>Despite its remarkable success in zero-shot image-text matching, CLIP remains highly vulnerable to adversarial perturbations on images. As adversarial fine-tuning is prohibitively costly, recent works explore various test-time defense strategies; however, these approaches still exhibit limited robustness. In this work, we revisit this problem and propose a simple yet effective strategy: Augmentation-based Test-time Adversarial Correction (ATAC). Our method operates directly in the embedding space of CLIP, calculating augmentation-induced drift vectors to infer a semantic recovery direction and correcting the embedding based on the angular consistency of these latent drifts. Across a wide range of benchmarks, ATAC consistently achieves remarkably high robustness, surpassing that of previous state-of-the-art methods by nearly 50\% on average, all while requiring minimal computational overhead. Furthermore, ATAC retains state-of-the-art robustness in unconventional and extreme settings and even achieves nontrivial robustness against adaptive attacks. Our results demonstrate that ATAC is an efficient method in a novel paradigm for test-time adversarial defenses in the embedding space of CLIP.</description><author>Linxiang Su, András Balogh</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:30:06 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17362v1</guid></item><item><title>SuperQuadricOcc: Multi-Layer Gaussian Approximation of Superquadrics for Real-Time Self-Supervised Occupancy Estimation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17361v1</link><description>Semantic occupancy estimation enables comprehensive scene understanding for automated driving, providing dense spatial and semantic information essential for perception and planning. While Gaussian representations have been widely adopted in self-supervised occupancy estimation, the deployment of a large number of Gaussian primitives drastically increases memory requirements and is not suitable for real-time inference. In contrast, superquadrics permit reduced primitive count and lower memory requirements due to their diverse shape set. However, implementation into a self-supervised occupancy model is nontrivial due to the absence of a superquadric rasterizer to enable model supervision. Our proposed method, SuperQuadricOcc, employs a superquadric-based scene representation. By leveraging a multi-layer icosphere-tessellated Gaussian approximation of superquadrics, we enable Gaussian rasterization for supervision during training. On the Occ3D dataset, SuperQuadricOcc achieves a 75\% reduction in memory footprint, 124\% faster inference, and a 5.9\% improvement in mIoU compared to previous Gaussian-based methods, without the use of temporal labels. To our knowledge, this is the first occupancy model to enable real-time inference while maintaining competitive performance. The use of superquadrics reduces the number of primitives required for scene modeling by 84\% relative to Gaussian-based approaches. Finally, evaluation against prior methods is facilitated by our fast superquadric voxelization module. The code will be released as open source.</description><author>Seamie Hayes, Reenu Mohandas, Tim Brophy, Alexandre Boulch, Ganesh Sistu, Ciaran Eising</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:26:31 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17361v1</guid></item><item><title>A Training-Free Style-Personalization via SVD-Based Feature Decomposition</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.04482v2</link><description>We present a training-free framework for style-personalized image generation that operates during inference using a scale-wise autoregressive model. Our method generates a stylized image guided by a single reference style while preserving semantic consistency and mitigating content leakage. Through a detailed step-wise analysis of the generation process, we identify a pivotal step where the dominant singular values of the internal feature encode style-related components. Building upon this insight, we introduce two lightweight control modules: Principal Feature Blending, which enables precise modulation of style through SVD-based feature reconstruction, and Structural Attention Correction, which stabilizes structural consistency by leveraging content-guided attention correction across fine stages. Without any additional training, extensive experiments demonstrate that our method achieves competitive style fidelity and prompt fidelity compared to fine-tuned baselines, while offering faster inference and greater deployment flexibility.</description><author>Kyoungmin Lee, Jihun Park, Jongmin Gim, Wonhyeok Choi, Kyumin Hwang, Jaeyeul Kim, Sunghoon Im</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:25:35 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.04482v2</guid></item><item><title>Don't Learn, Ground: A Case for Natural Language Inference with Visual Grounding</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17358v1</link><description>We propose a zero-shot method for Natural Language Inference (NLI) that leverages multimodal representations by grounding language in visual contexts. Our approach generates visual representations of premises using text-to-image models and performs inference by comparing these representations with textual hypotheses. We evaluate two inference techniques: cosine similarity and visual question answering. Our method achieves high accuracy without task-specific fine-tuning, demonstrating robustness against textual biases and surface heuristics. Additionally, we design a controlled adversarial dataset to validate the robustness of our approach. Our findings suggest that leveraging visual modality as a meaning representation provides a promising direction for robust natural language understanding.</description><author>Daniil Ignatev, Ayman Santeer, Albert Gatt, Denis Paperno</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:23:17 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17358v1</guid></item><item><title>UAM: A Unified Attention-Mamba Backbone of Multimodal Framework for Tumor Cell Classification</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17355v1</link><description>Cell-level radiomics features provide fine-grained insights into tumor phenotypes and have the potential to significantly enhance diagnostic accuracy on hematoxylin and eosin (H&amp;E) images. By capturing micro-level morphological and intensity patterns, these features support more precise tumor identification and improve AI interpretability by highlighting diagnostically relevant cells for pathologist review. However, most existing studies focus on slide-level or patch-level tumor classification, leaving cell-level radiomics analysis largely unexplored. Moreover, there is currently no dedicated backbone specifically designed for radiomics data. Inspired by the recent success of the Mamba architecture in vision and language domains, we introduce a Unified Attention-Mamba (UAM) backbone for cell-level classification using radiomics features. Unlike previous hybrid approaches that integrate Attention and Mamba modules in fixed proportions, our unified design flexibly combines their capabilities within a single cohesive architecture, eliminating the need for manual ratio tuning and improving encode capability. We develop two UAM variants to comprehensively evaluate the benefits of this unified structure. Building on this backbone, we further propose a multimodal UAM framework that jointly performs cell-level classification and image segmentation. Experimental results demonstrate that UAM achieves state-of-the-art performance across both tasks on public benchmarks, surpassing leading image-based foundation models. It improves cell classification accuracy from 74% to 78% ($n$=349,882 cells), and tumor segmentation precision from 75% to 80% ($n$=406 patches). These findings highlight the effectiveness and promise of UAM as a unified and extensible multimodal foundation for radiomics-driven cancer diagnosis.</description><author>Taixi Chen, Jingyun Chen, Nancy Guo</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:18:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17355v1</guid></item><item><title>DSeq-JEPA: Discriminative Sequential Joint-Embedding Predictive Architecture</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17354v1</link><description>Image-based Joint-Embedding Predictive Architecture (I-JEPA) learns visual representations by predicting latent embeddings of masked regions from visible context. However, it treats all regions uniformly and independently, lacking an explicit notion of where or in what order predictions should be made. Inspired by human visual perception, which deploys attention selectively and sequentially from the most informative to secondary regions, we propose DSeq-JEPA, a Discriminative Sequential Joint-Embedding Predictive Architecture that bridges predictive and autoregressive self-supervised learning, integrating JEPA-style latent prediction with GPT-style sequential reasoning. Specifically, DSeq-JEPA (i) first identifies primary discriminative regions based on a transformer-derived saliency map, emphasizing the distribution of visual importance, and then (ii) predicts subsequent regions in this discriminative order, progressively forming a curriculum-like semantic progression from primary to secondary cues -- a form of GPT-style pre-training. Extensive experiments across diverse tasks, including image classification (ImageNet), fine-grained visual categorization (iNaturalist21, CUB-200-2011, Stanford-Cars), detection and segmentation (MS-COCO, ADE20K), and low-level reasoning tasks (Clevr/Count, Clevr/Dist), demonstrate that DSeq-JEPA consistently focuses on more discriminative and generalizable representations than I-JEPA variants. Project page: https://github.com/SkyShunsuke/DSeq-JEPA.</description><author>Xiangteng He, Shunsuke Sakai, Kun Yuan, Nicolas Padoy, Tatsuhito Hasegawa, Leonid Sigal</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:18:50 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17354v1</guid></item><item><title>Learning Latent Transmission and Glare Maps for Lens Veiling Glare Removal</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17353v1</link><description>Beyond the commonly recognized optical aberrations, the imaging performance of compact optical systems-including single-lens and metalens designs-is often further degraded by veiling glare caused by stray-light scattering from non-ideal optical surfaces and coatings, particularly in complex real-world environments. This compound degradation undermines traditional lens aberration correction yet remains underexplored. A major challenge is that conventional scattering models (e.g., for dehazing) fail to fit veiling glare due to its spatial-varying and depth-independent nature. Consequently, paired high-quality data are difficult to prepare via simulation, hindering application of data-driven veiling glare removal models. To this end, we propose VeilGen, a generative model that learns to simulate veiling glare by estimating its underlying optical transmission and glare maps in an unsupervised manner from target images, regularized by Stable Diffusion (SD)-based priors. VeilGen enables paired dataset generation with realistic compound degradation of optical aberrations and veiling glare, while also providing the estimated latent optical transmission and glare maps to guide the veiling glare removal process. We further introduce DeVeiler, a restoration network trained with a reversibility constraint, which utilizes the predicted latent maps to guide an inverse process of the learned scattering model. Extensive experiments on challenging compact optical systems demonstrate that our approach delivers superior restoration quality and physical fidelity compared with existing methods. These suggest that VeilGen reliably synthesizes realistic veiling glare, and its learned latent maps effectively guide the restoration process in DeVeiler. All code and datasets will be publicly released at https://github.com/XiaolongQian/DeVeiler.</description><author>Xiaolong Qian, Qi Jiang, Lei Sun, Zongxi Yu, Kailun Yang, Peixuan Wu, Jiacheng Zhou, Yao Gao, Yaoguang Ma, Ming-Hsuan Yang, Kaiwei Wang</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:16:30 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17353v1</guid></item><item><title>Convergence and stability of Q-learning in Hierarchical Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17351v1</link><description>Hierarchical Reinforcement Learning promises, among other benefits, to efficiently capture and utilize the temporal structure of a decision-making problem and to enhance continual learning capabilities, but theoretical guarantees lag behind practice. In this paper, we propose a Feudal Q-learning scheme and investigate under which conditions its coupled updates converge and are stable. By leveraging the theory of Stochastic Approximation and the ODE method, we present a theorem stating the convergence and stability properties of Feudal Q-learning. This provides a principled convergence and stability analysis tailored to Feudal RL. Moreover, we show that the updates converge to a point that can be interpreted as an equilibrium of a suitably defined game, opening the door to game-theoretic approaches to Hierarchical RL. Lastly, experiments based on the Feudal Q-learning algorithm support the outcomes anticipated by theory.</description><author>Massimiliano Manenti, Andrea Iannelli</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:13:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17351v1</guid></item><item><title>A Unified Voxel Diffusion Module for Point Cloud 3D Object Detection</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.16069v2</link><description>Recent advances in point cloud object detection have increasingly adopted Transformer-based and State Space Models (SSMs), demonstrating strong performance. However, voxelbased representations in these models require strict consistency in input and output dimensions due to their serialized processing, which limits the spatial diffusion capability typically offered by convolutional operations. This limitation significantly affects detection accuracy. Inspired by CNN-based object detection architectures, we propose a novel Voxel Diffusion Module (VDM) to enhance voxel-level representation and diffusion in point cloud data. VDM is composed of sparse 3D convolutions, submanifold sparse convolutions, and residual connections. To ensure computational efficiency, the output feature maps are downsampled to one-fourth of the original input resolution. VDM serves two primary functions: (1) diffusing foreground voxel features through sparse 3D convolutions to enrich spatial context, and (2) aggregating fine-grained spatial information to strengthen voxelwise feature representation. The enhanced voxel features produced by VDM can be seamlessly integrated into mainstream Transformer- or SSM-based detection models for accurate object classification and localization, highlighting the generalizability of our method. We evaluate VDM on several benchmark datasets by embedding it into both Transformerbased and SSM-based models. Experimental results show that our approach consistently improves detection accuracy over baseline models. Specifically, VDM-SSMs achieve 74.7 mAPH (L2) on Waymo, 72.9 NDS on nuScenes, 42.3 mAP on Argoverse 2, and 67.6 mAP on ONCE, setting new stateof-the-art performance across all datasets. Our code will be made publicly available.</description><author>Qifeng Liu, Dawei Zhao, Yabo Dong, Linzhi Shang, Liang Xiao, Juan Wang, Kunkong Zhao, Dongming Lu, Qi Zhu</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:08:58 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.16069v2</guid></item><item><title>Label-Efficient Skeleton-based Recognition with Stable-Invertible Graph Convolutional Networks</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17345v1</link><description>Skeleton-based action recognition is a hotspot in image processing. A key challenge of this task lies in its dependence on large, manually labeled datasets whose acquisition is costly and time-consuming. This paper devises a novel, label-efficient method for skeleton-based action recognition using graph convolutional networks (GCNs). The contribution of the proposed method resides in learning a novel acquisition function -- scoring the most informative subsets for labeling -- as the optimum of an objective function mixing data representativity, diversity and uncertainty. We also extend this approach by learning the most informative subsets using an invertible GCN which allows mapping data from ambient to latent spaces where the inherent distribution of the data is more easily captured. Extensive experiments, conducted on two challenging skeleton-based recognition datasets, show the effectiveness and the outperformance of our label-frugal GCNs against the related work.</description><author>Hichem Sahbi</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:06:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17345v1</guid></item><item><title>Loomis Painter: Reconstructing the Painting Process</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17344v1</link><description>Step-by-step painting tutorials are vital for learning artistic techniques, but existing video resources (e.g., YouTube) lack interactivity and personalization. While recent generative models have advanced artistic image synthesis, they struggle to generalize across media and often show temporal or structural inconsistencies, hindering faithful reproduction of human creative workflows. To address this, we propose a unified framework for multi-media painting process generation with a semantics-driven style control mechanism that embeds multiple media into a diffusion models conditional space and uses cross-medium style augmentation. This enables consistent texture evolution and process transfer across styles. A reverse-painting training strategy further ensures smooth, human-aligned generation. We also build a large-scale dataset of real painting processes and evaluate cross-media consistency, temporal coherence, and final-image fidelity, achieving strong results on LPIPS, DINO, and CLIP metrics. Finally, our Perceptual Distance Profile (PDP) curve quantitatively models the creative sequence, i.e., composition, color blocking, and detail refinement, mirroring human artistic progression.</description><author>Markus Pobitzer, Chang Liu, Chenyi Zhuang, Teng Long, Bin Ren, Nicu Sebe</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:06:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17344v1</guid></item><item><title>Refracting Reality: Generating Images with Realistic Transparent Objects</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17340v1</link><description>Generative image models can produce convincingly real images, with plausible shapes, textures, layouts and lighting. However, one domain in which they perform notably poorly is in the synthesis of transparent objects, which exhibit refraction, reflection, absorption and scattering. Refraction is a particular challenge, because refracted pixel rays often intersect with surfaces observed in other parts of the image, providing a constraint on the color. It is clear from inspection that generative models have not distilled the laws of optics sufficiently well to accurately render refractive objects. In this work, we consider the problem of generating images with accurate refraction, given a text prompt. We synchronize the pixels within the object's boundary with those outside by warping and merging the pixels using Snell's Law of Refraction, at each step of the generation trajectory. For those surfaces that are not directly observed in the image, but are visible via refraction or reflection, we recover their appearance by synchronizing the image with a second generated image -- a panorama centered at the object -- using the same warping and merging procedure. We demonstrate that our approach generates much more optically-plausible images that respect the physical constraints.</description><author>Yue Yin, Enze Tao, Dylan Campbell</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:02:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17340v1</guid></item><item><title>ReBaPL: Repulsive Bayesian Prompt Learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17339v1</link><description>Prompt learning has emerged as an effective technique for fine-tuning large-scale foundation models for downstream tasks. However, conventional prompt tuning methods are prone to overfitting and can struggle with out-of-distribution generalization. To address these limitations, Bayesian prompt learning has been proposed, which frames prompt optimization as a Bayesian inference problem to enhance robustness. This paper introduces Repulsive Bayesian Prompt Learning (ReBaPL), a novel method for Bayesian prompt learning, designed to efficiently explore the complex and often multimodal posterior landscape of prompts. Our method integrates a cyclical step-size schedule with a stochastic gradient Hamiltonian Monte Carlo (SGHMC) algorithm, enabling alternating phases of exploration to discover new modes, and exploitation to refine existing modes. Furthermore, we introduce a repulsive force derived from a potential function over probability metrics (including Maximum Mean Discrepancy and Wasserstein distance) computed on the distributions of representations produced by different prompts. This representation-space repulsion diversifies exploration and prevents premature collapse to a single mode. Our approach allows for a more comprehensive characterization of the prompt posterior distribution, leading to improved generalization. In contrast to prior Bayesian prompt learning methods, our method provides a modular plug-and-play Bayesian extension of any existing prompt learning method based on maximum likelihood estimation. We demonstrate the efficacy of ReBaPL on several benchmark datasets, showing superior performance over state-of-the-art methods for prompt learning.</description><author>Yassir Bendou, Omar Ezzahir, Eduardo Fernandes Montesuma, Gabriel Mahuas, Victoria Shevchenko, Mike Gartrell</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:00:13 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17339v1</guid></item><item><title>A new kid on the block: Distributional semantics predicts the word-specific tone signatures of monosyllabic words in conversational Taiwan Mandarin</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17337v1</link><description>We present a corpus-based investigation of how the pitch contours of monosyllabic words are realized in spontaneous conversational Mandarin, focusing on the effects of words' meanings. We used the generalized additive model to decompose a given observed pitch contour into a set of component pitch contours that are tied to different control variables and semantic predictors. Even when variables such as word duration, gender, speaker identity, tonal context, vowel height, and utterance position are controlled for, the effect of word remains a strong predictor of tonal realization. We present evidence that this effect of word is a semantic effect: word sense is shown to be a better predictor than word, and heterographic homophones are shown to have different pitch contours. The strongest evidence for the importance of semantics is that the pitch contours of individual word tokens can be predicted from their contextualized embeddings with an accuracy that substantially exceeds a permutation baseline. For phonetics, distributional semantics is a new kid on the block. Although our findings challenge standard theories of Mandarin tone, they fit well within the theoretical framework of the Discriminative Lexicon Model.</description><author>Xiaoyun Jin, Mirjam Ernestus, R. Harald Baayen</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:56:58 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17337v1</guid></item><item><title>Lung-DDPM+: Efficient Thoracic CT Image Synthesis using Diffusion Probabilistic Model</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.09327v2</link><description>Generative artificial intelligence (AI) has been playing an important role in various domains. Leveraging its high capability to generate high-fidelity and diverse synthetic data, generative AI is widely applied in diagnostic tasks, such as lung cancer diagnosis using computed tomography (CT). However, existing generative models for lung cancer diagnosis suffer from low efficiency and anatomical imprecision, which limit their clinical applicability. To address these drawbacks, we propose Lung-DDPM+, an improved version of our previous model, Lung-DDPM. This novel approach is a denoising diffusion probabilistic model (DDPM) guided by nodule semantic layouts and accelerated by a pulmonary DPM-solver, enabling the method to focus on lesion areas while achieving a better trade-off between sampling efficiency and quality. Evaluation results on the public LIDC-IDRI dataset suggest that the proposed method achieves 8$\times$ fewer FLOPs (floating point operations per second), 6.8$\times$ lower GPU memory consumption, and 14$\times$ faster sampling compared to Lung-DDPM. Moreover, it maintains comparable sample quality to both Lung-DDPM and other state-of-the-art (SOTA) generative models in two downstream segmentation tasks. We also conducted a Visual Turing Test by an experienced radiologist, showing the advanced quality and fidelity of synthetic samples generated by the proposed method. These experimental results demonstrate that Lung-DDPM+ can effectively generate high-quality thoracic CT images with lung nodules, highlighting its potential for broader applications, such as general tumor synthesis and lesion generation in medical imaging. The code and pretrained models are available at https://github.com/Manem-Lab/Lung-DDPM-PLUS.</description><author>Yifan Jiang, Ahmad Shariftabrizi, Venkata SK. Manem</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:55:52 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.09327v2</guid></item><item><title>Robot Confirmation Generation and Action Planning Using Long-context Q-Former Integrated with Multimodal LLM</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17335v1</link><description>Human-robot collaboration towards a shared goal requires robots to understand human action and interaction with the surrounding environment. This paper focuses on human-robot interaction (HRI) based on human-robot dialogue that relies on the robot action confirmation and action step generation using multimodal scene understanding. The state-of-the-art approach uses multimodal transformers to generate robot action steps aligned with robot action confirmation from a single clip showing a task composed of multiple micro steps. Although actions towards a long-horizon task depend on each other throughout an entire video, the current approaches mainly focus on clip-level processing and do not leverage long-context information. This paper proposes a long-context Q-former incorporating left and right context dependency in full videos. Furthermore, this paper proposes a text-conditioning approach to feed text embeddings directly into the LLM decoder to mitigate the high abstraction of the information in text by Q-former. Experiments with the YouCook2 corpus show that the accuracy of confirmation generation is a major factor in the performance of action planning. Furthermore, we demonstrate that the long-context Q-former improves the confirmation and action planning by integrating VideoLLaMA3.</description><author>Chiori Hori, Yoshiki Masuyama, Siddarth Jain, Radu Corcodel, Devesh Jha, Diego Romeres, Jonathan Le Roux</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:55:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17335v1</guid></item><item><title>Agentifying Agentic AI</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17332v1</link><description>Agentic AI seeks to endow systems with sustained autonomy, reasoning, and interaction capabilities. To realize this vision, its assumptions about agency must be complemented by explicit models of cognition, cooperation, and governance. This paper argues that the conceptual tools developed within the Autonomous Agents and Multi-Agent Systems (AAMAS) community, such as BDI architectures, communication protocols, mechanism design, and institutional modelling, provide precisely such a foundation. By aligning adaptive, data-driven approaches with structured models of reasoning and coordination, we outline a path toward agentic systems that are not only capable and flexible, but also transparent, cooperative, and accountable. The result is a perspective on agency that bridges formal theory and practical autonomy.</description><author>Virginia Dignum, Frank Dignum</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:54:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17332v1</guid></item><item><title>Meta-World+: An Improved, Standardized, RL Benchmark</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.11289v2</link><description>Meta-World is widely used for evaluating multi-task and meta-reinforcement learning agents, which are challenged to master diverse skills simultaneously. Since its introduction however, there have been numerous undocumented changes which inhibit a fair comparison of algorithms. This work strives to disambiguate these results from the literature, while also leveraging the past versions of Meta-World to provide insights into multi-task and meta-reinforcement learning benchmark design. Through this process we release a new open-source version of Meta-World (https://github.com/Farama-Foundation/Metaworld/) that has full reproducibility of past results, is more technically ergonomic, and gives users more control over the tasks that are included in a task set.</description><author>Reginald McLean, Evangelos Chatzaroulas, Luc McCutcheon, Frank Röder, Tianhe Yu, Zhanpeng He, K. R. Zentner, Ryan Julian, J K Terry, Isaac Woungang, Nariman Farsad, Pablo Samuel Castro</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:53:08 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.11289v2</guid></item><item><title>AI Workers, Geopolitics, and Algorithmic Collective Action</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17331v1</link><description>According to the theory of International Political Economy (IPE), states are often incentivized to rely on rather than constrain powerful corporations. For this reason, IPE provides a useful lens to explain why efforts to govern Artificial Intelligence (AI) at the international and national levels have thus far been developed, applied, and enforced unevenly. Building on recent work that explores how AI companies engage in geopolitics, this position paper argues that some AI workers can be considered actors of geopolitics. It makes the timely case that governance alone cannot ensure responsible, ethical, or robust AI development and use, and greater attention should be paid to bottom-up interventions at the site of AI development. AI workers themselves should be situated as individual agents of change, especially when considering their potential to foster Algorithmic Collective Action (ACA). Drawing on methods of Participatory Design (PD), this paper proposes engaging AI workers as sources of knowledge, relative power, and intentionality to encourage more responsible and just AI development and create the conditions that can facilitate ACA.</description><author>Sydney Reis</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:52:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17331v1</guid></item><item><title>Testing Hypotheses from the Social Approval Theory of Online Hate: An Analysis of 110 Million Messages from Parler</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.10810v2</link><description>We examined how online hate is motivated by receiving social approval via Walther's (2024) social approval theory of online hate, which argues (H1a) more signals of social approval on hate messages predicts more subsequent hate messages, and (H1b) as social approval increases, hate speech becomes more extreme. Using 110 million messages from Parler (2018-2021), we observed the number of upvotes received on a hate speech post was unassociated with hate speech in one's next post and during the next month, three-months, and six-months. The number of upvotes received on (extreme) hate speech comments, however, was positively associated with (extreme) hate speech during the next week, month, three-months, and six-months. Between-person effects revealed an average positive relationship between social approval and hate speech production at all time intervals. For comments, social approval linked more strongly to online hate than social disapproval. Social approval is a critical mechanism facilitating online hate propagation.</description><author>David M. Markowitz, Samuel Hardman Taylor</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:51:27 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.10810v2</guid></item><item><title>MusicAIR: A Multimodal AI Music Generation Framework Powered by an Algorithm-Driven Core</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17323v1</link><description>Recent advances in generative AI have made music generation a prominent research focus. However, many neural-based models rely on large datasets, raising concerns about copyright infringement and high-performance costs. In contrast, we propose MusicAIR, an innovative multimodal AI music generation framework powered by a novel algorithm-driven symbolic music core, effectively mitigating copyright infringement risks. The music core algorithms connect critical lyrical and rhythmic information to automatically derive musical features, creating a complete, coherent melodic score solely from the lyrics. The MusicAIR framework facilitates music generation from lyrics, text, and images. The generated score adheres to established principles of music theory, lyrical structure, and rhythmic conventions. We developed Generate AI Music (GenAIM), a web tool using MusicAIR for lyric-to-song, text-to-music, and image-to-music generation. In our experiments, we evaluated AI-generated music scores produced by the system using both standard music metrics and innovative analysis that compares these compositions with original works. The system achieves an average key confidence of 85%, outperforming human composers at 79%, and aligns closely with established music theory standards, demonstrating its ability to generate diverse, human-like compositions. As a co-pilot tool, GenAIM can serve as a reliable music composition assistant and a possible educational composition tutor while simultaneously lowering the entry barrier for all aspiring musicians, which is innovative and significantly contributes to AI for music generation.</description><author>Callie C. Liao, Duoduo Liao, Ellie L. Zhang</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:43:27 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17323v1</guid></item><item><title>NoPe-NeRF++: Local-to-Global Optimization of NeRF with No Pose Prior</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17322v1</link><description>In this paper, we introduce NoPe-NeRF++, a novel local-to-global optimization algorithm for training Neural Radiance Fields (NeRF) without requiring pose priors. Existing methods, particularly NoPe-NeRF, which focus solely on the local relationships within images, often struggle to recover accurate camera poses in complex scenarios. To overcome the challenges, our approach begins with a relative pose initialization with explicit feature matching, followed by a local joint optimization to enhance the pose estimation for training a more robust NeRF representation. This method significantly improves the quality of initial poses. Additionally, we introduce global optimization phase that incorporates geometric consistency constraints through bundle adjustment, which integrates feature trajectories to further refine poses and collectively boost the quality of NeRF. Notably, our method is the first work that seamlessly combines the local and global cues with NeRF, and outperforms state-of-the-art methods in both pose estimation accuracy and novel view synthesis. Extensive evaluations on benchmark datasets demonstrate our superior performance and robustness, even in challenging scenes, thus validating our design choices.</description><author>Dongbo Shi, Shen Cao, Bojian Wu, Jinhui Guo, Lubin Fan, Renjie Chen, Ligang Liu, Jieping Ye</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:41:51 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17322v1</guid></item><item><title>FORWARD: Dataset of a forwarder operating in rough terrain</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17318v1</link><description>We present FORWARD, a high-resolution multimodal dataset of a cut-to-length forwarder operating in rough terrain on two harvest sites in the middle part of Sweden. The forwarder is a large Komatsu model equipped with a variety of sensors, including RTK-GNSS, 360-camera, operator vibration sensors, internal CAN-bus signal recording, and multiple IMUs. The data includes event time logs recorded in 5 Hz with e.g., driving speed, fuel consumption, vehicle position with centimeter accuracy, and crane use while the vehicle operates in forest areas laser-scanned with very high-resolution, $\sim$1500 points per square meter. Production log files (StanForD standard) with time-stamped machine events, extensive video material, and terrain data in various formats are included as well. About 18 hours of regular wood extraction work during three days is annotated from 360-video material into individual work elements and included in the dataset. We also include scenario specifications of conducted experiments on forest roads and in terrain. Scenarios include repeatedly driving the same routes with and without steel tracks, different load weight, and different target driving speeds. The dataset is intended for developing models and algorithms for trafficability, perception, and autonomous control of forest machines using artificial intelligence, simulation, and experiments on physical testbeds. In part, we focus on forwarders traversing terrain, avoiding obstacles, and loading or unloading logs, with consideration for efficiency, fuel consumption, safety, and environmental impact. Other benefits of the open dataset include the ability to explore auto-generation and calibration of forestry machine simulators and automation scenario descriptions using the data recorded in the field.</description><author>Mikael Lundbäck, Erik Wallin, Carola Häggström, Mattias Nyström, Andreas Grönlund, Mats Richardson, Petrus Jönsson, William Arnvik, Lucas Hedström, Arvid Fälldin, Martin Servin</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:36:41 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17318v1</guid></item><item><title>Humanlike Multi-user Agent (HUMA): Designing a Deceptively Human AI Facilitator for Group Chats</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17315v1</link><description>Conversational agents built on large language models (LLMs) are becoming increasingly prevalent, yet most systems are designed for one-on-one, turn-based exchanges rather than natural, asynchronous group chats. As AI assistants become widespread throughout digital platforms, from virtual assistants to customer service, developing natural and humanlike interaction patterns seems crucial for maintaining user trust and engagement. We present the Humanlike Multi-user Agent (HUMA), an LLM-based facilitator that participates in multi-party conversations using human-like strategies and timing. HUMA extends prior multi-user chatbot work with an event-driven architecture that handles messages, replies, reactions and introduces realistic response-time simulation. HUMA comprises three components-Router, Action Agent, and Reflection-which together adapt LLMs to group conversation dynamics. We evaluate HUMA in a controlled study with 97 participants in four-person role-play chats, comparing AI and human community managers (CMs). Participants classified CMs as human at near-chance rates in both conditions, indicating they could not reliably distinguish HUMA agents from humans. Subjective experience was comparable across conditions: community-manager effectiveness, social presence, and engagement/satisfaction differed only modestly with small effect sizes. Our results suggest that, in natural group chat settings, an AI facilitator can match human quality while remaining difficult to identify as nonhuman.</description><author>Mateusz Jacniacki, Martí Carmona Serrat</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:34:42 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17315v1</guid></item><item><title>Fairness Evaluation of Large Language Models in Academic Library Reference Services</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.04224v3</link><description>As libraries explore large language models (LLMs) for use in virtual reference services, a key question arises: Can LLMs serve all users equitably, regardless of demographics or social status? While they offer great potential for scalable support, LLMs may also reproduce societal biases embedded in their training data, risking the integrity of libraries' commitment to equitable service. To address this concern, we evaluate whether LLMs differentiate responses across user identities by prompting six state-of-the-art LLMs to assist patrons differing in sex, race/ethnicity, and institutional role. We find no evidence of differentiation by race or ethnicity, and only minor evidence of stereotypical bias against women in one model. LLMs demonstrate nuanced accommodation of institutional roles through the use of linguistic choices related to formality, politeness, and domain-specific vocabularies, reflecting professional norms rather than discriminatory treatment. These findings suggest that current LLMs show a promising degree of readiness to support equitable and contextually appropriate communication in academic library reference services.</description><author>Haining Wang, Jason Clark, Yueru Yan, Star Bradley, Ruiyang Chen, Yiqiong Zhang, Hengyi Fu, Zuoyu Tian</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:33:14 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.04224v3</guid></item><item><title>HazeMatching: Dehazing Light Microscopy Images with Guided Conditional Flow Matching</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.22397v5</link><description>Fluorescence microscopy is a major driver of scientific progress in the life sciences. Although high-end confocal microscopes are capable of filtering out-of-focus light, cheaper and more accessible microscopy modalities, such as widefield microscopy, can not, which consequently leads to hazy image data. Computational dehazing is trying to combine the best of both worlds, leading to cheap microscopy but crisp-looking images. The perception-distortion trade-off tells us that we can optimize either for data fidelity, e.g. low MSE or high PSNR, or for data realism, measured by perceptual metrics such as LPIPS or FID. Existing methods either prioritize fidelity at the expense of realism, or produce perceptually convincing results that lack quantitative accuracy. In this work, we propose HazeMatching, a novel iterative method for dehazing light microscopy images, which effectively balances these objectives. Our goal was to find a balanced trade-off between the fidelity of the dehazing results and the realism of individual predictions (samples). We achieve this by adapting the conditional flow matching framework by guiding the generative process with a hazy observation in the conditional velocity field. We evaluate HazeMatching on 5 datasets, covering both synthetic and real data, assessing both distortion and perceptual quality. Our method is compared against 11 baselines, achieving a consistent balance between fidelity and realism on average. Additionally, with calibration analysis, we show that HazeMatching produces well-calibrated predictions. Note that our method does not need an explicit degradation operator to exist, making it easily applicable on real microscopy data. All data used for training and evaluation and our code will be publicly available under a permissive license.</description><author>Anirban Ray, Ashesh, Florian Jug</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:31:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.22397v5</guid></item><item><title>Self-supervised denoising of raw tomography detector data for improved image reconstruction</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17312v1</link><description>Ultrafast electron beam X-ray computed tomography produces noisy data due to short measurement times, causing reconstruction artifacts and limiting overall image quality. To counteract these issues, two self-supervised deep learning methods for denoising of raw detector data were investigated and compared against a non-learning based denoising method. We found that the application of the deep-learning-based methods was able to enhance signal-to-noise ratios in the detector data and also led to consistent improvements of the reconstructed images, outperforming the non-learning based method.</description><author>Israt Jahan Tulin, Sebastian Starke, Dominic Windisch, André Bieberle, Peter Steinbach</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:30:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.17312v1</guid></item></channel></rss>