<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Arxivlarge language model customization</title><link></link><description>Arxiv paper</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 13:00:11 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.0.0</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>CHOPS: CHat with custOmer Profile Systems for Customer Service with LLMs</title><link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2404.01343v3</link><description>Businesses and software platforms are increasingly turning to Large LanguageModels (LLMs) such as GPT-3.5, GPT-4, GLM-3, and LLaMa-2 for chat assistancewith file access or as reasoning agents for customer service. However, currentLLM-based customer service models have limited integration with customerprofiles and lack the operational capabilities necessary for effective service.Moreover, existing API integrations emphasize diversity over the precision anderror avoidance essential in real-world customer service scenarios. To addressthese issues, we propose an LLM agent named CHOPS (CHat with custOmer Profilein existing System), designed to: (1) efficiently utilize existing databases orsystems for accessing user information or interacting with these systemsfollowing existing guidelines; (2) provide accurate and reasonable responses orcarry out required operations in the system while avoiding harmful operations;and (3) leverage a combination of small and large LLMs to achieve satisfyingperformance at a reasonable inference cost. We introduce a practical dataset,the CPHOS-dataset, which includes a database, guiding files, and QA pairscollected from CPHOS, an online platform that facilitates the organization ofsimulated Physics Olympiads for high school teachers and students. We haveconducted extensive experiments to validate the performance of our proposedCHOPS architecture using the CPHOS-dataset, with the aim of demonstrating howLLMs can enhance or serve as alternatives to human customer service. Code forour proposed architecture and dataset can be found at{https://github.com/JingzheShi/CHOPS}.</description><author>Jingzhe Shi, Jialuo Li, Qinwei Ma, Zaiwen Yang, Huan Ma, Lei Li</author><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 11:33:28 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://arxiv.org/abs/2404.01343v3</guid></item><item><title>Review-LLM: Harnessing Large Language Models for Personalized Review Generation</title><link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2407.07487v1</link><description>Product review generation is an important task in recommender systems, whichcould provide explanation and persuasiveness for the recommendation. Recently,Large Language Models (LLMs, e.g., ChatGPT) have shown superior text modelingand generating ability, which could be applied in review generation. However,directly applying the LLMs for generating reviews might be troubled by the``polite'' phenomenon of the LLMs and could not generate personalized reviews(e.g., negative reviews). In this paper, we propose Review-LLM that customizesLLMs for personalized review generation. Firstly, we construct the prompt inputby aggregating user historical behaviors, which include corresponding itemtitles and reviews. This enables the LLMs to capture user interest features andreview writing style. Secondly, we incorporate ratings as indicators ofsatisfaction into the prompt, which could further improve the model'sunderstanding of user preferences and the sentiment tendency control ofgenerated reviews. Finally, we feed the prompt text into LLMs, and useSupervised Fine-Tuning (SFT) to make the model generate personalized reviewsfor the given user and target item. Experimental results on the real-worlddataset show that our fine-tuned model could achieve better review generationperformance than existing close-source LLMs.</description><author>Qiyao Peng, Hongtao Liu, Hongyan Xu, Qing Yang, Minglai Shao, Wenjun Wang</author><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 09:22:19 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://arxiv.org/abs/2407.07487v1</guid></item><item><title>PANGeA: Procedural Artificial Narrative using Generative AI for Turn-Based Video Games</title><link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2404.19721v3</link><description>This research introduces Procedural Artificial Narrative using Generative AI(PANGeA), a structured approach for leveraging large language models (LLMs),guided by a game designer's high-level criteria, to generate narrative contentfor turn-based role-playing video games (RPGs). Distinct from priorapplications of LLMs used for video game design, PANGeA innovates by not onlygenerating game level data (which includes, but is not limited to, setting, keyitems, and non-playable characters (NPCs)), but by also fostering dynamic,free-form interactions between the player and the environment that align withthe procedural game narrative. The NPCs generated by PANGeA arepersonality-biased and express traits from the Big 5 Personality Model in theirgenerated responses. PANGeA addresses challenges behind ingesting free-formtext input, which can prompt LLM responses beyond the scope of the gamenarrative. A novel validation system that uses the LLM's intelligence evaluatestext input and aligns generated responses with the unfolding narrative. Makingthese interactions possible, PANGeA is supported by a server that hosts acustom memory system that supplies context for augmenting generated responsesthus aligning them with the procedural narrative. For its broad application,the server has a REST interface enabling any game engine to integrate directlywith PANGeA, as well as an LLM interface adaptable with local or private LLMs.PANGeA's ability to foster dynamic narrative generation by aligning responseswith the procedural narrative is demonstrated through an empirical study andablation test of two versions of a demo game. These are, a custom,browser-based GPT and a Unity demo. As the results show, PANGeA holds potentialto assist game designers in using LLMs to generate narrative-consistent contenteven when provided varied and unpredictable, free-form text input.</description><author>Steph Buongiorno, Lawrence Jake Klinkert, Tanishq Chawla, Zixin Zhuang, Corey Clark</author><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 23:45:27 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://arxiv.org/abs/2404.19721v3</guid></item><item><title>FlowLearn: Evaluating Large Vision-Language Models on Flowchart Understanding</title><link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2407.05183v2</link><description>Flowcharts are graphical tools for representing complex concepts in concisevisual representations. This paper introduces the FlowLearn dataset, a resourcetailored to enhance the understanding of flowcharts. FlowLearn contains complexscientific flowcharts and simulated flowcharts. The scientific subset contains3,858 flowcharts sourced from scientific literature and the simulated subsetcontains 10,000 flowcharts created using a customizable script. The dataset isenriched with annotations for visual components, OCR, Mermaid coderepresentation, and VQA question-answer pairs. Despite the proven capabilitiesof Large Vision-Language Models (LVLMs) in various visual understanding tasks,their effectiveness in decoding flowcharts - a crucial element of scientificcommunication - has yet to be thoroughly investigated. The FlowLearn test setis crafted to assess the performance of LVLMs in flowchart comprehension. Ourstudy thoroughly evaluates state-of-the-art LVLMs, identifying existinglimitations and establishing a foundation for future enhancements in thisrelatively underexplored domain. For instance, in tasks involving simulatedflowcharts, GPT-4V achieved the highest accuracy (58%) in counting the numberof nodes, while Claude recorded the highest accuracy (83%) in OCR tasks.Notably, no single model excels in all tasks within the FlowLearn framework,highlighting significant opportunities for further development.</description><author>Huitong Pan, Qi Zhang, Cornelia Caragea, Eduard Dragut, Longin Jan Latecki</author><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 21:16:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://arxiv.org/abs/2407.05183v2</guid></item></channel></rss>