<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Arxivlarge language model grounding</title><link></link><description>Arxiv paper</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 18:35:02 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.0.0</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Evaluating Large Language Models with Grid-Based Game Competitions: An Extensible LLM Benchmark and Leaderboard</title><link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2407.07796v1</link><description>We introduce a novel and extensible benchmark for large language models(LLMs) through grid-based games such as Tic-Tac-Toe, Connect-Four, and Gomoku.The open-source game simulation code, available on GitHub, allows LLMs tocompete and generates detailed data files in JSON, CSV, TXT, and PNG formatsfor leaderboard rankings and further analysis. We present the results of gamesamong leading LLMs, including Claude 3.5 Sonnet and Claude 3 Sonnet byAnthropic, Gemini 1.5 Pro and Gemini 1.5 Flash by Google, GPT-4 Turbo andGPT-4o by OpenAI, and Llama3-70B by Meta. We also encourage submissions ofresults from other LLMs. In total, we simulated 2,310 matches (5 sessions foreach pair among 7 LLMs and a random player) across three types of games, usingthree distinct prompt types: list, illustration, and image. The resultsrevealed significant variations in LLM performance across different games andprompt types, with analysis covering win and disqualification rates, missedopportunity analysis, and invalid move analysis. The details of the leaderboardand result matrix data are available as open-access data on GitHub. This studyenhances our understanding of LLMs' capabilities in playing games they were notspecifically trained for, helping to assess their rule comprehension andstrategic thinking. On the path to Artificial General Intelligence (AGI), thisstudy lays the groundwork for future exploration into their utility in complexdecision-making scenarios, illuminating their strategic thinking abilities andoffering directions for further inquiry into the limits of LLMs withingame-based frameworks.</description><author>Oguzhan Topsakal, Colby Jacob Edell, Jackson Bailey Harper</author><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 16:14:34 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://arxiv.org/abs/2407.07796v1</guid></item><item><title>Using Natural Language Explanations to Rescale Human Judgments</title><link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.14770v3</link><description>The rise of large language models (LLMs) has brought a critical need forhigh-quality human-labeled data, particularly for processes like human feedbackand evaluation. A common practice is to label data via consensus annotationover human judgments. However, annotators' judgments for subjective tasks candiffer in many ways: they may reflect different qualitative judgments about anexample, and they may be mapped to a labeling scheme in different ways. We showthat these nuances can be captured by natural language explanations, andpropose a method to rescale ordinal annotations and explanations using LLMs.Specifically, we feed annotators' Likert ratings and corresponding explanationsinto an LLM and prompt it to produce a numeric score anchored in a scoringrubric. These scores should reflect the annotators' underlying assessments ofthe example. The rubric can be designed or modified after annotation, andinclude distinctions that may not have been known when the original errortaxonomy was devised. We explore our technique in the context of rating systemoutputs for a document-grounded question answering task, where LLMs achievenear-human performance. Our method rescales the raw judgments without impactingagreement and brings the scores closer to human judgments grounded in the samescoring rubric.</description><author>Manya Wadhwa, Jifan Chen, Junyi Jessy Li, Greg Durrett</author><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 15:03:44 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.14770v3</guid></item><item><title>Training A Small Emotional Vision Language Model for Visual Art Comprehension</title><link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2403.11150v2</link><description>This paper develops small vision language models to understand visual art,which, given an art work, aims to identify its emotion category and explainthis prediction with natural language. While small models are computationallyefficient, their capacity is much limited compared with large models. To breakthis trade-off, this paper builds a small emotional vision language model(SEVLM) by emotion modeling and input-output feature alignment. On the onehand, based on valence-arousal-dominance (VAD) knowledge annotated bypsychology experts, we introduce and fuse emotional features derived throughVAD dictionary and a VAD head to align VAD vectors of predicted emotionexplanation and the ground truth. This allows the vision language model tobetter understand and generate emotional texts, compared with using traditionaltext embeddings alone. On the other hand, we design a contrastive head to pullclose embeddings of the image, its emotion class, and explanation, which alignsmodel outputs and inputs. On two public affective explanation datasets, we showthat the proposed techniques consistently improve the visual art understandingperformance of baseline SEVLMs. Importantly, the proposed model can be trainedand evaluated on a single RTX 2080 Ti while exhibiting very strong performance:it not only outperforms the state-of-the-art small models but is alsocompetitive compared with LLaVA 7B after fine-tuning and GPT4(V). The code isavailable at https://github.com/BetterZH/SEVLM-code.</description><author>Jing Zhang, Liang Zheng, Meng Wang, Dan Guo</author><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 13:26:48 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://arxiv.org/abs/2403.11150v2</guid></item></channel></rss>